<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="rte">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:38:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Government to support IAG's bid for Aer Lingus</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703784-aer-lingus-sale/</Link>
        <Description>The Government is to support IAG's proposed takeover offer for Aer Lingus.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Speaking at a press conference, Mr Donohoe said the takeover was the "best way for securing Aer Lingus' future in an increasingly competitive airline market".
In addition, he said the sale would be the "best means of securing and enhancing Irelands connectivity with the rest of the world, and maintaining a vibrant and competitive air transport industry in Ireland".
Mr Donohoe said the deal would also be in the best interests of consumers and the wider tourism industry here.
Paschal Donohue says Govt has decided that it will support IAGs proposed takeover offer for Aer Lingus https://t.co/HKHWZvqG56
 RT News (@rtenews) May 26, 2015
Mr Donohoesaid the Government had obtained clear assurances from IAG - which were stronger than the assurances currently in place.
This will seetheAer Lingus brandremain, as will its head office in Dublin.
IAG has also saidit plans to grow the airline and potentially add an extra 635 new jobs by the end of the decade.
Press conference by Paschal Donohoe on decision to support IAG's proposed takeover offer for Aer Lingus
The companyalso assured the minister there were no plans for compulsory redundancy, while it has agreed to include "legally binding" agreements in its offer letter in relation to Aer Lingus' Heathrow slots and other routes.
The existing slots at Heathrow will remain under Aer Lingus control and is "unlimited" in time.
Mr Donohoe said the Government will receive 335m for its stake in Aer Lingus butwill retain oneshare in the airline.
Mr Donohoe said the sale proceeds would be used for a new connectivity fund under the State's Strategic Investment Fund.
There has been mixed reaction to the Government's decision this evening .
Aer Lingus said: "This is a compelling transaction for Aer Lingus, its shareholders, its employees, its customers and for Ireland."
It added:"The company will reap the commercial and strategic benefits of being part of the much larger and globally diverse IAG Group and as a member of the oneworld alliance of 17 airlines that together carry over 500 million passengers."
However, theIMPACT trade union "maintains the view that the proposed takeover of Aer Lingus is bad for jobs, for Aer Lingus workers and for Ireland's connectivity and economic development.
"The union remains concerned that any assurances given by either company offers no real guarantees to address these concerns."
IAG said the deal "is expected to provide substantial benefits to both IAG and Aer Lingus customers through an enhanced network, particularly toNorth America, using Dublin as a natural gateway hub for transatlantic routes".
In a statement released following the Government's decision , it said the company "hasagreed the basis for legally binding commitments with the Government of Ireland which ensure that Aer Lingus will continue to hold its existing slots at London Heathrow".
IAG reiterated some of the assurances given as part of its offer, andsaid Aer Lingus will operate its current daily winter and summer scheduled frequencies between London Heathrow and Dublin, Cork and Shannon for at least seven years.
It added that it would operate the airlines other London Heathrow slots on routes to and from airports on the island of Ireland for five years post acquisition.
Furthermore, "Aer Lingus will operate all of its scheduled international air transport passenger services under the Aer Lingus brand, and maintain Aer Lingus as its registered name and its head office and place of incorporation in the Republic of Ireland, in each case unless otherwise agreed by the Minister for Finance of Ireland."
The group also said the offer was conditional on Ryanair accepting the offer and selling all its Aer Lingus shares to IAG.
Ryanair said the airline'sboard has not yet received any offer from IAG for its Aer Lingus shares and will not be commenting until it does receive an offer.
If and when it does receive an offer it will consider it on its merits.
Aer Lingus CEO gives assurances over jobs
Earlier, the CEO of Aer Lingus has saidhe did not expect compulsory redundancies, or the increased use of agency staffat the airline, if it is acquired byIAG.
In aletter to Minister Donohoe , Stephen Kavanagh saidAer Lingus has a "strong preference"to directly employ people "wherever this can be done efficiently and effectively".
He also saidthe airline's preference is to continue to use Irish crew bases - provided it continues to be as competitive and efficient as at present - and to only restructure its business when required.
In the letter Mr Kavanagh saidemployment and union-relationsissues remain the responsibility of individual companies within IAG, meaning that these preferences should not change if a takeover goes ahead.
The airline also committed to expanding its existing registered employment agreements in order to include staff not already covered by them, he said.
"We believe that the collective agreements that we currently have provide flexibility and mobility across our workforce without unduly restricting other possible approaches," Mr Kavanagh says.
"Having clear registered employment agreements that safeguard the respective interests of employees and the company is mutually beneficial."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:42:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mixed reaction to Cabinet's decision on Aer Lingus</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/704012-aer-lingus-reaction/</Link>
        <Description>The IMPACT trade union said it maintained the view that the proposed takeover of Aer Lingus is "bad for jobs", while employers' group Ibec welcomed new commitments on connectivity.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The IMPACT trade union said it maintained the view that the proposed takeover is "bad for jobs, for Aer Lingus workers and for Ireland's connectivity and economic development".
In a statement, the union said it remains concerned that any assurances given by either company offers no real guarantees to address these concerns.
"For the staff at Aer Lingus, there are genuine concerns of compulsory redundancies if the deal goes through, along with the prospect of a further erosion of terms and conditions in the inevitable restructuring of the company.
"Any assurances on the future use of the Heathrow slots will evaporate once the seven-year period has elapsed, after which these vital connection points can be moved to where they will make larger profits for the airline."
However, employers'group Ibec said the takeover had the potential to improve air connectivity to Ireland over the coming years, which would bring with it significant business and tourism benefits.
The group "welcomed the additional commitment to protect vital connectivity to the regions in the latest IAG proposal".
Ibec Director of Policy and Corporate Affairs Mary Rose Burke said: "IAG's plan to use Aer Lingus as a springboard for further growth on the key North Atlantic routes could significantly increase the number and frequency of routes to and from Ireland.
"This will make the country more attractive as both an investment location and tourism destination.
"It will make visiting Ireland and doing business out of Ireland much easier for many."
SIPTU has said it will "vigorously oppose" the plan
SIPTU organiser Owen Reid, said: "SIPTU has been consistent with its position that the Government should not consider any sale, unless a legally binding commitment, such as a Register Employment Agreement, which directly addresses the issues of compulsory redundancies and no outsourcing of functions is agreed by the company."
He added: "Regrettably, it seems this is not the case. The workers who have made a huge contribution towards making Aer Lingus the success story it is today will ask the question why other legal guarantees can be entered into but not ones that give them some certainty.
"We will be calling on government and other TDs to vote against the Dil motion to sell the States remaining shares in Aer Lingus. SIPTU members will also resist by all means open to them any attempts by Aer Lingus to outsource functions or to pursue compulsory redundancies."
Tourism Ireland said the decision represents a major boost for tourism from North America.
In a statement, it said it "has the capacity to significantly increase both visitor numbers and revenue from one of Ireland's most important tourism markets".
The Irish Aviation Authority said it welcomes the Government's decision.

IAA Chief Executive Eamonn Brennansaid:"We believe that the proposal as approved by the Government offers significant benefits to Irish aviation, including guaranteed access to London Heathrow from Dublin, Cork and Shannon airports for a sustained period of time."
The DAA, which operates Dublin and Cork airports, welcomed the Government's decision.
DAA Chief Executive Kevin Toland said: "We believe that this transaction, should it be completed, offers significant potential benefits for both Dublin Airport and Cork Airport."
"Dublin Airport is already becoming a significant hub for transatlantic travel and this market segment would be further strengthened with IAG as the owner of Aer Lingus.
"This should enable additional long-haul connections and frequencies into Dublin's existing transatlantic hub."
Chambers Ireland also welcomed the announcement. CEO Ian Talbot said: "The Government has taken on board the concerns of Chambers around the country when considering IAG's proposed offer for its stake in Aer Lingus.
"The commitments made on the continuity of Heathrow slots and the potential to expand routes, and further develop links to North America in particular, will create significant opportunity for further economic growth and development."
The Chairman of Shannon Group, which operates Shannon Airport said the decision was a "positive opportunity for Ireland" which would safeguard the region's connectivity to Heathrow for a number of years.
"We are delighted that IAG has committed not only to sustain and strengthen Shannon's existing Aer Lingus services after the takeover but also to pursue furthergrowthopportunities from Shannon to NorthAmerica," chairmanRose Hynes said.
Management at Ireland West Airport has welcomed the Government's decision.
In a statement tonight, the airport said the sale would have positive implications for the facility by enhancing an existing service to London Gatwick and bringing the possibility of new routes out of Knock.
The Airport's Managing Director, Joe Gilmore, said he looked forward to actively working with IAG and Aer Lingus should the takeover proceed.
Filte Ireland also welcomed the decision, saying that the acquisition would help the long-term development of tourism in the country.
"As an island nation, air access is the lifeblood of Irish tourism and today's developments offer greater certainty regarding Aer Lingus' long term sustainability and, consequently, the continued growth of our tourism industry," saidFilte Ireland CEO Shaun Quinn.
Dublin Chamber of Commerce backed the news, saying:"The decision regarding whether to sell the State stake in Aer Lingus was never going to be easy.
"IAG has stated an intention to use the acquisition of Aer Lingus as a lever to grow transfer traffic at Irish airports. This would represent good news for Irish business travellers and consumers and would increase the likelihood of other airlines adding new routes or increasing capacity in and out of Dublin."
Meanwhile Aer Lingus'chairman Colm Barrington described theproposed deal as a "compelling transaction".
"The company will reap the commercial and strategic benefits of being part of the much larger and globally diverse IAG Group," he said.
Sinn Fin Transport Spokesperson Dessie Ellis said the decision is a bad deal for Ireland.
In a statement, he said: "I have grave concerns for the effect it will have on Ireland's connectivity into the future as well as the threat it poses to workers in Aer Lingus and to deferred pension members."
Before the announcement,SIPTU, the largest trade union at Aer Lingus, saidit wantedguarantees for existing workers at the airline that there will be no outsourcing or compulsory redundancies as part of the proposed saleto IAG.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:33:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stormont welfare reform bill fails</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703809-north-welfare/</Link>
        <Description>The Stormont Assembly has rejected a proposed bill on welfare reform.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
During the debate that began this morning, sharp divisions emerged between the two main partiesleading the power-sharing administration, the DUP and Sinn Fin. 
The DUP's Arlene Foster said Sinn Fin's position was influenced by electoral considerations in the south and accused it of indulging in fantasy politics. 
But Sinn Fin's Martin McGuinness, Northern Ireland's Deputy First Minister, said: "the crisis we are facing is not of the making of the parties in the Executive.
"It has been created by the austerity cuts agenda of a Tory administration in London, which is attempting to decimate our public services and punish the most vulnerable people in society."
Minister for Foreign Affairs Charlie Flanagan earlier said the impasse over welfare reforms in Northern Ireland has serious implications for the stability of the political institutions at Stormont.
He said the Government has agreed that every effort must be made to encourage the parties to reach an agreement that is "politically acceptable and financially viable".
Introducing the welfare reforms was a key plank of December's Stormont House Agreement.
Failure to introduce the changeswill endanger other deals struck at Stormont, such as the devolution of corporation tax powers and new structures to address the legacy of the Troubles.
But it will also pose a real existential threat to the Executive, as ministers will have failed to remove the burden of Treasury penalties for non-implementation, which are currently running at around 10 million a month.
DUP First Minister Peter Robinson was absent from the debate after suffering a suspected heart attack yesterday morning.
He was visited in Belfast's Royal Victoria Hospital tonight by two of his party colleagues, DUP Chairman, Maurice Morrow and Deputy Chairman, Rev Willie McCrea. 
He is said to be making good progress after a procedure yesterday. Mr Robinson was briefed about developments at Stormont.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:11:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man charged with indecently assaulting 10 children</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703845-abuse-arrest/</Link>
        <Description>A judge has ordered that the name of a 76-year-old man accused of abusing ten children over a 12-year period can be published.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Judge Cormac Dunneruled that the media could identify the accused following an application by RT.
Mr O'Brien was arrested this morningby garda from the Child Protection Unit and charged with 75counts of indecent assault on ten children - all male.
One of the indecent assault charges at St Patrick's Cathedral relates to a three-year period from 1977 to 1980, while another spans four years from 1978 to 1982.
Detective Garda Anthony Moloney from the Child Protection and Human Exploitation Bureau told the court that he arrested MrO'Brien at 8.10amand when he was charged he replied "no comment" to each of thealleged offences.
There was no garda objection to bail and no application for legal aid.
Judge Dunne granted MrO'Brien bail on his own bond of 500on condition that he surrender his passport, sign on daily and live at the same address on the charge sheet.
The judge also said it was implicit that he was not to interfere with witnesses.
Mr O'Brienwas remanded to appear in court againfor service of the Book of Evidenceon28July.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:36:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Europe to consider mandatory corporate tax base</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/704005-europe-commission-tax/</Link>
        <Description>The European Commission is to consider moves towards a mandatory corporate tax base across the European Union, RTÉ News has learned.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Tuesday 26 May 2015 19.36
The European Commission wants to discourage the use of sophisticated schemes aimed at reducing a company's tax burden
The European Commission is to consider moves towards a mandatory corporate tax base across the European Union, RT News has learned.
The idea comes amid deepening activity at EU level on the corporate tax issue, following recent allegations that multinationals have been involved in sophisticated schemes to avoid paying tax.
According to a discussion paper, seen by RT News, the Commission will examine the idea of a mandatory corporate tax base, so that there are common rules across the EU on which part of a company's profits can be taxed.
The paper describes the idea of a mandatory corporate tax base as "fundamental".
However, this would not be the same as a common tax rate, officials stress.
Following the so-called Luxleaks scandal, which revealed a system of alleged corporate tax avoidance involving some 300 companies and operating through Luxembourg, the Commission has been planning for some time to re-launch tighter rules on corporate taxation.
The Commission will publish its plans on 17 June, with all 28 commissioners - including Ireland's Phil Hogan - debating the issues tomorrow.
The discussion paper, which has been circulated among commissioners, suggests making a common corporate tax base "mandatory" to prevent multinationals shifting profits from one member state to another in order to minimise their tax liability.
A common tax base would mean harmonised rules on what can and cannot be offset against company profits for tax purposes.
The idea of creating a common tax base has been in the pipeline of EU legislation for several years, but it has been hampered by a lack of consensus among member states.
The issue looks in particular at how and where multinationals, which may have subsidiaries in several EU member states, pay tax and on what.
Part of the approach has been to make the tax base "consolidated."
This would mean adding up all the profits and losses of a company or group of companies with operations in different member states, in order to arrive at a net profit or loss for the whole of its activity in the EU.
An agreed formula would then be used to decide the final taxable base of the company or group of companies.
However, the formula method has proved highly contentious in discussions between member states and the European Commission in recent years.
For that reason, the Commission is considering postponing that element and in the meantime making a straightforward corporate base mandatory.
Although the Government here has long had reservations about CCCTB, it is understood that Dublin could see advantages in a straightforward harmonised tax base.
The reasoning is that if a multinational has clarity on the tax base in each member state it can then chose a country which has the most attractive corporate tax rate.
Government sources also denied a report in the German paper Handelsblatt that the Commission will propose a minimum corporate tax rate following pressure from Germany and France.
It is understood, however, that the Commission will discuss the idea of requiring multinational corporations to publish the tax arrangements they have in each member state.
The practice in several OECD countries is for multinationals to provide such information to the tax authorities, but not to make it publicly available.
It is understood the Government would have reservations about multinationals publicly disclosing tax arrangements as it would increase their regulatory burden.
Ireland is currently being investigated by the European Commission for is tax arrangements with Apple.
The Commission believes that two tax deals between Apple and Revenue in 1991 and 2007 amounted to preferential treatment, and therefore illegal state aid.
The Government has denied the charge and has vowed to challenge any finding against it at the European Court of Justice in Luxembourg.
The Netherlands and Luxembourg are also being investigated in relation to alleged tax rulings with Starbucks, Amazon and Fiat respectively.
Taxation remains a national competence with member states enjoying a veto on any EU tax rules. 
Due to the lack of agreement on CCCTB there was a proposal that a group of countries could forge ahead on their own with a CCCTB according to the method known as "enhanced cooperation."
Because tax remains a national competence there is some scepticism that a common tax base could be made mandatory.
Following the financial crisis in 2008-2009 the European Commission pushed the idea of CCCTB as a way of boosting the single market and the European economy, since harmonising the rules would give multinationals clarity when deciding to invest in the EU.
However, the issue failed to gain widespread support among member states.
Despite that, growing public disquiet over global corporations allegedly avoiding their tax obligations has pushed the issue centre stage once again.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:00:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kenny: No vote on Eighth Amendment before election</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703828-voting/</Link>
        <Description>Taoiseach Enda Kenny has told the Dáil that "there are great sensitivities that need to be carefully considered and there will not be a repeal of the Eighth Amendment in the lifetime of this Government".</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Mr Murphy asked for a referendum on the repeal of the Eighth Amendment to end the "barbaric" situation where a woman who terminates a pregnancy even in the case of fatal foetal abnormality faces the threat of 14 years in prison.
The Taoiseach said that Friday's vote demonstrates the importance of politics and he said that a big message from a small country was sent out.
He said that he does not believe the Dil should be "rushed into a situation" where it deals with something so sensitive as fatal-foetal abnormalities.
He said that in same-sex marriage people could point out exactly what the consequences of such a move would be but that is not possible in terms of repeal of the Eighth Amendment.
Mr Kenny said that referendum on marriage equality was about love, commitment and dedication. He said that a repeal of the Eighth Amendment deals with other elements that are not clear at all.
Mr Murphy said that last Friday marked a cry for a different type of society and the amendment is central to that.
He said that 20,000 women have travelled for abortions in the life of this country.
He recalled Savita Halappanavar and other cases and said that at the very least the Government should commit to have a referendum in the course of this Dil term.
The Taoiseach said the people voted in the referendum and that was interpreted by the Supreme Court and no government dealt with that until this Government introduced legislation; the Protection of Life During Pregnancy Act.
He said there will not be a referendum on this issue under this Government.
No referendum on voting rights before general election - Deenihan
No referendum on voting rights - Deenihan
Minister of State with responsibility for Diaspora AffairsJimmy Deenihan earlier said he cannot see a referendum taking place before the next general election to extend voting rights in presidential elections to Irish citizens living outside the State.
TDs will give their views in the Dil later today on broadening voting rights in presidential elections to Irish citizens who live abroad.
It follows a recommendation of the Constitutional Convention in 2013 to do so.
No referendum on voting rights - Deenihan
Speaking on RT's Morning Ireland, Mr Deenihan defended the delay in acting over the issue.
He said that there is plenty of time to change voting legislation before the next presidential election in 2018.
Mr Deenihan said there are around one million active Irish passport holders abroad.
However, hesaid this number may be greater as many more people may be entitled to an Irish passport.
Speaking on the same programme,Conor O'Neill said extending the vote for presidential elections would be a good stepping stone, butit cannot be the end of the issue.
Mr O'Neill is a recent Irish emigrant living in Brussels and co-founder of the group'We're Coming Back', which advocates for voting rights for Irish citizens abroad.
He said the efforts of all those who returned home to vote in Friday's referendums highlights that emigrants are keen to engage in matters of State.
He said because of the logistics of organising it, the 2018 presidential election would realistically be the first opportunity.
When asked about emigrant voting rights in the Seanad elections, Mr Deenihan said he would be in favour of it but would not clarify as to whether it would happen in the lifetime of this Government.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:55:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stay put on injunction at Dunnes Stores in Gorey</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703930-dunnes-story-gorey/</Link>
        <Description>A two-month stay has been placed on a High Court injunction linked to the closure of a branch of Dunnes Stores in Co Wexford to members of the public.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 26 May 2015 17.55
About 100 people are employed by Dunnes Stores at the Gorey store
A two-month stay has been placed on a High Court injunction linked to the closure of a branch of Dunnes Stores in Co Wexford to members of the public.
Dunnes Stores shut the branchat Gorey Shopping Centrelast Thursday after the High Court granted an injunction preventing the company from continuing to use a door that opened directly onto the centre's carpark.
The injunction was obtained by Paul McCann of Grant Thornton, who was appointed by AIB as receiver to run the centre.
Lawyers for the receiver argued the use of the door was a breach of Dunnes' lease obligations and the net effect was that customers could bypass smaller traders in the shopping centre.
Dunnes Stores had opposed the application, and urged the court not to grant the injunction.
In a ruling late last week, Mr Justice Brian McGovern granted the injunction preventing the supermarket chain from using the door that directly opened onto the carpark as an entrance to the store.
It was also ordered that the only entrance that could be used was the main entrance to the shopping centre.
At a vacation sitting of the High Court today, Mr Justice Donald Binchy was informed that both sides were consenting to a stay being placed on the injunction for a period of two months.
In what was a brief application, barrister Edward Farrelly Bl said the move was to allow the two sides, and "other stakeholders", to "engage with each other", in a bid to resolve the matter.
The court also heard the stay would not prejudice Dunnes Stores' right to appeal Mr Justice McGovern's decision to grant the injunction.
Mr Justice Binchy, in adjourning the matter, agreed to place the stay on the injunction until 24 July.
The court was not told if the Co Wexford store is to be reopened to the public or not.
Approximately 100 people are employed by Dunnes Stores at the Co Wexford store.
The closure of the store to the public had been criticised by trade Union Mandate, which represents workers at the store.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:33:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Aylward takes up seat at Leinster House</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703851-averil-power-fianna-fail/</Link>
        <Description>Bobby Aylward arrived in Leinster House today on the back of his victory in the Carlow-Kilkenny by-election, but the row over Averil Power's departure from Fianna Fáil continued.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Ms Power yesterday announced that she wasquittingthe party and said she will continue in politics as an independent.
Mr Aylwardwas flanked by supporters and the parliamentary party, minus Senator Power, as he arrived at Leinster House.
He said he would focus on the issues raised by his constituents.
The new deputy was announced and congratulated in the Dil, but Taoiseach Enda Kenny made reference to the party's recent woes, saying: "You win some, you lose some."
Mr Aylward's director of elections, Barry Cowen, said Ms Power's decision to leave the party had overshadowed his arrival.
However, he said it should not have been the case as he said the party had worked through other divisive referendum campaigns.
Ms Power said the coordinated personal attacks against her over the last 24 hours were hurtful and an attempt by the party to minimise the damage to the party.
Fianna Fil TDs criticise Power's resignation
Fianna Fil justice spokesperson Niall Collins todaycriticised the way SenatorPower left the party.
Ms Power hadsaidmany Fianna Fil TDs and senators had not canvassed for the same-sex marriage referendum andthat was the "final straw"for her.
Speaking on RT'sToday with Keelin Shanley, MrCollins said that he was disappointed with Ms Power'sdecision to leave the party and the manner in which she did so.
He also rejected Senator Power's comments that the vast majority of Fianna Fil public representatives refused to campaign during the referendum.
He defended his involvement in the campaign, saying he was personally engaged in press conferences and media launches.
He said: "I was very disappointed with Averil's decision yesterday and indeed the manner in which she made her announcement without at least giving Michel Martinthe respect that he deserved in terms of contacting him beforehand to discuss it with him, given the amount of political capital Martin invested in Averil Power."
Senator Power has said she feels she has been "personally attacked"by members of Fianna Fil following her departure from the party.
Speaking on the same programme, she said she is disappointed by the tone from the party after yesterday's events.
Responding to comments made by Mr Collins, she said: "I would have hoped that instead of going on a personal attack that they would have actually dealt with issues that I've raised.
"To say that they didn't know I was unhappy is just completely untrue. I've raised issues at parliamentary parties. It was clear I was unhappy."
Mr Collins saidSenator Power never expressed any concern to him, as the party's director of elections, about Fianna Fil's campaign during that time.
He said Fianna Fil engaged in a very vibrant campaign right across the country but acknowledged that some party representatives did notpull their weight.
He said: "I think it is fair to say you could point to TDs in all of the political parties ... who you could say allegedly didn't pull their weight.
"From that point of view, she might have a valid criticism there but I think that's a valid criticism forsome members within all parties."
Haughey did not canvasfor Yes vote
Fianna Fil councillor for Dublin Bay North Sean Haughey has saidhe did not canvas for aYesvote in the same-sex marriage referendum because he did not have the conviction to do so, as he wanted to listen to both sides of the debate.
But he said he had not let his party down by not campaigning.
Mr Haugheysaid: "I felt that I couldn't canvass with conviction and that I wanted to listen to all the arguments and I listened to the arguments right up to polling day.
"I'm passionate about our country and oursociety and the way it should develop and at the end of the day, it's a secret ballot."
He also saidhe was sorry to see SenatorPower leave the party.
Mr Haughey said hewas confident shewould have been on the Fianna Fil ticket for the constituency in the next general election.
He said while he had not discussed the matter with MrMartin, he"always felt hopeful that I would come through the convention and I always understood that Senator Averil Power would be added to the ticket and I felt that would be a balanced ticket".
Party activist resigns in Cork
Meanwhile, theFianna Fil organisation in Cork city and county has been dealt a blow with the resignation of party activist Ken Curtin.
Mr Curtin, who was Fianna Fil's Public Relations Officerfor Cork Eastand secretary of the party'sCobh Cumann, announced on social media that he was resigning from both positions and from the party.
I've been crying a lot over last few days but today I'm crying having made a hugely tough decision to walk away from the party I loved
 Ken Curtin (@kencurtin) May 26, 2015
MrCurtin led the YesEquality Cork campaign and had expressed disquiet at the lack of party support on the ground for the campaign.
He hadflagged at the weekend that he would be considering his position.
He said he had reached his decision independently of Ms Power.
Mr Curtin said he felt that Fianna Fil was no longer a right fit for him and for people with a more liberal outlook.
He said their voices are being drowned out by very elderly, conservative voices.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:55:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>HSE reports deficit of €91m to end of March</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/704007-hse-budget/</Link>
        <Description>The Health Service Executive has reported a deficit to the end of March of €91m.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 26 May 2015 19.55
The HSE had a deficit of over 58m to the end of February
The Health Service Executive has reported a deficit to the end of March of 91m.
It compares with a deficit of over 58m to the end of February.
A large part of the overspend is on demand-led schemes, State clams and pensions, according to its latest performance report.
There were 405,000 patients waiting to be seen at an outpatient clinic, and 61,668 adults and 6,700 children waiting for day case, or inpatient treatment.
Inpatient admissions and outpatient attendances were up on the February figures.
Minister for Health Leo Varadkar said that while waiting times continue to worsen, the figures indicate that hospitals are starting to catch up on procedures that were cancelled in the busy January period.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:53:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At least 800 dead in India as temperatures soar</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703876-india-heatwave/</Link>
        <Description>At least 800 people have died in a heatwave in India as temperatures neared 50 Celsius and roads melted in the capital, New Delhi.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 26 May 2015 17.53
1 of 2
An Indian boy takes a bath at a fountain at India Gate in New Delhi
A man rests in the shelter of a tree in the city of Mumbai as the heatwave continues
At least 800 people have died in a heatwave in India as temperatures neared 50 Celsius.
Hospitals were on alert to treat victims of heatstroke and authorities advised people to stay indoors with no end in sight to the searing conditions.
In the southern state of Andhra Pradesh, worst-hit by the soaring temperatures, 551 people have died in the past week.
An official said the state government has instructed people not to go outside and to drink plenty of water.
He said:"We have also requested NGOs and government organisations to open up drinking water camps so that water will be readily available for all the people in the towns."
Large parts of India, including Delhi, have endured days of sweltering heat, prompting fears of power cuts asair conditioners work overtime.
The Hindustan Times daily said the maximum temperature in the capital hit a two-year high of 45.5Cyesterday - five degrees higher than the seasonal average.
The paper carried a front-page photo of a main road in the city melting in the heat, its zebra pedestrian crossing stripes curling and spreading into the asphalt.
In Telangana state, which borders Andhra Pradesh in the south, 231 people have died in the last week as temperatures hit 48C over the weekend.
In the western state of Orissa, 11 people were confirmed to have died from the heat.
India's Meteorological Department issued a "Red Box" warning for the state for today and tomorrow- meaning the maximum temperatures would remain above 45C.
Another 13 people have died in the eastern state of West Bengal, where unions urged drivers in the city of Kolkata to stay off the roads during the day.
Hundreds of people -mainly from the poorest sections of society - die at the height of summer every year across the country, while tens of thousands suffer power cuts from an overburdened electricity grid.
India's power industry has long struggled to meet rapidly rising demand in Asia's third largest economy, with poorly maintained transmission lines and overloaded grids.
With no end in sight to the hot, dry conditions, the Hindustan Times warned that some of the worst-affected states could be plunged into drought before the monsoon rains arrive.
The monsoon is forecast to hit the southern state of Kerala towards the end of this month before sweeping across the country, but it will be weeks before the rains reach the arid northern plains.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:12:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Most of Westport still under boil-water notice</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703960-westport-boil-water-notice/</Link>
        <Description>A boil-water notice remains in place for the vast majority of homes in Westport, Co Mayo, three weeks after an outbreak of cryptosporidium compromised the public supply.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Tuesday 26 May 2015 17.12
A swathe of residential areas south of the rail line through the town are still affected by the notice
A boil-water notice remains in place for the vast majority of homes in Westport, Co Mayo, three weeks after an outbreak of cryptosporidium compromised the public supply.
Irish Water has announced that certain areas in the town are no longer subject to the notice, after an alternative supply from Lough Mask was provided to the town centre.
While this eases the situation for many businesses, a swathe of residential areas south of the rail line through the town are still affected by the notice.
The boil notice was issued on 6 May, following an increase in the number of people presenting with symptoms of cryptosporidiosis.
In a statement this afternoon, Irish Water said the notice remained in place for those areas served by the Westport public supply.
Those affected by the notice are being told to boil tap water if they intend to drink it, prepare food, brush teeth, make ice or prepare infant feeds.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:18:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Appeal to trace missing Wexford man</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/704008-missing-karl-otoole/</Link>
        <Description>Gardaí have appealed for assistance tracing 30-year-old Karl O'Toole, who has been missing from Enniscorthy, Co Wexford since Saturday 23 May.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Tuesday 26 May 2015 20.18
Karl O'Toole was last seen in the area of Friary Hill, Enniscorthy on Saturday afternoon, at about 3pm
Garda have appealed for assistance tracing 30-year-old Karl OToole, who has been missing from Enniscorthy, Co Wexford since Saturday 23 May.
Mr OToole was last seen in the area of Friary Hill, Enniscorthy onSaturday afternoon, at about 3pm.
He is 1.83m(6) tall, of thin build, and is bald.
When last seen he was wearing a dark jacket and trousers. He also wore black shoes and was carrying a dark rucksack.
Garda are concerned for his welfare and anyone with information on his possible whereabouts is asked to contact them at Enniscorthy Garda Station on 053-9242580, the Garda Confidential Line 1800-666111 or any garda station.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:36:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Danish radio host kills baby rabbit live on air</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703961-denmark-radio-rabbit/</Link>
        <Description>A Danish radio DJ killed a baby rabbit with a bicycle pump live on air, prompting a storm of criticism despite claims it had simply wanted to highlight cruelty in farming.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 26 May 2015 22.36
Allan the baby rabbit pictured before he was killed during radio programme (Pic: Facebook/radio24syv)
A Danish radio DJ killed a baby rabbit with a bicycle pump live on air, prompting a storm of criticism despite claims it had simply wanted to highlight cruelty in farming.
"We didn't do it for the sake of entertainment," talk radio station Radio24syv wrote on Twitter.
"Thousands of animals die each day so that people can eat them," it added.
The broadcaster said radio host Asger Juhl killed the rabbit - named Allan - with repeated blows to the head to highlight "hypocrisy" in Danes' attitudes towards animal welfare.
"We buy and eat animals that have had an awful life. And animals that have been killed under the same controlled conditions as the rabbit in the studio," the station wrote in a statement.
Reality TV show star and animal rights activist Linse Kessler tried to grab the animal and chased Mr Juhl around the studio several times before being asked to leave.
"They wanted to see if they could kill him in the end or if they had gotten too attached to him," she said in a video clip on her Facebook page.
Ms Kessler said she thought she was capable of wresting the animal from Mr Juhl but feared it would die a more painful death if she grabbed it.
"I hit it hard over the neck twice so that the cervical vertebrae fractured," Mr Juhl told broadcaster TV 2.
"I was instructed by a zookeeper from Aalborg Zoo who hits several baby rabbits every week (to feed) the snakes," he added.
Mr Juhl said he had brought the dead rabbit to his home - where he skinned and cut it up with his children, aged six and eight - and that he later would have rabbit stew for dinner with fellow morning host Kristoffer Eriksen.
A Copenhagen zoo prompted international outrage last year by putting down a healthy giraffe, known as Marius, and then dissecting it in front of children.
That incident, just like the radio station's stunt, drew a mixed response in Denmark where agriculture is a key export industry.
"To provoke and to promote itself," Twitter user Steffen Andersen in Aarhus wrote, while journalist Brian Esbensen tweeted: "What if people were just as outraged over drowned refugees."
Radio24syv said it wanted to put more focus on "one of the world's most industrialised agriculture sectors."
Danish farming "allows 25,000 piglets to die every day because farming has been streamlined and (breeds) pigs that give birth to far more offspring than the mother pig can handle," it said.
International reactions on social media were overwhelmingly negative, with users calling the radio host "sick" and "sadistic", even after the station issued a statement in English on its Facebook page.
"Denmark is one of the top countries in the world when it comes to consumption of meat products and consumers do not hesitate to buy cheap meat in stores without asking questions," it said
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:34:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Parents warned over publishing images of children</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703926-online-pictures-parents/</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have claimed that some parents are sharing more than 900 images of their children online before the children's fifth birthday, despite many not checking their social network privacy settings.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 26 May 2015 18.34
Facebook is the most common platform for photo-sharing
Researchers have claimed that some parents are sharing more than 900 images of their children online before the children's fifth birthday, despite many not checking their social network privacy settings.
On average, 973 photos are posted online by parents before their children turn five, despite 17% of parents admitting they had never checked privacy settings.
Facebook is the most common platform for photo-sharing, with 53% of the 2,000 parents surveyed saying they have uploaded images of their children on the site.
Instagram was second with 14%, and more than one in ten (125) of parents uploadedimages of their chidren to Twitter.
Facebook enables users to limit who can see what they post to the site by tweaking privacy settings between public and private.
The research also claimed that 46%of those surveyed had only checked their settings once or twice.
Theresearch wascarried out by online safety site The Parent Zone on behalf of the UK safety campaign Knowthenet.
The campaign claims parents are running the risk of over-sharing and creating a digital footprint their child has no control over.
The Knowthenet campaign is being run by internet registry site Nominet, whose chief executive Russell Haworth said: "We all love to share those precious moments in our children's lives with friends and family and sites like Facebook have made it easier than ever.
"While the web helps relatives to keep in touch and participate in our everyday lives, it also has the potential to lead to accidental over-sharing.
"It's important to ensure that the correct privacy settings are in place to safeguard our personal information and content.
"Parents are creating a large digital footprint for their child from a young age and the right settings are important if you want to stay in control."
Parent Zone's founder Vicki Shotbolt said: "Today's youth is the first generation to grow up with social networks as an integral part of everyday life so it's important we stop and think about how they might feel about content that's shared now when they're older.
"No one would want a potential employer browsing through their baby photos, so making sure privacy settings are applied properly is always a good idea.
"Of course, parents should feel comfortable uploading photos to social networks but thinking about whether it's an appropriate image first will go a long way to avoiding any unwanted repercussions in the future."
The Knowthenet campaign also issued a list of tips to parents for sharing photos online.
It encouragesparentsto check their privacy settings and change them from the default, to thinkbefore they upload as well as staying up to date with updates to social media site terms of service and new features.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:34:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>6% increase in average farm income in 2014</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703887-average-farm-income-increased-6-in-2014/</Link>
        <Description>Farm incomes rose by 6% in 2014, thanks in part to declining input costs, according to Teagasc's National Farm survey.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The dairy sector had a particularly good year but the figures show that incomes of beef farm families fell and run at just one fifth of what diary farmers are earning.
This survey of farm incomes has been running for 40 years and aims to measure the financial performance of almost 80,000 family farms in Ireland.
Speaking at the launch of the survey, Dr Thia Hennessy of Teagascsaid while prices received for farm outputs fell, farmers benefited from good weather and a recovery from the 2013 fodder crisis.
Dairy farmers benefited from increased production in the lead-up to the abolition of milk quotas, however as a result of this some farmers were also penalised for over-production through superlevy bills.
A turbulent year in the beef sector sawlower slaughter prices lead to a12% fall in income for beef finishers.
Farmers involved in cattle rearing for the beef sector did however experience an 8% rise in income compared to 2013.
Income on sheep farms rose by 24% in 2014, although this is still lower than the average income recorded in 2012 following a steep fall in income in 2013.
Good growing conditions and falling prices combined to leave the average income on tillage farms almost unchanged at 28,468.
The average income on dairy farms was almost 69,000 in 2014, compared to an average of just over 10,000 on cattle rearing farms.
Less than 20%of Ireland's farms earned an income of 50,000 or more, while 40% earned less than 10,000.
The Teagasc report also noted farming continues to rely on direct payments, with the average direct payment of 18,859 comprising 70% of average farm income.
Responding to the figures, IFA President Eddie Downey said they show "profitability at farm level remains a major challenge".
Mr Downey also said the increase in income was due to a drop in input prices rather than due to stronger prices for farm produce.
The survey also shows the typical farmer in Ireland is now 57-years-old, the average farm is 47 hectares, and 51%of farm households have off farm employment.
It shows the average income subsidy payment to farmers was 19,000, but that without that income the average cattle and sheep farmers would have made no money at all.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:16:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Galway psychiatric nurses in industrial action</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703779-psychiatric-nurses/</Link>
        <Description>Psychiatric nurses at Galway University Hospital have started industrial action in a dispute over safety and staffing concerns.</Description>
        <MainBody>Last month, nurses at the Acute Psychiatric Unit at the hospitalrefused to go on dutyover concerns for their safety and that of patients.
The Psychiatric Nurses Association subsequently voted to begin industrial action.
From today staff are only carrying out essential, core duties at the unit.
The PNA saidit wants an agreed staff complement on the ward at all times, particularly given the need for some patients to have one-on-one care.
The union has called on the HSE to engage in "meaningful talks" and to lift the threat of sanctions against those who failed to report for work last month.
The HSE saidit is happy to explore the issues raised by the nurses and that it has already moved on staffing levels.
However, it saidit cannot ignore the failure of nurses to work and that this issue will have to be dealt with at some point.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:14:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>38 die in nursing home blaze in China</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703829-china-fire-nursing-home/</Link>
        <Description>A fire that broke out at a nursing home in China has killed 38 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chinese PresidentXi Jinpinghas called on officials to "identify the cause of the accident and pursue culpability in accordance with the law".
He also urged them to "resolutely prevent and curb all kinds of accidents from happening".
China has a history of similar disasters. Workers are often poorlytrained or ill-equipped to protect themselves from accidents.
A fire at a warehouse in Guangdong province killed at least 17 people lastFebruary, and a blaze at a poultry slaughterhouse in theprovince of Jilin in 2013 killed 120 people.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:46:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Family homelessness at 'another crisis point'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703778-homelessness/</Link>
        <Description>Homelessness charity Focus Ireland has warned family homelessness has reached yet another crisis point in Dublin</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Focus Ireland's Director of Advocacy Mike Allensaidthe charity is increasingly coming across families sleeping in cars or other inappropriate places.
The charity has written to Minister Kelly calling for an increase in rent supplement to match market rents to keep families in their existing homes.
Mr Allen saidwithout immediate action and resources, it is simply a matter of time before young children and their parents are sleeping on the streets.
He said while the charity iscurrently able to provide shelter for them, they are going to reach a point where they do not meet a family or they do not have the resources themselves.
He said Focus Ireland does not want this to become something that people take for granted.
"When you go to you Paris, you'll walk past families who are in tents sleeping on the side of the road.
"We want to make a very clear statement that Dublin does not want to be a city like that," Mr Allen said.
He added that this problem is becoming an issue in other cities including Cork and Galway.
The charity stressed that prevention is the best cure and an increase in rent supplement would keep families in their existing homes and prevent them becoming homeless.
In response to the figures, a spokesperson for Mr Kelly said a series of actions have andare being taken to address the situation for those facing homelessness.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:05:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News in Brief</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703783-news-in-brief/</Link>
        <Description>A round-up of Irish and international stories.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 26 May 2015 17.05
Benny Whitehouse was shot dead in his car in Balbriggan on 25 September 2014
Two arrested over fatal Balbriggan shooting
Two people have been arrested in connection with thefatal shooting of Benny Whitehouse in Balbriggan, Co Dublin last September.
Mr Whitehouse was shot deadin his car on Clonard Street on 25 September 2014.
A 34-year-old manand a 28-year-old womanare being detained at Balbriggan and Swords Garda stations.
Aggravated robbery at house in Co Wicklow
An investigation is under way into anaggravated robbery at a house in Laragh, Co Wicklow.
Just before midnight,a couple returned to their home and became aware there were a number of intruders in the house.
The woman raised the alarm.
The man was confronted by four masked men, one of whom was armed with what is believed to be a shotgun.
The intrudersescaped with a small amount of cash and a mobile phone.
Washington Post spy trial begins in Iran
The trial of Washington Post correspondent Jason Rezaian on espionage charges has completed its first day behind closed doors in Tehran, Iran's ISNA news agency reported.
Mr Rezaian, 39, is accused of "espionage, collaboration with hostile governments, gathering classified information and disseminating propaganda against the Islamic republic," according to his lawyer Leila Ahsan.
She has condemned the charges saying there is "no justifiable proof" to substantiate them.
Five Kenyan police wounded in al-Shabaab ambush
Five Kenyan police officers were wounded by Somali militants who attacked two patrols in rural areas in the east of the country, Kenya's police chief said, contradicting earlier reports that about 20 people were killed in the attacks.
Two officers were critically wounded and three sustained minor injuries when the patrols were attacked in the Fafi andYumbis areas.
Al-Shabaab said it killed 25 officers while local media had earlier put the death toll at about 20.
Burma reaches agreement to repatriate 200 migrants
Burma,also known as Myanmar, has said it has reached an agreement with neighbouring Bangladesh to repatriate 200 Bangladeshis rescued from a boat off the Burmese coast last week.
A migrant crisis has flared up in Southeast Asia as Rohingya Muslims fleeing persecution in Burma and Bangladeshis trying to escape poverty at home become prey to human traffickers.
After Thailand cracked down on the practice, traffickers began abandoning overloaded boats on the open sea rather than trying to smuggle travellers through Thailand.
Some 3,500 are stranded, the United Nations refugee agency has said.
Australia may scrap controversial tampon tax
The Australian government bowed to pressure and took the first step to end a controversial sales tax on women's sanitary products, a day after a student carrying a giant tampon confronted FederalTreasurer Joe Hockeyon television with a petition demanding change.
Other products like condoms and sunscreen are exempt from the 10% goods and services tax which is otherwise added to all items sold in Australia from day-to-day groceries to large-scale building materials.
Yesterday, university student Subeta Vimalarajah presented MrHockey with the result of an online petition which found that 90,000 people supported cutting the tax on sanitary items.
In a brief statement today, Mr Hockey said that once the Treasury calculates the cost of cutting the tax from sanitary products, "I will write to the states for them to consider the issue ahead of our next meeting in July".
Saudi beheads 88th person, exceeds 2014 total
The number of people beheaded in Saudi Arabia this year has overtaken the total for all of 2014, despite activists' concerns that trials are not conducted fairly.
According to AFP tallies, the executions of two Saudis for drug trafficking and a third for murder brought to 88 the number carried out in the conservative Islamic kingdom this year.
That exceeded the 87 death sentences carried out in 2014.
The interior ministry said two men were executed in the northern region of Jawf after they were convicted of smuggling amphetamines.
Thethird man was put to death in the southwestern region of Asir for a stabbing murder.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:30:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Volcano erupts on Galápagos Islands</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0526/703916-galapagos-islands-volcano/</Link>
        <Description>A volcano in the Galápagos Islands whose eruption raised fears for the world's only population of pink iguanas has calmed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 26 May 2015 19.30
The Wolf volcano has been dormant for the last 33 years
A volcano in the Galpagos Islands whose eruption raised fears for the world's only population of pink iguanas has calmed, sparing the unique critters from danger.
Wolf volcano is still showing signs of activity but has died down since puffing smoke and spilling bright orange streams of lava yesterday, officials at the Galapagos National Park and Ecuador's Geophysics Institute said.
Alexandra Alvarado of the Geophysics Institute said: "We haven't had any more explosions like yesterday's, which suggests a decrease in activity.
"However, there are still lava flows, which is normal in these cases."
The island, Isabela, is home to the only known pink land iguanas in the world.
The species, Conolophus marthae, lives at the foot of the volcano and is listed as critically endangered, with a population of only about 500.
The area, which is uninhabited by humans, is also home to members of a rare species of giant tortoise, Chelonoidis becki.
But the animals live on the northwest side of the volcano, opposite the lava flows, and appear to have been spared from harm, a park official said.
"We will likely carry out more flights over the area, but the pink iguanas are safe, and the tortoises, because the lava is flowing down the opposite side," the official said.
Wolf volcano had last erupted in 1982.
It is one of five volcanoes on Isabela island, the largest in the Galpagos.
The Pacific archipelago, which sits about 1,000km off the coast of Ecuador, was made famous by Charles Darwin's studies of its breathtaking biodiversity, which was crucial in his development of the theory of evolution by natural selection.
UNESCO, which has declared the Galpagos a World Heritage Site, has warned the islands' environment is in danger from increased tourism and the introduction of invasive species.
The pink iguanas, which were discovered in 1986, were established as a separate species in 2009 after an analysis of their genetic makeup determined they were distinct from their cousins, the Galapagos land iguanas.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
