<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="rte">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:08:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dáil backs sale of Government's Aer Lingus stake</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704294-aer-lingus/</Link>
        <Description>The Dáil has voted to sell the Government's 25.1% stake in Aer Lingus to International Consolidated Airlines Group (IAG).</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
"I spoke with the Minister for Transport, the Tnaiste, as well as experts in European law before concluding that the sale was not in the best interest of the country, and in particular regional development.
Mr McNamara added:We are an island nation and connectivity to the world market is essential for both industry and tourism. I am not prepared to gamble with what I believe is key to the economic development of this State, all of this State.
Speaking on RTs Six-One News he raised doubts over the enforcement of the Government's golden share (the mechanism to protect connectivity).
Mr McNamara said attempts in the past to protect the Government's golden share have not worked and that IAG may decide to renege on its commitment and dispose of its Heathrow slots.
He added he is still a member of the Labour Party and he would hope to run as a Labour Party candidate in the next general election.
However, Labour Chief Whip Emmet Stagg has written to Mr McNamara and informed him he has lost the party whip over his decision to vote against the Government on the sale of Aer Lingus.
He informed him he can no longer represent the Labour parliamentary party on committees of the house, attend parliamentary party meetings and he must vacant the office assigned to him by the parliamentary party.
Speakingin Ballaghadereen in Co Roscommon, TaoiseachEnda Kenny said that despite unions not agreeing in principletothe sale of the State's share in Aer Lingus, it isa "very good deal" because the Irish public have not owned the airline for quite awhile.
Mr Kenny said the State owns a share worth 25.1% and in the case of disposal of assets another 5% is needed in order to get a blocking mechanism.
He said this no longerapplies, however,because of the new arrangement where it is invested in the finance ministerof the day and for many years to come.
The Taoiseach said itwas about restoringinfluence over the use or disposal of slots that we did nothave,or were given away by the previous administration.
He also said that it is anew opportunity to grow the airline and create more than 600jobs.
Mr Kennywas critical of comments that the decision to sell was rushed through the Dil, sayingthe Government has held a two-day debate with 12hours of discussion.
The Taoiseach said many of the Labour TDs who had expressed concern about the sale have now agreed as a block to say this is a very good deal.
Mr Kenny saidhe heard Labour TDstoday saying that all the issues have now been dealt with and it was time to get on with the decision of the Government to dispose of the assets and get on with the remainder of the process. 
IAG and Aer Lingus welcome Dil vote
IAG and Aer Lingus have both welcomed the Dils decision to approve the sale.
Aer Lingus Chairman Colm Barrington said it was a compelling transaction for Aer Lingus and its stakeholders.
He said: Shareholders will realise an attractive return through the premium that the IAG offer provides over the level of our share price immediately prior to the announcement of IAG's offer.
Aer Lingus will reap the commercial and strategic benefits of being part of the much larger and globally diverse IAG Group and as a member of the Oneworld alliance of 17 airlines that together carry over 500 million passengers, he added.
IMPACT trade union said that the vote would elevate staff concerns about possible redundancies when the takeover is completed.
IMPACT National Secretary Matt Staunton commented, "We face a mounting challenge to secure the jobs and pay for existing and future staff.
Too many questions remain about what management will look to extract from its workforce when the inevitable restructuring phase commences under new ownership.
"For the staff at Aer Lingus, genuine concerns about compulsory redundancies, the prospect of a further erosion of their terms and conditions, and the fallout from future restructuring under IAG all remain", he said.
Opposition critical of Dil approval of Aer Lingus sale
Opposition parties have also criticised the Dils approval to sell its stake in the airline to IAG.
Sinn Fin President Gerry Adams has challenged the Taoiseach's assertion that the Government sell off of Aer Lingus is a good deal.
Mr Adams said: "The Taoiseach says this because he believes in dismantling state assets. He believes in privatisation across the board. He has no concern in the interests of the workers, passengers, or citizens that made a profitable."
Meanwhile, Renua leader Lucinda Creighton has supported the sale, but said it is a matter of grave concern that there has been no opportunity to engage in a proper and full question-and-answer session with the minister.
Attempts to holddebate to postpone vote 'dealt with'
Meanwhile, a spokesman for the Oireachtassaid that Fianna Fil's attempts to hold a debate to postpone the vote on the share sale were dealt with as part of the Government's motion on the sale.
Fianna Fil wanted the vote on the sale of the State share in the airline delayed until the Nyras report is debated.
The Dil this afternoon voted against postponing the vote on the sale in order for it to be considered further by the transport committee.
Fianna Fil's Timmy Dooley then called for the Dil to sit next week rather than guillotining the vote this evening, but that was also put to a vote and defeated.
Earlier, Aer Lingus management moved to reassure Labour Party TDs that it will not introduce compulsory redundancies or outsource employment.
The move came after an internal report for the airline identified cuts of more than 58 million.
Theanalysis of the finances at the airline was carried out by international aviation consultancy companyNyras.
It concludes the airline should set aggressive but achievable targets for short-haul cost efficiency at a minimum of 60m.
Aer Lingus Chief Executive Stephen Kavanagh said redundancies or the outsourcing of jobs will not happen where the savings can be made within the airline.
He made the assurances in a letter to Minister of State Nash and Chairman of the Labour Parliamentary Party Jack Wall last night.
However, Mr Kavanagh said such a commitment would involve flexibility from staff and trade union representatives to achieve these savings.
There was also a pledge to engage with unions to register employment agreement across the company.
Speaking on RT's Morning Ireland, Mr Kavanagh saidground-handling jobs at the airline will be maintained if Aer Lingus maintains efficiency.
He said savings can be achieved through the manner in which services for ground handling, not directly provided by Aer Lingus, are procured.
He said the ground-handlingservices referred to in the reportarethird-party services that are bought by the airline.
He said that cutting costs in this area will have no impact on direct employment at Aer Lingus.
SIPTU representative at Aer LingusOwen Reidyhas welcomed Aer Lingus' commitment to the registered employment agreements should the sale go ahead.
Mr Reidy told RT's News at One, that while he welcomes this progress, he is still against the sale of State assets.
He said if Aer Lingus does what it hassaid itwill in the letter from Mr Kavanagh, then the union will have vindicated its position and that it will give some comfort to its members.
He said entering into the registered employment agreements should be done before the sale of Aer Lingus.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:50:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Public servants could get up to €1,000 next year</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704515-public-pay-sector/</Link>
        <Description>Talks are reported to be at a critical stage this evening on the restoration of public sector pay.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Thursday 28 May 2015 23.50
As a result of the talks public sector workers may receive up to 1,000 in additional earnings next year
Talks are reported to be at a critical stage this evening on the restoration of public sector pay.
One union representative said there was a determination to complete the talks in this session and there is an expectation they will run into the early hours.
A two-year extension of the Haddington Road agreement is being considered, with reports that public servants will receive up to 1,000next year and the year after, but nothing has been signed off on.
It is understoodchanges to the pension levy would come into effect in the first year and the low paid would be a priority in second year.
In return the unions would sign up again to the same procedures and processes for settling disputes and in relation to other issues.
A senior Government source said the draft agreement involves a re-commitment to the flexibilities contained in the Haddington agreement and stressed the need for reform and change.
IBEC,the employers' groupwhich is not involved in the talks,said that for taxpayers to get value for money, there would need to be a strong commitment to productivity, outsourcing and competition.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:08:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>TD outlines details of IBRC-O'Brien relationship</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704498-dail-leaders/</Link>
        <Description>Independent TD Catherine Murphy has spoken in the Dáil about the business relationship between Denis O'Brien and the Irish Bank Resolution Corporation (IBRC) - the former Anglo Irish Bank - including alleged details of his loans.</Description>
        <MainBody>On Thursday 21 May the High Court granted Denis O'Brien an injunction against RT, which prevented the broadcaster from broadcasting any confidential information giving details of the businessman's personal banking arrangements with IBRC.
The injunction did not cover a statement Ms Murphy previously made in the Dil on 6 May.
In this statement she said Mr O'Brien's loans had expired and he had written to Kieran Wallace, the special liquidator of IBRC, seeking the same terms as the previous management of IBRC had allowed him to pay off his loans in his own time at low interest rates.
This afternoon under Dil privilege, Ms Murphy gave further details of Mr OBriens relationship with IBRC. However, RT is legally restricted from reporting what she said, because to do so would breach the injunction already granted against it.
Mr O'Brien today accused Ms Murphy of making false statements about him. He said it was a deliberate abuse of Dil privilege.
He claimed her ultimate objective was electoral advancement with a disregard for the truth.
Ms Murphy has reacted strongly, saying she got information from a number of reliable sources and that it was without doubt in the public interest.
She said she had a duty to put that information into the public domain and she added she fully intended to fulfil her democratic mandate.
She said she would not be intimidated by statements accusing her of wrongdoing.
Former CEO of IBRC Mike Aynsley issued a lengthy statement responding to Ms Murphy's comments in the Dil. RT cannot report all of his statement. He said he totally rejected her objectionable and untrue statements.
Mr Aynsley said he was concerned Ms Murphy had used Dil privilege to make defamatory comments.
He said he was also concerned about remarks she had made on social media and he said the matter was now in the hands of his solicitors.
He said after he was appointed following the nationalisation of Anglo in August 2009, he overhauled how the bank operated to ensure it did not repeat the mistakes of the past.
Mr Aynsley said clients and credit management activities were subject to ongoing oversight and scrutiny by people who were independent of the day-to-day management of the client relationships and governed by a credit control and committee approval process also independent of the day-to-day management structure.
He said he welcomed any review of the Siteserv transaction or any other transaction completed during the wind-down process, provided such a review was conducted fully and fairly.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:24:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FF selects election candidates for Galway West</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704542-fianna-fail-election-candidates/</Link>
        <Description>Fianna Fáil has selected three candidates to contest the forthcoming general election in the Galway West constituency.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 28 May 2015 23.24
Sitting TD amon 'Cuv was selected by delegates at a convention in Galway
Fianna Fil has selected three candidates to contest the forthcoming general election in the Galway West constituency.
Outgoing TD amon 'Cuv was selected by delegates at this evening's convention in Galway. He will be joined on the ticket by former County Councillor John Connolly and the current Cathaoirleach of Galway County Council, Mary Hoade.
Mr 'Cuv and Mr Connolly reached the quota on the first count. The distribution of Mr 'Cuv's surplus saw Cllr Hoade reach the quota ahead of the only other candidate, Stephanie Murphy-Penn.
Two other prospective candidates withdrew from the contest before tonight's vote.
The party's local Comhairle Dilcheantair had already voted to adopt a three-candidate strategy and the geographical spread of the chosen candidates means it is unlikely another candidate will be added to the ticket.
Following the last Constituency Commission, Galway West will take in a bigger area for the next general election. Some 10,000 voters from nine electoral areas around Ballinrobe in Co Mayo will transfer into the constituency. Galway West remains a five-seat constituency.
A total of 310 delegates voted at tonight's convention, which was chaired by the party's Mayo TD Dara Calleary.
Meanwhile, Cllr John Lahart has been selected to contest the general election for the partyin Dublin South West.
He was selectedat a convention at the Maldron Hotel in Tallaght this evening.
Elsewhere,Fianna Fil members in Waterford selected Councillor Mary Butler to contest the general election for the party.
Cllr Butler was the only candidate selected at aconvention in Dungarvan, CoWaterford.
Councillor Jackie Cahill was selected to contest the general election for the partyin Tipperary.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:09:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>LÉ Eithne rescues 201 migrants off Libyan coast</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704489-le-eithne-rescue-migrants/</Link>
        <Description>Irish naval vessel LÉ Eithne has rescued 201 migrants off the coast of Libya this afternoon.</Description>
        <MainBody>Members of the Irish Navy, wearing protective suits, deployed from the ship in their own rigid inflatable boat to meet the migrants vessels, which were packed to capacity with men women and some children.
The L Eithne crew gave the migrants food, water and first aid at the scene.
They willbe transferred to the British navy vessel HMS Bulwark before being brought ashore in Italy.
The L Eithne joined the humanitarian rescue operation in the Mediterranean earlier this month.
Footage of L Eithne personnel involved in the rescue of migrants off the coast of Libya https://t.co/7nme1sjm5r
 RT News (@rtenews) May 28, 2015
The rescue took place 60km off the coast of Libya and was the first such engagement for the 70 crew of the L Eithne since they arrived in the Mediterranean on their 10-week mission to tackle the migrant crisis.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:59:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter refuses to take responsibility for scandal</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704292-uefa/</Link>
        <Description>FIFA President Sepp Blatter has said he cannot be held responsible for the corruption scandal at the organisation and it must earn lost trust back.</Description>
        <MainBody>Visa threatened to break off its contract while other global brands such as Nike, adidas and Budweiser issued strongly-worded statements putting pressure on FIFA to take immediate action to restore its reputation.
Visa said its "disappointment and concern" was "profound" as it warned FIFA to begin changes immediately.
It said: "Our sponsorship has always focused on supporting the teams, enabling a great fan experience, and inspiring communities to come together and celebrate the spirit of competition and personal achievement - and it is important that FIFA makes changes now, so that the focus remain on these going forward.
"Should FIFA fail to do so, we have informed them that we will reassess our sponsorship."
Mr Blatter is under increasingpressure to resign before tomorrow's leadership election.
FAI Chief Executive John Delaney has said David Gill will reject a place onFIFA's Executive Committee if Mr Blatter is re-elected.
The vice-chairman of the English FA told a meeting of UEFA members he will not take up his place ifPrince Ali loses the election.
Mr Delaney also said the meeting agreed to throw its full weight behind Prince Ali.
British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said a UK politician in the same position as Mr Blatter "would be struggling to cling on".
"There's nodoubt, and there's been no doubt for many years, that FIFA needs to clean up its act," he told Sky News.
British Prime Minister David Cameron has also backed Prince Ali.
Britain has long been a critic of FIFA and unsuccessfully bid for the 2018 World Cup which was awarded to Russia.   
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said it "would make sense" to delay tomorrow's vote in light of the latest corruption investigation.
Mr Fabius said time was needed to establish exactly what was going on at FIFA.
"It's been several years that there have been accusations of corruption. It would make sense to take a bit of time, see what is true and not and then the authorities can adjudicate, but for now, it's giving a disastrous image," Mr Fabius told France Inter radio.
"I'm saying this on a personal level, but it would seem to make sense [to delay the election]," he said.
South Africa denies bribes paid to host tournament
South African sports minister Fikile Mbalula hasdenied allegations that huge bribes were paid to win the right to host the 2010 World Cup, sayingpublic money had not been given to "criminals".
The US attorney general allegesFIFA officials took cash in return for awarding the tournament to South Africa.
The US indictment alleged that bundles of cash in a briefcase were handed over at a Paris hotel as a bribe by a "high-ranking South African bid committee official".
It also alleged the South Africa government agreed that $10 million that was due to be paid to South Africa to run the World Cup was instead transferred from FIFA's funds to pay bribes to former FIFA vice president Jack Warner.
Mr Mbalula criticised how the US had made its allegations without consulting South Africa.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:14:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Progress in mortgage arrears 'damagingly slow'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/business/2015/0528/704447-honohan-finance/</Link>
        <Description>The Governor of the Central Bank has said that standard variable mortgage rates had moved arguably higher than a "fair-minded customer" might have reasonably expected.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The Central Bank Governor was appearing before the Oireachtas Finance Committee.
Mr Honohan said that there would be a case for Government intervention, if it was not for the firm conviction that this would have "a stultifying effect on bank efficiency and a chilling effect on the entry of other banks".
He said banks should move to publishing a clear and quantified statement of their standard variable interest rate policy.
Professor Honohan said the Central Bank wrote to each of the banks in February to ask for a clear statement of each bank's pricing behaviour around standard variable rate mortgages (SVRs).
"In their responses, none of the banks have so far provided what I would regard as a clear and quantified statement of their policy with respect to adjustments of the SVR interest rate," he stated.
The Governor also told members that the crisis continues to have serious legacy issues that "cannot be resolved easily or painlessly". 
He emphasised that delays and uncertainties surrounding the resolution of non-performing loans remains a much more acute problem. He said progress in this area "remains damagingly slow".
ProfessorHonohansaid he would like to get back to a situation where we have five or six players competing for banking business.
He acknowledged that there was not much competition in the sector at the moment and that the volume of mortgage arrears could be putting foreign players off.
He said Ireland does not spring to mind as a place to open a new branch for most European banks and that one of the reasons for this isthe mortgage arrears on non-performing loans.
ProfessorHonohan also said theinertia banks seeon the part of borrowers who could switch acted as a disincentiveto drop rates.
In response to a question from Labour's TD Pat Rabbitte, he said research conducted by the Central Bank showed that 15,000 customers could benefit from switching.
He said they could save a four figure sum a year.
Responding to a question from Pat Rabbitte on quantitative easing, ProfessorHonohan agreed this had had a 'helpful' impact on our borrowings.
On Anglo promissory note deal, he said in their annual report of the Central Bank they showed the value of the unrealised capital gains on the remaining assets of the 9bn portfolio.
He said they had already made a 1bn on the IRBC portfolio.
"The 9 billion isn't in the bag but if interest rates went up again then the gain would be smaller" he said. "Still things are going well on that front" he added.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:01:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News in Brief</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704297-news-in-brief/</Link>
        <Description>A round-up of national and international news stories.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 28 May 2015 23.01
The students are calling for college director, Declan McGonagle, to resign
NCAD students protest over college 'mismanagement'
Several hundred students from the National College of Art and Design in Dublin marched to the Department of Education this afternoon in protest at what they say ismismanagement at the college.
The students say they no longer have confidence in college director Declan McGonagleand are calling on him to resign.
Last year the Comptroller and Auditor Generalpublished a report criticising accountability and governance at NCAD.
In a statement the college has saida new governance plan has been drawn up following the NCAD report and it is now being implemented. The college also said core funding has been halved over the past five years.
NCAD students march over alleged mismanagement at the college
Over 13 million cigarettes seized in Dublin and Tyrone
Over 9 million cigarettes with a retail value of4.5m have been seized at Dublin port.
The cigarettes, thought to be counterfeit, were held in a container labelled as vacuum cleaners, which departed from China.
In a separateoperation today, five men were arrested following the seizure of over 4 million cigarettes,along with a suspected mobile fuel laundering plant,in Co Tyrone.
Women criticise North's PPS over Starmer review
Two women whose cases of alleged sex abuse were reviewed along with that of Mira Cahill, have strongly criticised the Public Prosecution Service in Northern Ireland.
The women, who wish to remain anonymous, were part of a review by Sir Keir Starmer published last week in to the PPS handled complaints by three women and concluded they were let down.
In a statement issued through their solicitors, the two women criticised the Director of the PPS in Northern Ireland, Barra McGrory, over his response to the Starmer review.
They said they felt Mr McGrory, in recent interviews, had attempted to completely misrepresent the findings of the report, in an attempt to deflect responsibility for the shortcomings of the his office, to a time before held the position of director.
Experts establish what causes holes to form in Swiss cheese
Swiss scientists have established a reason forthe holes in Swiss cheese, which they say has been the subject of study since at least 1917.
Experts from Agroscope, a state centre for agricultural research, said the phenomenon,which marks famous Swiss cheeses such as Emmental and Appenzell,was caused by tiny bits of hay present in the milk and not bacteria as previously thought.
They found that the mystery holes in such cheeses became smaller or disappeared when milk used for cheese-making was extracted, using modern methods.
Study shows social media alters pupils' writing
The rise of social media is changing the language children use, according to a new study.
Researchers looked at the entries to a children's short story competition and analysed the results which showed the increasing popularity of terms including hashtag, selfie and emoji.
Out of120,421 entries, the report foundhashtag and its corresponding symbol, #, was used more and more by children in their writing.
Number of passengers using Irish airports rose 6.9%
The numbers of passengers using Irish airports rose 6.9% last year with all the main airports increasing numbers apart from Cork Airport.
Almost 26.5 million passengers passed through Irish airports in 2014. This is still five million passengers lower than the 2007 peak of 31.5m passengers.
Passenger numbers increased in Dublin, Donegal, Knock, Shannon, and Waterford airports. Dublin Airport accounted for 81.9% of all passengers.
Iran hopeful over nuclear deal
Iran's foreign minister Mohammad Javad Zarif has said he is hopeful Iran and world powers would reach a final conclusion on a nuclear deal "within a reasonable period of time".
Iran, the United States, Britain, France, Germany, Russia and China reached a tentative framework for a nuclear deal on 2 April, but several issues remain unresolved.
They have a self-imposed 30 Junedeadline to arrive at a comprehensive agreement.
PNA agrees to talks at Labour Relations Commission
The Psychiatric Nurses Association has agreed to take part in talks at the Labour Relations Commission, aimed at resolving a dispute over staffing at Galway University Hospital.
Nursing staff at the acute psychiatric unit embarked on a work to rule action earlier this week in protest at staff and safety concerns on the ward.
The PNA said it would recommence talks at the LRC, after the HSE agreed to lift a threat of sanctions against staff who failed to report for work on 22 April citing safety issues as a result of what they said was understaffing.
The PNA saidthe "work to rule" will remain in place pending the outcome of the reconvened LRC talks.
Investigation into garda death in Donegal
The Garda Sochna Ombudsman Commission is investigating the sudden death of a member of the gardaat Ballyshannon Garda Station in Co Donegal.
He was found in the early hours of this morning.
His death is not being treated as suspicious.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:40:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Senior garda arrested over information disclosure</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704346-garda-arrest/</Link>
        <Description>A senior Garda officer is still being questioned tonight as part of an investigation into the unlawful disclosure of information to the media.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
They have interviewed and taken statements from a number of gardawho worked with the man and also sought but did not succeed in interviewing a journalist
The investigation began last year following a report by the former Children's Ombudsman Emily Logan into the removal by gardaof two children from their families in Athlone and Dublin in October 2013.
The report found that while the Health Service Executivecould not be ruled out, the release of details in relation to one of the children probably came from someone within the Gardaand may have been an offence.
The officer was arrested this morning after he was suspected of breaching the Garda Sochna Act. His period of detention was extended this afternoon.
RTNews has learned that he was authorised to speak to the media at the time the children were removed from their families.
He is the most senior garda officer everto have been arrested as part of a criminal investigation and the Government has been informed.
Garda Commissioner Nirn OSullivanhas suspended him from duty.
The Garda Press Office would neither confirm nor deny the officer's arrest.
In a statement, it said that the investigation into the disclosure of confidential and sensitive information was ongoing.
The garda was arrested after he arrived at a CoDublin garda station by appointment at 7.30am this morning.
He is suspected of unlawfully disclosing information to the media likely to have a harmful effect.
Commissioner O'Sullivan established theinquiry last Julyfollowing the publication of a report by Ms Logan into the use of legislation by gardain Tallaght and Athlone to remove two children from their families and place them in care.
The children were subsequently returned to their families.
However, MsLogan's report found that while the HSE could not be categorically ruled out as the source, the publication in an article of details in relation to one of the children "on the balance of probabilities" came from someone within an Garda Sochnaand may have been an offence.
The investigation is being led by a Chief Superintendent and a Detective Superintendent based in Dublin city centre.
The office of the garda in custody has been searched and his phone and computer records examined.
This evening the National Union of Journalists has said it is concerned about what appears to be a number of unusual aspects in relation to the arrest of a senior member of thegarda for thealleged unlawful disclosure of information.
National Secretary Seamus Dooley said itis vital that journalists are allowed to do their work in the public interest and that further barriers to the release of information are not erected.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:45:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IMF says Greek exit from eurozone a 'possibility'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/business/2015/0528/704408-greece-ecb-funds/</Link>
        <Description>The chief of the International Monetary Fund has said a Greek exit from the eurozone is a possibility, but would not signify an end to the single currency.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 28 May 2015 17.45
ECB officials play down easy money for Greece
The chief of the International Monetary Fund has said a Greek exit from the eurozone is a possibility, but would not signify an end to the single currency.
In a newspaper interview, IMF chief Christine Lagarde said such a scenario would not be a "walk in the park" for the single currency, but would "probably not be an end to the euro".
Inhe interview, which was carried in German dailyFrankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, Ms Lagarde rejected Athens' assertion that a deal with its creditors was imminent.
"It is very unlikely that we'll reach a comprehensive solution in the coming days," she said.
After positive signals had come from Greece 10 days ago, "we've been sobered again in the last week," Ms Lagarde said.
There was still a lot of work to be done, she said, and the IMF was not prepared to pay out more funds without a clear reform pledge.
"We have rules. We have principles. There will be no half-baked programme review," Lagarde said.
Earlier today, European Central Bank policymakers played down the prospects of any immediate loosening of funding for cash-strapped Greece.
They said that when it came to accepting Greek bonds as security for central bank credit, the answer remained 'no'.
The ECB's vice president underlined the seriousness of the situation facing Greece, talking openly about a possible default, which would be the first of its kind in the 16-year-old currency bloc.
"Only when the final review of the programme will be completed and successful we, the Governing Council, can consider changing that. But not before," Vitor Constancio said.
His remarks echoed those made earlier by Ewald Nowotny, who as head of the Austrian central bank also sits on the ECB's policy-setting Governing Council.
Both counter the optimism of the Greek government that a deal is near.
"There is always a lot of noise in such a situation and I think the important point is to distinguish the noise from the facts," Nowotny said.
"For us, it is quite clear that we have certain conditions to be met. The one condition is ... whether we can accept for instance Greek assets, Greek bonds, as collateral. The answer is, for the time being: No," said

In February, the European Central Bank abruptly cancelled its acceptance of Greek bonds in return for funding, shifting the burden onto Athens' central bank to finance its lenders and isolating Greece unless it strikes a new reform deal.
The move, which means the Greek central bank provides banks with tens of billions of euros of emergency liquidity, was in response to what many in Frankfurt saw as the Greek government's abandoning of its aid-for-reform programme.
Constancio signalled that while Greece would not leave the euro, it could default.
"The end result is that a Greek exit will not happen," he said, adding: "That's not to exclude several things that are not nice that may happen."
Commenting on the state of Greece's banks in the event of default, he said: "They can sustain the impact of a big potential impairment in Greek public debt."
He signalled that the ECB may also take a lenient view if this were to happen, a hint that they could still qualify for the emergency central bank funding that is keeping them afloat. This requires them to be solvent.
IMF will cut offGreece if payment missed
Greece will be cut off from additional IMFfinancing if it misses a loan payment to the crisis lender, an IMF spokesman has said.
"Any country that doesn't meet its commitment with the Fund... is declared in arrears and they have no access to IMF funding," IMF spokesman William Murray said.
But Murray said the IMF believed that Athens would not miss any of the looming payments.
"As we stand here right now, we expect the Greek authorities will pay us," Murray said at a regularly scheduled news conference.
Greece's interior minister, Nikos Voutsis, said Sunday that heavily indebted Greece had "no money" to make a series of repayments to the IMF that are due beginning June 5, totaling 1.6bn.
But Greek officials negotiating to unlock some 7.2bnin bailout cash with creditors have not suggested that a payment would be missed.
The IMF spokesman also said that the Greek government had not asked the the Fund to regroup the payments to give the country a little more time to make them. "There's been no request for a bundling," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:14:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Motorcyclist seriously injured in M50 collision</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704422-m11-rta/</Link>
        <Description>A motorcyclist has been taken to hospital with serious injuries following a collision on the M11.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The northbound section of the M11/M50 at Junction 7 was closed for several hours following the collision,but has since been reopened.
Traffic is reported to still beheavy around Bray, particularly on Killarney Rd, Upper Dargle Rd, Greystones Rd and on Main Streetand motorists are being asked to avoid the area if possible.
There were traffic tailbacks through Shankhill and towards Bray town earlier today.
Delays were also reportedon Dublin Bus on the 45a and 145 routes operating to and from Bray Station.
There are diversions on the 84 route from Bray to Newcastle and delays have also been reported on the 184 route.
M11 UDPATE: M11 northbound has just opened at J5 Bray North and diversions have been lifted. Heavy delays remain. http://t.co/qvBPcgxUj8
 AA Roadwatch (@aaroadwatch) May 28, 2015
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:15:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tallaght Hospital to convert ward for adult use</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704492-tallaght-hospital/</Link>
        <Description>Tallaght Hospital says it plans to convert one of its 16-bed paediatric wards into an adult ward to cope with increased pressures.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Tallaght says there will be no diminution of services or reduction in activity.
Currently the hospital has 61 inpatient paediatric beds and 16 of these beds have been closed since 2012.
It says that even with these closures, there is still 30% unused capacity in paediatric inpatient beds.
Tallaght has 414 adult inpatient beds and saysthis service is overcapacity, due to the ageing population and greater case complexity.
The planned change would see the redesignation and conversion of the paediatric 'Beech Ward' into an adult ward.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:38:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Inquest of divers finds death by misadventure</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704523-diver-death/</Link>
        <Description>An inquest into the deaths of two experienced divers off the south coast of Ireland last summer has returned verdicts of misadventure.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 28 May 2015 20.38
1 of 2
Jonathan Scott's body was recovered some hours later following a major search operation
Stephen Clarke was airlifted to hospital where he died a short time later
An inquest into the deaths of two experienced divers off the south coast of Ireland last summer has returned verdicts of misadventure.
The two men, 65-year-old Stephen Clarke from Surrey in England and 61-year-old Jonathan Scott from Morley in Western Australia, were diving on the wreck of a WW2 German submarine, the U260, eight miles from Baltimore, west Cork,when they got into trouble on 3 July 2014.
The court heard that barotraumas or 'the bends' may have been a factor leading to their deaths after they ascended too quickly from the 45 metre deep dive.
Mr Clarke was airlifted to hospital where he died a short time later.
Mr Scott's body was recovered some hours later following a major search operation.
Both men were among a party of friends on a diving holiday in Ireland.
They had been diving for several days in and around West Cork on board the 'Wave Chieftain' skippered by their friend Gerry Smith of the Baltimore-based Aquaventures.
The court was told that their equipment was not a factor in their deaths.
Garda Dave Finn of the Garda Water Unit, who examined the data retrieved from their dive computers said that it showed that after spending two minutes longer than planned at the wreck site, both men began coming up rapidly.
When they reached 24 metres, for some unknown reason they went back down to 32 metres, before coming up quickly to the surface.
The coroner accepted it was not possible to say why this happened or why they did not make the three planned 'decompression stops' they were due to make on the way back up.
Dr Cullinane said all that is known is that the ascent was rapid, the decompression stops were missed, too long was spend on the bottom, and they went below again, before, one descended to the seabed, and the other to the surface, unconscious.
Assistant State Pathologist Dr Margaret Bolster found that Mr Scott died of acute cardiovascular failure consistent with drowning while diving, associated with barotrauma.
Mr Clarke died of acute cardiovascular failure consistent with drowning while diving, associated with heart disease, and barotrauma.
Cork City Coroner Dr Myra Cullinane extended her deepest sympathies to both families and said she hoped in time they would be able to come to terms with "this terrible tragedy".
Dr Cullinane said the wreck site of the U260 submarine - which lies at up to 45 metres - attracts over 200 experienced divers every year and it is a timely reminder that recreational diving is a sport with risks.
All divers, she added, should comply with the rules of the Irish Underwater Council.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:22:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gardaí appeal for information over fatal shooting</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704306-shooting/</Link>
        <Description>Gardaí in Tallaght in Dublin have appealed for witnesses to come forwards after a 35-year-old man was shot dead night.</Description>
        <MainBody>It is believed he was set upon after he had just got out of his car.
He died later in hospital.
Two men were arrested after garda werecalled to theKiltalown road areafollowing reports of a car actingsuspiciously.
Two gardaapproached the driver of aNissan Almera at which pointtwo men were seen running towards the Almera from anothervehicle that had just been set alight.
Garda arrested an 18-year-old man and a 28-year-old man, who are still being questioned.
A third man fled the scene.
Today garda said MrO' Neillwas not known to them and appealed for witnesses to come forward.
The sceneof the shooting and the burnt out carare being preserved for a technical examination.
A post-mortem examinationis expected to be held later today.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:16:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>81 beaches and five marinas given Blue Flag status</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704440-beaches/</Link>
        <Description>Eighty-one beaches and five marinas have been awarded the International Blue Flag for 2015 by An Taisce.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Minister for the Environment Alan Kelly said the awards are something to be cherished and a testament to the sterling efforts of local authorities, An Taisce and local communities.
There are two first time recipients this year, Ballinesker Beach in Co Wexford and the Marina at Kinsale Yacht Club in Co Cork.
In addition, seven beaches which had previously lost their Blue Flag status managed to regain it this year.
They included Redbarn and Garretstown in Cork, Rossbeigh in Kerry, Miltown Malbay and Spanish Point in Clare, as well as Mulranny and Bertra in Mayo.
Against that, three beaches, Brittas Bay North in Co Wicklow, Enniscrone in Co Sligo, and Skerries South Beach in Fingal, lost their status this year.
Theyall failed in relation to water quality.
In addition to the Blue Flag awards for officially identified bathing areas An Taisce also awarded 58 National Green Coast awards for non-identified bathing waters which do not have the full range of facilities required for Blue Flag status but are still considered to be excellent places to visit.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:32:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU status quo not good enough -David Cameron</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704293-britain-eu/</Link>
        <Description>David Cameron has warned the EU must be "flexible and imaginative enough" to respond to demands for reform, as he visited Paris as part of a two-day diplomatic tour.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
But he expressed confidence that solutions could be found to make Europe more competitive and "address the concerns of the British people" ahead of an in-out referendum on membership.
After Mr Hollande stressed France wanted the UK to remain in the EU and signalled that he was ready to look at "suitable" proposals for change, Mr Cameron said: "My priority is to reform the European Union to make it more competitive, and to address the concerns of the British people about our membership.
"The status quo is not good enough. I believe there are changes we can make that will not just benefit Britain, but the rest of Europe too.
"Of course the priority for Francois is to strengthen the eurozone to ensure a successful single currency, and Britain supports that.
"We want to help the eurozone work better and we do not want to stand in the way of closer integration. So we have different priorities but we share one objective, which is to find solutions to these problems.
"What matters is that the EU and its 28 members are flexible and imaginative enough to respond to these issues and to work together to find answers that will make the EU more successful.
"That is the challenge of our times and I believe strongly that we can meet it."
Speaking earlierBritish Foreign Secretary Philip Hammondsaid the European Union must amend its founding treaties to accommodate Britains renegotiation drive.
Mr Hammond warned the UK needed a meaty deal to persuade voters to stay in the bloc.
Speaking to BBC radio, Mr Hammond said "if our partners do not agree with us, do not work with us to deliver that (reform) package, then we rule nothing out."
"The advice we're getting is that we will need treaty change," he said, explaining it was necessary to render changes Mr Cameron wants irreversible and safe from legal challenge.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:36:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Over 200 women accept symphysiotomy payments</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704412-symphysiotomy-payments/</Link>
        <Description>Nearly 200 women have accepted payments made under the Surgical Symphysiotomy Payment Scheme set up by the Government.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 28 May 2015 18.36
The surgical procedure to break the pelvis during childbirth was performed between 1944 and 1984
Nearly 200 women have accepted payments made under the Surgical Symphysiotomy Payment Scheme set up by the Government.
It has so far made 206 offers, with one rejected and 11 offers awaiting a response.
Minister for Health Leo Varadkar told the Dil today that 118 awards were assessed at 50,000 each, 71 at 100,000each and five at 150,000 each.
When the ex-gratia scheme was set up last November with three paymentbands, it was expected that around 350 women would apply.
There have been 576 applications to date, which are being assessed by former High Court judge, Maureen Harding Clarke.
The scheme has a fund of around 34 million.
The surgical procedure to break the pelvis during childbirth to allow a baby to be born was performed between 1944 and 1984.
Marie O'Connor, Chairperson of Survivors of Symphysiotomy said in a statement this evening: "The Minister's homily to the Diltoday contained no proposals as to how this Government proposes to to meet its human rights obligations to women subjected to this involuntary surgery. "
She said "the scheme is evidently imposing a burden of proof that applicants cannot meet" and that the scheme suffers from "a lack of appropriate expertise."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:44:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bakery to appeal decision over 'gay cake'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704358-ashers-bakery/</Link>
        <Description>The Christian Institute has said that the owners of Ashers Baking Company are to appeal a Belfast court ruling that the bakery discriminated against a customer by refusing to make a cake with a slogan supporting same-sex marriage.</Description>
        <MainBody>"This is direct discrimination for which there can be no justification."
Ashers was ordered to pay agreed damages of 500 (690) plus court costs.
Mr Lee, a member of the LGBT advocacy group Queer Space, had wanted a cake featuring Sesame Street puppets Bert and Ernie with the slogan Support Gay Marriage.
He wanted the cakefor a private function marking International Day AgainstHomophobia.
In a statement today the McArthur family, who own and run Ashers, said: "After much careful and prayerful consideration given to legal advice, we have decided to appeal the judgment handed down last Tuesday."
The statement added:"We continue to insist that we have done nothing wrong as we have discriminated against no individual but rather acted according to what the Bible teaches regarding marriage.
"As many other people have already noted, Christian beliefs seem to have been trampled over in this judgement and we believe this only has negative effects for our society.
"Our hope and prayer would be that an appeal will allow us and other Christians to live out their faith in Jesus Christ in every part of their lives, including their workplace."
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:16:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Banking supervisory measures were 'not sufficient'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704298-bank-inquiry/</Link>
        <Description>Former financial regulator Patrick Neary has told the banking inquiry that the supervisory measures were not sufficient to meet the challenges posed by the crisis and the recession that emerged.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
He also said nationalising Anglo alone could have hurt other banks, and he said they advised it was better to guarantee all banks.
Mr Neary said that the regulator did not run the banks and that it relied on the Central Bank, the Department of Finance and the ESRI for economic outlook.
He said the financial regulator had difficulty hiring adequately trained staff and thatstaff were stretched thinin banking supervision.
Mr Neary is facingquestions from members of the committee, as part of its Nexus Phase public hearings.
During the Nexus Phase the committee is engaging with institutions and individuals who had roles relating to the crisis.
Committee ChairmanLabour TD Ciarn Lynchhas said this morning's hearing will focus on the role of the Central Bank and the Financial Regulator.
Stream provided by HEAnet
Too much money loaned to property and construction
Mr Neary conceded they did have powers to curb lending but did not use them and said banks loaned too much money to property and construction.
If they had really set hard limits, they would have been able to control the situation, he said.
Pushed by Fianna Fil's Michael McGrath on whether he had refused six extra banking supervision staff, Mr Neary said he had sanctioned the additional people but they were unable to recruit them. 
Mr Neary blamed the system of regulation.
Asked about his role in applying the system, he said it was the type of regulation which was not appropriate.
He said he first heard about Sen Quinn's use of certain share dealings known as Contracts for Difference (CFDs)in September 2007 when Anglo Irish Bank's chief executive David Drumm met him to ask what he knew.
Mr Neary said he knew nothing other than rumours.
He tried to make inquiries but there was nothing hard and fast.
He had a meeting with Mr Quinn in January 2008 who said he was "not long in financials".
Mr Neary's view was it was a matter for Mr Quinn.
He took him to mean that whatever CFDs he had, had been converted. The facts were established in March 2008 he said.
Asked by Mr McGrath whether he had taken adequate steps to establish the facts since first becoming aware of the situation, Mr Neary said there was no information only rumour.
Zero loan impairment before downturn
Mr Neary said he did not believe he could have imposed sanctions for banks breaching lending limits.
He said he accepted that these rules were allowed go into abeyance and accepted responsibility for that.
Mr Neary said he had no comment on the remark allegedly made by a former AIB chairman that he was a "hopeless regulator".
Mr Lynch asked him if the banks had lent 440 billion and economy was worth 160 billion how did he think the banks had enough capital to withstand a property downturn.
Mr Neary responded that prior to the downturn there was zero loan impairments in Irish banks.
He said the size of the entire banking sector was the responsibility of the Central Bank.
The conclusion of analysis by the OECD was there would be soft landing.
He said he regretted that Mary Burke, the former banking supervisor, felt she was being undermined by the CEOs of banks meeting her superiors without her knowledge.
Mr Neary said principal-based regulation meant that banks were best placed to assess risks and it was the boards of the banks who let their shareholders down. 
Central Bank governor 'patriarch' of organisation
Mr Neary told the inquiry that he reported to the chairman of the Irish Financial Services Regulatory Authority.
Within the organisation the Governor of the Central Bank was seen as the patriarch of the organisation, Mr Neary said.
He said the Governor would have been aware that no action was taken against banks because he would have seen board minutes of the Regulator.
The resource needs of the Regulator was handled by the remuneration committee, he said.
Mr Neary said the problems hiring staff were caused because the salaries offered Regulator were not high enough because they were tied to civil service wage scales.
Asked about a meeting with former Bank of Ireland boss Brian Goggin about not taking action on 100% mortgages, Mr Neary said it was made clear very early on that it was not the role of the Regulator to ban products.
He said there were no minutes of a meeting with Mr Drumm regarding Mr Quinn's investment in Anglo because the meeting had been arranged informally.
Patrick Neary has said it was a mistake to print golf balls with the Financial Regulator's logo on them https://t.co/ZOOKlLrxQK
 RT News (@rtenews) May 28, 2015
MrNeary also said it was a mistake to print golf balls with the Regulator's logo on them.
He said these were purchased as promotional materials and it shouldn't have happened, addingthey were discontinued quickly.
Socialist Party TD Joe Higgins suggested to Mr Neary that he would have done well as Regulator in the 1950s, but was at sea in cut-throat 2005 and was out of his depth.
Mr Neary said the Authority didn't see it like that and the system failed.
He said he could not interfere in relationships between banks and clients.
Pushed by Sinn Fin's Pearse Doherty on how Anglo and Irish Nationwide loaned so much to few clients, he said the law allowed it as long as loans were not impaired.
Fine Gael's Eoghan Murphy asked if carrying out 50 inspections between 2003 and 2008 was being presented as a positive. Mr Neary said it was what they could do on tight resources.
Fine Gael Senator Michael D'Arcy asked if they banks loaned recklessly. Mr Neary said he would not use the word reckless and had no evidence.
He agreed that the Regulator had signed off jointly on the Financial Stability reports with the Central Bank. 
Fianna Fil TD Michael McGrath asked if he was trying to deflect by apportioning responsibility for the reports onto the Central Bank, Mr Neary said he had no intention of deflecting blame anywhere.
Mr Neary said he told Prime Time in early October 2008 that the Irish banks were among the best-capitalised in Europe because he believed it fully at the time based on the information at his disposal.
Sinn Fin's Pearse Doherty said the banks needed 10 billion within 70 days.
On his severance and pension, MrNeary said they reflected civil service arrangements and were what the Authority agreed to provide.
On his departure from IFSRA, he said there was a corporate governance issue in one of the banks which reflected badly on the Authority. 
He felt the Authority's position was going to be difficult as the focus would be on his role.
Mr Neary didn't believe any institution was insolvent on 30 September2008, the date of the guarantee.
He said having a social relationship with some bankers was certainly no longer appropriate. 
He was asked about a golfing outing and dinner with some Anglo executives. He said it was only coffee and a sandwich and banking talk had no place in golfing societies or social events.
He said the collapse of Northern Rock sent a shiver down the spine and heightened awareness
Neary arguably the worst regulator - McWilliams
Economist David McWilliams has said Mr Neary was, arguably, the worst financial regulator the world had ever seen, but said you can not blame one person.
Speaking on RT's News at One, Mr McWilliams said the institutions were sick and problematic, and the people at the top reflected the institutions.
He said that it's laughable, if it wasn't so patheticaly serious, that Mr Neary is blaming the system itself, adding just because you belong to an institutiondoes not mean that you loose your common sense, or rationality.
Mr McWilliams addedthe Central Bank, Financial Regulator and the Department of Finance failed profoundly and, in so doing, endangered the entire economy.
'Irish banks are resilient' - Prime Time interview
In October 2008, Mr Neary was interviewed on RT's Prime Time, when he stood by a statement he made the previous month that "Irish banks are resilient and have good shock-absorption capacity to cope with the current situation".
Asked by presenter Mark Little if he regretted the statement, Mr Neary said: "Absolutely not."
Among the issues which will be addressed with Mr Neary today relating to his role in the Central Bank and as the Chief Executive Officer of the IFSRAare the appropriateness of the regulatory regime, the effectiveness and appropriateness of the supervision policy and powers, and the effectiveness of the use of supervisory powers.
Other lines of inquiry include the nature and appropriateness of the relationship between the Central Bank, the Financial Regulator, the Department of Finance and the banking institutions.
Nexus Phase hearings will run until the middle of September.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:21:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Barman guilty over death of man who drank 56 shots</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704434-shots-france/</Link>
        <Description>A French barman has received a suspended jail sentence after he was convicted of manslaughter for letting a man drink 56 shots during a drinking contest that led to his death.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thursday 28 May 2015 14.21
The bar had displayed a shots record on a noticeboard
A French barman has received a suspended jail sentence after he was convicted of manslaughter for letting a man drink 56 shots during a drinking contest that led to his death.
Renaud Prudhomme, 56, broke the in-house shots record last October at Starter, a bar in the central French town of Clermont-Ferrand.
He had spent the evening with his daughter and some friends who helped him home in his inebriated state, but they soon had to phone the emergency services.
Mr Prudhomme died in hospital the following day.
Barman Gilles Crepin, 47, admitted at an earlier hearing that he had made "a mistake" by displaying a shots record on a noticeboard, encouraging the victim to go too far.
He was given a four-month suspended sentence by a local court and banned from working in a bar for a year.
His lawyer said he would appeal the ruling.
"It's a decision guided by emotion and the unconscious desire to set an example," said Renaud Portejoie, who had called for the case to be thrown out.
Mr Portejoie said his client bore no responsibility, adding that it was the man's daughter who had pushed him to break the record, and that he had existing respiratory and alcohol abuse problems.
"We can't ask every customer who buys alcohol to present their medical certificates," said Mr Portejoie.
Antoine Portal, a lawyer for Mr Prudhomme's daughter, said she was not at the bar at the time of the drinking competition.
"My client is relieved by this decision," Mr Portal said of the ruling forbidding Crepin from working as a barman.
"We want to remind some professionals that it is illegal to serve alcohol to clients that are in an advanced state of inebriation," he added.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
