<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="rte">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:56:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Legal action over strike will 'strengthen resolve'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/697992-bus-strike/</Link>
        <Description>The National Bus and Rail Union has warned that the threat by the State bus companies to take legal action against unions to recoup the costs of the two-day strike can only lead to a hardening of resolve among staff.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
In a letter today to Minister for Transport Paschal Donohoe and the Chief Executives of Dublin Bus, Bus ireann and the National Transport Authority, NBRU General Secretary Dermot O'Leary saysthat the threat of legal action against unions has done a disservice to employees and customers.
He tells the chief executives of Dublin Bus and Bus ireann, Paddy Doherty and Martin Nolan, thatattacking workers and their representatives can only lead to a hardening of resolve among staff.
Mr O'Leary says that the companies, the NTA and the minister will all be aware that the process initiated by the Labour Relations Commission last August was intended to resolve all of the issues at the heart of the current dispute.
He says that central to this process was what he called an "agreed interlocked agenda" which contained issues tabled by the parties, including those raised by the bus companies.
He said the agenda included:
1. The issue of direct award contracts after 2019, the capacity of the state bus companies to tender, and related issues;
2. Pension issues;
3. The National Transport Authority role in ensuring commitments on terms and conditions are honoured by new providers;
4. The timeframe regarding the phasing of the 10% of route tenders and the issue of growth;
5. Engagement on route selection for Bus ireann;
6. Clarification of legacy cost issues;
7. The application of Transfer of Undertakings legislation for workers potentially transferring to private operators;
8. Clarification of the tender process.
In today's letter, Mr O'Leary says that all of those issues need to be addressed to the point where "nothing is agreed until everything is agreed".
He says that the minister's intervention earlier this week assuring that no employee would have to transfer to a private operator was interpreted by the NBRU as a vehicle for talks to recommence.
However, he said that the recent intervention by NTA Chief Executive Anne Graham had led to a "crystallisation" of the fears and concerns of members.
Mr O'Leary says the NBRU message to stakeholders is that no one party to the process can resolve the dispute, and that it behoves all stakeholders on both sides of the debate to collectively address the issues on the agreed interlocked agenda.
He concludes by saying that the NBRU remains implacably opposed to privatisation, and will continue to highlight what he calls the "flawed ideologically based attempt to hijack publicly-owned bus companies".
He says this policy is a bad deal for the taxpayer and will trigger a race to the bottom.
Last resort
A Bus ireann spokesperson this afternoon said: "Bus ireann and Dublin Bus wished to exhaust every avenue of talks and discussion, before embarking on a legal action as a last and final resort. 
"We remained optimistic that there were be a breakthrough and aversion of the strike, right up until the breakdown of exploratory talks at the LRC yesterday evening.
"It was only then that the decision wasfinalisedto initiate a legal challenge."
Bus strike causes major travel disruption
Hundreds of thousands of bus passengers have had their travel plans disrupted fortoday and tomorrow, as a result of thestrike at Bus ireann and Dublin Bus.
A last-ditch bid to avert the stoppage at the Labour Relations Commission yesterday afternoon failed.
Dublin Bus estimates the strike will cost 600,000 a day in lost revenue - not including a daily fine from the National Transport Authority of 150,000 a day.
The strike is expectedto cost Bus ireann 1.5mplus an NTA fine of around 80,000 a day.
Politicians and business interests have strongly criticised the strike.
Bus lanes are operating as normal and can only be used by taxis, cyclists, private bus companies and emergency services.
LRC chief executive Kieran Mulvey said he has let both sides in thedispute know that the commission is prepared to engage in an intensive period of negotiations to prevent a further five days of strikes from happening.
Speaking on RTs Morning Ireland he called on both sides in the dispute to end their "war of words".
Mr Mulvey said most industrial relations issues can be resolved and if the LRC could engage with the parties more constructively then these issues could be further clarified.
No winners
Taoiseach Enda Kenny this afternoon said there are no winners as a result of the industrial action by bus workers.
Speaking in Castlebar this afternoon, Mr Kenny said he hoped that further strike action would be called off.
He said he noted the comments of Mr Mulvey that the LRC had a role and function to try to bring all parties together so that "common sense" could prevail.
The Taoiseach said he felt it was unlikely that the action today and tomorrow would be called off but he said it was in the interests of businesses and commuters that further disruption was avoided.
He said he hoped the invitation extended to the disputing parties to negotiate would be taken up in the coming days.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:54:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman loses symphysiotomy High Court action</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/698093-symphysiotomy/</Link>
        <Description>A 74-year-old woman who suffered life-long pain after a symphysiotomy was performed on her 12 days before the birth of her baby in 1963 has lost her High Court action.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 01 May 2015 12.54
The case was heard in the High Court over 15 days
A 74-year-old woman who suffered life-long pain after a symphysiotomy was performed on her 12 days before the birth of her baby in 1963 has lost her High Court action.
In what was viewed as a test case for others, the woman had sued for negligence, claiming there was no justification for the controversial procedure.
In her action the woman claimed she suffered life-long pain and could not bond with her baby and had a nervous breakdown.
The case was heard in the High Court over 15 days.
In his judgment Mr Justice Kevin Cross found that "the practice of prophylactic symphysiotomy in 1963 was not a practice without justification".
Hesaid it was indeed a controversial practice but it was also strongly defended and the strength of the defence made it impossible for the plaintiff to prove her case.
The judge described the plaintiff as a remarkable lady whose story deserved to be told and said he would have taken "hold of twig or twine-thread" to uphold her case, but he had to find her case must fail.
Mr Justice Cross said there was no doubt that the operation would not have been performed on the plaintiff today or on any date after the introduction of "active management of labour".
He said in this case the plaintiff, whether as a result of the timing of the symphysiotomy or otherwise, did suffer and indeed continued to suffer consequences throughout her life.
However, he said every medical procedure now common place must once have been unprecedented and indeed may well have been very controversial.
He said in this case the hospital notes indicate that the treating doctors were convinced that a vaginal delivery would not be possible.
Accordingly they proceeded on a course of symphysiotomy, which at the time they had reason to believe was not generally adverse in its effect to the mother and it was safer as far as the child was concerned.
He said that he hadfurther come to the conclusion that, given the real fears of multiple caesarean sections and the perceived benign effects of symphysiotomyand also given the wide acceptance of this practice among the leading consultants in the Coombe and National Maternity Hospital, the plaintiff has not established this practice was one with such inherent defects that ought to have been obvious to any person giving the matter due consideration.
The judgesaid there was no evidence of any peer criticism of the plaintiff's procedure.
Speaking afterwards spokesperson for Survivors of SymphysiotomyMarie O Connor said it was a "devastating outcome for survivors of symphysiotomy everywhere".
She said it also highlighted the need for a full and independent inquiry into the practice.
Mark Kelly of the Council for Civil Liberties said the case again demonstrates that "requiring women in their 70s and 80s to come to the High Court is not an effective way to give justice to survivors".
He said the onus was not on elderly women to come and convince the judge that they have suffered permanent damage.
"The onus is on the State to carry out an independent inquiry to explain to women why this practice, which had been banned in other jurisdictions was re-introduced here."
"Yet again, dragging women through the courts is not living up to its human rights responsibility," he said.
"The Government needs to realise this practice of stoutly resisting women has to stop ... the compensation scheme is not an alternative to an inquiry".
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:56:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man jailed for life for murdering drug dealer</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/698075-sean-connolly-eamon-kelly/</Link>
        <Description>A 35-year-old Dublin man has been sentenced to life in prison for the murder of veteran criminal Eamon Kelly in Killester, Dublin two-and-a-half years ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Two other charges of IRA membership and possession of a firearm against Connolly were not proceeded with.
Kellys daughter Alison said in a victim impact statement that the brutal and senseless murder destroyed the familys lives and they still do not know why a much loved father and grandfather was killed.
Investigating garda described the killing as a highly professional murder.
Kelly was known to go to a bookmakers in Killester in the mornings and afternoons.
The 65-year-old left Ladbrokes at 4pm on 4 December 2012 to walk home, but his killer met him as he came out of Dun Luce Lane - just 70 metres from his front door.
Kelly ran but he was shot four times in the back.
Officers from the Special Detective Unit arrested Connolly a short time later.
Petrol vapours were detected on his shoes from a burned-out getaway car and firearms residue was found on his person.
Connolly, a Real IRA gunman who was ordered to murder Kelly, has already served terms of four and six years in prison for IRA membership and possession of guns and ammunition.
He admitted he intended to kill Kelly and was sentenced to life in prison.
Kelly's family left the Special Criminal Court this afternoon grateful to gardafor what they described as a "tireless investigation".
Kelly was shot dead three months after the murder of Real IRA leader Alan Ryan - at a time when there were tensions between gangland criminals and dissident republicans.
He was aware his life was in danger andthere had been a previous attempt to shoot him two years before.
Garda had consistently warned him of the threats to his life.
Connolly pleaded guilty to the murder but Mr Justice Paul Butler said the court was in no position to acknowledge that plea and had to sentence him to life in prison.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:40:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>1,000 Europeans missing, 12 dead after Nepal quake</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/697994-nepal-earthquake/</Link>
        <Description>Up to 1,000 people from the European Union are missing in Nepal and 12 are confirmed dead, nearly a week after a devastating earthquake.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
He said that many of them had now returned to Ireland but the department's Consular Division and Ireland's embassy in New Dehli remains in contact with a number of Irish people who are still in Nepal.
Langtang is a trekking region to the north of Kathmandu that has been hit by a huge avalanche and mudslides.
Luklais is the jumping off point for walkers and climbers making the nine-day trek to Everest base camp.
Meanwhile, theRed Cross has warned of "total devastation" in remote areas near the epicentre of Nepal's devastating earthquake as the death toll rose past6,200.
Fresh aftershocks have made it hard for nervous survivors to return to their homes in the capital Kathmandu and elsewhere.
Disposal of the hundreds of bodies, still being found six days after the 7.9 magnitude quake devastated the Himalayan nation of 28 million people, was becoming a problem for officialswho have ordered immediate cremations.
Aid was slowly beginning to reach remote towns and villages nestled in the mountains and foothills.
Many Nepalis have been sleeping in the open since Saturday's quake. According to the United Nations, 600,000 houses have been destroyed or damaged.
The countrys finance minister said Nepal would need at least $2bn (1.78bn) to rebuild homes, hospitals, government offices and historic buildings and appealed for help from international donors.
The United Nations has said eight million people had been affected, with at least two million in need of tents, water, food and medicines over the next three months.
A home ministry official said the death toll had risen to 6,204, with 13,924 injured.
Officials have said the chances of finding any more survivors were fading, even though a boy and a woman had yesterday been pulled from the rubble where they had lain trapped for five days.
As rescuers slowly started reaching outlying areas, witnesses reported seeing 70 to 80% of buildings severely damaged in Chautara, northeast of Kathmandu.
Anger over the pace of the rescue has flared in some areas, with Nepalis accusing the government of being too slow to distribute international aid that has flooded into the country.
It has yet to reach many in need, particularly in areas hard to reach given the quake damage, poor weather and aftershocks.
Tensions between foreigners and Nepalis desperate to be evacuated have also surfaced.
In Ashrang village in Gorkha, one of the worst-hit districts about four hours by road west of Kathmandu, hundreds of villagers were living outdoors with little food and water even as boxes of biscuits, juice and sacks of rice and wheat were stored in a nearby government office.
Nepal is also appealing to foreign governments for more helicopters help the 20 at work in rescue operations.
In the Himalayas, climbing is set to reopen on Mount Everest next week after damage caused by avalanches triggered by the quake is repaired, although many have abandoned their ascents.
A massive avalanche killed 18 climbers and sherpa mountain guides at the Everest base camp.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:54:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Review of colonoscopies 'precautionary'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/698033-colonoscopy-health/</Link>
        <Description>The Health Service Executive has said it has extended a review of colonoscopies carried out at Wexford General Hospital, which was originally announced in February, as a precautionary measure.</Description>
        <MainBody>A colonoscopy involves an examination of the bowel to look for abnormalities.
The additional 330 patients have been notified and appointments are being set up.
The HSE says the extension is an extra precaution to ensure all patients have had a colonoscopy of the highest quality.
Of the extra 330 patients being called for a repeat procedure, 210 previously underwent a screening colonoscopy under the BowelScreen programme.
A further 121 patients who previously underwent a diagnostic colonoscopy have been recalled for an outpatient appointment.
The HSE has saida small number of these may require a colonoscopy and so far 30 patients have attended for their appointment.
The HSE says that all patients have been contacted and an information line remains open at Callsave 1850-241850 for anyone with queries or concerns.
The review started because the HSE's BowelScreen programme and Wexford General raised concerns about the quality of screening procedures, after two patients in October and November 2014 were identified with interval cancers, a cancer that is detected between bowel screenings.
Ken Mealy, consultant surgeon at Wexford General, has said that the HSE is proceeding on the basis that some bowel cancers may have been missed at the initial colonoscopy but he could not say that yet with certainty.
Speaking on RTs Today with Sean O' Rourke, he said that when the review process is complete, the HSE will be able to speak about any cancers that may have been missed.
He said that one of the problems was whether a cancer might have been missed, or if it had grown since the initial test, and experts may disagree on this matter.
Mr Mealy insisted that the HSE was committed to open disclosure in relation to the total of over 600 patients concerned.
This issue is separate to the review of x-rays and other scans involving three locum consultant radiologists that was reported yesterday.
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:57:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>O'Brien's injunction case adjourned until 12 May</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/698059-denis-obrien-court/</Link>
        <Description>Businessman Denis O'Brien's application for an injunction against RTÉ, preventing a report about what he says are his private banking affairs from being broadcast, has been adjourned until 12 May.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 01 May 2015 11.57
Denis O'Brien was given permission yesterday to give short notice to RT about injunction
Businessman Denis O'Brien's application for an injunction against RT, preventing a report about what he says are his private banking affairs from being broadcast, has been adjourned until 12 May.
Senior Counsel for Mr OBrienMichael Cushsaid the sides had reached an agreement in relation to an adjournment.
He said RT had undertaken not to publish or disclose the material at the centre of the application in the meantime.
Lawyers for RT said they consented to giving that undertaking.
Lawyers for the Irish Bank Resolution Corporation told the court they are also seeking an injunction against RT in relation to the report.
The IBRC's application was also adjourned until 12 May.
Yesterday, Mr Cush handed two sealed envelopes to Mr Justice Paul Gilligan.
He said the first contained a letter from RT to Mr O'Brien outlining the fact that work was being carried out by the news department on a report to be broadcast today.
He told the court yesterday that the report was to state certain matters and ask certain questions but at no point was it suggested there was wrongdoing on anyone's part which would be relevant to the public interest.
The second letter was written by Mr O'Brien and referred to details of particular sums of money representing his indebtedness to the IBRC.
Mr Cush said it referred to Mr O'Brien's personal banking facilities and was undoubtedly confidential.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:33:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Honohan departure marks 'end of era' - Noonan</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/698079-patrick-honohan-central-bank/</Link>
        <Description>Central Bank Governor Patrick Honohan has said he asked the Minister for Finance early last month to begin the process of finding his successor.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
He said Michael Noonan was surprised to be told of his retirement, but was understanding about it.
ProfHonohan said he felt it was a good time to go as it is a time of change and transition where the bank has moved from a crisis management phase and is now in a consolidation phase.
He said there has been a lot of change over the past six years.
Prof Honohan said he will be 66 in October and he wanted to give the Government six months to find a replacement. He intends to stay on as governor until November.
He also did not rule out the possibility of writing a book on the banking crisis and his time as Central Bank governor.
Mr Noonan said Prof Honohan's retirement willmark the end of an era.
He said he had "left an enduring legacy in his contribution to the stability of the country which is now beginning to strengthen and grow".
Taoiseach Enda Kenny has paid tribute to the work carried out by ProfHonohan as governor of the Central Bank.
Mr Kenny said ProfHonohan had informed him about his plans to retire yesterday saying he had saidhe was stepping down because he felt it was the right time for him to leave the post.
Mr Kenny described ProfHonohan as a "refreshing and very enthusiastic" governor.
The Taoiseach said every decision Prof Honohanhad made had been taken in a deeply-heldbelief that it was in the best interests of Ireland and her people.
Mr Kenny said ProfHonohan had a very difficult job to do and had approached it with dedication.
He wished him well in his retirement.
The process is now under way to identify candidates to replace Prof Honohan and under the Central Bank Act the appointment of a new governor is made by the president on the nomination of the Government.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:35:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bruton added to Fine Gael election ticket</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/698092-politics/</Link>
        <Description>The Fine Gael executive council has added Richard Bruton to the party's general election ticket for the Dublin Bay North constituency.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Meanwhile,Alex White has been selected as theLabour Party general election candidate for the new Dublin Rathdown constituency.
The Minister for Communications, Energy andNatural Resourceswas the only candidate nominated by members and his nomination was ratified at the Labour Party Dublin Rathdown selection convention.
The Taoiseach said last night's selection convention in the Dublin Bay North constituency would lead to "a little more competition" between party candidates.
Speaking in Castlebar, Co Mayo, Enda Kenny denied the vote by delegates was a rejection of the Government's gender quota policy for the general election campaign.
He said it there had been previous instances where sitting TDs had not been selected over the years.
The Taoiseach said that the three candidates would give voters a very formidable Fine Gael team.
He said the extra competition among candidates was probably a good thing in a democratic contest and said he issure all Fine Gael candidates would strive to do their very best.
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:40:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Motorcyclists urged to take care over weekend</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/698061-rsa-warning/</Link>
        <Description>Gardaí and the Road Safety Authority are urging motorists to take care over the bank holiday weekend, and to keep a particular look out for motorcyclists.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 01 May 2015 11.40
Five motorcyclists have died in crashes so far this year
Gardaand the Road Safety Authority are urging motorists to take care over the bank holiday weekend, and to keep a particular look out for motorcyclists.
Five people died on the country's roads over the May bank holiday weekend last year.
Five motorcyclists have died in crashes so far this year compared to two over the same period last year.
Drivers are being urged to constantly be on the lookout for motorcyclists.
Motorcyclists are asked to be extremely careful when overtaking, when negotiating bends and to be particularly mindful of their speed.
Figures show a greater number of motorcycle fatalities over the summer months in 2013 and 2014 due to good weather.
Minister for Transport Paschal Donohoe has appealed to all road users, ahead of the bank holiday, to take extra care when using the roads.
"The May bank holiday weekend was a very bad weekend for road safety last year.
"We lost five lives and six people sustained serious injuries over that four day period. I would appeal to everyone to be mindful of how you use the road, whether you are walking, cycling, riding a motorbike or driving,"he said.
Assistant Commissioner John Twomey of theGarda National Traffic Bureau said: "Members of An Garda Sochna will be out in force over the Bank Holiday Weekend to keep the roads safe from careless and dangerous drivers."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:17:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Staff at Tyndall institute strike over pay</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/698082-tyndall/</Link>
        <Description>Around 100 researchers, engineers, administration, technical and IT staff at one of the country's leading research institutions have gone on strike for a third time as a result of an ongoing pay dispute.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 01 May 2015 13.17
Workers say they will also strike next Wednesday and Thursday if the matter is not addressed
Around 100 researchers, engineers, administration, technical and IT staff at one of the country's leading research institutions have gone on strike for a third time as a result of an ongoing pay dispute.
Pickets were placed on entrances to the Tyndall National Institute in Cork at 7am by members of the SIPTU trade union and the Irish Federation of University Teachers, and will continue until 5pm.
The striking workers say there is pay inequity of 10-20% between them and those doing the same or similar work on the main campus of University College Cork, which the institute is a part of.
According to IFUT, the pay anomaly has resulted in research staff in senior supervising roles being paid lower wages than junior doctorate temporary contract staff.
The federation also claims that permanent research staff are being charged for a public service pension but denied access to public service pay and conditions.
The workers say they will conduct two further days of work stoppages next Wednesday and Thursday if the matter is not addressed.
The strikers also warn that if the five-year-long dispute is not resolved by 13 May, they will escalate their action by placing pickets on six entrances to the main campus at UCC.
They want a more robust appeals process put in place for staff who may be unhappy with the outcome of a job evaluation exercise conducted by external consultants.
This is the third time the workers have gone on strike over the issue.
Pickets were placed on the Tyndall facility on days in January and February last year.
The unions have given an assurance to students that exams will not be affected by their action.
UCC says it cannot accept that there is a reasonable justification for the industrial action, particularly given that it is exam season.
The university says the unions involved in the dispute are seeking to depart from an agreed process and are demanding a new appeals process on terms which have the potential to compromise the integrity of the entire exercise.
UCC says it is committed to implementing the agreement struck at the Labour Relations Commission in February last year and to engaging and cooperating fully with the agreed appeals process.
It also says that the agreed appeals mechanism, and the normal industrial relations machinery, remain open to staff dissatisfied with the outcome of the Job Evaluation Exercise.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:29:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Central Bank makes €2.1 billion profit last year</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/business/2015/0501/698060-central-bank-report/</Link>
        <Description>The Central Bank has reported profits of €2.1 billion for last year, €1.7 billion of which will be paid to the Exchequer.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 01 May 2015 13.29
Central Bank Governor confirms his intention to step down later this year
The Central Bank has reportedprofits of 2.1 billion for last year, which brings its profits over the last six years to 8 billion.
In its annual report, the Central Bank said the "unprecedented"scale of profits for the recent years reflects several exceptional crisis-related factors and the manner in which they have been handled by the bank.
It said that a total of 1.7 billion of this profit is being paid to the Exchequer.
Speaking at the launch of the Central Bank's annual report, its Governor Patrick Honohan said that this washis final report launch.
Professor Honohan said he believed this was a good time to go as the Central Bank is in a time of change and transition and is moving from a crisis management phase to a consolidation phase.
He said that there were no rows behind his decision to resign, adding that he is not getting any younger and that he had been asking himself for a long time as to when was the best moment to go.
Mr Honohan said he had asked the Minister for Finance in early April to start process of finding a successor. He will stay on to November, he added.
He said Michael Noonan was surprised to be told of his retirement, but was understanding about it.
He said there has been a lot of change over the past six years.
Professor Honohan said he will be 66 in October and he said he wanted to give the Government six months to find a replacement. He also did not rule out the possibility of writing a book on the banking crisis and his time as Central Bank governor.
Finance minister Michael Noonan said Professor Honohan's retirement will mark the end of an era.
He said he had "left an enduring legacy in his contribution to the stability of the country which is now beginning to strengthen and grow".
The process is now under way to identify candidates to replace Professor Honohan and under the Central Bank Act the appointment of a new governor is made by the President on the nomination of the Government.
Speaking at today's press conference, Mr Honohan said relations with Minister Noonan and Department of Finance have been very good. He said he goes there monthly with the National Treasury Management Agencyto "thrash out financial stability issues".
He also said that he personally has a very good working relations with senior officials at the department.
Mr Honohan said there was still a lot of damage evident in economy and he would liked to have seen much more progress on "curing" mortgage arrears.
He added that he should have expected slow progress on arrears as he knew from others that it takes a decade to clear financial crises.
The Central Bank boss also said that fragility is still a big issue for the Irish economy. He said the country's high levels of debtleaves the economy vulnerable to shocks and caution is still needed.
He also said that he had not changed his view that banks should be allowed to set interest rates for products independently,despite Government pressure on lenders to cut mortgage rates.
The country's banks have been urged to reduce standard variable rate mortgages, with Michael Noonan saying he expected them to cede to a request to do so, while other ministers have threatened to increase its annual bank levy.
"I don't know of any successful economy these days that attempts to have administrative regulation of retail interest rates," Mr Honohan stated today.
On Jean-Claude Trichet's appearance in Dublin yesterday, Mr Honohan said he thought it was great that the former ECB head had cometo Ireland.
He said Mr Trichetwanted to tell his story and the Irish wanted to hear it. He called the IIEA event"extraordinary" and very useful.
Professor Honohan said that Mr Trichet "has always been a friend of Ireland". He added that he did not disagree with anything Mr Trichet had said yesterday.
On the Government's Spring Economic Statement, which was delivered earlier this week, the Central Bank boss said it puts a degree of structure and discipline on the budget process.
He said the Central Bank has its own forecasts, which are slightly different. But he said the bank has no message it wants to deliver at this stage.
In the annual report, the Central Banksaid that after emerging from the EU-IMF programme at the end of 2013, the Irish economy continued to experience a recovery last year.
Itnoted that progress was made in the banking sector, with the banks' balance sheets gradually being repaired. However, Professor Honohan said that some challenges remain, especially around longer term loan arrears.
During the year, the Central Bank continued to engage directly with banks on the issue of the elevated levels of mortgage arrears.
The Governor said that after a slow start, the capacity and approach of the banks for dealing with distressed borrowers has "materially improved".
He noted that there has been a significant shift from relying on short-term measures to longer term, sustainable solutions.
Central Bank to stick to bond sales timetable
The Central Bank also said today that it will not change the timetable for bond sales tied to a 2013 deal the Government struck with the European Central Bank to ease the burden of its bank debt.
The Government won ECB approval in 2013 to stretch out the cost of bailing out the collapsed Anglo Irish Bank after nearly 18 months of talks, cutting billions off the country's borrowing needs and cutting its budget deficit.
As part of the debt swap, the NTMA pledged to issue new bonds worth 25 billion, but to slowly feed them into the market via the Central Bank, selling at least 500m a year from 2014 to 2018.
The ECB has since stated that the deal raised serious monetary financing concerns. These could be mitigated by a more ambitious sales schedule, the ECB said in its annual report released last month.
The Central Bank disposed of the minimum 500m of the long-dated government bonds in December last year.
"The policy in relation to disposals from this portfolio remains unchanged, i.e. they will be sold as soon as possible, provided conditions of financial stability permit," the Central Bank said in its annual report today.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two men arrested over fatal Limerick stabbing</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/697993-limerick/</Link>
        <Description>An investigation is under way after a 30-year-old man died following a stabbing in Co Limerick last night.</Description>
        <MainBody>Two men, aged 20 and 32, have been arrested in connection with the investigation and are being held at Henry Street and Roxboro Road Garda Stations.
The area has been sealed-off for a forensic examination.
The State Pathologist's office has been notified.
A garda spokesman said it was two early to confirm a motive for the incident and would not comment on reports that the victim had tried to intervene in dispute between a woman and another man.
Garda believe there wasup to eightpeople in the house at the time.
Garda have appealed for anyone with information to contact Bruff Garda Station on 061-382940, the Garda Confidential Line 1800 666111 or any Garda station.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:06:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>AIB to cut interest rates on some mortgages</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/697996-aib-economy/</Link>
        <Description>AIB has announced it is to cut mortgage interest rates on both occupier and buy-to-let mortgages.</Description>
        <MainBody>Earlier this week at the group's annual general meeting, Chairman Richard Pym hinted that cuts to mortgage interest rates were being considered.
That came as shareholders criticised AIB for "milking their customers" as the bank returns to profit.
At the time MrPym said AIB, as a commercial institution, needed to make sure that lending is at sustainable rates to see that it is able to rebuild its capital to insulate it against any future adverse shocks.
Today's cutis AIB's second reduction in mortgage interest rates in six months, reflecting the bank's improved financial performance.
The Taoiseach has welcomed the decision by AIB to lower variable interest rates for mortgage holders.
Enda Kennysaid it was a small but important step, which he hoped would be followed by other banks.
Hesaid he wanted to see the banks go further and reduce rates by a greater percentage andsaid it was not fair that banks could borrow money at very low rates but were charging customers significantly more.
Mr Kennycalled on all financial institutions to understand the "realism" that variable rates should fall.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:51:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News in Brief</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/698030-news-in-brief/</Link>
        <Description>Round-up of Irish and international stories</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 01 May 2015 13.51
Melih Gogcek referred to Marie Harf as 'stupid blonde' in his tweets over rioting in Baltimore
US ambassador to Turkey hits back over sexist remarks
The US ambassador to Turkey hit back at sexist remarks by Ankara's mayor to the US State Department spokeswoman in unusual style, posting a picture of himself with blond hair.
Ankara Mayor Melih Gokcek on Wednesday tweeted over the Baltimore rioting, telling the US State Department acting spokeswoman Marie Harf to "come on blonde answer now."
"Where are you stupid blonde, who accused Turkish police of using disproportionate force?" he added, referring to US criticism of the harsh response by Turkish police to demonstrations.
US ambassador to Turkey John Bass took to Instagram to make his response, posting a picture of himself with his normally brown hair turned blond. "American diplomats: we're all blonde," he wrote in English and Turkish.
Man dies in Co Waterford house fire
A man has died in a house fire in CoWaterford.
Emergency services from Carrick-on-Suir and Kilmacthomas were called to the scene in the Clonea Power/Rathgormack area at 7.30am.
The body of a man was discovered at the house, which was substantially damaged by fire.
Mass grave found in southern Thailand
Around 30 graves believed to belong to migrants from Burma and Bangladesh have been discovered in southern Thailand, a rescue worker said, in an area criss-crossed with trafficking routes.
"There are 32 graves, four bodies have now been exhumed," a rescue worker said.
A local policeman said 30 suspected graves had been found in a remote jungle camp.
Residents evacuated in Belfast security alert
Residents of homes thatwere evacuated during a bomb alert in east Belfast this morning have been allowed to return to their houses.
The alert began after a suspicious object was discovered in the area.
In north Belfast, police aresearching the Brompton Park and Crumlin Road areas and have warned the public not to touch any suspiciousobjects they may find.
Meanwhile, the PSNI are investigating after a pipe bomb type device was thrown into the front garden of a house in east Belfast early today.
Two people believed to have been involved in the bomb attack in the Island Street area made off on a motorcycle.
A motorbike thought to have been involved in the incident was recovered by police a short time later near Castlereagh Street.
Detectives are also investigating whether a single vehicle road traffic collision just before 5am today involving a red coloured Honda Civic car was also linked to the incident.
Broadband boost for Castlebar
 Pat McGrath (@patmcgrath) May 1, 2015
The Taoiseach's home town of Castlebar looks set to get a boost in broadband speed.
Network operator enet is to invest 1.5m of its own cash in the construction of afibre network around the town.
Construction of the ducts, sub ducts and fibre optic cables are due to begin immediately, and should be complete by November.
The open access network will be available for use by all broadband providers. Enet already operates 94 Metropolitan Area Networks (MANs) on behalf of the State, but Castlebar does not currently have one.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:54:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore prosecutors ask for patience</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/697995-baltimore-maryland/</Link>
        <Description>There have been fresh protests in the US city of Baltimore over the death of a black man who died from injuries sustained while in police custody.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 01 May 2015 08.54
1 of 2
People took to the streets of Baltimore ahead of the curfew
Police are under investigation after the death of Freddie Gray
There have been fresh protests in the US city of Baltimore over the death of a black man who died from injuries sustained while in police custody.
Hundreds of people marched through thestreets and similar protests were held in Philadelphia.
Baltimore's Police Commissioner Anthony Batts has urged the public to adhere to the curfew, which remains in place in the city.
Baltimore officials asked for patience while prosecutors decide whether to charge six officers involved in the arrest of Freddie Gray.
The office of the state's attorney, Marilyn Mosby, will include the internal report as part of its own investigation into the death of Mr Gray.
Hesuffered spinal injuries sometime between his 12 April arrest for carrying a switchblade knife and his arrival at a police station.
Mr Gray's death a week later has become the latest flashpoint in a national outcry over the treatment of African-Americans and other minority groups by police.
After a night of rioting in Baltimore on Monday, protests spread to other major cities later in the week in a reprise of demonstrations last year set off by police killings of unarmed black men in Ferguson, Missouri; New York; and elsewhere.
A few hundred protesters marched through Baltimore in a noisy but peaceful march yesterday ahead of a 10pm local time curfew that city officials said would continue through the weekend.
A rally of about 1,000 people in Philadelphia briefly turned tense as protesters tried to march onto a highway and were blocked by police.
In Milwaukee, Wisconsin, a small group marched to mark the one-year anniversary of the shooting death of Dontre Hamilton, shot 14 times by a police officer during a struggle.
Ms Mosby said her staff was regularly briefed by police investigators during the course of their investigation, and at the same time, her office has been conducting its own independent inquiry.
"We are not relying solely on their findings but rather the facts that we have gathered and verified," Ms Mosby said in a statement.
"We ask for the public to remain patient and peaceful and to trust the process of the justice system."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:45:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>7.1 magnitude earthquake off Papua New Guinea</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/698028-papua-new-guinea-earthquake/</Link>
        <Description>An earthquake of magnitude 7.1 has struck off Papua New Guinea, 128km south-south-west of Rabaul, at a depth of 61km, the United States Geological Survey reported.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 01 May 2015 12.45
Two earthquakes have struck off Papua Guinea in two days (Pic: Google Maps)
A 7.1 magnitude earthquake hit off Papua New Guinea, the US Geological Survey said, a day after a 6.7 magnitude tremor in the region.
The quake hit at 9.06am Irish time, 689km northeast of the Pacific nation's capital Port Moresby, in the New Britain region at a depth of 53km.
There were no tsunami warnings, the Pacific Tsunami Warning Centre said.
A 6.7 magnitude quake hit the same region yesterday, 131km southwest of Kokopo, but there were no reports of serious damage.
"This is the second earthquake that has occurred in that region over the last two days," co-director of the Joint Australian Tsunami Warning Centre Daniel Jaksa told AFP.
"The previous one was about 10km to the southeast of this particular epicentre. It's a very uninhabited region off the island of New Britain.
"The earthquake was a measure of 7.1, so that's about 30 times smaller than the earthquake in Nepal.
"It should be like the one yesterday - no real impact."
New Britain, the largest island of the Bismarck Archipelago, is east of mainland New Guinea and has a population of around 500,000 people.
The island lies on the 4,000km long Pacific Australia plate, which forms part of the "Ring of Fire," a hotspot for seismic activity due to friction between tectonic plates.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:30:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Climate change threatens 1 in 6 animals and plants</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0501/698094-climate-change-threatens-1-in-6-animals-and-plants/</Link>
        <Description>One in six of the animals and plants on the planet could face extinction if nothing is done to reduce the rate of climate change, a study has found.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 01 May 2015 13.30
Polar bears are one species which could disappear in the wild due to  climate change
One in six of the animals and plants on the planet could face extinction if nothing is done to reduce the rate of climate change, a study has found.
The new research suggests that biodiversity loss is accelerating with each Celsius degree rise in temperature.
If global warming continues unabated, raising the Earth's temperature by 4.3C compared with its pre-industrial level, 16% of species could be at risk, it is claimed.
Certain regions of the Earth are likely to be hardest hit, according to the forecast, with 23% of species affected in South America and 14% in Australia and New Zealand.
North America and Europe had the smallest proportion of species facing extinction, 5% and 6% respectively.
All taxonomic groups - extended families of animals and plants - were equally at risk.
The research is based on an analysis of 131 different biodiversity studies taking into account a range of factors including modelling technique, taxonomic group, location, global temperature and species distribution.
Results published in the journal Science show that species loss is closely linked to climate change - not only increasing but accelerating as temperatures rise.
Author Dr Mark Urban, from the University of Connecticut in the US, wrote: "The factor that best explained variation in extinction risk was the level of future climate change.
"Global extinction risks increase from 2.8% at present to 5.2% at the international policy target of a 2C post-industrial rise, which most experts believe is no longer achievable.
"If the Earth warms to 3C the extinction risk rises to 8.5%. If we follow our current, business-as-usual trajectory ... climate change threatens one in six species (16%)."
He added that regions around the world differed "significantly" in extinction risk.
South America, Australia and New Zealand all harboured vulnerable diverse groups of endemic species with small ranges.
Extinction risk in Australia and New Zealand was exacerbated by small habitats that limited the ability of species to move to new homes.
Dr Urban pointed out that in 1981 scientists predicted the signal of global climate change would soon emerge from the background "noise" of weather.
He said: "Thirty years later we are reaching a similar threshold for the effects of climate change on biodiversity.
"Extinction risks from climate change are expected not only to increase but to accelerate for every degree rise in global temperatures. The signal of climate change-induced extinctions will become increasingly apparent if we do not act now to limit future climate change."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:37:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trichet denies stopping burning of bondholders</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0430/697732-banking-inquiry/</Link>
        <Description>The former head of the ECB, Jean Claude Trichet, has denied it blocked the burning of senior bondholders by Ireland.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mr Trichet said he did not think it would have been wise for Ireland to burn junior bondholders at a time when it was regaining the market's trust.
However, he said he did not threaten to withdraw ECB assistance to Ireland if they did so.
Speaking onRT's Prime Time,Mr Trichet said in the run up to the 2008 bank guarantee he did not ask former finance minister Brian Lenihan to save the banks at all costs.
He said it was thesentiment ofall governments of the world at the timeto avoid a collapse, adding"these were dramatic circumstances.
He said he had a "confident" relationship with Mr Lenihan.
"We were in a situation where a depression -not a recession - a depression was at stake" he said.
Mr Trichet said the ECB helped Ireland more than any other country in Europe. "I think it has to be known Ireland was helped by the ECB in an extraordinary fashion" he said.
He said he had a lot of admiration for Ireland and described the country as a success story.
"Ireland has always accepted its responsibilities. It has never played a game that other countries would have played" he said.
Bank guarantee a 'thunderbolt' - Trichet
Speaking earlier today at an eventorganised by the Institute of International and European Affairs,Mr Trichet describedthe bank guarantee as a "thunderbolt".
He said the ECB had warned all governments to be careful following the "drama" coming from the collapse of Lehman Brothers in the United States.
Mr Trichetsaid ministers around Europe were saying that they would not allow a similar collapse in their countries.
Domestic and European failures played a role in Ireland's financial crisis, he said, thoughlarge imbalances in Ireland inflictedserious economic damage.
Mr Trichet led the ECB when Ireland introduced the bank guarantee and when the country went into a rescue programme with the European Union and the IMFin controversial circumstances.
He said Ireland did not seek advice from the ECB about a bank guarantee and the ECB did not give any.
He said the ECB learned of the Irish guarantee through the media.
Mr Trichet said the guaranteewas a response to the mounting financing pressures on the Irish banking sector and in this context could be understood.
He said Mr Lenihan did what he thought was best in traumatic circumstances, and thatit was important to note that the Government went ahead with the guarantee without any co-ordination from the ECB or any of its European partners.
When asked if the ECB spoke to anyone in Ireland about a guarantee of any kind prior to September 2008, Mr Trichet said no.
The absence of a European framework meant that financial imbalances like these went uncorrected, Mr Trichet said.
He also said his systematic warnings on labour costs were ignored in Europe.
He admitted that European governance was not good enough to deal with the challenges posed by the crisis, but said national failures were a more significant part of the problem.
Mr Trichet says he tried to point out problems in banks in Europe, but national central banks were the regulators.
This was a bad system, he said, but it has now changed.
Mr Trichetsaid Europe now has mechanisms to ensure that, if a bank fails, it will not bring down a country.
He also defended the actions of the ECB, saying it and other central banks prevented the financial crisis from becoming a 1930s-style depression.
Mr Trichet said Ireland had had the full support of the ECB, pointing out that 25% of all refinancing for euro area banks went to banks in Ireland.
Aspart of a compromise agreement with the banking inquiry, Mr Trichet answered questions from inquiry members after his lecture at the IIEA event in Kilmainham.
Initially, the ECB had insisted that it is not accountable to national parliaments or the bank inquiry, but afterprotracted representations by the Government a compromise was reached.
Responding to a question from banking inquiry Chairman Ciarn Lynch, Mr Trichet said the ECB is only accountable to the European Parliament and so can not participate in a national parliament's inquiry.
Banking inquiry Chairman Ciaran Lynch has asked Jean-Claude Trichet why he did not appear before the inquiry https://t.co/VF1JLbqjJc
 RT News (@rtenews) April 30, 2015
Opening his address, Mr Trichet said that Ireland returned to market financing before the end of its bailout programme, while the banking industry has seen a return to stability and the country's economy is recovering at an impressive pace.
But he saidhe remembered the huge uncertainty about where Europe was going during the crisis, whichcould have resulted in great global depression.
Mr Trichet said the terrible lesson of the crisis was that you cannot rely on market discipline to control government finances.
He said problems can be hidden by good numbers and good governance was needed to identify this.
He paid homage to those involved in governments which hadled the country through the crisis, as well as the general public.
Mr Trichetpraised the flexibility of the Irish workforce, as well as the understanding of people in doing what was necessary to regain competitiveness.
He said confidence was importance for Ireland as the country gained the confidence of people, markets and investors through its actions.
He saidthe strength of return to economic soundness and market credibility was impressive.
Trichet warns over future economic uncertainty pic.twitter.com/XAgUaLgydA
 RT News (@rtenews) April 30, 2015
But he said it was no time to declare victory as there were still challenges facing the country.
One was the "overhang" from the crisis, he said, pointing to debt levels and youth unemployment in particular.
The second was the issue of non-performing loans that remain on Irish banks' balance sheets.
Sinn Fin's Pearse Doherty asks Jean-Claude Trichet how the ECB acted on Irish stability reports https://t.co/GaifSskJIe
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:02:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Richard Bruton not selected at FG convention vote</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0430/697973-fine-gael/</Link>
        <Description>Minister for Jobs, Entreprise and Innovation, Richard Bruton, was not selected to run for Fine Gael in the general election at the Dublin Bay North Selection convention this evening.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 01 May 2015 00.02
The Fine Gael executive council is due to add him to the ticket tomorrow
Stephanie Regan and CouncillorNaoise O' Muiri were selected to run for Fine Gael in the general election at theDublin Bay North Selection convention this evening.
Minister for Jobs, Entreprise and Innovation, Richard Bruton, was not selected.
The Fine Gael executive council is due to add him to the ticket tomorrow.
This was unanimously agreed by the convention.
It is understood there was a directive from Fine Gael HQ to pick two candidates.
Stephanie Regan has said she is delighted to have been selected and thatshe had a lot of support at the meeting.
She added that she was sorry that Richard Bruton was not selected, andsaid she cannot explain why that happened.
Ms Regan added that she represents the North East end of the constituency, and she believes geography was a big factor.
Cllr Naoise O'Muir said he had wanted to be a Fine Gael candidate in the general election, and had put his name forward to members who had chosen him.
He added that he had seconded the proposal to add Richard Bruton to the ticket, who he described as an excellent minister.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:43:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Polls say Cameron topped TV election special</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0430/697975-polls-say-cameron-tops-televised-election-special/</Link>
        <Description>British Prime Minister David Cameron came out on top in a poll following the last televised set piece of the UK's general election campaign.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 01 May 2015 07.43
1 of 2
David Cameron faced questions about about his party's plans to cut welfare
Ed Miliband said he will not have Labour government if it means a deal with the SNP
British Prime Minister David Cameron came out on top in a poll following the last televised set piece of the UK's general election campaign.
Mr Cameron was speaking on a BBC 1 Question Time general election leaders' special where he, along with Labour leaderEd Miliband and Liberal Democratleader Nick Clegg separately answeredquestions from a studio audience.
The programme was airedin a format devised after Mr Cameron refused to take part in a head-to-head encounter with his Labour rival proposed by UK broadcasters.
The Prime Minister faced tough questioning from the studio audience about Conservative plans to cut welfare.
Mr Miliband was also put on the spot over the last Labour government's spending.
He was questionedon whether he would do a deal with the Scottish National Party but insisted there would be no Labour government if it meant relying on their support.
Mr Cameron rejected suggestions he was planning to cut 8 billion from child benefit and child tax credit.
But both Mr Miliband and Mr Clegg responded that his comments did not amount to a guarantee that the benefits were safe.
Mr Miliband said he did not accept that the last Labour government overspent while in office and promised the party was "absolutely, deadly serious"about balancing the books in the next parliament.
An instant poll of Question Time viewers conducted by ICM for The Guardian showed that44% thought Mr Cameron had "done best on the night", against 38% for Mr Miliband and 19% for Mr Clegg.
An audience member directly asked Mr Miliband: "Do you accept that when Labour was last in power it overspent?"
He replied: "No, I don't ... There was a global financial crisis which caused the deficit to rise. President Obama isn't dealing with a high deficit because we built more schools and hospitals.
"He is dealing with a deficit because of the global financial crisis."
As he explained the financial difficulties the coalition faced when it entered office in 2010, Mr Cameron took from his pocket the famous letter left by former Treasury minister Liam Byrne telling his successor "there's no money left".
He said he had been "carrying it with me everywhere"during the campaign, but Mr Miliband dismissed it as "his regular prop".
Mr Clegg reiterated his assertion that the Lib Dems would first try to seek a coalition deal with the largest party in terms of votes and seats after 7 May.
But the Deputy Prime Minister also indicated that if a deal cannot be struck then he would consider speaking to the second-placed party.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
