<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="rte">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:12:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trial hears FitzPatrick was concerned about 'mate'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713227-anglo-trial/</Link>
        <Description>Seán FitzPatrick was concerned about the name of his "mate" Denis O'Brien being included on a list of non-resident account holders in Anglo Irish Bank to be submitted to Revenue in 2003, the Dublin Circuit Criminal Court has heard.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Tiarnan O'Mahoney, Aoife Maguire and Bernard Daly deny the charges.
Mr Gillespie described Mr FitzPatrick's concern that the name of his brother-in-law, John Peter O'Toole, was to be submitted to the Revenue Commissioners as a non-resident account holder following a High Court order in 2003.
Mr Gillespie said at no time did Mr FitzPatrick ask him to delete the account from the list to be provided to Revenue.
But Mr Gillespie said he got the impression that if he had found it within himself to not report the account, then Mr FitzPatrick would be greatly pleased.
Mr Gillespie said he was very clear and consistent - the order was very straightforward and there was no way he was going to leave Mr O'Toole's account out.
Mr Gillespie said that while the focus was on Mr O'Toole, Mr FitzPatrick did ask him about another name on the list of accounts to be submitted to Revenue.
He said Mr FitzPatrick referred to the name "Denis O'Brien" and referred to him as "my mate, Denis".
Mr Gillespie told the court he was able to reassure Mr FitzPatrick as he did not believe then and he does not believe for a second that the name had anything to do with the Denis O'Brien most people have in their minds.
He said it was a common enough name and this was a different individual who had an address in the UK.
Mr Gillespie said he recalled that Mr FitzPatrick described him as "a bit naive".
He told the court he did not believe this Mr O'Brien was the better known Denis O'Brien.
Mr Gillespie told the court that in 2003 he was asked to supply documentation to Revenue on non-resident accounts on which Deposit Interest Retention Tax (DIRT) may have been owed.
Mr Gillespie said that Revenue had obtained a High Court order requiring Anglo to hand over details of non-resident accounts which had been closed.
He said the High Court order was for non-resident accounts but not necessarily bogus non-resident accounts.
He said he would supply requested accounts and Revenue would decide if they were bogus or not.
Mr Gillespie said he recalled being called up to the office of Sen FitzPatrick, who was then chief executive.
He said he did not know why he was there but that it soon became clear it was in relation to the High Court order.
Mr Gillespie told the court yesterday and under cross-examination today that Mr FitzPatrick asked him why an account in the name of his brother-in-law John Peter O'Toole was being included in the return to the Revenue Commissioners.
He said Mr FitzPatrick said his brother-in-law lived in the UK and was now living in Australia and supporting his mother.
He said Mr FitzPatrick was concerned that his brother-in-law was going to be "reported"" to the Revenue.
He said he was aware that Mr FitzPatrick was protective about his family members in a normal way.
He said he explained that Mr O'Toole's account met the criteria outlined in the High Court order but he said he told Mr FitzPatrick that did not mean it was a "bogus non-resident account" and that the order covered accounts where there was absolutely no issue as well as those where there was an issue.
He agreed that explanation did not really satisfy him.
He said he was again summoned to Mr FitzPatrick's office a week or two later.
He said Mr FitzPatrick said he had had a conversation with another director of the bank, Peter Killen, and that Mr Killen had told Mr FitzPatrick to "just tell Brian to delete the account".
Mr Gillespie described Mr FitzPatrick's speech as a "monologue" and said he did not get an opportunity to respond to specifics.
But he said when Mr FitzPatrick had finished, he reminded him about the criteria in the High Court order and said they had no choice but to comply and to provide the information requested.
He said not long afterwards, he was called to Mr FitzPatrick's office again.
This time Mr FitzPatrick told him he was concerned that a relative was going to be "reported" to the Revenue and was losing sleep over it.
He said this time Mr FitzPatrick gave him a different version of a conversation with Peter Killen.
He said that Mr FitzPatrick said that he (Mr FitzPatrick) had suggested to Mr Killen that he should just tell Brian to delete the account.
Mr Gillespie said at no time did Mr FitzPatrick ask him to delete the account from the list to be provided to Revenue.
But Mr Gillespie said he got the impression that if he had found it within himself to not report the account, then Mr FitzPatrick would be greatly pleased.
Mr Gillespie said he was very clear and consistent - the order was very straightforward and there was no way he was going to leave Mr O'Toole's account out.
He said Mr FitzPatrick said to him that he wanted him to be comfortable with his actions, in case he was ever called before a tribunal.
He said it was clear to him that if he did not report the account, Mr FitzPatrick would view it positively.
But Mr Gillespie said that was not going to happen.
Mr Gillespie said that while the focus was on Mr O'Toole, Mr FitzPatrick did ask him about another name on the list of accounts to be submitted to Revenue.
He said Mr FitzPatrick referred to the name "Denis O'Brien" and referred to him as "my mate, Denis".
Mr Gillespie said he was able to reassure Mr FitzPatrick as he did not believe then and he does not believe for a second that the name had anything to do with the Denis O'Brien that most people have in their minds.
He said it was a common enough name and this was a different individual who had an address in the UK.
He said he recalled that Mr Fitzpatrick described him as a bit naive.
He agreed again that he did not believe this Mr O'Brien was the better known Denis O'Brien.
Mr Gillespie said he had tried to raise what Mr FitzPatrick had said with his superior, Director of Finance, Willie McAteer but he said Mr McAteer was in some sort of dispute with Mr FitzPatrick at the time and did not want to talk about him.
He said he had a conversation with Tiarnan O'Mahoney who said he must have been under terrible pressure and it must have been stressful talking to Mr FitzPatrick about this.
He said Mr O'Mahoney told him he should not include Mr O'Toole on the list for Revenue without getting back to him.
He said he told him afterwards that Mr O'Toole was to be included and he said Mr O'Mahoney said "Fine".
Former company secretary Mr Daly, 65, of Collins Avenue West, Whitehall, Dublin; former chief operations officer Mr O'Mahoney, 54, of Glen Pines, Enniskerry, Co Wicklow; and Aoife Maguire, 60, of Rothe Abbey, South Circular Road, Kilmainham, Dublin have pleaded not guilty to seven alleged offences committed in 2003 and 2004.
The three are accused of trying to delete references to two accounts in the name of John Peter O'Toole from Anglo's Core Banking System (CBS).
Mr Daly and Mr O'Mahoney also deny omitting the name of Mr O'Toole from a list provided to the Revenue Commissioners of people who held non-resident accounts worth more than 100,000 in 1995.
Mr O'Mahoney and Ms Maguire further deny attempting to delete six other accounts, connected to Mr FitzPatrick.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:02:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman loses case for damages over hysterectomy</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713209-galway-clinic-court/</Link>
        <Description>A woman who claimed she suffered chronic pain and had difficulty walking after a hysterectomy has lost her High Court case for damages.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.02
The judgment was issued today at the High Court by Mr Justice Anthony Barr
A woman who claimed she suffered chronic pain and had difficulty walking after a hysterectomy has lost her High Court case for damages.
Mary McNicholas from Kiltimagh, Co Mayo, had sued Andrea Hermann, a consultant obstetrician,who carried out the procedure at the Galway Clinic in 2005.
Ms McNicholas had told the court she suffered nerve damage as a result of the operation causing continuing numbness and severe pain in her left leg.
She had alleged that the pre-operative care given by Dr Hermann was deficient as she had not been advised to lose weight before the operation.
She also claimed that the use of aself-retaining retractor during the operation had caused injury to her femural nerve.
Ms McNicholas had called expert witnesses who said the retractor should be released a number of times during surgery to prevent nerve damage.
However, the defendant had also called expert witnesses who said releasing the retractor during the operation would have delayed the procedure and placed her at greater risk from blood loss.
In a judgment issued today, following a hearing in January, Mr Justice Anthony Barr said Ms McNicholas had been previously advised by another doctor of the need to lose weight before the surgery.
She then went to Dr Hermann for a second opinion and was told the operation could be carried out whenever she wanted.
The judge said this was an "honest difference of opinion"and he was satisfied that the approach of both doctors was reasonable.
In this regard he did not find that Dr Hermann had departed from the appropriate standard of care in deciding that she could undergo the operation.
The judge said he was also satisfied that the procedure itself was carried out correctly and that negligence had not been established.
He said he could not find that in failing to release the self-retaining retractor the doctor had departed from the expected standard of care.
He said if she had done so it would have exposed Ms McNicholas to even more danger.
He dismissed the case.
Lawyers for Ms McNicholas have said they need time to study the judgment before deciding on an appeal.
The case was adjourned to24July.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:25:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Juncker wants Greek exit to be 'avoided'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713111-greece-economy/</Link>
        <Description>European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker has said he was against an exit by Greece from the euro.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
However, he added that the eurozone is made up of 19 democracies so the choices made by the other 18 democracies must be respected.
The head of the European Parliament, Martin Schulz, said he was in favour of Greece remaining in the eurozone.
Speaking at a press conference in Strasbourg, Mr Schulz said: "Those people who want to split up the eurozone I think are wrong," he said.
"My personal opinion is that Grexit cannot be our aim."
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras will present new proposals to theemergency summit in Brussels for a deal on his country's deepening debt crisis.
Taoiseach Enda Kenny has said he believes the Greek Prime Minister will bring credible and economically sensible proposals to European leaders.
Speaking on his way into this morning's Cabinet meeting, Mr Kenny said Greece was doing the right thing in bringing new propositions to the European institutions.
The European Central Bank has increased pressure on the Greek financial system by refusing to increase the level of emergency lending to Greek banks.
The banks, which had been due to reopen today, will now not open until at least Thursday.
The Athens stock exchange will also remain closed until tomorrow, the Greek Capital Markets Commission said.
Syriza MEP Dimitris Papadimoulis said the government is submitting proposals that will lead to growth and address the problem of non-sustainable public debt.
He told reporters in Strasbourg that the "message of the Greek government and Syriza is not to have a conflictWe cannot pursue the punishment of the Greek people. We want realism to prevail."
"We are submitting a programme full of reforms in order to set an end to bureaucracy, corruption and nepotism."
Speaking through an interpreter, Mr Papadimoulis added "we are willing to discuss any idea that could help in order to achieve a mutually accepted agreement."
"We could examine the idea of a bridging loan that would allow all sides towards a solution. We are moving towards the edge of the cliff."
The leaders of France and Germany told Greece yesterday to come up with serious proposals in order to restart financial aid talks.
In a warning shot to the banks, the ECB raised the amount of collateral they must post for any loans.
The move does not affect the lenders right away, but served as a reminder that their fate lies in its hands.
Late last night, Mr Tspiras's office said he had spoken with Mr Juncker and French President Francois Hollande, but did not provide details about the conversations.
Senior officials in both the USand Japan called on both sides to seek a resolution.
US Treasury Secretary Jack Lew spoke with both Mr Tsipras and his new finance minister Euclid Tsakalotos, following the resignation of Yanis Varoufakis yesterday.
Mr Lew said Washington looked forward to Athens and other parties resuming conversations towards resolving the Greek situation, a Treasury spokeswoman said.
Mr Lew voiced hope such an outcome "will allow Greece to make difficult but necessary fiscal and structural reforms, return to growth, and achieve debt sustainability within the eurozone," the Treasury statement said.
Similarly, Japan's economics minister, Akira Amari, said Greece and the European Union should work hard to strike a win-win deal that would keep Greece in the currency union.
A German Finance Ministry official dismissed the idea that Berlin would be willing to concede some debt relief to Athens, a position that Mr Tsipras's government has long sought.
But an ECB governing council member, Ewald Nowotny, held out the possibility of bridge funding for Greece while a new bailout programme is being negotiated.
"Whether it's possible is something that has to be discussed," he told Austrian state TV.
Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte said Greece must accept deep reforms if it wants to remain in the euro.
The Greek bank association chief said the bank closures that have crippled the economy would continue today and tomorrow and the daily cash machine withdrawal limit of 60 would be maintained.
There were long lines at ATMs, where 20 banknotes have largely run out.
After five years of economic crisis and mass unemployment, Greek electors voted 61.3% No to the bailout conditions already rejected by their government, casting Greece into uncharted territory.
Minister for Public Expenditure and Reform Brendan Howlin said he believes there will be solidarity among European leaders as they meet over Greece.
Speaking ahead of this morning's Cabinet meeting, Mr Howlin said Ireland wanted a deal to be reached with Greece, and wanted the country to remain in the eurozone.
He said he hoped that terms that are fair to every country would be agreed.
Mr Howlin said he also hoped that a deal involving debt re-profiling, rather than debt relief, would be reached with Athens, which was the sametype of agreement that had been made with Ireland.
He also said that as far as he was aware Minister for Finance Michael Noonan had not made any complaints against Mr Varoufakis.
The former Greek finance minister said in a blog posting announcing his resignation that he had been"made aware" that some members of the eurozone considered him unwelcome at meetings of finance ministers.
Western Union restarts money transfer service in Greece
Western Union said it restarted its money transfer service in Greece, allowing customers in the country to receive funds from overseas.
The company said although the full amount transferred would be credited to account holders, users would be able to withdraw only 60 a day as per the Greek government's recent capital control measures.
Western Union had said on June 29 that it would remain closed for business in Greece for the entire week. 
Analysis: Paul Cunningham
We still don't know what the deal is. We don't know whether this is a radical Syriza plan -one which talks about a write-down on debt or whether it is an amendment of the previous plans being worked on by Jean Claude Juncker with one or two changes.
So we are still somewhat in the dark.
The other big question is whether or not other eurozone ministers, including Michael Noonan, believe it forms the basis of negotiation.
If they think that's the case, then they will send a recommendation to eurozone leaders, who are due to meet around 5.30pm Irish time in Brussels.
That will probably be another two or three hour discussion.
No major decisions [will] be taken but basically what they will say is, there's enough to be working on here, let's see if we can hammer out a deal.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:27:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stolen boating equipment worth €150K recovered</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713224-boats/</Link>
        <Description>Boating equipment worth €150,000 has been recovered by gardaí investigating the theft of boat engines.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
They have managed to locate an owner for one of the engines butthey are now appealing for boat owners who may have had an engine stolen recently to view the items on the garda social media sites to see if their engine is amongthe property.
Detective Sgt John Healysaid: "We feel that the engines could belong to people countrywide, so we're asking everyone from Killybegs to Castletownbere to look at the photos.
"We've set up a dedicated email for people to contact us and make an appointment to view if they believe that their property is here with us".
One caravan, eight trailers and two generators were also recovered in the searches.
The public isasked to email portlaoise.property@garda.ie or ring 057 8674100 to arrange viewing.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:26:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant dies in Channel Tunnel</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713168-migrant-channel-tunnel/</Link>
        <Description>A migrant has died on a freight shuttle trying to reach the UK, Channel Tunnel operator Eurotunnel has confirmed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 14.26
Migrants have been seen trying to climb onto trucks queuing in Calais
A migrant has died on a freight shuttle trying to reach the UK, Channel Tunnel operator Eurotunnel has confirmed.
The incident on the French side of the Channel happened at around 5am Irish time.
Freight traffic is being disrupted and there are also delays to passenger services following the incident near Calais.
The migrant crisis in Calais has escalated in recent months, with around 3,000 people displaced from countries including Eritrea, Syria and Afghanistan setting up camp near the port.
Last week more than 3,000 truckers had to queue for several days in high temperatures on the M20 following a wildcat strike by ferry workers in France.
Industrial action by ferry workers this summer has come on top of the problems faced by hauliers with migrants desperately trying to clamber on board their HGVs to the UK.
French authorities have faced claims they are not doing enough to safeguard lorry drivers from intimidation, violence and attempts by migrants to climb on.
British Home Secretary Theresa May and her French counterpart Bernard Cazeneuve last week agreed to increase the joint intervention fund to improve security around the port and the Channel Tunnel.
French aid workers have reported a "catastrophic" situation, with predictions that 2,000 more migrants could arrive over the summer at the camp, dubbed Jungle II.
Volunteers from L'Auberge Des Migrants say up to 50 new migrants are arriving every day at the camp, and there are not enough tents, blankets or food
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wallace sees no value in discussing NAMA at PAC</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713131-nama-northern-ireland/</Link>
        <Description>Independent TD Mick Wallace has said he does not feel any purpose would be served by appearing before the Public Accounts Committee to answer questions about his NAMA claims.</Description>
        <MainBody>In a letter seen by RT News, Mr Wallace tells the clerk ofthe committeethat his appearance would not serve any purpose.
He said what was needed was an independent inquiry to investigate the entire NAMA operation.
Last year a US investment company, Cerberus Capital Management, bought a NAMA portfolio of Northern Ireland-based debtors.
It had a book value of 4.5bn. The purchase price was not disclosed but NAMA said at the time it was the biggest single transaction in the agency's history.
Mr Wallace claimeda routine auditshowed7m in funding ended up in an Isle of Man bank account.
He said the moneywas "reportedly earmarked for a Northern Ireland politician".
Meanwhile, the Finance Committee of the Stormont Assembly, which is considering the claims,has saidit wants to begin hearing evidence next week.
It is to invite Mr Wallace along with representatives of NAMA and the Belfast law firm involved to answer questions.
However, it is understood that Mr Wallace sees no purpose in acceding to that request either.
Finance Committee Chairman DaithMcKaysaid it would be asking the questions the public are asking.
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:13:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain marks 10th anniversary of 7 July bombings</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713115-july-7-bombings-london/</Link>
        <Description>Remembrance services to commemorate the 10th anniversary of attacks targeting London public transport, which killed 52 people, are under way.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
British Prime Minister David Cameron and Mayor of LondonBoris Johnson laid wreaths at the permanent memorial to the victims in Hyde Park at 8.50am - the time a series of explosions hit the transport network on 7 July 2005.
That morning during rush-hour, four young British Muslims travelledto London where they detonated homemade bombs hidden in rucksacks on three underground trains and a bus.
Inspired by al-Qaeda, they killed themselves and 52 other people and wounded around 700 others.
Citizens from Poland, Israel, Australia, France, Italy, Afghanistan, Nigeria, New Zealand and a Vietnamese-American were among the victims.
In a note attached to his wreath, Mr Cameron wrote: "To the victims of terrorism in London ten years ago today. We grieve your loss and will honour your memory for ever."
Also laying wreaths at the Hyde Park memorial were Transport Commissioner Sir Peter Hendy, Fire Commissioner Ron Dobson, and chief executive of London Ambulance Dr Fiona Moore.
Others were speaker of the House of Commons John Bercow and MP Harriet Harman.
The wording on the wreath laid by Mr Johnsonread: "Ten years may have passed, but London's memory is undimmed. We honour again today the victims of 7/7. You will live forever in the hearts of the people of this city. Boris Johnson"
My thoughts today are with all who were killed and injured in the appalling 7 July bombings in London 10 years ago.
 Daniel Mulhall (@DanMulhall) July 7, 2015
Mr Cameron said in a statement this morning:"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly."
He said: "The murder of 30 innocent Britons whilst holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact. But we will never be cowed by terrorism."
Ceremoniesinclude a national minute of silence, which was marked at 11.30am.
Itcomes just four days after Britain paid a similar tribute to those killed when an Islamist gunman opened fire at the Tunisian resort of Sousse.
A further service will be held later at the memorial site for survivors and relatives, which Prince William will attend.
Britain is currently on its second highest alert level of "severe".
That means a militant attack is considered highly likely, mainly due to the danger the authorities say is posed by so-called Islamic State groupfighters and Britons who have joined them.
On Thursday 7 July 2005, Shehzad Tanweer, 22, MohammedSidique Khan, 30, Hasib Hussain, 18 and Jermaine Lindsay, 19, arrived at King's Cross at around 8.23am.
At 8.30am four men fitting their descriptions are seen hugging before splitting up.
Khan boarded a west-bound Circle Line train, Tanweer an east-bound Circle Line train, and Lindsay a south-bound Piccadilly Line train. Hussain also appears to walk towards the Piccadilly Line entrance.
At 8.50am three bombs exploded within a minute on London Underground trains.
Tanweer detonated his bomb at Aldgate, Khan set his device off at Edgware Road and Lindsay blew himself up between King's Cross and Russell Square.
Hussain detonated his device on a number 30 bus at Tavistock Square at 9.47am.
Twenty-six died in the bombing at Russell Square on the Piccadilly line, six in the bombing at Edgware Road on the Circle line, seven in the bombing at Aldgate on the Circle line, and 13 in the bombing on the bus at Tavistock Square.
One of those who died at Russell Square was 22-year-old Ciaran Cassidy, whose parents are from Ireland. He worked at alegal and stationery firm in Chancery Lane and was saving up to go to Australia.
Source: Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:25:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>House price growth slows in Dublin</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713114-house-prices/</Link>
        <Description>The growth in house prices in Dublin was significantly slower than elsewhere in the country for the second quarter in a row.</Description>
        <MainBody>Prices were up by 4.4% in Cork, in Galway they climbed by 3.8% and in Waterford they grew by 3.4%.
Outside the major cities prices were up 2.8% over the same period.
For the country as a whole, the average asking price for a house in Ireland grew by 1.9% in the second quarter of 2015.
This means that in all but one of the last seven quarters, the average price has risen nationwide.
Daft.ie said the average price of a house nationwide is now 202,000, compared to a low of 164,000 in mid-2013 and a peak of 370,000 in 2007.
Author of the reportRonan Lyonssaid the figures showthe new lending rules introduced by the Central Bank have taken effect.
Mr Lyons said Dublin is now responsible for dragging the national asking price down, instead of pushing it up, as it had been doing two or three years ago.
Speaking on RTs Morning Ireland, he said the new rules are having a cooling-off effect on house prices in Dublin, which, he said, should be a permanent affect.
He said: "There is also a potential temporary effect, in that once you introduce these rules, you reshuffle demand a little bit around the country, in particular from Dublin to the counties around it."
He added: "The Central Bank's aim here was really to make sure people didn't borrow too much.
"And people were borrowing most relative to their capacity to pay back in Dublin.
"So it was clear that if they were going to have an impact anywhere, it was going to be, particularly in terms of cooling off house prices, it was going to be in Dublin."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:25:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News in Brief</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713124-news-in-brief/</Link>
        <Description>A round-up of Irish and other international news.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 14.25
Frances Fitzgerald said there were 550 new garda recruits in the past year
Garda force stood at 12,772 at end of May
Minister for Justice and Equality Frances Fitzgerald has told the Dil that of 31 May, the current strength of An Garda Sochna stood at 12,772.
Speaking during Minister's Questions, she said there were 550 new recruits in the past year and she had a commitment of two further intakes of 225 each.
She was responding to Fianna Fil Justice Spokesperson Niall Collins, who asked about the minister's projections for total garda numbers up to 2017.
Three men gored during Pamplona bull run
Three men were gored and ten others taken to hospital on the first day of Pamplona's week-long San Fermin festival in the northern Spanish city where bulls chase runners in red scarves through the streets.
The run lasted two minutes and 23 seconds.
One man was gored in the chest and was in a stable condition, a doctor at the event said. The Red Cross said two other men were gored, one in the back, but gave no further details.
Many Spanish towns hold festivals involving bulls during the summer. San Fermin is the most famous internationally and attracts thousands of revellers, many from abroad.
Space weather warning system developed
A warning system about space weather events that have the potential to damage communication and energy systems has been developed by scientists at Trinity College Dublin and the Dublin Institute of Advanced Studies (DIAS).
The magnetometer network enables researchers to monitor and model magnetic storms in near-real time, giving them advance knowledge of when a potentially damaging solar storm is about to hit.
The system got its first big test on 17 March when the two enormous eruptions from the Sun caused particles to collide at millions of kilometres per hour with Earth's magnetic field.
The result was the biggest geomagnetic storms in a decade, which led to spectacular displays of the northern lights.
The Trinity and DIAS team is now focusing on trying to understand how these large storms might impact on Earth and on improving their forecasting system.
NineSport NI board members resign
Nine members of the Sport NI board have resigned.
They offered their resignations just before a meeting with Stormont Sports Minister Carl N Chuiln.
The meeting was due to discuss a report from the Department of Culture Arts and Leisure into the workings of Sport NI.
The minister accepted the resignations and is to meet the remaining five board members later this week.
Japan: Ex-Toyota executive to be released
Tokyo prosecutors plan to release former Toyota Motor Corp executive Julie Hamp from custody after she was arrested last month on suspicion of illegally importing the painkiller oxycodone into Japan, Kyodo News reported.
Kyodo said Ms Hamp, who resigned last week just three months after her appointment as Toyota's first female managing officer, is set to be released without indictment, the latest she can be held without a formal charge.
A spokeswoman for the Tokyo District Public Prosecutors Office declined to comment on the report.
"We have not announced anything (on Hamp)," she said.
Turkish Airlines flight diverted to Delhi after 'bomb threat'
A Turkish Airlines flightlanded in the Indian capital, New Delhi, on Tuesday after a supposed bomb threat, an Indian security official said.
"There was a bomb threat to the Turkish Airlines flight andtherefore they decided to land it in New Delhi," an official from the federal Central Industrial Security Forces said.
He declined to be named because of the sensitivity of the information.
India's crack National Security Guards had been put on alert, Times Now TV said.
It said the plane with 148 passengershad made an emergency landing in New Delhi during the Istanbul-Bangkok TK-65 flight.
Dog dons robe to help owner collect degree
A student and his dog will don graduation robes today after the pet helped his owner complete his university degree.
Jack Proctor, 34, joined forces with cocker spaniel Fudge to complete a series of assignments as he studied for his BDes (Hons) in design and digital arts at Edinburgh Napier University.
The six-year-old dog starred in Mr Proctors introductory video and course work, and featured prominently in his dissertation.
To mark Fudge's supporting role in his owner's academic journey, the dog will join the graduation ceremony wearing bespoke robes made by Mr Proctor's wife.
14 killed in Kenya gun attack
At least 14 people were killed and 11 wounded when gunmen attacked a northern Kenyan village, close to the border with Somalia, officials and Red Cross said.
There was no immediate claim of responsibility but Somali-led al-Shabaab militants have carried out a string of attacks in the region, highlighting the insecurity that plagues parts of the country.
The attack occurred at an area called Soko Mbuzi, a livestock market just outside the town of Mandera in Kenya's far northeastern region, bordering Somalia and Ethiopia.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:50:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Interim Iran nuclear deal extended to Friday</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713237-iran-nuclear-talks/</Link>
        <Description>An interim nuclear agreement between Iran and six major powers will be extended to Friday to provide more time for talks on a final agreement, the United States has said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.50
Talks are taking place in Vienna to reach an agreement over Iran's nuclear programme
An interim nuclear agreement between Iran and six major powers will be extended to Friday to provide more time for talks on a final agreement, the United States has said.
      
"We've made substantial progress in every area, but thiswork is highly technical and high stakes for all of the countries involved," Marie Harf, the spokeswoman for the USdelegation, said in a statement.
      
"We're frankly more concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock, though we also know that difficult decisions won't get any easier with time - that is why we are continuing to negotiate," she added.
Six world powers are meeting in Vienna tryingto meet themidnight deadline for a nuclear deal with Iran.
They were expected to meet with Iran's Foreign Minister, Mohammad Javad Zarif, and Iran's nuclear negotiators later in the day.
A dispute over UNsanctions on Iran's ballistic missile programme and a broader arms embargo were among issues holding up a nuclear deal between Tehran and the powers on the day of the latest self-imposed deadline, diplomats said.
The deal under discussion is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy.
The US and its allies fear Iran is using its civilian nuclear programme as a cover to develop nuclear weapons capability. Iran says its programme is peaceful.
An agreement would be the most important milestone in decades towards easing hostility between the US and Iran, enemies since Iranian revolutionaries captured 52 hostages in the USembassy in Tehran in 1979.
A deal could reduce the chance of any military strike against Iran's nuclear facilities, something Washington has refused to rule out, and the possibility of a wider war in the Middle East, where conflicts already rage in Iraq, Syria and Yemen.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:04:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Call for experienced divers to assist Cork search</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713136-cork-search-baltimore/</Link>
        <Description>Search teams in west Cork are appealing to experienced divers to assist them in their search for the body of a 20-year-old man missing off Baltimore since last Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 14.04
The search continues for the body of Barry Davis Ryan
Search teams in west Cork are appealing to experienced divers to assist them in their search for the body of a 20-year-old man missing off Baltimore since last Tuesday.
Barry Davis Ryan was one of a group of people walking close to the Beacon when one of them was swept into the sea.
Two others attempted a rescue before all three got into difficulty.
The bodies of 20-year-old Niamh O'Connor and Barry's father, 51-year-oldBarry Ryan,were later recovered from the sea.
Their funerals took place over the weekend.
John Kearney of West Cork Underwater Search and Rescue said there is a "weather window" on Thursday and Friday but the weather was set to change at the weekend.
He said a very detailed search needs to be carried out and it is important that divers are experienced as the terrain is difficult and the search needs to be carried out carefully "so we don't have to repeat and go over the area again".
Mr Kearney said local fishermen were laying a lot of ground lines so divers have a route to follow to make sure the area is "gridded completely".
Holiday home owners andaccommodation providers in the Baltimore area are being asked to help with accommodation for up to 40 divers due in the village on Thursday.
Barry Ryan senior,a son of Penneys founder Arthur Ryan,was asenior executive with the retail clothing company.
Ms O'Connor from Glanmireworked at a Penneys store in Cork city.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:14:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>LÉ Eithne on standby as Mediterranean mission ends</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713113-le-eithne-migrants/</Link>
        <Description>The Irish navy's LÉ Eithne is tied up in Valetta, Malta, this morning as its mission in the Mediterranean comes to an end.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Since it deployed in May the crew of L Eithne rescued 3,400 migrants attempting to cross the Mediterranean in small boats. Among that number were 179 minors.
A breakdown of nationalities of the migrants rescued shows that 12% were from Eritrea; 12% from Nigeria; 11%from Sudan; and 9% from Syria.
Other nationalities included Ghanaians, Moroccans, Somalians and Ethiopians.
This morning Minister for Defence Simon Coveney, Minister for Justice Frances Fitzgerald and Minister of State at Department of Foreign Affairs Sean Sherlock visited the ship and metthe commander and crew.
Speaking on RT's Morning Ireland, Mr Coveney saidan Irish naval presence will be maintained until at least the end of September when it will be reassessed and a decision made at Government level on whether the presence will be continued.
He said Ireland had responded to the tragedy of the drowning of hundreds of migrants earlier this yearand wanted to be part of the European solution to the "immediate problem" of the migrant crisis, but acknowledged that this did not deal with the core issues of war, poverty and extremism. 
Mr Coveney said Ireland hascommitted to taking in 540 refugees from Syria over the next two years.
He also said Italy was right to demand that other EU countries share the burden of taking in migrants.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:14:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cosby obtained sedatives to have sex with women</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713159-bill-cosby/</Link>
        <Description>Comedian Bill Cosby testified in 2005 that he had obtained Quaaludes with the intent of giving the sedatives to young women in order to have sex with them, according to court documents unsealed yesterday.</Description>
        <MainBody>The case was settled for an undisclosed sum in 2006 but the documents in the case were unsealed yesterday after the Associated Press went to court.
Mr Cosby's lawyers had argued that the documents would cause severe embarrassment to the comedian-actor.
Mr Cosby is best known for playing Dr Cliff Huxtable on the hit TV comedy series "The Cosby Show" in the 1980s and 1990s.
A representative for Mr Cosby did not immediately respond to requests for comment yesterday.
More than 40 women have come forward in the past year alleging Mr Cosby drugged and sexually assaulted them in incidents dating back decades.
His attorneys have consistently denied the allegations.
Mr Cosby has never been criminally charged and most of the allegations exceed the statute of limitations.
However, his career has taken a hit in the past year with TV projects and live shows being cancelled.
He also stepped down from the board of trustees at Temple University, his alma mater.
Mr Cosby testified that in the 1970s he had obtained seven prescriptions for Quaaludes, the brand name for a sedative and muscle relaxant that was widely abused as a recreational drug in the 1970s.
"When you got the Quaaludes, was it in your mind that you were going to use these Quaaludes for young women that you wanted to have sex with?" Mr Cosby was asked in the 2005 deposition.
"Yes," he replied.
Asked whether he ever gave them to young women, his lawyers raised a lengthy series of objections.
Mr Cosby testified later that he gave Ms Constand one and a half pills of the over-the-counter antihistamine drug Benadryl.
Mr Cosby has said little directly about the allegations against him, telling ABC television in an interview in May that he did not wish to discuss them.
Source: Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:13:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fewer people on outpatient clinic waiting lists</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713230-waiting-lists-health/</Link>
        <Description>New figures show that the number of people waiting to be seen at an outpatient clinic, or for inpatient or day case treatments, has reduced.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.13
There are now 402,156 people waiting for an outpatient appointment
New figures show that the number of people waiting to be seen at an outpatient clinic, or for inpatient or day case treatments, has reduced.
There are now 402,156 people waiting for an outpatient appointment, according to the National Treatment Purchase Fund.
It compares with the May figure of over 415,400.
The number of people waitng over a year for an outpatient visit is also down by over 14,500 to 70,564.
The latest report for June also shows the number of people waiting for an inpatient, or day case treatment is at 67,195 - down slightly on the previous figure of 67,359.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:14:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ICTU discusses historic 'mass mobilisation'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713192-ictu/</Link>
        <Description>The president of the Irish Congress of Trade Unions has described the anti-water charges movement as the biggest mass social mobilisation since the foundation of the State.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
However, hesaid the extensive concessions secured by it would be enjoyed by all trade unionists.
He said that if members of thetrade union movement had been totally absent from the anti-water charges movement, it would have severely damaged its credibility.
As an election year loomed, he said,trade unionists had to grasp the nettle of political power within their membership bases.
He said no union could profess to be non-political, and their vision could never be achieved by industrial agitation alone.
They needed to campaign for a mass mobilisation akin to what they had witnessed during the same-sex marriage referendum, he said, to secure the political ground to deliver the social and industrial agenda.
He also said trade unions were not interested in a social dialogue which confined or constrained the legitimate role of their members.
The trade union movement, he said,had rediscovered its activism and shaken off the shackles of top down centralised bargaining.
He said it was cutting the teeth of a whole new generation of trade union and community activists in struggles such as Greyhound, the Paris Bakery, Rhatigans, Clerys, Vita Cortex and Dunnes Stores.
He cited a number of victories for the trade union movement, including the restoration of the sectoral wage setting arrangements, though he called for stronger legislation to ensure that employers could not obstruct their implementation.
He described new legislation on collective bargaining as far from perfect, but a foundation on which to build further.
He referred to Northern Ireland as the most deprived region in the UK. The welfare cuts and the 20,000 public sector job losses sought by the Tory government would plunge Northern Ireland into the dark ages if not challenged, he said.
The British and Irish governments needed to recognise Northern Ireland as a region emerging from conflict, where austerity policy were doubly damaging, he added.
Mr Douglas called for lifting of the debt burden in Greece and delegates stood and applauded in solidarity with the Greek people.
He called for a European debt conference to consider the issue of debt restructuring from the social perspective of the peoples of Europe, rather than solely from the financial institutions of Europe and the ideologues of austerity.
He also urged trade unionists to campaign against international free trade agreements.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:16:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alcohol use while pregnant 'prevalent' in Ireland</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713112-alcohol-pregnancy/</Link>
        <Description>Alcohol use before and during pregnancy is "prevalent and socially pervasive" in Ireland, according to an international study.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.16
Research was based on a large sample of women in Ireland, UK, Australia and New Zealand
Alcohol use before and during pregnancy is 'prevalent and socially pervasive' in Ireland, according to an international study.
The research was based on three existingpopulation-based studies in Ireland, the UK, Australia and New Zealand and found higher levels of alcohol consumption in Ireland before and during pregnancy than in the other three countries.
Ireland has the highest prevalence of any alcohol consumption pre-pregnancy at 90% and during pregnancy at 82%.
The research, published in the BMJ Open , also found Ireland has the highest reported binge alcohol consumption before - 59% -and during - 45% -pregnancy.
The Irish element of the research, assessed by experts in University CollegeCork, found expectant mothers in Ireland were significantly more likely to be drinkers if they were also smokers.
Researchers described the widespread consumption of even low levels of alcohol during pregnancy as a "significant public health concern".
The study had a large sample size of almost 18,000 women and looked at the drinking patterns of Irish women as assessed in two previous Irish studies and one international study.
It founddrinking during pregnancy was commonplace in all four countries, ranging from 20% to 80% in Ireland and from 40% upwards in the UK, Australia and New Zealand.
The amount of alcoholconsumed dropped substantially for all countries in the second trimester, along with the level of binge drinking.
The research found that non-white women were less likely to drink, along with younger women, those who were more highly educated, obese or already had children.
Researchers said the findings show there is low adherence to alcohol guidelines advising complete abstinence from alcohol during pregnancy in Ireland, New Zealand and Australia, and the National Institute for Health and Care Excellenceguidelines in the UK, which advisesconsumption of no more than one to two units once or twice a week.
Although most women who drink during pregnancy do so at low levels, those who drink heavily are putting their unborn baby at risk of Foetal Alcohol Syndrome (FAS), which affects their physical and mental development.
Consultant Obstetrician and Gynecologist at the National Maternity Hospital Dr Peter Boylan said he agreed with the findings and said any excessive amount of alcohol use, or binge drinking, is a concern.
Speaking on RT's Morning Ireland, he said Ireland has a well-known dysfunctional relationship with alcohol so "its no surprise the same thingextends into pregnancy".
However, Dr Boylan said there is no evidence that a small amount of alcohol during pregnancy is harmful, but it is important togetthebalance right and reiterated that binge drinking while pregnant is very concerning.
He said: "The evidence from international studies is that a small amount of alcohol, maybe one or two units a week, does not seem to do any harm at all."
He said the Government has a role to play in the restriction of the easy availability of alcohol andthe association with sporting events and the glamorisation of alcohol consumption, and saideducation and the restriction of cheap alcohol sales is the way to go.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:16:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Several injured in Washington ice cave collapse</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713162-washington-ice-cave/</Link>
        <Description>Several people have been injured in the partial collapse of an ice cave in Washington state that officials had warned was too dangerous for exploration due to unseasonably warm weather.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.16
The Big Four Ice Caves are home to a popular hiking trail
Several people have beeninjured in the partial collapse of an ice cave in Washington state thatofficials had warned was too dangerous for exploration due to unseasonably warm weather.
A spokeswoman from the Snohomish County Sheriff's Office said rescue workers were still trying to confirm how many people were in the Big Four Ice Caves near Granite Falls, 64kmnorth of Seattle, when a cave gave way yesterday.
The Everett Herald reported nine people were injured, citing a figure from the USForest Service.
Granite Falls ice cave collapse
The injured were all takento local hospitals, the newspaper said.
The caves are home to a popular hiking trail and are part of the Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest.
In May, the USForest Service warned hikers against entering the Big Four Ice Caves after several sections collapsed in unusually warm spring temperatures in the Pacific Northwest.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:16:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Over 150,000 South Sudanese sheltering in UN bases</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713179-south-sudan/</Link>
        <Description>The number of South Sudanese civilians sheltering in United Nations bases has risen above 150,000 for the first time in 18 months of civil war, the UN has said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.16
153,769 civilians are seeking safety at six peacekeeping bases
The number of South Sudanese civilians sheltering in United Nations bases has risen above 150,000 for the first time in 18 months of civil war, the UN has said.
A total of 153,769 civilians are now seeking safety behind the barbed wire of six peacekeeping bases of the UN Mission in South Sudan (UNMISS).
Many fled into the campsas war broke out in December 2013 and have never left.
But tens of thousands more have entered the bases during an upsurge in fighting since April, taking those seeking shelter to the highest number yet.
Over 10,000 have arrived in the past week alone, according to official figures released by UNMISS.
Over 28,000 are based in the capital Juba.
Aid workers there are trying to stamp out a cholera outbreak that has killed at least 32 people since cases were first recorded last month, including inside the UN base.
Another 91,500 are sheltering in Bentiu, capital of the northern battleground state of Unity, where a UN report last month described how South Sudan's army raped then burned girls alive inside their homes during a recent campaign marked by "new brutality and intensity".
More than 30,000 are also in the UN base in Malakal, capital of the northeastern Upper Nile state.
The town has been left in ruins by intense fighting, swapping hands several times.
Government forces retookit again yesterday after around a week under rebel control during which gunmen fired on the civilians inside the UN base.
UNMISS said that attack may constitute a war crime.
On Thursday, the world's youngest nation marksits fourth year since winning independence from north Sudan.
The UN has listedSouth Sudan as "lower in terms of human development than just about every other place on earth".
Civil war began when President Salva Kiir accused his former deputy Riek Machar of planning a coup.
That setoff a cycle of retaliatory killings across the country that has split the poverty-stricken, landlocked country along ethnic lines.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:51:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rabbitte will not contest next general election</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0706/713080-rabbitte/</Link>
        <Description>Former Labour leader and minister Pat Rabbitte has confirmed he will not be running in the next General Election.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
He was one of the founding members of the Democratic Left, which merged with the Labour Party in 1999.
He came from a trade union background and in the 1970s, was active in student politics and was formerly president of the Union of Students in Ireland.
He was a Minister of State in the rainbow government from 1994-1997.
@MartinaFitzg assesses Pat Rabbitte's decision not to contest the next general election. https://t.co/K5RE4dlh5E
 RT News (@rtenews) July 6, 2015
Mr Rabbitte succeeded Ruairi Quinn as Labour Leader in 2002, having been elected by members of the party.
During the subsequent general election campaign he made a pre-election pact with Fine Gael known as the Mullingar Accord.
He stood down as Labour leader in 2007.
Pat Rabbitte has done the State distinguished service and will go down as one of the finest parliamentarians of this or any other generation
 Joan Burton (@joanburton) July 6, 2015
In the 2011 general election he got the highest number of votes of any Labour candidate whenhe was elected in Dublin South West.
Mr Rabbitte was then appointed as Minister for Communications, Energy and Natural Resources, but was dropped from the cabinet when Joan Burton took over as leader last year.
A recent poll by the party suggested he would retain the seat, however, he did not reveal his decision on whether or not to run until this evening.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:02:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US 'speeding up' troop training in Iraq and Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0706/713088-obama-troop-training/</Link>
        <Description>The President of the United States has said the US military is "speeding up" the rate at which it is training local fighters in Iraq and Syria.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Tuesday 07 July 2015 00.02
Barack Obama says recent IS losses prove the group can be defeated and the US is 'going after' IS leadership in Syria
The President of the United States has said the US military is "speeding up" the rate at which it is training local fighters in Iraq and Syria.
Speaking after he was briefed at the Pentagon on the progress of the campaign against the group styling itself Islamic State, Barack Obama said it would not be a "quick" battle but rather was a "long-term campaign" against a group that was "opportunistic and nimble".
He confirmed the US had so far carried out over 5,000 airstrikes against IS targets.
He said recent IS losses proved the group could be defeated and that the US was now "going after" the IS leadership in Syria.
Mr Obama said there was a "glimmer of good news" as there was now recognition from all the partners in the region that they needed to work together.
Speaking at the Pentagon President Obama said the coalition had been "moving too slowly", but with the extra forces that he had authorised last month, they were now "speeding up the training", and delivering more anti-aircraft missiles.
He said it was important to "develop local security forces that can sustain progress", as it was not "enough" to send in American troops to temporarily set back the IS fighters, which then created a void that was filled again, adding that local forces need to succeed and sustain in terms of security and governance in the region.
He stressed if the US tried to do everything itself, there would be "a whole lot of unintended consequences" that would make the US "less secure".
President Obama said the coalition had made it harder for IS to carry out large scale attacks but lone wolf attacks were harder to work against.
He again repeated that the US was not "at war with Islam" but rather it was fighting terrorists "who distort Islam and whose victims were mostly Muslims".
He admitted that the "large battle for hearts and minds" would be a "generational struggle".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
