<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="rte">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:12:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trial hears FitzPatrick was concerned about 'mate'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713227-anglo-trial/</Link>
        <Description>Seán FitzPatrick was concerned about the name of his "mate" Denis O'Brien being included on a list of non-resident account holders in Anglo Irish Bank to be submitted to Revenue in 2003, the Dublin Circuit Criminal Court has heard.</Description>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:33:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>27 killed in attack on tourist hotels in Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710815-tunisia-attack/</Link>
        <Description>At least 27 people have died in an attack on two tourist hotel near the Tunisian coastal town of Sousse, about 150km south of the capital, Tunis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 13.33
Local police moved tourists and locals to a safe area (File picture)
At least 27peoplehave died in an attack on twotourist hotels near the Tunisian coastal town of Sousse, about 150kmsouth of the capital, Tunis.
An interior ministry official has said that the foreigners are among the dead.
Gunshots were fired in the vicinity of the Marhaba Sousse Hotel, which is popular with Irish holidaymakers.
It isunderstood that one gunman entered the hotel at around noon and opened fire.
A security source at the scene said the body of a gunmanarmed with a Kalashnikov assault rifle lay where police had shot him dead.
Ministry spokesman Mohamed Ali Aroui told Mosaique radio that two hotels were attacked.
Local police moved tourists and locals to a safe area.
The Department of Foreign Affairs is liaising with Irish diplomatic staff in the region.
The Department is aware of an incident in Sousse, Tunisia. If you have any concerns for family members there, please call 01-4082000
Dublin woman caught up in attack
A Dublin woman in the Tunisian resort of Sousse described what she saw when the attack happened.
Speaking to RT's News At One, Elizabeth O'Brien said: "I thought it was fireworks and then I thought 'Oh my God' it sounds like gunfire.
"I ran to the sea to my children and grabbed our things and, as I was running towards the hotel, the waiters and the security on the beach started shouting 'Run, run, run'.
"We ran to our room, which is like a little bungalow, so we are actually trapped in our room, because we have no contact the phone here doesn't work to call reception.
"The consul from Madrid who is over Tunisia as well said it is a terrorist attack in the hotel next door.
"She told me to stay put, my travel agent said to go to the reception to speak to the rep, but I'm afraid, so I'm stuck here in the room with my two sons not knowing what's going on.
"The agent said the attack was isolated to the hotel next door. The consul told me it was a terrorist attack.
"I just ran as soon as I heard the noise, I don't know what's happening now I'm sort of cut off from the world."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:38:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hollande says factory attack a 'terrorist' act</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710748-france-attack/</Link>
        <Description>A head covered in Arabic writing was found at a US gas company in southeast France this morning, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 12.38
1 of 3
French police and firefighters secure the entrance of the factory
Several explosive devices were at the factory (Pic: Dauphine Libere)
A decapitated body was found near the factory (Pic: Dauphine Libere)
A head covered in Arabic writing was found at a US gas company in southeast France this morning, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.
Speaking from a European Union summit in Brussels, French President Francois Hollande described it at a terrorist attack and said all measures would be taken to stop any future attacks on a country still reeling from Islamist assaults in January.
One suspect had been arrested and was already known to French intelligence sources, Mr Hollande said.
"Two individuals deliberately rammed a car into the gas containers to trigger an explosion," a police source said.
Suspected accomplices have also been detained.     
It was not known whether the victim, so far the only known fatality in the incident that also injured two people, was decapitated before or after the car smashed into the building, or whether the victim had been on site at the time of the attack, or killed elsewhere.
"The attack was of a terrorist nature since a body was discovered, decapitated and with inscriptions," Mr Hollande told the news conference.
Police sources earlier said the decapitated body was found at the site, along with a flag bearing Islamist inscriptions.
Local newspaper Le Dauphine said the head covered in Arabic writing was found on a fence.
The French public prosecutor said its anti-terrorist section had been deployed to investigate.
France, which has deployed aircraft to the international coalition fighting Islamic State insurgents in Iraq, has long been named on Islamist sites as a primary target for attacks.
In April, Prime Minister Manuel Valls said no fewer than five attacks had been thwarted in the country since the Charlie Hebdo killings in January.
Then, Islamist gunmen killed 17 people in the offices of the Charlie Hebdo satirical weekly and a Jewish food store.
Noting that hundreds of French nationals are in Syria where they risked being radicalised by Islamist fighters, Mr Valls said "never has the threat been so high".
The site belonged to Air Products, a US industrial gases and chemicals company, according to a spokeswoman for Air Liquide, a French company in the same sector.
It was immediately sealed off by police and emergency services.
The chairman and CEO of Air Products is Seifi Ghasemi, who in 2011 testimony to a US Senate committee described himself as Iranian-born.
Mainly Shia Iran is a sworn enemy of Sunni-dominated Islamic State. 
No group claimed responsibility for the attack and the motive was unknown.
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve was at the site in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, around 30km southeast of the city of Lyon.
French media said the government had ordered security to be stepped up around sensitive sites in the surrounding Rhone-Alpes region.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:30:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Court backs refusal to hold Finucane inquiry</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710711-pat-finucane/</Link>
        <Description>The High Court in Belfast has backed British Prime Minister David Cameron's refusal to hold a public inquiry into the 1989 murder of human rights lawyer Pat Finucane.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Friday 26 June 2015 11.30
Pat Finucane was shot dead in front of his wife and their three children in their Belfast home in 1989
The High Court in Belfast has backed British Prime Minister David Cameron's refusal to hold a public inquiry into the 1989 murder of human rights lawyer Pat Finucane.
Mr Finucanes death remains a lightning rod for anger over state collusion with pro-British paramilitaries.
The lawyer, who represented leading republicans in court, was shot dead in front of his family at his north Belfast by loyalists believed to have been acting in collusion with British security forces.
This morning, a judicial review rejected an appeal by Mr Finucane's family for a public inquiry into the shooting, saying Mr Cameron's 2011 decision not to hold one was lawful.
Mr Cameron instead commissioned an independent investigation, whose report was published in 2012.
The 2012 report severely criticised members of the British intelligence services and army and the Northern Irish police for colluding in the killing and covering it up.
The solicitor's family has long campaigned for a full independent public inquiry, but Mr Cameron insisted such an exercise would not shed any more light on the events.
He instead commissioned a review of the case papers by QC Desmond de Silva.
Mr de Silva's report detailed shocking levels of state involvement.
It included spreading malicious propaganda that Mr Finucane was sympathetic to the IRA; one or possibly more police officers proposing him as a target to loyalists; and the mishandling of state agents inside the UDA who were involved in the murder.
While Mr de Silva found no evidence of an overarching conspiracy by the authorities to target the 38-year-old lawyer, he said the actions of a number of state employees had "furthered and facilitated" the UDA shooting while there had also been efforts to thwart the subsequent criminal investigation.
As he accepted the report's findings in the House of Commons in December 2012, Mr Cameron reiterated an apology to the Finucane family and also pledged that the government would examine the review in detail to identify potential lessons.
Mr Finucane was shot dead in front of his wife and their three children inside their north Belfast home in February 1989.
The judicial review focused on a commitment made by the UK government at Weston Park in 2001 during peace process negotiations with the Government.
The Weston Park talks resulted in Canadian judge Peter Cory being asked to examine the grounds for public inquiry in a number of controversial Troubles deaths.
The British government said such inquiries would be implemented if the judge recommended that course of action.
Judge Cory subsequently did recommend public inquiries for a number of killings, including Mr Finucane's.
But while the government ordered inquiries into the other deaths, it did not give the green light for one in the Finucane case.
Speaking following the judgment,Minister for Foreign AffairsCharlie Flanagan said:"I note this morning's judgment in the judicial review and will be studying it closely. The Irish Government's position remains unchanged. 
"We continue to believe that an independent public inquiry into the murder of Pat Finucane, in line with the political commitments made by the British and Irish governments at Weston Park in 2001, should be honoured.
"This is a matter which the Government has consistently raised with the British Government. I raised it most recently with Secretary of State for Northern Ireland Theresa Villiers on 19 May, and the Taoiseach discussed the case with Prime Minister Cameron when they met in London last week.
"My thoughts at this time are with Geraldine Finucane and all the Finucane family, who have campaigned so tirelessly for more than a quarter of a century in pursuit of the full truth in the case of Pat Finucane, including the role of collusion in his murder."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:45:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece offered billions in funding to agree deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/business/2015/0626/710721-greece-euro-zone/</Link>
        <Description>The leaders of Germany and France have offered to release billions in frozen aid, in a last-minute push to talk Greece into contentious pension reforms in exchange for vital funding for Athens' until November.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The creditors laid out terms in a document that went to Greece yesterday and was seen by Reuters news agency today.
It said Greece could have 15.5bn in EU and IMF funding in four installments to see it through to the end of November, including 1.8bn by Tuesday as soon as the Athens parliament approved the plan.
The total is slightly more than Greece needs to service its debts over the next six months but contains no new money.
A French source said Ms Merkel and Mr Hollande discussed outstanding differences on reforms Greece needs to accept - centred on pension reform, labour law and increasing VAT - as well as an extension to Athens' bailout programme and financing.
The German and French leaders both said Saturday's emergency meeting of euro zone finance ministers would be decisive to seal a deal before Greece has to make a key IMF repayment for which the government has said it lacks the money.
"Saturday's meeting is crucial because we are on the eve of a date, June 30, when the Greek authorities have to meet a payment obligation," Mr Hollande told a news conference.
"It's also crucial because there are parliaments that have to meet if there's a deal," he added.
The Eurogroup ministers will meet at 4pm Irish time on Saturday and Greece will be asked whether it accepts a revised offer from the European Commission, the European Central Bank and the International Monetary Fund, a euro zone official said.
Greece's commitment to euro zone 'absolute' - Varoufakis
Earlier,Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis saidGreece has a moral responsibility to reach agreement not only for his country but for the euro zone also.
Mr Varoufakis was speaking toRT's Morning Irelandas talks between the Greek government and international creditors remain deadlocked.
He said it was not a game of guessing chances and that Greece was obliged to find a viable solution for the benefit of the whole of the euro zone.
He said it is up to the institutions to now "come to the party".
Mr Varoufakissaid Greece are "debtors,representatives of the social economy in recession for the last seven years."
He said the Irish people knew very well about international creditors.
He said it was important for people to understand that the negotiations were being conducted between the member states and the international creditors - not among the member states themselves.
He said the Government had been kept in the dark about what Greece had offered and that if TaoiseachEnda Kennyand Minister for Finance Michael Noonanknew the details of the offer,theywould change theirperspective.
"If your finance minister and I were to sit down and I were to explain my proposals....Michael Noonan would agree that they are very reasonable" he said.
Mr Varoufakis described as "absolute" Greece's commitment to remain in the euro zone, adding that Greece had bent over backwards to accommodate what he described as the "strange demands of creditors".
He also said that he will not accept any debt solution he considers to beunviable.
He said Greece was asking to take debt from the pocket of the ECB and put it in the pocket of ESM in order to "even out a very spiky debt repayment schedule, so as to make it easier for us to make the repayments for the benefit of the creditors."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:38:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supermac's in trademark battle with McDonald's</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/business/2015/0626/710800-supermacs-mcdonalds-registration-battle/</Link>
        <Description>Fast food chain Supermac's has stepped up its battle with McDonald's to have its company name registered across Europe with Managing Director Pat McDonagh personally handing in a submission in Spain today.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Friday 26 June 2015 12.38
McDonald's lodged a 41-page objection over Supermac's plans to the office that oversees trademarks and designs in the EU
Fast food chain Supermac's has stepped up its battle with McDonald's to have its company name registered across Europe with Managing Director Pat McDonagh personally handing in a submission in Spain today.
Mr McDonagh travelled to Alicante to deliver a submission to the Office for Harmonisation in the Internal Market (OHIM), following moves by McDonald's to stop the Supermac's trademark being registered throughout Europe.
Supermac's operates over 100 outlets in Ireland and Mr McDonagh, a former schoolteacher who opened the first premises in Ballinasloe in Co Galway in 1978, said the company has received requests to open in 15 cities across Europe.
However, expansion plans have met with opposition from McDonald's, with the American fast-food giant lodging a 41-page objection to the OHIM, which oversees trademarks and designs.
Mr McDonagh has now responded to that objection by delivering Supermac's submission today.
"I am optimistic that common sense will prevail. Supermac's has traded successfully alongside McDonald's in Ireland and Northern Ireland for over 30 years and I don't believe this could be any different in other countries," said Mr McDonagh, who is in the process of opening eight new outlets in Ireland this year.
He based the name of the new business in 1978 on his nickname from his schholdays in Carmelite College in Moate, when he became known as 'Supermac' in deference to the Newcastle United and England footballer Malcolm MacDonald.
"I am confident that the true facts of Supermac's case have been presented clearly to the Office for Harmonisation in the Internal Market today. Supermac's has long been regarded as a steadily growing business throughout its 37 years in existence.
"We are responding to demands coming from fifteen cities internationally for the opening of Supermac's restaurants," he added.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:34:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>166 IBRC loan accounts paid rate of less than 1%</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/business/2015/0626/710750-ibrc-interest-rates/</Link>
        <Description>New data shows that a total of 166 Irish Bank Resolution Corporation commercial loans accounts were charged an interest rate of less than 1%.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 11.34
Accounts charged less than 1% interest were mainly related to distressed loans
New data shows that a total of 166 Irish Bank Resolution Corporation commercial loans accounts were charged an interest rate of less than 1%.
In a written reply to Fianna Fil finance spokesman Michael McGrath, the Finance Minister said IBRC's Special Liquidators confirmed that accounts with a rate of less than 1% were mainly related to distressed loans.
This was where the loan was restructured or where the borrower was in the liquidation or administration and the prospect of any future recovery was "remote".
Today's data from the Finance Minister also shows that 920 accounts at the bank were charged a rate of between 1-1.99% on their loans. These loans amounted to 399m.
The largest number of loans at the former Anglo Irish Bank - 2,729 - were charged interest rates of between 2-2.99% on loans worth a total of 7.232 billion.
920 saw rates of between 1-1.99% on loans worth 8.658 billion, while a further 1,568 were charged at rates between 3-3.99% on loans totalling 4.894 billion.
392 IBRC customers paid interest rates of 4-4.99%, while 271 paid rates of 5-5.99%.
Another 132 customers paid rates of between 6 and 6.99%, 67 paid interest rates of 7-7.99% while a total of 66 paid interest rates of over 8% on their loans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:59:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Couples win right to challenge NI gay marriage ban</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710732-gay-marriage-northern-ireland/</Link>
        <Description>Two couples have cleared the first legal hurdle in their bid to challenge a ban on gay marriage in Northern Ireland.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 12.59
Thousands attended a march for marriage equality in Belfast earlier this month (Pic: Amnesty International)
Two same-sex couples seeking to overturn a ban on gay marriage in Northern Ireland have welcomed a judicial decision to let their case proceed.
A judge in Belfast High Court granted them leave to judicially review the refusal to legalise same sex marriage in the region.
Grainne Close and Shannon Sickles and Chris and Henry Flanagan-Kane are taking the joint action.
They were, respectively, the first and second couples in the UK to enter into a civil partnership after Northern Ireland became the first part of the UK to make that option available to same-sex couples in December 2005.
The Northern Ireland Assembly has rejected a proposal calling for the introduction of gay marriage on four occasions since, with unionists opposed to the move using a contentious voting mechanism to effectively veto it.
Neither couple was in court today when Mr Justice Treacy granted leave for a judicial review but their solicitor, Mark O'Connor, spoke on their behalf afterwards.
"On behalf of our clients we are delighted we have been able to get over the first hurdle in relation to the judicial process in that the judge today has granted leave for us to bring this judicial review," he said.
"We are thankful that the judge has made that decision today. We believe that religious policy and religious views should not be affecting public policy before the courts today and thankfully the judge today appears to have accepted there is an arguable case to answer for the (Stormont) departments and hopefully we will have success in the future in relation to this matter," Mr OConnor added.
Following the "Yes" vote in May's referendum on same-sex marriage in the Republic, Northern Ireland is now set to be the only part of the UK or Ireland where civil marriage is denied to gay couples.
Earlier this month, about 20,000 campaigners marched in Belfast city centre demanding a change in the law.
The case has been listed for a mention hearing in September.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:22:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Motion to protect Poolbeg chimneys deferred</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710803-poolbeg-chimneys-dublin/</Link>
        <Description>Efforts to have Dublin's Poolbeg chimneys listed as a protected structure are to be deferred to allow the ESB to carry out preservation work and further tests.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 12.22
Councillors have been told that the ESB would need planning permission to have the chimneys demolished
Efforts to have Dublin's Poolbeg chimneys listed as a protected structure are to be deferred to allow the ESB to carry out preservation work and further tests.
Labour councillor Dermot Lacey, who led the attempt to have the chimneys listed, saidhe will defer a motion that was due to be voted on by Dublin City councillors.
The ESB recently announced a 250,000 ten-year maintenance programme, which included repainting and steel capping to stop further deterioration.
ESB's Communications Manager Bernadine Maloney saidfurther tests will have to be carried out to assess the structural integrity of the chimneys.
A recent report to councillors from the Heritage Council stated that the chimneys are an "iconic" and "integral" part of the Dublin skyline with many references in popular culture.
There has not been any official recommendation on whether they should be added to the Record of Protected Structures.
The report also stated that brickwork had deteriorated because of moisture coming into the chimneys and that some of the outer concrete had become dislodged.
Confirming that a motion to have the chimneys listed will be deferred, Cllr Lacey said he believes the ESB is committed to saving them.
Councillors have been told that the ESB would have to apply for planning permission to have them demolished.
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:32:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU migrant deal reached, Kenny returns to summit</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710710-migrants/</Link>
        <Description>Taoiseach Enda Kenny has returned to the EU leaders summit today after a fractious overnight session which focused on how to respond to the migrant crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 12.32
Last night a voluntary scheme of 60,000 migrants per country was reached
TaoiseachEnda Kennyhas returned to the EU leaders summit today after a fractious overnight session which focused on how to respond to the migrant crisis. 
The scale of the problem has been charted by the UN which says 63,000 migrants arrived in Greece by sea in 2015 so far, with a further62,000 arriving in Italy.
The European Commission had been pushing for a mandatory quota for each member state, but it ended-up being a voluntary plan due to strong opposition from Poland and other Baltic countries.
Last night during a seven hour debate it was agreedmigrants fleeing war and poverty in North Africa and the Middle East would be shared out, based on a voluntary scheme of 60,000.
An exclusion granted for Hungary, which earlier described the plan as absurd, as well as for Bulgaria, one of the EU's poorest countries. 
There are 40,000 Syrian and Eritrean asylum seekers now in Italy and Greece and another20,000 people outside the EU.      
"It was a very intensive debate," German Chancellor Angela Merkel told reporters after the meeting ended.
Shedescribedthe migrant crisis "as the biggest challenge I have seen in European affairs in my time as chancellor".
Expressing his frustration, Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker described the plan as one of "modest ambition" and said at one point in the meeting he had told EU leaders "I don't give a damn" about objections to the plan's underlying methodology.
"We have to find out if the system works. It doesn't matter if it is voluntary or mandatory, it is whether it can help 60,000 refugees," Mr Juncker told a news conference in the early hours of this morning. 
However, the EU's chief executive had been hoping to set a precedent for Europe-wide action that limited national opt-outs. 
During the summit dinner, Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi rebuked his fellow leaders for their reluctance to support a plan that was meant as an emergency response to the tragedy of 2,000 migrant deaths in the Mediterranean year but has been overshadowed by divisions, particularly in eastern Europe.
"If we think Europe is only about budgets, it is not the Europe we thought of in 1957 in Rome," Mr Renzi said, referring to the European Union's founding treaty.
The summit became so tense that a speech by British Prime Minister David Cameron served as an interlude to cool tempers, with the much awaited address to pitch for a new deal for Britain in the European Union reduced to barely ten minutes.
The mood was a long way from the unity showed by EU ministers in April immediately after the deaths of 900 migrants off the Libyan coast in a single weekend.
While the political deal was a breakthrough, implementing the plan still faces hurdles. The criteria to share migrants among member states must be decided by the end of July.
Such factors as the size of a member state's economy and population must be considered.
"There's much, much more argument to come," said one senior EU diplomat. "I don't yet see the full way forward."
The criteria system replaces unpopular proposals for mandatory quotas on each country, which Poland, the Czech Republic, Slovakia, Hungary and others fought against, arguing their ex-Communist economies still lacked the capacity to cope.
The debate has also strained the EU's commitment to its Schengen agreement on passport-free travel.
This week, Austria threatened to re-impose controls on its border with Hungary and Britain called for more security around the French port of Calais.
Britain and Spain want a bigger focus on returning migrants to their countries of origin.
Analysis: Europe Correspondent Paul Cunningham
The European Commission hasbeen pressing, and pressing very hard, for a mandatory deal  for each member state to be given a quota.
However,the ECwas pressed hard by countries in the Baltics, particularly countries like Poland who wanted a voluntary deal.
There were seven hours of talks, they were described as "fractious", "very heated", and at the end of it, it was decided it would be voluntary  countries would opt in to see what they take.
The deal which was agreed last night has noteven be printed, so still it is very early stages.
After it is printed,it will go to EU Justice Ministers in July who will complete the plan. Then we will have some idea how it works.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:48:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>DA denies Irish pressure led to balcony inquiry</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710708-berkeley/</Link>
        <Description>The Office of the District Attorney for Berkeley in California has denied that it was pressurised by the Irish community to launch a formal investigation into the balcony collapse after local authorities said their involvement was over.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
In an interview with RT News, Ms O'Malley also said her office would be looking closely at previous lawsuits that had been taken against the developers and contractors who had built the Library Gardens apartment complex.
In relation to criticism about how the authorities had handled the investigation into the balcony collapse to date, Ms O'Malley said that her office had been monitoring the situation from the outset and decided to commence this investigation once the City of Berkeley local authority and police department had announced their involvement was over.
Her office confirmed there had been a lot of communication with members of the Irish community but there had been "no pressure" to launch an investigation as a result.
It is understood that legal representatives of some of those involved in the balcony collapse had contacted the DA's office in recent days and that there had also been communication on behalf of the Government following the news that the Berkeley authorities would not be pursuing the matter further.
The DA also said they would be closely examining the outcome of other lawsuits against the builders and water-proofing contractors and would investigate what action they had taken in other properties as a result of these lawsuits.
She said her investigation would be "thorough and exhaustive" and she was not setting a time-limit on it, although the statute of limitations for gross criminal negligence was three years from the date of the crime.
She said this was "an unusual case" and it was not something that a municipal police force like the Berkeley PD would normally handle.
The Berkeley city authorities had not carried out forensic or laboratory examinations on the wooden joists that had held the balcony in place, she said, but added that her department would.
She said she did not know what they would find during the investigation, adding there was a chance that there would be no grounds to bring a criminal prosecution.
She said that the investigation would be "going systematically from the very beginning right up until the tragedy happened".
She said they would start with how the construction occurred, pointing out that there were responsibilities not just to file plans with the local government but that inspectors also came to the site to make sure the builders were following the codes and had permits.
Ms O'Malley said they will be examining the practices of the developer and builders.
District Attorney O'Malley said it was interesting that there had been previous lawsuits filed against the developer - Segue Construction - for "similar types of situations" and that there had "certainly" been "some construction issues".
She said they would examine whether the outcome of these lawsuits served to put the developer or the contractors "on notice" that "what they were doing was dangerous", and that "they were creating a dangerous situation that could result in someone's death or serious injury".
Questions have also arisen surrounding the chain of custody of the collapsed balcony and the one itfell onto underneath, which was subsequently removed from the property as it was found to also have significant dry-rot and was considered a "collapse hazard".
At a Berkeley City press conference on Tuesday, officials said that they had already given the balconies and other related material back to the owner.
This would potentially cause an issue now that the DA has launched a full-scale criminal investigation.
However, Ms O'Malley confirmed today that the collapsed balcony remains in the possession of the Berkeley Police Department.
She said that the second balcony had been released by the Berkeley City local authority and made available to the owner, however before it was collected from the building where it was being held, individuals from the District Attorney's office had gone to that location and taken possession of the balcony.
It was now being moved, she said, from that locked facility to another secure location where the DA's Sheriff's Department would guard it.
Ms O'Malley also confirmed that her office had already contacted some of the injured people and the families of those who had been killed to inform them of the investigation and to discuss how her office could help with resources.
She said that she had a special victim-witness division in her office - the first of its kind in the US - and it was focused on working with those directly involved with this tragedy.
She said they would give them as much information as they wanted.
Ms O'Malley said that the hearts of those in her office were grieving with the families, especially as both she and her chief assistant Kevin Dunleavy had "strong ties to Ireland".
Her family members are originally from Mayo and Clare, Mr Dunleavy's are from Clare and Leitrim.
As District Attorney for Alameda County, she said would do everything they could for them and said she would "guarantee" that she would conduct a "thorough and exhaustive" investigation to determine whether not they could make a case and prove it in a court of law and hold those accountable who had caused the deaths and injuries.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:41:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suicide bomber kills at least 13 in Kuwait mosque</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710819-kuwait-mosque-attack/</Link>
        <Description>A suicide bomber has attacked a Shiite mosque in Kuwait, killing at least 13 and wounding dozens, officials and witnesses said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 13.41
The attack is the first such bombing targeting Kuwaiti Shiite Muslims
A suicide bomber has attacked a Shiite mosque in Kuwait,killing at least 13 and wounding dozens, officials and witnesses said.
Medics have confirmed that at least 13 people have beenkilled and 25 have been hospitalised.
Eight people are reported to be in critical conditions.
No one has claimed responsibility for the blast, but the so-called Islamic State group said it carried out recent bombings Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia and Yemen.
The blast hit the Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City during the main weekly prayers, security officials and witnesses said.
The country'sofficialnews agency KUNA confirmed that there were "dead and wounded," but did not provide details.
A security official said "it is a suicide bombing."
Witnesses gave a similar account, saying a suicide bomber entered the mosque during the weekly noon prayers.
The area has been cordoned off by police.
The attack is the first such bombing targeting Kuwaiti Shiite Muslims, who make up around one-third of the country's native population of 1.3 million people.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:35:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alleged misuse of political funds in NI probed</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710740-northern-ireland-political-party-funding/</Link>
        <Description>Police in Northern Ireland are investigating alleged misuse of public funding for a political party.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 09.35
Assembly authorities have been notified of the investigation
Police in Northern Ireland are investigating alleged misuse of public funding for a political party.
Two men, aged 41 and 43, have been interviewed by police and will now be reported to the Public Prosecution Service.
PSNI chief superintendent Peter Farrar said the allegations were in connection to "potential fraud and theft" by a "small number of individuals" relating to money available under the Financial Assistance to Political Parties Fund.
"A number of items have been seized as part of on-going police inquiries," he said.
"Authorities at the Assembly have been advised of the police investigation."
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:54:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>DNA samples to be taken from bodies found in Meath</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710709-disappeared-remains-meath/</Link>
        <Description>Work resumes this morning on the recovery of human remains found in Co Meath yesterday during the search for members of the so-called Disappeared - people abducted, murdered and buried in secret by the IRA.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 11.54
1 of 2
Last night it emerged that there are at least two bodies in a grave uncovered in
Kevin McKee disappeared in 1972
Work resumes this morning on the recovery of human remains found in Co Meath yesterday during the search for members of the so-called Disappeared - people abducted, murdered and buried in secret by the IRA.
The remains were discovered during a search for Joe Lynskey, who disappeared over 40 years ago.
However, last night it emerged that there are at least two bodies in the grave.
Coghalstown is about 10km north of Navan.
Forty years ago the area was wild bog land, but it is now mainly farmland.
Since March,the Commission for the Location of Victims Remains has been excavating in the area looking for the remains of Mr Lynskey.
The former Cistercian monk disappeared in 1972 as a result of an internal IRA feud.
Yesterday, human remains were found and initially it was believed they were those of Mr Lynskey.
However, it emerged last night that more than one body is in the uncovered grave.
This means the remains may well be those of Seamus Wright and Kevin McKee, who disappeared from Belfast a few weeks after Mr Lynskey, and were murdered and buried in the same area.
Lead Forensic Scientistand Investigator with Commission ,Geoff Knupfer,has said this islikely to be the case.
He said it was a huge relief that the bodies 'remained intact'.
Mr Knupfer said the bodies were found lying on top of each other.
He said he believed they may have originally been buried about a metre underground.
Mr Knupferadded that if it turns out that the remains are not those of Mr Lynskey, the search will continue for him in this location.
It may be several weeks before the bodies can be identitfied as post-mortem examinations and DNA analysis have to be carried out.
Family members of Seamus Wright and Kevin McKeehave arrived at the site.
Commenting on the discovery of the two bodiesMinister for JusticeFrances Fitzgerald said she hoped "the suffering of the families of some of those who were Disappeared over the course of the Troubles in Northern Ireland will now be eased".
In a statement Minister Fitzgerald said the Commission will continue to undertake the "humanitarian task" of working to find the "remains of those who have yet to be found".
Both the Commission and Sinn Fin president Gerry Adams have renewed their calls for those with information about other Disappeared to come forward.
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:32:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Call for more inspections of private rentals</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710715-rental-inspections/</Link>
        <Description>Local authority figures obtained by RTÉ show just 6% of private rental property across the country were inspected last year.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 07.32
'Paul' says when it rains he just waits for water to come through his ceiling
Local authority figures obtained by RT show just 6% of private rental property across the country were inspected last year.
There are currently around 303,000 rental properties, with just 17,700 of these inspected in 2014.
More than 50% of the accommodation inspected failed to meet minimum standards set out in the housing regulations.
In one example, Paul has been living for three years in accommodation that is in a state of disrepair and has been deemed a fire hazard by Dublin City Council.
He said: "Dublin City Council has been out to examine the conditions of the house and the environmental health officer said the housing conditions are atrocious. There is damp, mould, the ceiling is ready to fall in," he says.
"There is water coming down over the light so that's very serious. Dublin City Council was out to inspect that they have the report on that.
"Any time it goes to rain the first thing you're looking at is the light, it's just a matter of when that's going to go up on fire."
His landlord was given three months to repair the house but that time expired last week and no work has been carried out.
Paul says that if he is forced to vacate his property he will not be able to afford the soaring cost of rent in Dublin.
"My main concern now is that I feel I'm going to be left homeless after this".
"I've never lived in conditions like this even in my student days so as it stands now a middle-class working person is the new homeless," he says.
Local authority figures show that in Dublin 63% of dwellings inspected failed, in Cork city 26% of properties inspected did not meet the standards required, while in Kerry 32% of rented properties inspected failed.
Some of the county councils contacted by RT said they were not in a position to categorise the figures into minor and serious breaches of the regulations.
Dublin city was among the councils that did provide detailed figures, which showed that out of 3,500 inspections, 930 dwellings did not reach regulatory requirements and of these 65 legal actions were initiated.
In Waterford 90% of failures resulted from lack of proper smoke alarms and/or fire blankets, while in 10% of cases there were damp and mould issues.
Out of a total of 387 cases in Roscommon four of the breaches were categorised as serious while in Galway and Kilkenny most of the failures were due to minor breaches of regulations.
Housing charity Thresholds Chief Executive, Bob Jordan, has raised concerns about the low level of inspections.
"There is huge anomalies within these figures... for instance if we take the example of Cavan carrying out 800 inspections compared with Galway City Council, which really is one of the centres of the private rented sector, and theyre carrying out less than 150.
"So there's a real issue about the number of inspections that are been carried out.
"I think the other issue is around the quality of these inspections. The fact that Donegal carried out just under 600 inspections and found no properties to be substandard, Tipperary - 200 again found nothing.
"Nobody believes there is no sub-standard properties in those counties so there's a real question about what they're actually going out and looking at," he said.
Mr Jordan is calling for a certification scheme to ensure rented accommodation is up to standard: "I think the issue is this approach where local authorities inspected private rented properties was set up at a time when we had a very small private rented sector.
"Now one in five households live in the private rented sector and clearly local authorities in the main are not up to carrying out these inspections. So what we are saying is that the boot should be put on the other foot," he said.
"The responsibility should be on the landlord to prove that their property is up to scratch before a tenant moves in and that it would be the job of the local authorities that landlords have those certs because with the best will in the world local authorities are not going to get around to every single property."
However, the Residential Landlords Association is against a certification scheme - which it says would create another layer of bureaucracy for landlords.
"We're one of the most highly-regulated rented sectors now in western Europe. We're governed by a wide range of legislation and of course the private rented tenancies board is the overarching supervisory body of the rented sector.
"It's expensive for landlords to comply with regulations it is expensive for them to register with the PRTB as well as all of the other tax obligations they have."
He says the standard of rented accommodation in Ireland is high by international standards.
"I served on two international bodies and we routinely carried out comparative analysis of the standards and regulations applying to rented property in other jurisdictions and there is no question but we have been very high here.
"The figures listed by the local authorities don't surprise me but what is worth bearing in mind is that they include a wide range of issues bearing from the very minor to some quite serious."
"Many things that have been listed for improvement would be like dampness in a room or a fire blanket to be supplied but when told by the local authority to comply landlords are given three months to comply and by in large most of them do," Mr McNamara added.
Related Files
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:15:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama to give eulogy for victim of church shooting</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710766-south-carolina-funeral/</Link>
        <Description>US President Barack Obama is expected to deliver the eulogy for the pastor that died in the mass shooting in South Carolina.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Friday 26 June 2015 12.15
The president will be accompanied by both First Lady Michelle Obama and Vice President Joe Biden to the funeral
US President Barack Obama is expected to deliver the eulogy for the pastor that died in the mass shooting in South Carolina.
Reverend Clementa Pinckney was a pastor at the Charlestons Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church where the shooting took place.
He was among the nine people who died when a gunman opened fire during Bible study.
The eight other victims were named as Susie Jackson, 87; Reverend Daniel Simmons, 74; Ethel Lance, 70; Myra Thompson, 59;Cynthia Hurd, 54; DePayne Middleton-Doctor, 49; Sharonda Coleman Singleton, 45; and Tywanza Sanders, 26.
The first of the victims funerals took place yesterday, when Ethel Lance and Sharonda Coleman-Singleton were laid to rest.
The church is the oldest African Methodist Episcopal church in the southeastern US and was founded by slaves.
The presidentwill be accompanied by both First Lady Michelle Obama and Vice President Joe Biden to Reverend Pinckneys funeral in Charleston.
All three knew Reverend Pinckney personally.
During his presidency, President Obama has spoken at six memorial services for victims of mass shootings, in Texas, Arizona, Colorado and Connecticut.
Speaking at the White House last week, he said: "I've had to make statements like this too many times. Communities like this have had to endure tragedies like this too many times."
The president repeated his calls for tougher gun laws, a controversial issue in the US where the constitution guarantees the right to own guns.
The mass shootinghas sparked a dialogue across the southern states over the legacy of slavery and its symbols, centering on the Civil War-era battle flag of the Confederacy.
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley and other Republicans have called for the Confederate flag to be removed from the State House grounds.
Some major retailers are removing merchandise with Confederate images from stores and websites.
The Department of Justice has opened a hate crime investigation into the shooting.
A 21-year-old white man, Dylann Roof, has been arrested in connection with the shooting. He faces nine murder charges and one gun charge.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:03:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama interviews Attenborough on climate change</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710712-barack-obama-david-attenborough/</Link>
        <Description>US President Barack Obama has turned interviewer for the BBC, in a special programme with naturalist David Attenborough.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Friday 26 June 2015 07.03
Barack Obama told David Attenborough: 'I have been a huge admirer of your work for a very long time'
US President Barack Obama has turned interviewer for the BBC, in a special programme with naturalist David Attenborough.
Mr Obama and Mr Attenborough discuss climate change in the interview, to be aired on Sunday.
Climate change is one of Mr Obama's top issues for his remaining time in office.
"I have been a huge admirer of your work for a very long time," Mr Obama told Mr Attenborough.
It is the latest in a series of unusual media appearances for Mr Obama, who has been keen to tap almost any avenue that reaches as many people as possible to get his message out.
Last week, Mr Obama was interviewed by comedian Marc Maron for a viral podcast known as "WTF".
Earlier this year, he talked to green-lipstick-wearing comedian GloZell Green and other YouTube celebrities with huge followings.
To reach young people he wanted to sign up for Obamacare, his signature health care insurance program, he talked to comedian Zach Galifianakis for the web series "Between Two Ferns".
Mr Attenborough, 89, has been making television documentaries for 60 years.
The BBC has called him "the godfather of natural history TV".
Mr Obama's interview with Attenborough about climate change was taped on 8 May, and will air on BBC, BBC America and 20 other broadcasters around the world, a White House official said.
It comes as Mr Obama's administration is finalising rules to curb carbon emissions from power plants.
Mr Obama has pushed world leaders to agree to new targets at a summit later this year in Paris.
Mr Obama told Mr Attenborough that kids are "much more environmentally aware" than adults, citing his daughters Malia, 16, and Sasha, 13, as examples.
"They do not dispute, for example, the science around climate change," Mr Obama said in the clip.
Mr Attenborough agreed that adults lose the fascination with nature that is common among children.
"A five-year-old, turning over a stone and seeing a slug, and says, 'What a treasure!' Kids understand the natural world," Mr Attenborough said.
. @POTUS . David Attenborough. Talking climate change. Watch a sneak peek of their interview: http://t.co/SaiaqQzAqN https://t.co/e8bNWiIXgQ
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:02:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tests on BSE cow confirm it was an isolated case</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0625/710650-bse-cow-results/</Link>
        <Description>The Department of Agriculture has said final tests on the recent suspected case of BSE found in a cow in Co Louth have confirmed that it was an isolated case in a single animal.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The department also saidthe cow's mother and grandmother had also been tested and they too were found to be clear of the disease.
In addition, the department confirmed the integrity of the commercial feed supply chain to the farm on which the BSE cow was found.
It said between 2009 and 2010 more than 3,800 animal feed inspections and almost 2,500 feed samples were taken, including 52 from suppliers to the farm infected.
In all cases, the tests on the feeds were found to be clear of all signs of processed animal proteins and all tested negative for meat and bone meal.
The department will now inform the EU Commission and the World Animal Health Organisation of the findings of its tests.
It says it expects the health agency will reassign the BSE control risk status to Ireland as a result of this confirmation.
Reacting to the results IFA President Eddie Downey said consumers can be re-assured about the robustness of the food safety controls in place in Ireland.
He said:This and the high quality of Irish food has rightly reassured export markets from all over the world.
Meanwhile, ICSA President Patrick Kent warned that today's confirmation of a BSE case must not be used as an excuse to drive down price.
Farmers have seen a welcome tightening of prices in recent days, and meat processors cannot use this result, an isolated one-off case, as a stick to hammer farmers with," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:03:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three men charged over murder of biker in Limerick</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0625/710644-limerick-murder-charge/</Link>
        <Description>Three men have been charged in connection with the investigation into the fatal shooting of 51-year-old biker Andrew O'Donoghue at Mountfune, Murroe, Co Limerick last week.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Both men were granted free legal aid and remanded in custody to appear in court by video link on 30 June next.
A third man  50-year-old Dermot McKenna of Hillview Park, St Patricks Road in Limerick  was charged with possession of a shotgun and recklessly discharging it at an apartment in Castletroy on the day after the murder.
Garda allege this incident is connected with the murder and was carried out in retaliation for Mr O'Donoghues murder.
Two other men, aged in their late 40s, arrested in connection with the investigation have been released without charge and a file is being prepared for the Director of Public Prosecutions.
Mr ODonoghue was shot in the head at a bikers club outside Murroeon Saturday afternoon, when a man in a car pulled up and shot him.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:03:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Berkeley tragedy will be 'thoroughly' investigated</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0625/710662-berkeley-balcony-investigation/</Link>
        <Description>The Alameda County District Attorney has promised the families of those killed and injured in the Berkeley balcony collapse that the case will be "thoroughly and exhaustively" investigated.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Seven other students were injured in the incident.
Speaking at a press conference at her office,Ms O'Malley said the tragedy had devastated the Greater Bay Area and Ireland.
She said the DA's office would be the lead agency in this criminal investigation.
Ms O'Malley said she would be investigating whether there was cause to bring charges of criminal negligence in relation to the balcony collapseand whether there was enough evidence to prove those charges beyond reasonable doubt in a court of law.
She said she had 66 investigators at her disposal and she would also bring in outside experts.
She said her office would also be working with agencies from the State of California.
She said the City of Berkeley hada limited scope in terms of the investigationit had carried out but she could guarantee the families of those killed and those who were injured that she would carry out a complete investigation.
Ms O'Malley said she was happy that the city authority and the police department would be supporting her investigation.
In terms of evidence she said that the collapsed balcony was in police possession and the balcony from the floor beneath was in a secure location guarded by sheriffs.
She said there was no timeline on the investigation butany charges of criminal negligence needed to be brought within three years of the crime.
Despite having declared their examinations to be finished, the City of Berkeley local authority and the police department are now co-operating with the District Attorney's formal investigation.
The City of Berkeley local authority announced on Tuesday that its investigation into the tragic balcony collapse at the Library Gardens apartment complex had concluded. 
Its inspectors, it said, were satisfied that extensive dry rot was the sole cause of the failure of the wooden joists holding the balcony in place.
Meanwhile, the funeral of Lorcn Miller took place today while the funerals of Niccolai Schuster and Olivia Burke took place yesterday andEoghan Culligan and Eimear Walsh were laid to rest on Tuesday in Dublin.
The funeral mass forAshley Donohoe, a cousin of Olivia Burke, was held in California last weekend.
Two of the seven students injured in the balcony collapse have beendischarged from hospital. Two of the injuredremain in a critical condition in hospital in California.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:00:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eurogroup talks end with no deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0625/710475-greece-talks/</Link>
        <Description>EU leaders spent two hours of unscheduled talks on the Greek debt crisis at their summit in Brussels yesterday, however, there was no breakthrough.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Despite hours of talks between the Greek Prime Minister and international creditors, another meeting of the eurozone finance ministers, and two hours of talks with EU leaders, Greece is no closer to securing a deal on its debt.
EU officials said Mr Tsipras urged his fellow EU leaders to take responsibility and not leave Greece's fate in the hands of the International Monetary Fund, but they refused to intervene and argued the talks must continue to be conducted by finance ministers.
Later today Greek negotiators will resume contacts with the EU, IMF and ECB in a bid to narrow the points of differences on issues such as pensions, VAT and government spending.
If successful, eurozone finance ministers are prepared to return to Brussels on Saturday.
The head of the eurozone finance ministers group, Jeroen Dijsselbloem, tried to strike a note of optimism when he said: "The door is still open for the Greek side to come with new proposals."
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis told reporters: We'll continue until we find a solution."
However, time is rapidly running out for these negotiations, and tempers are fraying.
Greece could default as early as Tuesday if it does not have the money to replay 1.6bn to the IMF.
Speakingon arrival in Brussels for theEU summit, Taoiseach Enda Kenny said: "Clearly you are in the closing hours of making decisions here. It's in the red sector."
Asked whether Ireland, in principle, would support the continuing Greek demand for debt relief, the Taoiseach replied simply: "No."
Giving his view on yet another suspension of the eurozone finance ministers meeting this afternoon, Mr Kenny said it appeared there was "a complication about putting credible papers on the table.
"It is very important that the propositions, which are tabled, make economic sense and that they are financially sustainable and that they are fair."
Citing Ireland's example in negotiations with international creditors, the Taoiseach said: ".. we did not increase income tax; we did not increase VAT; and we did not increase PRSI. But we putup alternatives to those measure that were proposed."
Mr Kenny argued this Irish policy was put in place " in order to keep a pro-growth policy, and make our country competitive, and grow our economy, and provide jobs for our people."
Taking issue with the Greek proposals for higher taxes on people and companies, Mr Kenny said: "It's difficult to see the beneficial effect of measures that increase the tax on labour; that increase income tax; and that increase PRSI. These are not in the interest of pro-growth.'
He added: "Obviously that's what the [Finance Minister] discussions are about. But I think there is a frustration among the Minister for Finance that they don't have figures they can work off; and suggest better proposals that might be better in growing the economy of Greece and providing jobs for their people."
An Irish Government official clarified that the Taoiseach "continues to support debt reprofiling for Greece", in anydeal with its international lender.
The official cited Ireland's promissory note deal was an example of debt reprofiling "that can ease the burden of debt on taxpayers and give a small economy the space to grow".
Analysis: Europe CorrespondentPaul Cunningham
The hope is a deal can be concluded before eurozone Finance Ministers meet at lunchtime, but no one has any great confidence this new deadline will be met.
Yesterday, there was a cautious welcome to Greeces proposals but there were difficulties as far as some of the countries did not see it the same way. One person to look to is the German Finance Minister, and when he came to Brussels he said not much progress had been made.
It also appears that the IMF in particularhad major concerns on Greeces tax take measures.
The IMF is concerned that theyve heard previous promises from Greece and Greece before and tax collection has not worked out well.
The IMF does not believe Greece will raise enough in taxes to meet their targets and thats why the IMF is insisting on more cuts. However, for Syriza thats just not going to work  thats why the talks are deadlocked and thats why the Greek government say they remain firm in their positions.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:32:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ECB to maintain emergency credit line to Greece</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711122-greece-economy/</Link>
        <Description>The European Central Bank said it would keep its emergency cash lifeline to Greece at current levels, while closely monitoring financial markets and "the potential implications for the monetary policy stance".</Description>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Tiarnan O'Mahoney, Aoife Maguire and Bernard Daly deny the charges.
Mr Gillespie described Mr FitzPatrick's concern that the name of his brother-in-law, John Peter O'Toole, was to be submitted to the Revenue Commissioners as a non-resident account holder following a High Court order in 2003.
Mr Gillespie said at no time did Mr FitzPatrick ask him to delete the account from the list to be provided to Revenue.
But Mr Gillespie said he got the impression that if he had found it within himself to not report the account, then Mr FitzPatrick would be greatly pleased.
Mr Gillespie said he was very clear and consistent - the order was very straightforward and there was no way he was going to leave Mr O'Toole's account out.
Mr Gillespie said that while the focus was on Mr O'Toole, Mr FitzPatrick did ask him about another name on the list of accounts to be submitted to Revenue.
He said Mr FitzPatrick referred to the name "Denis O'Brien" and referred to him as "my mate, Denis".
Mr Gillespie told the court he was able to reassure Mr FitzPatrick as he did not believe then and he does not believe for a second that the name had anything to do with the Denis O'Brien most people have in their minds.
He said it was a common enough name and this was a different individual who had an address in the UK.
Mr Gillespie said he recalled that Mr FitzPatrick described him as "a bit naive".
He told the court he did not believe this Mr O'Brien was the better known Denis O'Brien.
Mr Gillespie told the court that in 2003 he was asked to supply documentation to Revenue on non-resident accounts on which Deposit Interest Retention Tax (DIRT) may have been owed.
Mr Gillespie said that Revenue had obtained a High Court order requiring Anglo to hand over details of non-resident accounts which had been closed.
He said the High Court order was for non-resident accounts but not necessarily bogus non-resident accounts.
He said he would supply requested accounts and Revenue would decide if they were bogus or not.
Mr Gillespie said he recalled being called up to the office of Sen FitzPatrick, who was then chief executive.
He said he did not know why he was there but that it soon became clear it was in relation to the High Court order.
Mr Gillespie told the court yesterday and under cross-examination today that Mr FitzPatrick asked him why an account in the name of his brother-in-law John Peter O'Toole was being included in the return to the Revenue Commissioners.
He said Mr FitzPatrick said his brother-in-law lived in the UK and was now living in Australia and supporting his mother.
He said Mr FitzPatrick was concerned that his brother-in-law was going to be "reported"" to the Revenue.
He said he was aware that Mr FitzPatrick was protective about his family members in a normal way.
He said he explained that Mr O'Toole's account met the criteria outlined in the High Court order but he said he told Mr FitzPatrick that did not mean it was a "bogus non-resident account" and that the order covered accounts where there was absolutely no issue as well as those where there was an issue.
He agreed that explanation did not really satisfy him.
He said he was again summoned to Mr FitzPatrick's office a week or two later.
He said Mr FitzPatrick said he had had a conversation with another director of the bank, Peter Killen, and that Mr Killen had told Mr FitzPatrick to "just tell Brian to delete the account".
Mr Gillespie described Mr FitzPatrick's speech as a "monologue" and said he did not get an opportunity to respond to specifics.
But he said when Mr FitzPatrick had finished, he reminded him about the criteria in the High Court order and said they had no choice but to comply and to provide the information requested.
He said not long afterwards, he was called to Mr FitzPatrick's office again.
This time Mr FitzPatrick told him he was concerned that a relative was going to be "reported" to the Revenue and was losing sleep over it.
He said this time Mr FitzPatrick gave him a different version of a conversation with Peter Killen.
He said that Mr FitzPatrick said that he (Mr FitzPatrick) had suggested to Mr Killen that he should just tell Brian to delete the account.
Mr Gillespie said at no time did Mr FitzPatrick ask him to delete the account from the list to be provided to Revenue.
But Mr Gillespie said he got the impression that if he had found it within himself to not report the account, then Mr FitzPatrick would be greatly pleased.
Mr Gillespie said he was very clear and consistent - the order was very straightforward and there was no way he was going to leave Mr O'Toole's account out.
He said Mr FitzPatrick said to him that he wanted him to be comfortable with his actions, in case he was ever called before a tribunal.
He said it was clear to him that if he did not report the account, Mr FitzPatrick would view it positively.
But Mr Gillespie said that was not going to happen.
Mr Gillespie said that while the focus was on Mr O'Toole, Mr FitzPatrick did ask him about another name on the list of accounts to be submitted to Revenue.
He said Mr FitzPatrick referred to the name "Denis O'Brien" and referred to him as "my mate, Denis".
Mr Gillespie said he was able to reassure Mr FitzPatrick as he did not believe then and he does not believe for a second that the name had anything to do with the Denis O'Brien that most people have in their minds.
He said it was a common enough name and this was a different individual who had an address in the UK.
He said he recalled that Mr Fitzpatrick described him as a bit naive.
He agreed again that he did not believe this Mr O'Brien was the better known Denis O'Brien.
Mr Gillespie said he had tried to raise what Mr FitzPatrick had said with his superior, Director of Finance, Willie McAteer but he said Mr McAteer was in some sort of dispute with Mr FitzPatrick at the time and did not want to talk about him.
He said he had a conversation with Tiarnan O'Mahoney who said he must have been under terrible pressure and it must have been stressful talking to Mr FitzPatrick about this.
He said Mr O'Mahoney told him he should not include Mr O'Toole on the list for Revenue without getting back to him.
He said he told him afterwards that Mr O'Toole was to be included and he said Mr O'Mahoney said "Fine".
Former company secretary Mr Daly, 65, of Collins Avenue West, Whitehall, Dublin; former chief operations officer Mr O'Mahoney, 54, of Glen Pines, Enniskerry, Co Wicklow; and Aoife Maguire, 60, of Rothe Abbey, South Circular Road, Kilmainham, Dublin have pleaded not guilty to seven alleged offences committed in 2003 and 2004.
The three are accused of trying to delete references to two accounts in the name of John Peter O'Toole from Anglo's Core Banking System (CBS).
Mr Daly and Mr O'Mahoney also deny omitting the name of Mr O'Toole from a list provided to the Revenue Commissioners of people who held non-resident accounts worth more than 100,000 in 1995.
Mr O'Mahoney and Ms Maguire further deny attempting to delete six other accounts, connected to Mr FitzPatrick.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:02:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman loses case for damages over hysterectomy</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713209-galway-clinic-court/</Link>
        <Description>A woman who claimed she suffered chronic pain and had difficulty walking after a hysterectomy has lost her High Court case for damages.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.02
The judgment was issued today at the High Court by Mr Justice Anthony Barr
A woman who claimed she suffered chronic pain and had difficulty walking after a hysterectomy has lost her High Court case for damages.
Mary McNicholas from Kiltimagh, Co Mayo, had sued Andrea Hermann, a consultant obstetrician,who carried out the procedure at the Galway Clinic in 2005.
Ms McNicholas had told the court she suffered nerve damage as a result of the operation causing continuing numbness and severe pain in her left leg.
She had alleged that the pre-operative care given by Dr Hermann was deficient as she had not been advised to lose weight before the operation.
She also claimed that the use of aself-retaining retractor during the operation had caused injury to her femural nerve.
Ms McNicholas had called expert witnesses who said the retractor should be released a number of times during surgery to prevent nerve damage.
However, the defendant had also called expert witnesses who said releasing the retractor during the operation would have delayed the procedure and placed her at greater risk from blood loss.
In a judgment issued today, following a hearing in January, Mr Justice Anthony Barr said Ms McNicholas had been previously advised by another doctor of the need to lose weight before the surgery.
She then went to Dr Hermann for a second opinion and was told the operation could be carried out whenever she wanted.
The judge said this was an "honest difference of opinion"and he was satisfied that the approach of both doctors was reasonable.
In this regard he did not find that Dr Hermann had departed from the appropriate standard of care in deciding that she could undergo the operation.
The judge said he was also satisfied that the procedure itself was carried out correctly and that negligence had not been established.
He said he could not find that in failing to release the self-retaining retractor the doctor had departed from the expected standard of care.
He said if she had done so it would have exposed Ms McNicholas to even more danger.
He dismissed the case.
Lawyers for Ms McNicholas have said they need time to study the judgment before deciding on an appeal.
The case was adjourned to24July.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:25:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Juncker wants Greek exit to be 'avoided'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713111-greece-economy/</Link>
        <Description>European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker has said he was against an exit by Greece from the euro.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
However, he added that the eurozone is made up of 19 democracies so the choices made by the other 18 democracies must be respected.
The head of the European Parliament, Martin Schulz, said he was in favour of Greece remaining in the eurozone.
Speaking at a press conference in Strasbourg, Mr Schulz said: "Those people who want to split up the eurozone I think are wrong," he said.
"My personal opinion is that Grexit cannot be our aim."
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras will present new proposals to theemergency summit in Brussels for a deal on his country's deepening debt crisis.
Taoiseach Enda Kenny has said he believes the Greek Prime Minister will bring credible and economically sensible proposals to European leaders.
Speaking on his way into this morning's Cabinet meeting, Mr Kenny said Greece was doing the right thing in bringing new propositions to the European institutions.
The European Central Bank has increased pressure on the Greek financial system by refusing to increase the level of emergency lending to Greek banks.
The banks, which had been due to reopen today, will now not open until at least Thursday.
The Athens stock exchange will also remain closed until tomorrow, the Greek Capital Markets Commission said.
Syriza MEP Dimitris Papadimoulis said the government is submitting proposals that will lead to growth and address the problem of non-sustainable public debt.
He told reporters in Strasbourg that the "message of the Greek government and Syriza is not to have a conflictWe cannot pursue the punishment of the Greek people. We want realism to prevail."
"We are submitting a programme full of reforms in order to set an end to bureaucracy, corruption and nepotism."
Speaking through an interpreter, Mr Papadimoulis added "we are willing to discuss any idea that could help in order to achieve a mutually accepted agreement."
"We could examine the idea of a bridging loan that would allow all sides towards a solution. We are moving towards the edge of the cliff."
The leaders of France and Germany told Greece yesterday to come up with serious proposals in order to restart financial aid talks.
In a warning shot to the banks, the ECB raised the amount of collateral they must post for any loans.
The move does not affect the lenders right away, but served as a reminder that their fate lies in its hands.
Late last night, Mr Tspiras's office said he had spoken with Mr Juncker and French President Francois Hollande, but did not provide details about the conversations.
Senior officials in both the USand Japan called on both sides to seek a resolution.
US Treasury Secretary Jack Lew spoke with both Mr Tsipras and his new finance minister Euclid Tsakalotos, following the resignation of Yanis Varoufakis yesterday.
Mr Lew said Washington looked forward to Athens and other parties resuming conversations towards resolving the Greek situation, a Treasury spokeswoman said.
Mr Lew voiced hope such an outcome "will allow Greece to make difficult but necessary fiscal and structural reforms, return to growth, and achieve debt sustainability within the eurozone," the Treasury statement said.
Similarly, Japan's economics minister, Akira Amari, said Greece and the European Union should work hard to strike a win-win deal that would keep Greece in the currency union.
A German Finance Ministry official dismissed the idea that Berlin would be willing to concede some debt relief to Athens, a position that Mr Tsipras's government has long sought.
But an ECB governing council member, Ewald Nowotny, held out the possibility of bridge funding for Greece while a new bailout programme is being negotiated.
"Whether it's possible is something that has to be discussed," he told Austrian state TV.
Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte said Greece must accept deep reforms if it wants to remain in the euro.
The Greek bank association chief said the bank closures that have crippled the economy would continue today and tomorrow and the daily cash machine withdrawal limit of 60 would be maintained.
There were long lines at ATMs, where 20 banknotes have largely run out.
After five years of economic crisis and mass unemployment, Greek electors voted 61.3% No to the bailout conditions already rejected by their government, casting Greece into uncharted territory.
Minister for Public Expenditure and Reform Brendan Howlin said he believes there will be solidarity among European leaders as they meet over Greece.
Speaking ahead of this morning's Cabinet meeting, Mr Howlin said Ireland wanted a deal to be reached with Greece, and wanted the country to remain in the eurozone.
He said he hoped that terms that are fair to every country would be agreed.
Mr Howlin said he also hoped that a deal involving debt re-profiling, rather than debt relief, would be reached with Athens, which was the sametype of agreement that had been made with Ireland.
He also said that as far as he was aware Minister for Finance Michael Noonan had not made any complaints against Mr Varoufakis.
The former Greek finance minister said in a blog posting announcing his resignation that he had been"made aware" that some members of the eurozone considered him unwelcome at meetings of finance ministers.
Western Union restarts money transfer service in Greece
Western Union said it restarted its money transfer service in Greece, allowing customers in the country to receive funds from overseas.
The company said although the full amount transferred would be credited to account holders, users would be able to withdraw only 60 a day as per the Greek government's recent capital control measures.
Western Union had said on June 29 that it would remain closed for business in Greece for the entire week. 
Analysis: Paul Cunningham
We still don't know what the deal is. We don't know whether this is a radical Syriza plan -one which talks about a write-down on debt or whether it is an amendment of the previous plans being worked on by Jean Claude Juncker with one or two changes.
So we are still somewhat in the dark.
The other big question is whether or not other eurozone ministers, including Michael Noonan, believe it forms the basis of negotiation.
If they think that's the case, then they will send a recommendation to eurozone leaders, who are due to meet around 5.30pm Irish time in Brussels.
That will probably be another two or three hour discussion.
No major decisions [will] be taken but basically what they will say is, there's enough to be working on here, let's see if we can hammer out a deal.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:27:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stolen boating equipment worth €150K recovered</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713224-boats/</Link>
        <Description>Boating equipment worth €150,000 has been recovered by gardaí investigating the theft of boat engines.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
They have managed to locate an owner for one of the engines butthey are now appealing for boat owners who may have had an engine stolen recently to view the items on the garda social media sites to see if their engine is amongthe property.
Detective Sgt John Healysaid: "We feel that the engines could belong to people countrywide, so we're asking everyone from Killybegs to Castletownbere to look at the photos.
"We've set up a dedicated email for people to contact us and make an appointment to view if they believe that their property is here with us".
One caravan, eight trailers and two generators were also recovered in the searches.
The public isasked to email portlaoise.property@garda.ie or ring 057 8674100 to arrange viewing.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:26:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant dies in Channel Tunnel</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713168-migrant-channel-tunnel/</Link>
        <Description>A migrant has died on a freight shuttle trying to reach the UK, Channel Tunnel operator Eurotunnel has confirmed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 14.26
Migrants have been seen trying to climb onto trucks queuing in Calais
A migrant has died on a freight shuttle trying to reach the UK, Channel Tunnel operator Eurotunnel has confirmed.
The incident on the French side of the Channel happened at around 5am Irish time.
Freight traffic is being disrupted and there are also delays to passenger services following the incident near Calais.
The migrant crisis in Calais has escalated in recent months, with around 3,000 people displaced from countries including Eritrea, Syria and Afghanistan setting up camp near the port.
Last week more than 3,000 truckers had to queue for several days in high temperatures on the M20 following a wildcat strike by ferry workers in France.
Industrial action by ferry workers this summer has come on top of the problems faced by hauliers with migrants desperately trying to clamber on board their HGVs to the UK.
French authorities have faced claims they are not doing enough to safeguard lorry drivers from intimidation, violence and attempts by migrants to climb on.
British Home Secretary Theresa May and her French counterpart Bernard Cazeneuve last week agreed to increase the joint intervention fund to improve security around the port and the Channel Tunnel.
French aid workers have reported a "catastrophic" situation, with predictions that 2,000 more migrants could arrive over the summer at the camp, dubbed Jungle II.
Volunteers from L'Auberge Des Migrants say up to 50 new migrants are arriving every day at the camp, and there are not enough tents, blankets or food
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wallace sees no value in discussing NAMA at PAC</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713131-nama-northern-ireland/</Link>
        <Description>Independent TD Mick Wallace has said he does not feel any purpose would be served by appearing before the Public Accounts Committee to answer questions about his NAMA claims.</Description>
        <MainBody>In a letter seen by RT News, Mr Wallace tells the clerk ofthe committeethat his appearance would not serve any purpose.
He said what was needed was an independent inquiry to investigate the entire NAMA operation.
Last year a US investment company, Cerberus Capital Management, bought a NAMA portfolio of Northern Ireland-based debtors.
It had a book value of 4.5bn. The purchase price was not disclosed but NAMA said at the time it was the biggest single transaction in the agency's history.
Mr Wallace claimeda routine auditshowed7m in funding ended up in an Isle of Man bank account.
He said the moneywas "reportedly earmarked for a Northern Ireland politician".
Meanwhile, the Finance Committee of the Stormont Assembly, which is considering the claims,has saidit wants to begin hearing evidence next week.
It is to invite Mr Wallace along with representatives of NAMA and the Belfast law firm involved to answer questions.
However, it is understood that Mr Wallace sees no purpose in acceding to that request either.
Finance Committee Chairman DaithMcKaysaid it would be asking the questions the public are asking.
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:13:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain marks 10th anniversary of 7 July bombings</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713115-july-7-bombings-london/</Link>
        <Description>Remembrance services to commemorate the 10th anniversary of attacks targeting London public transport, which killed 52 people, are under way.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
British Prime Minister David Cameron and Mayor of LondonBoris Johnson laid wreaths at the permanent memorial to the victims in Hyde Park at 8.50am - the time a series of explosions hit the transport network on 7 July 2005.
That morning during rush-hour, four young British Muslims travelledto London where they detonated homemade bombs hidden in rucksacks on three underground trains and a bus.
Inspired by al-Qaeda, they killed themselves and 52 other people and wounded around 700 others.
Citizens from Poland, Israel, Australia, France, Italy, Afghanistan, Nigeria, New Zealand and a Vietnamese-American were among the victims.
In a note attached to his wreath, Mr Cameron wrote: "To the victims of terrorism in London ten years ago today. We grieve your loss and will honour your memory for ever."
Also laying wreaths at the Hyde Park memorial were Transport Commissioner Sir Peter Hendy, Fire Commissioner Ron Dobson, and chief executive of London Ambulance Dr Fiona Moore.
Others were speaker of the House of Commons John Bercow and MP Harriet Harman.
The wording on the wreath laid by Mr Johnsonread: "Ten years may have passed, but London's memory is undimmed. We honour again today the victims of 7/7. You will live forever in the hearts of the people of this city. Boris Johnson"
My thoughts today are with all who were killed and injured in the appalling 7 July bombings in London 10 years ago.
 Daniel Mulhall (@DanMulhall) July 7, 2015
Mr Cameron said in a statement this morning:"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly."
He said: "The murder of 30 innocent Britons whilst holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact. But we will never be cowed by terrorism."
Ceremoniesinclude a national minute of silence, which was marked at 11.30am.
Itcomes just four days after Britain paid a similar tribute to those killed when an Islamist gunman opened fire at the Tunisian resort of Sousse.
A further service will be held later at the memorial site for survivors and relatives, which Prince William will attend.
Britain is currently on its second highest alert level of "severe".
That means a militant attack is considered highly likely, mainly due to the danger the authorities say is posed by so-called Islamic State groupfighters and Britons who have joined them.
On Thursday 7 July 2005, Shehzad Tanweer, 22, MohammedSidique Khan, 30, Hasib Hussain, 18 and Jermaine Lindsay, 19, arrived at King's Cross at around 8.23am.
At 8.30am four men fitting their descriptions are seen hugging before splitting up.
Khan boarded a west-bound Circle Line train, Tanweer an east-bound Circle Line train, and Lindsay a south-bound Piccadilly Line train. Hussain also appears to walk towards the Piccadilly Line entrance.
At 8.50am three bombs exploded within a minute on London Underground trains.
Tanweer detonated his bomb at Aldgate, Khan set his device off at Edgware Road and Lindsay blew himself up between King's Cross and Russell Square.
Hussain detonated his device on a number 30 bus at Tavistock Square at 9.47am.
Twenty-six died in the bombing at Russell Square on the Piccadilly line, six in the bombing at Edgware Road on the Circle line, seven in the bombing at Aldgate on the Circle line, and 13 in the bombing on the bus at Tavistock Square.
One of those who died at Russell Square was 22-year-old Ciaran Cassidy, whose parents are from Ireland. He worked at alegal and stationery firm in Chancery Lane and was saving up to go to Australia.
Source: Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:25:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>House price growth slows in Dublin</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713114-house-prices/</Link>
        <Description>The growth in house prices in Dublin was significantly slower than elsewhere in the country for the second quarter in a row.</Description>
        <MainBody>Prices were up by 4.4% in Cork, in Galway they climbed by 3.8% and in Waterford they grew by 3.4%.
Outside the major cities prices were up 2.8% over the same period.
For the country as a whole, the average asking price for a house in Ireland grew by 1.9% in the second quarter of 2015.
This means that in all but one of the last seven quarters, the average price has risen nationwide.
Daft.ie said the average price of a house nationwide is now 202,000, compared to a low of 164,000 in mid-2013 and a peak of 370,000 in 2007.
Author of the reportRonan Lyonssaid the figures showthe new lending rules introduced by the Central Bank have taken effect.
Mr Lyons said Dublin is now responsible for dragging the national asking price down, instead of pushing it up, as it had been doing two or three years ago.
Speaking on RTs Morning Ireland, he said the new rules are having a cooling-off effect on house prices in Dublin, which, he said, should be a permanent affect.
He said: "There is also a potential temporary effect, in that once you introduce these rules, you reshuffle demand a little bit around the country, in particular from Dublin to the counties around it."
He added: "The Central Bank's aim here was really to make sure people didn't borrow too much.
"And people were borrowing most relative to their capacity to pay back in Dublin.
"So it was clear that if they were going to have an impact anywhere, it was going to be, particularly in terms of cooling off house prices, it was going to be in Dublin."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:25:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News in Brief</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713124-news-in-brief/</Link>
        <Description>A round-up of Irish and other international news.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 14.25
Frances Fitzgerald said there were 550 new garda recruits in the past year
Garda force stood at 12,772 at end of May
Minister for Justice and Equality Frances Fitzgerald has told the Dil that of 31 May, the current strength of An Garda Sochna stood at 12,772.
Speaking during Minister's Questions, she said there were 550 new recruits in the past year and she had a commitment of two further intakes of 225 each.
She was responding to Fianna Fil Justice Spokesperson Niall Collins, who asked about the minister's projections for total garda numbers up to 2017.
Three men gored during Pamplona bull run
Three men were gored and ten others taken to hospital on the first day of Pamplona's week-long San Fermin festival in the northern Spanish city where bulls chase runners in red scarves through the streets.
The run lasted two minutes and 23 seconds.
One man was gored in the chest and was in a stable condition, a doctor at the event said. The Red Cross said two other men were gored, one in the back, but gave no further details.
Many Spanish towns hold festivals involving bulls during the summer. San Fermin is the most famous internationally and attracts thousands of revellers, many from abroad.
Space weather warning system developed
A warning system about space weather events that have the potential to damage communication and energy systems has been developed by scientists at Trinity College Dublin and the Dublin Institute of Advanced Studies (DIAS).
The magnetometer network enables researchers to monitor and model magnetic storms in near-real time, giving them advance knowledge of when a potentially damaging solar storm is about to hit.
The system got its first big test on 17 March when the two enormous eruptions from the Sun caused particles to collide at millions of kilometres per hour with Earth's magnetic field.
The result was the biggest geomagnetic storms in a decade, which led to spectacular displays of the northern lights.
The Trinity and DIAS team is now focusing on trying to understand how these large storms might impact on Earth and on improving their forecasting system.
NineSport NI board members resign
Nine members of the Sport NI board have resigned.
They offered their resignations just before a meeting with Stormont Sports Minister Carl N Chuiln.
The meeting was due to discuss a report from the Department of Culture Arts and Leisure into the workings of Sport NI.
The minister accepted the resignations and is to meet the remaining five board members later this week.
Japan: Ex-Toyota executive to be released
Tokyo prosecutors plan to release former Toyota Motor Corp executive Julie Hamp from custody after she was arrested last month on suspicion of illegally importing the painkiller oxycodone into Japan, Kyodo News reported.
Kyodo said Ms Hamp, who resigned last week just three months after her appointment as Toyota's first female managing officer, is set to be released without indictment, the latest she can be held without a formal charge.
A spokeswoman for the Tokyo District Public Prosecutors Office declined to comment on the report.
"We have not announced anything (on Hamp)," she said.
Turkish Airlines flight diverted to Delhi after 'bomb threat'
A Turkish Airlines flightlanded in the Indian capital, New Delhi, on Tuesday after a supposed bomb threat, an Indian security official said.
"There was a bomb threat to the Turkish Airlines flight andtherefore they decided to land it in New Delhi," an official from the federal Central Industrial Security Forces said.
He declined to be named because of the sensitivity of the information.
India's crack National Security Guards had been put on alert, Times Now TV said.
It said the plane with 148 passengershad made an emergency landing in New Delhi during the Istanbul-Bangkok TK-65 flight.
Dog dons robe to help owner collect degree
A student and his dog will don graduation robes today after the pet helped his owner complete his university degree.
Jack Proctor, 34, joined forces with cocker spaniel Fudge to complete a series of assignments as he studied for his BDes (Hons) in design and digital arts at Edinburgh Napier University.
The six-year-old dog starred in Mr Proctors introductory video and course work, and featured prominently in his dissertation.
To mark Fudge's supporting role in his owner's academic journey, the dog will join the graduation ceremony wearing bespoke robes made by Mr Proctor's wife.
14 killed in Kenya gun attack
At least 14 people were killed and 11 wounded when gunmen attacked a northern Kenyan village, close to the border with Somalia, officials and Red Cross said.
There was no immediate claim of responsibility but Somali-led al-Shabaab militants have carried out a string of attacks in the region, highlighting the insecurity that plagues parts of the country.
The attack occurred at an area called Soko Mbuzi, a livestock market just outside the town of Mandera in Kenya's far northeastern region, bordering Somalia and Ethiopia.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:50:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Interim Iran nuclear deal extended to Friday</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713237-iran-nuclear-talks/</Link>
        <Description>An interim nuclear agreement between Iran and six major powers will be extended to Friday to provide more time for talks on a final agreement, the United States has said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.50
Talks are taking place in Vienna to reach an agreement over Iran's nuclear programme
An interim nuclear agreement between Iran and six major powers will be extended to Friday to provide more time for talks on a final agreement, the United States has said.
      
"We've made substantial progress in every area, but thiswork is highly technical and high stakes for all of the countries involved," Marie Harf, the spokeswoman for the USdelegation, said in a statement.
      
"We're frankly more concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock, though we also know that difficult decisions won't get any easier with time - that is why we are continuing to negotiate," she added.
Six world powers are meeting in Vienna tryingto meet themidnight deadline for a nuclear deal with Iran.
They were expected to meet with Iran's Foreign Minister, Mohammad Javad Zarif, and Iran's nuclear negotiators later in the day.
A dispute over UNsanctions on Iran's ballistic missile programme and a broader arms embargo were among issues holding up a nuclear deal between Tehran and the powers on the day of the latest self-imposed deadline, diplomats said.
The deal under discussion is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy.
The US and its allies fear Iran is using its civilian nuclear programme as a cover to develop nuclear weapons capability. Iran says its programme is peaceful.
An agreement would be the most important milestone in decades towards easing hostility between the US and Iran, enemies since Iranian revolutionaries captured 52 hostages in the USembassy in Tehran in 1979.
A deal could reduce the chance of any military strike against Iran's nuclear facilities, something Washington has refused to rule out, and the possibility of a wider war in the Middle East, where conflicts already rage in Iraq, Syria and Yemen.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:04:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Call for experienced divers to assist Cork search</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713136-cork-search-baltimore/</Link>
        <Description>Search teams in west Cork are appealing to experienced divers to assist them in their search for the body of a 20-year-old man missing off Baltimore since last Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 14.04
The search continues for the body of Barry Davis Ryan
Search teams in west Cork are appealing to experienced divers to assist them in their search for the body of a 20-year-old man missing off Baltimore since last Tuesday.
Barry Davis Ryan was one of a group of people walking close to the Beacon when one of them was swept into the sea.
Two others attempted a rescue before all three got into difficulty.
The bodies of 20-year-old Niamh O'Connor and Barry's father, 51-year-oldBarry Ryan,were later recovered from the sea.
Their funerals took place over the weekend.
John Kearney of West Cork Underwater Search and Rescue said there is a "weather window" on Thursday and Friday but the weather was set to change at the weekend.
He said a very detailed search needs to be carried out and it is important that divers are experienced as the terrain is difficult and the search needs to be carried out carefully "so we don't have to repeat and go over the area again".
Mr Kearney said local fishermen were laying a lot of ground lines so divers have a route to follow to make sure the area is "gridded completely".
Holiday home owners andaccommodation providers in the Baltimore area are being asked to help with accommodation for up to 40 divers due in the village on Thursday.
Barry Ryan senior,a son of Penneys founder Arthur Ryan,was asenior executive with the retail clothing company.
Ms O'Connor from Glanmireworked at a Penneys store in Cork city.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:14:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>LÉ Eithne on standby as Mediterranean mission ends</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713113-le-eithne-migrants/</Link>
        <Description>The Irish navy's LÉ Eithne is tied up in Valetta, Malta, this morning as its mission in the Mediterranean comes to an end.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Since it deployed in May the crew of L Eithne rescued 3,400 migrants attempting to cross the Mediterranean in small boats. Among that number were 179 minors.
A breakdown of nationalities of the migrants rescued shows that 12% were from Eritrea; 12% from Nigeria; 11%from Sudan; and 9% from Syria.
Other nationalities included Ghanaians, Moroccans, Somalians and Ethiopians.
This morning Minister for Defence Simon Coveney, Minister for Justice Frances Fitzgerald and Minister of State at Department of Foreign Affairs Sean Sherlock visited the ship and metthe commander and crew.
Speaking on RT's Morning Ireland, Mr Coveney saidan Irish naval presence will be maintained until at least the end of September when it will be reassessed and a decision made at Government level on whether the presence will be continued.
He said Ireland had responded to the tragedy of the drowning of hundreds of migrants earlier this yearand wanted to be part of the European solution to the "immediate problem" of the migrant crisis, but acknowledged that this did not deal with the core issues of war, poverty and extremism. 
Mr Coveney said Ireland hascommitted to taking in 540 refugees from Syria over the next two years.
He also said Italy was right to demand that other EU countries share the burden of taking in migrants.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:14:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cosby obtained sedatives to have sex with women</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713159-bill-cosby/</Link>
        <Description>Comedian Bill Cosby testified in 2005 that he had obtained Quaaludes with the intent of giving the sedatives to young women in order to have sex with them, according to court documents unsealed yesterday.</Description>
        <MainBody>The case was settled for an undisclosed sum in 2006 but the documents in the case were unsealed yesterday after the Associated Press went to court.
Mr Cosby's lawyers had argued that the documents would cause severe embarrassment to the comedian-actor.
Mr Cosby is best known for playing Dr Cliff Huxtable on the hit TV comedy series "The Cosby Show" in the 1980s and 1990s.
A representative for Mr Cosby did not immediately respond to requests for comment yesterday.
More than 40 women have come forward in the past year alleging Mr Cosby drugged and sexually assaulted them in incidents dating back decades.
His attorneys have consistently denied the allegations.
Mr Cosby has never been criminally charged and most of the allegations exceed the statute of limitations.
However, his career has taken a hit in the past year with TV projects and live shows being cancelled.
He also stepped down from the board of trustees at Temple University, his alma mater.
Mr Cosby testified that in the 1970s he had obtained seven prescriptions for Quaaludes, the brand name for a sedative and muscle relaxant that was widely abused as a recreational drug in the 1970s.
"When you got the Quaaludes, was it in your mind that you were going to use these Quaaludes for young women that you wanted to have sex with?" Mr Cosby was asked in the 2005 deposition.
"Yes," he replied.
Asked whether he ever gave them to young women, his lawyers raised a lengthy series of objections.
Mr Cosby testified later that he gave Ms Constand one and a half pills of the over-the-counter antihistamine drug Benadryl.
Mr Cosby has said little directly about the allegations against him, telling ABC television in an interview in May that he did not wish to discuss them.
Source: Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:13:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fewer people on outpatient clinic waiting lists</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713230-waiting-lists-health/</Link>
        <Description>New figures show that the number of people waiting to be seen at an outpatient clinic, or for inpatient or day case treatments, has reduced.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.13
There are now 402,156 people waiting for an outpatient appointment
New figures show that the number of people waiting to be seen at an outpatient clinic, or for inpatient or day case treatments, has reduced.
There are now 402,156 people waiting for an outpatient appointment, according to the National Treatment Purchase Fund.
It compares with the May figure of over 415,400.
The number of people waitng over a year for an outpatient visit is also down by over 14,500 to 70,564.
The latest report for June also shows the number of people waiting for an inpatient, or day case treatment is at 67,195 - down slightly on the previous figure of 67,359.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:14:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ICTU discusses historic 'mass mobilisation'</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713192-ictu/</Link>
        <Description>The president of the Irish Congress of Trade Unions has described the anti-water charges movement as the biggest mass social mobilisation since the foundation of the State.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
However, hesaid the extensive concessions secured by it would be enjoyed by all trade unionists.
He said that if members of thetrade union movement had been totally absent from the anti-water charges movement, it would have severely damaged its credibility.
As an election year loomed, he said,trade unionists had to grasp the nettle of political power within their membership bases.
He said no union could profess to be non-political, and their vision could never be achieved by industrial agitation alone.
They needed to campaign for a mass mobilisation akin to what they had witnessed during the same-sex marriage referendum, he said, to secure the political ground to deliver the social and industrial agenda.
He also said trade unions were not interested in a social dialogue which confined or constrained the legitimate role of their members.
The trade union movement, he said,had rediscovered its activism and shaken off the shackles of top down centralised bargaining.
He said it was cutting the teeth of a whole new generation of trade union and community activists in struggles such as Greyhound, the Paris Bakery, Rhatigans, Clerys, Vita Cortex and Dunnes Stores.
He cited a number of victories for the trade union movement, including the restoration of the sectoral wage setting arrangements, though he called for stronger legislation to ensure that employers could not obstruct their implementation.
He described new legislation on collective bargaining as far from perfect, but a foundation on which to build further.
He referred to Northern Ireland as the most deprived region in the UK. The welfare cuts and the 20,000 public sector job losses sought by the Tory government would plunge Northern Ireland into the dark ages if not challenged, he said.
The British and Irish governments needed to recognise Northern Ireland as a region emerging from conflict, where austerity policy were doubly damaging, he added.
Mr Douglas called for lifting of the debt burden in Greece and delegates stood and applauded in solidarity with the Greek people.
He called for a European debt conference to consider the issue of debt restructuring from the social perspective of the peoples of Europe, rather than solely from the financial institutions of Europe and the ideologues of austerity.
He also urged trade unionists to campaign against international free trade agreements.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:16:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alcohol use while pregnant 'prevalent' in Ireland</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713112-alcohol-pregnancy/</Link>
        <Description>Alcohol use before and during pregnancy is "prevalent and socially pervasive" in Ireland, according to an international study.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.16
Research was based on a large sample of women in Ireland, UK, Australia and New Zealand
Alcohol use before and during pregnancy is 'prevalent and socially pervasive' in Ireland, according to an international study.
The research was based on three existingpopulation-based studies in Ireland, the UK, Australia and New Zealand and found higher levels of alcohol consumption in Ireland before and during pregnancy than in the other three countries.
Ireland has the highest prevalence of any alcohol consumption pre-pregnancy at 90% and during pregnancy at 82%.
The research, published in the BMJ Open , also found Ireland has the highest reported binge alcohol consumption before - 59% -and during - 45% -pregnancy.
The Irish element of the research, assessed by experts in University CollegeCork, found expectant mothers in Ireland were significantly more likely to be drinkers if they were also smokers.
Researchers described the widespread consumption of even low levels of alcohol during pregnancy as a "significant public health concern".
The study had a large sample size of almost 18,000 women and looked at the drinking patterns of Irish women as assessed in two previous Irish studies and one international study.
It founddrinking during pregnancy was commonplace in all four countries, ranging from 20% to 80% in Ireland and from 40% upwards in the UK, Australia and New Zealand.
The amount of alcoholconsumed dropped substantially for all countries in the second trimester, along with the level of binge drinking.
The research found that non-white women were less likely to drink, along with younger women, those who were more highly educated, obese or already had children.
Researchers said the findings show there is low adherence to alcohol guidelines advising complete abstinence from alcohol during pregnancy in Ireland, New Zealand and Australia, and the National Institute for Health and Care Excellenceguidelines in the UK, which advisesconsumption of no more than one to two units once or twice a week.
Although most women who drink during pregnancy do so at low levels, those who drink heavily are putting their unborn baby at risk of Foetal Alcohol Syndrome (FAS), which affects their physical and mental development.
Consultant Obstetrician and Gynecologist at the National Maternity Hospital Dr Peter Boylan said he agreed with the findings and said any excessive amount of alcohol use, or binge drinking, is a concern.
Speaking on RT's Morning Ireland, he said Ireland has a well-known dysfunctional relationship with alcohol so "its no surprise the same thingextends into pregnancy".
However, Dr Boylan said there is no evidence that a small amount of alcohol during pregnancy is harmful, but it is important togetthebalance right and reiterated that binge drinking while pregnant is very concerning.
He said: "The evidence from international studies is that a small amount of alcohol, maybe one or two units a week, does not seem to do any harm at all."
He said the Government has a role to play in the restriction of the easy availability of alcohol andthe association with sporting events and the glamorisation of alcohol consumption, and saideducation and the restriction of cheap alcohol sales is the way to go.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:16:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Several injured in Washington ice cave collapse</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713162-washington-ice-cave/</Link>
        <Description>Several people have been injured in the partial collapse of an ice cave in Washington state that officials had warned was too dangerous for exploration due to unseasonably warm weather.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.16
The Big Four Ice Caves are home to a popular hiking trail
Several people have beeninjured in the partial collapse of an ice cave in Washington state thatofficials had warned was too dangerous for exploration due to unseasonably warm weather.
A spokeswoman from the Snohomish County Sheriff's Office said rescue workers were still trying to confirm how many people were in the Big Four Ice Caves near Granite Falls, 64kmnorth of Seattle, when a cave gave way yesterday.
The Everett Herald reported nine people were injured, citing a figure from the USForest Service.
Granite Falls ice cave collapse
The injured were all takento local hospitals, the newspaper said.
The caves are home to a popular hiking trail and are part of the Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest.
In May, the USForest Service warned hikers against entering the Big Four Ice Caves after several sections collapsed in unusually warm spring temperatures in the Pacific Northwest.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:16:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Over 150,000 South Sudanese sheltering in UN bases</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0707/713179-south-sudan/</Link>
        <Description>The number of South Sudanese civilians sheltering in United Nations bases has risen above 150,000 for the first time in 18 months of civil war, the UN has said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tuesday 07 July 2015 13.16
153,769 civilians are seeking safety at six peacekeeping bases
The number of South Sudanese civilians sheltering in United Nations bases has risen above 150,000 for the first time in 18 months of civil war, the UN has said.
A total of 153,769 civilians are now seeking safety behind the barbed wire of six peacekeeping bases of the UN Mission in South Sudan (UNMISS).
Many fled into the campsas war broke out in December 2013 and have never left.
But tens of thousands more have entered the bases during an upsurge in fighting since April, taking those seeking shelter to the highest number yet.
Over 10,000 have arrived in the past week alone, according to official figures released by UNMISS.
Over 28,000 are based in the capital Juba.
Aid workers there are trying to stamp out a cholera outbreak that has killed at least 32 people since cases were first recorded last month, including inside the UN base.
Another 91,500 are sheltering in Bentiu, capital of the northern battleground state of Unity, where a UN report last month described how South Sudan's army raped then burned girls alive inside their homes during a recent campaign marked by "new brutality and intensity".
More than 30,000 are also in the UN base in Malakal, capital of the northeastern Upper Nile state.
The town has been left in ruins by intense fighting, swapping hands several times.
Government forces retookit again yesterday after around a week under rebel control during which gunmen fired on the civilians inside the UN base.
UNMISS said that attack may constitute a war crime.
On Thursday, the world's youngest nation marksits fourth year since winning independence from north Sudan.
The UN has listedSouth Sudan as "lower in terms of human development than just about every other place on earth".
Civil war began when President Salva Kiir accused his former deputy Riek Machar of planning a coup.
That setoff a cycle of retaliatory killings across the country that has split the poverty-stricken, landlocked country along ethnic lines.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:51:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rabbitte will not contest next general election</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0706/713080-rabbitte/</Link>
        <Description>Former Labour leader and minister Pat Rabbitte has confirmed he will not be running in the next General Election.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
He was one of the founding members of the Democratic Left, which merged with the Labour Party in 1999.
He came from a trade union background and in the 1970s, was active in student politics and was formerly president of the Union of Students in Ireland.
He was a Minister of State in the rainbow government from 1994-1997.
@MartinaFitzg assesses Pat Rabbitte's decision not to contest the next general election. https://t.co/K5RE4dlh5E
 RT News (@rtenews) July 6, 2015
Mr Rabbitte succeeded Ruairi Quinn as Labour Leader in 2002, having been elected by members of the party.
During the subsequent general election campaign he made a pre-election pact with Fine Gael known as the Mullingar Accord.
He stood down as Labour leader in 2007.
Pat Rabbitte has done the State distinguished service and will go down as one of the finest parliamentarians of this or any other generation
 Joan Burton (@joanburton) July 6, 2015
In the 2011 general election he got the highest number of votes of any Labour candidate whenhe was elected in Dublin South West.
Mr Rabbitte was then appointed as Minister for Communications, Energy and Natural Resources, but was dropped from the cabinet when Joan Burton took over as leader last year.
A recent poll by the party suggested he would retain the seat, however, he did not reveal his decision on whether or not to run until this evening.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:02:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US 'speeding up' troop training in Iraq and Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0706/713088-obama-troop-training/</Link>
        <Description>The President of the United States has said the US military is "speeding up" the rate at which it is training local fighters in Iraq and Syria.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Tuesday 07 July 2015 00.02
Barack Obama says recent IS losses prove the group can be defeated and the US is 'going after' IS leadership in Syria
The President of the United States has said the US military is "speeding up" the rate at which it is training local fighters in Iraq and Syria.
Speaking after he was briefed at the Pentagon on the progress of the campaign against the group styling itself Islamic State, Barack Obama said it would not be a "quick" battle but rather was a "long-term campaign" against a group that was "opportunistic and nimble".
He confirmed the US had so far carried out over 5,000 airstrikes against IS targets.
He said recent IS losses proved the group could be defeated and that the US was now "going after" the IS leadership in Syria.
Mr Obama said there was a "glimmer of good news" as there was now recognition from all the partners in the region that they needed to work together.
Speaking at the Pentagon President Obama said the coalition had been "moving too slowly", but with the extra forces that he had authorised last month, they were now "speeding up the training", and delivering more anti-aircraft missiles.
He said it was important to "develop local security forces that can sustain progress", as it was not "enough" to send in American troops to temporarily set back the IS fighters, which then created a void that was filled again, adding that local forces need to succeed and sustain in terms of security and governance in the region.
He stressed if the US tried to do everything itself, there would be "a whole lot of unintended consequences" that would make the US "less secure".
President Obama said the coalition had made it harder for IS to carry out large scale attacks but lone wolf attacks were harder to work against.
He again repeated that the US was not "at war with Islam" but rather it was fighting terrorists "who distort Islam and whose victims were mostly Muslims".
He admitted that the "large battle for hearts and minds" would be a "generational struggle".
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:11:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Irish couple may have died in Tunisia attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/710988-tunisia-attack/</Link>
        <Description>Gardaí in Westmeath are liaising with the family of a couple in their 50s from the Athlone area who are believed to have died in a terrorist attack on a beach in Tunisia yesterday.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
One Irish person has been confirmed so far among the 38victims killed yesterday afternoon when a gunman opened fire at a beach resort inSousse.
Lorna Carty , a mother of two,from Robinstown in Co Meath isbelieved to have been on the beach when the attack began.
Shewas in the resort with her husband Declan, who was uninjured, but said to be "absolutely distraught".
Minister for ForeignAffairs CharlieFlanagan has said it will takea period of time to complete a full and formal identification of the victims of the attack.
He said the Irish Ambassador to Spainand Consulareworking closely with the authorities in Tunisia.
Meanwhile, the number of Britons confirmed to have died in the attack has risen to 15.
One Belgian and one German national have also been confirmed dead.
A further 39 people are said to have been wounded in the attack, which has been claimed by the so-called Islamic State group.
Tunisian Prime Minister Habib Essidsaid reserve troops would be called up to reinforce security at "sensitive sites... and places that could be targets of terrorist attacks" after the massacre, the second against tourists in Tunisia this year.
The "exceptional plan to better secure tourist and archaeological sites" will include "deploying armed tourist security officers all along the coast and inside hotels from 1 July," he added.
He also announced that a national anti-terrorism congress would be held in September and that financial rewards would be given to anyone who comes forward with information leading to the capture of any terrorists.
The Department of Foreign Affairs has advised Irish people planning on travelling to Tunisia or who may already be in the country to follow the advice of the Tunisian authorities and maintain contact with tour organisers.
Anyone who may have concerns about family or friends in Tunisia should contact 01-4082000.
Irish embassy staff, including Irish Ambassador to Spain David Cooney, who is also accredited with Tunisia,arrived in Sousse late Fridaynight to provide consular assistance to citizens caught up in the attack.
In a statement, Meath GAA has confirmed that allmatches and training involving Dunderry and Kilmessan have been cancelled until further notice following the killing of Ms Carty in Tunisia.
Her son Simon is part of the Meath senior panel and was a member of the county's U-21 team, while Ms Carty was very involved in the GAA and with her local club Dunderry.
The Leinster SFC semi-final match between Meath and Westmeath in Croke Park tomorrow will go ahead as scheduled.
Glanbia chairman Henry Corbally expressed sympathy to the Carty family.
"This is a terrible tragedy to afflict a highly respected and popular farming family.
"On behalf of all members of Glanbia, I wish to express my deepest sympathy to Lornas husband Declan and their children Simon and Hazel."
The gunman wasa 23-year-old student who disguised himself as a tourist and began firing at holidaymakers on a beach using a Kalashnikov he had hidden in a beach umbrella.
The student, identified as Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani, was reportedly laughing as he carried out the massacre and deliberately selected western tourists, before being shot dead by police.
'Four hours of hell'
Meanwhile, Irish holidaymakers who returned on Friday nightfrom Tunisia described scenes of chaos during the attack at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel.
Many described a large explosion as well as gunfire andpraised hotel staff for helping them.
Marian King from Lucan, who was staying in the hotel, said the last four hours of their holiday had turned into hell.
Speaking at Dublin airport after the Aer Lingus flight from Monastir arrived home she said she and her family had managed to get into a hotel bedroom when the shooting started.
"People were running down the corridors screaming to be let into bedrooms". She described hearing more shooting and hiding in the bathroom for about two hours until after it had it subsided.
Anthony and Betty Tunstead from Glasnevin Avenue in Dublin were part of a group of four who cut their holiday short to come home last night.
MsTunstead described screaming and chaos as the shooting started.
"We went into one room and kept there for a while. I came back out and here's a boyo in the lobby with a machine gun.
"We didnt make eye contact because he was looking to see where he was jumping off the parapet. He didn't see me."
Ms Tunstead said had it been a different day they might not have escaped alive. She said they normally met up with a couple from Meath and would have been sitting with them had they not been about to move hotel.
The group she was with expressed concern for another Irish couple they had been with at the hotel who they believed had been caught up in the shooting, and who they had not heard from.
Cathy Piper from Wicklow was having a beer on the beach when the attack began around noon and says she saw an attacker.
"I saw him from a distance - a guy dressed in black walking along the beach.
She followed a staff member in a side door to safety. "The hotel staff were great. They ran to the creche to get the kids out."
Patricia Sheehan from Dungarvan who was in a hotel 2km from the scene said she contacted the Irish authorities in Dublin, and they kept in contact with her through the day.
"We didnt have any male members of our family with us so we felt a little bit unsafe. I was trying to put people in the complex at ease and keep them up to date," she said.
Denis Purcell from Glasnevin described having to comfort an English man whose fiance was killed. "We were around him talking to him.
"He was devastated trying to find out was she brought to a hospital. It was killing him to think she was still lying inside the hotel."
Mr Purcell said the Tunisian prime minister visited the hotel.
"There was more security for the prime minister than came to the hotel after the explosions," he said.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
