<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="rte">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:32:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ECB to maintain emergency credit line to Greece</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711122-greece-economy/</Link>
        <Description>The European Central Bank said it would keep its emergency cash lifeline to Greece at current levels, while closely monitoring financial markets and "the potential implications for the monetary policy stance".</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Meanwhile, Greece's finance minister has denied saying the government preferred the imposition of capital controls, saying the move would be incompatible with the concept of a monetary union, a statement from his ministry said.
BBC Radio earlier quoted Yanis Varoufakis saying Athens would consider imposing capital controls tonight in addition to losing the country's banks tomorrow.
Mr Varoufakis insisted that Greece's exit from the eurozone is not inevitable.
He said the bailout crisis was a "dark hour" for Europe, but the country had a "clear conscience" over its actions.
Greece's Financial StabilityCouncil is conveningthis afternoon to discuss the situation in the country's banking system, a source said.
The council comprises Mr Varoufakis, his deputy Dimitris Mardas, Central Bank Governor Yiannis Stournaras, the head of the Greek Banks Association, the chairman of the HFSF bank bailout fund and the head of the Capital Markets Commission.
      
Long lines formed in front of ATMs yesterdayas people rushed to pull their money out while the banks were still operating normally.
Huge pressure has been piling up on Greek banks after talks between Athens and its creditors for a cash-for-reforms deal collapsed.
Mr Varoufakis also said that German Chancellor Angela Merkel "holds the key" to resolving his country's crisis, and stressed that the government remains open to further talks with international creditors.
He told Germany's Bild newspaper that EU leaders must act and "and among them she, as the representative of the most important country, holds the key in her hand. I hope she uses it."
Ms Merkel has invited leaders from all the major German parties to a crisis meeting in Berlin tomorrow to discuss the Greece crisis.
A senior German official saidthe chairmen and parliamentary leaders of all the parties represented in the German parliament, including the opposition Greens and Left, had been invited to attend the meeting.
ECB should not cut support - Valls
Earlier, France's Prime Minister said the ECBshould not cut off support to Greek banks even if the country misses a 30 June deadline for debt repayments it cannot afford to make.
"The European Central Bank is independent, but I don't doubt it will assume its responsibilities," Manuel Valls said in an interview broadcast on Europe 1 radio.
"I don't think it can cut off support, to put it another way."
Mr Valls also sounded a warning to Greek voters that a "no" vote in the upcoming referendum on a proposed debt deal could amount to a decision to leave the euro zone.
"The Greek people must be able to decide lucidly," Mr Vallssaid.
"If there's a negative vote, there is a real risk ...of exiting the euro zone."
Greece has called a 5 July referendum so thatvoters can decide on whether to accept new, tougher bailout terms that the government itself opposes.
Austria's Finance Minister has said a Greek exit from the euro would only be possible if Greece got the permission of other member countries.
"Greece would have to file a request to do so. The other EU countries would have to approve the request.
"Only then could Greece leave the eurozone," saidHans Jorg Schelling in an interview with Austrian newspaper Die Presse.
It's clear that one country can under no circumstances blackmail the European Commission and the euro countries," Mr Schelling said.
Yesterday, eurozone finance ministers refused to extend the bailout, blaming the Greek government for unilaterally ending talks with creditors and announcing a surprise referendum.
In turn, the Greek government criticised the European Union for failing to live up to its founding principles of solidarity and equality and trying to impose a debt plan which would hurt the poorest and only deepen the country's economic crisis.
Eurozone finance ministers expressed confidence in the euro and its ability to withstand economic shocks, but conceded the single currency bloc is heading into uncharted waters. 
The Greek parliament approved thereferendum by a majority vote late last night, according to the assembly's count.
In a speech prior to the vote, Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras said he was confident that "the Greek people will say an emphatic no to the ultimatum" by the country's EU-IMF creditors, but "a big yes to European solidarity".
He also expressed confidence that "in the aftermath of this proud no, the negotiating power of the country (with the country's creditors) will be strengthened".
The Greeks, according to the text of the proposed referendum, must say "yes" or "no" to the measures submitted by the country's EU-IMF creditors to the government Friday at one of the final rounds of negotiations that have been going on since late February. 
Source: AFP/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:38:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three Irish confirmed dead in Tunisia attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711121-tunisia-attack/</Link>
        <Description>A couple from Athlone in Co Westmeath are confirmed to have died in Friday's terror attack in Tunisia, bringing to three the number of Irish people killed.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The couplehave one daughter.
Mr Hayes was a school bus inspector with Bus ireann and had worked at the company for 20 years, beginning as a bus driver in Galway.
The companyextended its sympathy to the couple's family, andfriends as well as Mr Hayes' colleagues.
Garda and officials from the Department of Foreign Affairs are liaising with the family.
The third Irish victim is Lorna Carty, a mother-of-two from Robinstown in Co Meath.
She was on holidayin the popular beach resort of Sousse with her husband Declan when the attack happened.
Minister for Foreign Affairs Charlie Flanagan urged people travelling to Tunisia to exercise extreme caution.
"I'm not in the business of imposing travel bans but I would say to people be extremely vigilant and extremely cautious in implementing any holiday plans in the region and keep in close contact with the tour operators and the police authorities."
Tour companies have already evacuated thousands of holidaymakers from Tunisia following the attack in which 38 people died, the majority of whom were British.
Tunisia's tourism minister called the attack a "catastrophe" and authorities vowed to toughen security, drafting in army reserves and arming tourism police at beaches and hotels.
Sousses tourism commissioner said more than 3,000 foreign tourists had left the town yesterday, including around 2,200 British and nearly 600 Belgians.
The British Foreign Office confirmed that 15 Britons had died in the attack, which was carried out by a lone gunman.
Among the British citizens killed was Joel Richards, 22, who played for James Connolly Gaelic Football Club in Birmingham and was also actively involved in Birmingham County FA Youth Council.
Sad to learn that one of those killed in Tunisia was Joel Richards, who played Gaelic Football for the James Connolly club in Birmingham.
 Daniel Mulhall (@DanMulhall) June 28, 2015
1/3 James Connollys GFC is devastated to learn of the death of one of our players, Joel Richards, during the horrific attack in Tunisia.
 Connollys GFC (@Connollys_Gaa) June 27, 2015
Mr Richards' uncle, 46-year-old Adrian Evans and his 78-year-old grandfather Patrick Evans, were also killed in the attack.
His 16-year-old brother Owen survived.
Lincolnshire Photographer Carly Lovett, 24, was killed as were Sue Davey and her partner Scott Chalkley from Staffordshire.
Another British couple, Jim and Ann McQuire from Cumbernauld, are also among the dead.
Tunisian studentSaif Rezgui opened fire on the beach of the Imperial Marhaba hotel before making his way to the pool and hotel before being shot dead by police.
Tunisian authorities said Rezgui was not on any watchlist of known potential militants.
But one source said he appeared to have been radicalised over the last six months by Islamist militant recruiters.
The self-styled Islamic State group later claimed responsibility for the attack.
It identified the gunman asAbu Yahya al-Qayrawani - a "soldier of the caliphate".
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have gone to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighbouring Libya, where some have set up training camps and vowed to return to attack their homeland.
Traveller safety 'paramount' - Sunway
A spokeswoman for Irish tour operator Sunway saidit istrying to contact as many of its customers as possible, including a large number who no longer want to travel to Tunisia.
Sunway said while it is still flying to Tunisia, traveller safety is paramount and it will be guided by the Department of Foreign Affairs.
The 177 people due to travel to Tunisia next Friday are being offered a full refund or a change of destination depending on availability.
Tanya Airey confirmed a high proportion wanted to change their destination and Friday's flight to Monastir is being kept under review.
For departures from 10 July, passengers can cancel for a fee, stay with Tunisia, or be offered a chance to switch to another destination.
There will be no full refunds for departures from 10 July.
Sunway is also facilitating those traveled to Tunisia despite the attack with 59 of the 177 booked on Fridays flight deciding not to go to Tunisia.
"We are holding welcome meetings for them at hotels," Ms Airey said, adding that many of the hotels are at another resort around half an hour away from Sousse where the attack occurred.
Sunway only deals with a proportion of Irish holidaymakers to Tunisia.
Many others are travelling with English companies who are taking direction from the British Foreign office.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:08:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ervia unions to refer bonus payments to LRC</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711169-irish-water/</Link>
        <Description>Ervia's group of unions has referred the company's decision not to pay controversial bonuses awards to Irish Water workers, to the Labour Relations Commission.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sunday 28 June 2015 14.08
Workers say they have earned their bonuses and are entitled to them
Ervia's group of unions has referred the company's decision not to pay controversial bonuses awards to Irish Water workers, to the Labour Relations Commission.
Workers at the company insist they have earned the bonuses and are now entitled to receive them.
The issue of bonus payments at the new water utility has been politically sensitive since details of the performance related awards became public last year.
Details included the fact that some staff who are deemed to "need improvement" can still benefit from a pay award.
The controversy prompted Minister for the Environment Alan Kelly to say at the time that he did not want to see a "bonus culture" emerge at Irish Water.
RT's This Week understands that unions and management at Irish Water's parent company Ervia will attend a conciliation conference at the LRC on 13 July, on the dispute.
The bonus payments were introduced as part of a new pay model at Ervia (then known as Bord Gais ireann) in 2013.
Irish Water inherited the new pay model when it was established as a utility under Ervia two years ago.
No performance related awards have been paid out at Irish Water yet but they were due to be paid earlier this year to cover work done in 2014.
However, company management informed the unions that this would not go ahead.
Ervia has repeatedly defended the pay model saying that it had brought considerable savings when compared to the previous increment-based pay model at Bord Gais.
It also rejected descriptions of the performance awards as being comparable to a traditional 'bonus' and instead they have described it as a 'pay-at-risk' element of pay.
In a statement, Ervia confirmed that the group of unions had referred the dispute to the LRC in recent weeks and that a conciliation conference had been scheduled for 13 July.
Speaking on This Week, Adrian Kane of SIPTU said Irish Water workers were angry that they were not being paid their performance related awards - and that it appeared to them that the decision was made at board level without a clear or consistent rationale being given for the non-payment of the bonus awards.
He said the performance-related awards were a key element of the pay model negotiated between the unions and the company back in 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:06:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>LÉ Eithne rescues 593 migrants off Libya coast</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711173-le-eithne-migrants/</Link>
        <Description>Almost 600 migrants have been rescued from six separate inflatable vessels by Irish naval vessel LÉ Eithne off the coast of Libya.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sunday 28 June 2015 14.06
L Eithne involved in rescue of almost 3,000 people since its deployment in May
Almost 600 migrants have been rescued from six separate inflatable vessels by Irish naval vessel L Eithne off the coast of Libya.
The rescue operation began at 4am Irish time around 50 nautical miles northwest of Tripoli when 101 people were taken from a rubber craft.
Five other rescue operations were also carried out and 593 people, including 92 women and five children, were taken on board L Eithne by 1pm.
L Eithne has rescued 2,729 people since its deployment on 16 May to assist Italian authorities in search and rescue operations in Mediterranean.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:09:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Appeal to trace man missing from Co Tipperary</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711152-john-ryan-appeal/</Link>
        <Description>An appeal has been issued to trace 30-year-old John Ryan who has been missing from Co Tipperary since 7 June.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Sunday 28 June 2015 11.09
John Ryan was last seen driving his car at the Cliffs of Moher in Liscannor on 7 June
An appeal has been issued to trace a 30-year-old man missing from Co Tipperary since 7 June.
John Ryan is missing from Faranaderry in Templemore and was last seen at the Cliffs of Moher, Liscannor driving his car.
He is described as 1.77m (5'10") tall, of slim build with short brown hair and green eyes.
Mr Ryan was wearing a light grey zip hoodie, black t-shirt, blue jeans and white runners when last seen.
Garda say they are concerned for his welfare and have asked anyone with information on his whereabouts to contact Ennistymon Garda Station on 065 7072180, the Garda Confidential Line 1800 666111 or any Garda station.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:25:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Driver killed in Belgium school tour bus crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711149-belgium-crash/</Link>
        <Description>A Northern Ireland bus company vehicle with 34 children on board overturned and crashed on a motorway in Belgium this morning, killing a driver.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The children, from Brentwood School in Essex, areaged between 11 and 13 and wereaccompanied by six teachers.
They were travelling to Cologne in Germany when the crashoccurred ona stretch of the E40 motorway near the Belgian coast.
Aspokesman from Richmond Coaches, of Ballinderry Road, Lisburn, Co Antrim, confirmed that one of its vehicles had been involved in the crash.
He said what had happened was "a tragedy" and the company was co-operating with the authorities.
He said the company's thoughts were with everyone involved.
Brentwood School said in a statement that two senior members of staff have travelled to Belgium.
It said all the pupils "walked off the coach and several pupils and teachers have been taken to local hospitals. One pupil is in intensive care receiving treatment for a head injury".
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:09:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>519 injured in Taiwan dance party fire</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711136-taiwan-fire/</Link>
        <Description>More than 500 people have been injured in a fire at a Taiwan water amusement park, with around 180 listed as being in intensive care.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Authorities have banned the use of the powder until the investigation is completed.
"The next few days will be a critical time for the injured," Taiwan Premier Mao Chi-kuo said, adding that 410 people were still in hospital, with 194 being treated for serious injuries.
In the immediate aftermath of the explosion, rescuers treated hundreds of people, most of them aged between 20 and 30, wearing wet swimsuits and lying on inflatable plastic doughnuts.
Television showed images of people running from sky-high flames.
No deaths have been reported.
One 18-year-old girl had burns to 80% of her body, according to local media reports.
Soldiers, army vehicles and medical services joined the rescue effort, while hospitals in four municipal precincts, along with Taipei, are treating victims.
The amusement park has been closed temporarily.
Taipei has sweltered in temperatures exceeding 30C in recent weeks. 
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:11:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canadian police investigate French attack photo</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711127-france-attack/</Link>
        <Description>Canadian authorities are working with French police to help find the recipient of a photograph purportedly taken by an Islamist suspected of decapitating his boss in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The message was sent to a Canadian number, but investigators said they were still working to determine the final recipient, as the number used could be a relay to another phone in another location.
Authorities are questioning Mr Salhi about the attack, during which he also drove his van into a warehouse packed with dangerous gases in an apparent bid to blow up the factory and himself.
A source close to the investigation said Mr Salhi has admitted killing his boss, 54-year-old Herve Cornara.
Canadian officials did not give details about how they are helping the French, but police powers allow them to trace calls or locate a phone by its number.
"A government's first duty is to ensure the safety of its citizens," the spokesman said.
French police found the head of Mr Cornara, manager of the transport firm that employed Mr Salhi, attached to a fence at the plant owned by USgroup Air Products, framed by black and white flags bearing Islamic slogans.
The body of Mr Cornaraalso bore signs of strangulation suggesting that he may have been killed at an unknown location prior to his decapitation.
      
Investigators searching Mr Salhi'shome in Saint-Priest, near Lyon, seized a laptop, a tablet computer and a fake pistol but found no trace of explosives or radical propaganda.
      
"We don't know whether we're dealing with a fundamentalist who just lost it or a real terrorist," asource said.
Canada has seen the radicalisation of some of its citizens, with about 100 people thought to have gone to Syria to join the Islamic State group.
Politicians recently endorsed a new anti-terror law that boosts powers of Canada's spy agency amid concerns of attacks within the country.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:12:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man critical after Dublin stabbing</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711125-dublin/</Link>
        <Description>A man is in a critical condition after a stabbing incident in Dublin city centre last night.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sunday 28 June 2015 15.12
The man is being treated at St James's Hospital
A man is in a critical condition after a stabbing incident in Dublin city centre last night.
The incident occurred at around 8pm in Fleet Street in Temple Bar.
It is understood the man was stabbed in the face.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:37:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>MERS death toll in South Korea rises to 32</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711129-south-korea-mers/</Link>
        <Description>The death toll in an outbreak of MERS in South Korea has risen to 32 as the virus's mortality rate continued to rise even as the pace of the outbreak appeared to slow.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sunday 28 June 2015 08.37
A little girl wears a face mask as the death toll in MERS outbreak continues to rise
The death toll in an outbreak of MERS in South Korea has risen to 32 as the virus's mortality rate continued to rise even as the pace of the outbreak appeared to slow.
A 55-year-old man died yesterday of Middle East Respiratory Disease, the health ministry said, putting the latest mortality rate at 17.5%.
That is up from 15% a week ago and 10% two weeks ago, though still lower than World Health Organisation figures which put the mortality rate for the disease at around 36%.
The man was diagnosed on 9 June after contracting the virus at Samsung Medical Centre in Seoul - where about 90 patients, visitors and medical staff had been infected.
The total number of infections remained unchanged at 182 and 15 patients were in critical condition, the health ministry said.
A total of 91 patients have recovered and been released from hospital, including one yesterday.
A total of 2,562 people were under quarantine either at state facilities or at home.
The outbreak started on 20 May when a 68-year-old man was diagnosed after returning from a trip to Saudi Arabia.
Since then the potentially deadly virus - for which there is no vaccine - has spread at an unusually rapid pace in the Asia's fourth-largest economy, becoming the largest outbreak outside Saudi Arabia.
South Korea's government is facing criticism for failing to stop the outbreak.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:01:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Double boxing gold for Ireland at European Games</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/sport/other-sport/2015/0627/711003-magees-lose-out-in-baku-badminton-doubles-final/</Link>
        <Description>Ireland have claimed two gold medals at the European Games with Katie Taylor winning the women's lightweight title, and Michael O'Reilly securing the men's middleweight crown in Baku.</Description>
        <MainBody>Double boxing gold for Ireland at the European Games as Katie Taylor and Michael O'Reilly prevail at Baku 2015
By Tadhg Peavoy | Updated: Saturday, 27 Jun 2015 23:01 | Comments
Katie Taylor won all four rounds of the lightweight final Sam and Chloe Magee have bowed out at the last-four stage of the badminton mixed doubles
European Games, Baku, Azerbaijan
Boxing
Ireland have claimed two gold medals at the European Games with Katie Taylor winning the women's lightweight title, and Michael O'Reilly securing the men's middleweight crown, at the Crystal Hall, Baku.
28-year-oldTaylor won gold with a unanimous decision against Frances Estelle Mossely in a performance of consummate class, prevailing 40-36, 40-36, 39-37to claim an 18th major international title.
Laois man O'Reilly saw off Azeri boxer Xaybula Musalov, also on a unanimous decision,29-28, 29-28, 29-28, in a fight that oozed athleticismand power from both men.
22-year-old O'Reilly took the first round, lostthe second, and appearedto be behind in the third, before a superb closing 90 seconds from the Irishmansecured the top prize.
Boom! Said it from Day 1 that Michael Oreilly would win gold and he's just gone and done it! Thats 2 golds 1 silver and 1 bronze ?? #teamire
 Paddy Barnes (@paddyb_ireland) June 27, 2015
Bray womanTaylor adds the European Games title to hercurrent Olympic, world, European and EU crowns, once more cementing her unrivalled status as female boxings biggest star.
Taylor and Mossely had previously met in the European Championships decider in 2014, and the EU Championships finalin 2013, with Taylor winning both fights against the Frenchwoman.
The opening roundin Baku was very close, with both fighters battling hard for control of the centre of the ring. Taylor edged it 2-1 with some powerful combinations and right hooks, while Mossely replied withleft jabs and hooks to excellent effect.
The second round was perhaps somewhat generously given to Taylor on a 3-0 call from the judges, despite Mossely looking to have had the better of the scoring punches as she advanced furiously on Taylor, with the Olympic champion fighting on the counter for those two minutes.
Mossely came out in the third needing something special and landed some powerful lefts but Taylor managed to land solid left hooks and rights to ensure another 3-0 verdict from the judges, putting the bout out of sight.
The fourth round saw Taylor hammer Mossely with combinations in the opening 30 seconds, before Mossely responded with a superb pair of lefts to the Irishwomans jaw, but with just 15 seconds to go the fight was well beyond Mosselys reach. Once more the judges went with Irishwomanin the fourth to give Taylor a clean sweep, four-round unanimous victory.
The judges scored the bout 3-0 overall,40-36, 40-36 and39-37 in Taylor's favour.
OReilly came into the ring shortly before 4pm Irish time, looking to double Ireland's gold tally within the space of two hours and was immediatelycaught withfour lefts, as well as a right hook,by hisAzeri opponentMusalov in the opening round.
But the Laois man was far busier throughout the three minutes,landing combinations with both hands. The neutral might have given it to the host nation fighter, but the judges went 3-0 for OReilly.
The second round saw OReilly back off and let the Azeri come on to him. That resulted in Musalov landing a number of lefts, and although OReilly managed to counter wellhe lost the round 3-0.
That made it a awinner-takes-all scenario in the third round, with both fighters poised at 19 points apiece. The Azeri dominated with powerful right hooks for the first 90 seconds, but the second 90 was more impressive from OReilly, as he upped the gears and pumped combinations and uppercuts to turn it around and win the round 3-0 and the fight on a unanimous decision.
There was also good news forBelfast's Sean McComb. The Irishmans semi-final conqueror, Azeri fighter Albert Selimov, won lightweight gold today against Frances Sofiane Oumiha.
Thatwinguarantees McComb a place in the World Championships in Qatar in Octoberas the semi-final loser to the eventual champion.
Badminton
Irish mixed doubles duo Sam and Chloe Magee have lost their European Games mixed doubles semi-final clash at the European Games in Baku, Azerbaijan.
The top seeds lost in straight games21-12, 23-21, to the French duo ofGaetanMittelheisser and Audrey Fontaine,in a match lasting 38 minutes.
The Magees take home a bronze as there is no third-place play-off.
It is Sam's second bronze of the Games after collecting a bronze with his brother Joshua in the men's doubles yesterday.
Swimming
Emma Reid failed to make the 50m butterfly final after finishing eighth in her semi-final in a time of 28.04, over half a second behind heat winner Caroline Pilhatsch of Poland.
Reidhad earlier made the semis with atime of 28:16 and fifth place in her heat, which made herjoint 14th-fastest qualifier.
Reid's compatriots Danielle Hill and Niamh Kilgallen didn't make the cut, however, with overall placingsof 37th and 42nd respectivelyleaving them well outside the qualification spots.
Andrew Moore, James Brown and Benjamin Doyleall swam in the 400m individual medley heats, but none of the trio made the final, with finishesof seventh, fifthand sixth respectivelyplacing them30th, 31st and 33rd overall and out of the qualification spots for the final.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:07:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tens of thousands attend Pride Parade in Dublin</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/711057-tens-of-thousands-attend-pride-parade-in-dublin/</Link>
        <Description>Tens of thousands of people attended Dublin's annual Pride Parade in the city centre, the first event of its kind since the passing of the same-sex marriage referendum.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saturday 27 June 2015 23.07
1 of 2
Tens of thousands marched across Dublin city centre
This is the first Pride Parade since the passing of the referendum on same-sex marriage
Tens of thousands of people attended Dublin's annual Pride Parade in the city centre , the first paradeof its kind since the passing of the same-sex marriage referendum.
Organisers have said it was the biggest turnout in the history of the event.
The march was led by a float with a banner that read, "the future is equal", while many participants waved rainbow flags.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:06:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Polls indicate drop in support for Labour and SF</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/711065-red-c-poll/</Link>
        <Description>Support for the Labour party and Sinn Féin has fallen in two latest opinion polls.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fianna Fil are up one point to 20%.
Sinn Fin stands at 18%, a drop of three points.
The biggest shift in support is the five point increase for Independents and smaller parties.
That group is on 27% according to this poll.
A separate nationwide Sunday Independent/Millward Brown also indicates support for Labour andSinn Fin has declined.
Excluding those who were undecided,Fine Gael stand at 29%, up four points from the last comparable poll in April, Labour are down two points to6%,Fianna Fil stand at 23% up four points,Sinn Fin stands at 21% down three points andindependents and smaller parties stand at 21%, down two points.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:03:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Katie Taylor: I want to be the greatest</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/sport/boxing/2015/0627/711056-katie-taylor-i-want-to-be-the-greatest/</Link>
        <Description>Ireland's Olympic champion Katie Taylor said she wanted to go down as the greatest female boxer of all time after she added a European Games gold medal to her glittering list of titles on Saturday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Katie Taylor: I want to be the greatest
Updated: Saturday, 27 Jun 2015 18:03 | Comments
Comments
Katie Taylor stands to attention for Amhrn na bhFiann as Olympic Council of Ireland, and European Games, president Pat Hickey (second left) looks on
Ireland's Olympic champion Katie Taylor said she wanted to go down as the greatest female boxer of all time after she added a European Games gold medal to her glittering list of titles on Saturday.
      
The 28-year-old lightweight, Olympic, five-times world and six-times European champion, registered a unanimous points victory over Frenchwoman Estelle Mossely to claim her country's first gold medal in Baku, and her 18th major international title.
      
"I want to go down in the history books as one of the greatest female boxers of all time and I think I'm on the right path," Taylor, one of the highest-profile athletes at the continental games, told reporters at the Crystal Hall.
      
"It's definitely [mission accomplished]. I am European Games champion now as well as Olympic champion, European champion and world champion.
      
"I've got every single major title out there so it's great to add this one to the list," she added.
      
"When you're so consistent people have to stand up and take notice. I don't think people recognise or praise consistency enough."
"I want to go down in the history books as one of the greatest female boxers of all time and I think I'm on the right path" - Katie Taylor
Saturday's victory was not without its concerns, however, and though Taylor looked strong throughout, the 22-year-old Mossely landed a number of damaging punches.
      
Taylor was also tested in a tense semi-final victory against Azerbaijan's Yana Alekseevna in a weight division that is increasingly competitive.
      
Victory in the inaugural multi-sport continental games was the 18th major title of her illustrious career but Taylor said her desire to remain the dominant fighter in the division had not dwindled.
      
"I'm as hungry now as I ever was, maybe even more hungry," Taylor, whose medal was presented by compatriot and president of the European Olympic Committees (EOC) Patrick Hickey, added.
      
"I just want to continue to improve and add to that list (of titles). There's a lot of people on the way up who want to take my place so it's up to me to continue to improve.
      
"It's great just to continue to produce great performances and collect these gold medals all the time. Europe is the strongest continent for boxing. I think it was a great showcase for women's boxing."
Taylor's compatriot Michael O'Reilly beat Azerbaijan's Xaybula Musalov on Saturday to win the men's middleweight title and secure Ireland's second gold and sixth medal overall. 
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:20:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New York prison escapee shot dead by police</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/710993-prisoners-new-york/</Link>
        <Description>One of two prisoners who broke out of a maximum security prison in New York three weeks ago has been shot dead by police.</Description>
        <MainBody>"You never want to see anyone lose their life, but I would remind people that Mr Matt was an escaped murderer from a state prison," New York Governor Andrew Cuomo said at a news conference.
"Mr Matt killed two people that we know about."
Authorities said they have no evidence to confirm the whereabouts of the second escapee but have no reason to believe he was not with Matt recently and still in the area.
Malone is about 43km northwest of the Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, where the convicts staged their elaborate escape and were discovered missing on 6 June.
The manhunt has involved as many as 1,100 law enforcement officers.
Police started focusing the search in the Malone area, just south of the Canadian border, when two burglaries were reported this week at backwoods cabins, and items believed to have been dropped by Matt were found, said Joseph D'Amico, superintendent of the New York State Police.
Authorities were alerted to a third break-in near Malone yesterday.
When officers arrived at that cabin, they confronted Matt in the woods outside, Supt D'Amico said, and warned him to drop the firearm he was holding.
When Matt failed to comply, the Border Patrol agents shot and killed him, even though the escapee fired no shots of his own, the superintendent said. He declined to elaborate further.
In making their escape three weeks ago, Matt and Sweat cut through the walls of their adjoining cells and sneaked along a catwalk to a steam pipe, then crawled through it and climbed out of a manhole outside the prison walls.
Two prison workers have been charged with aiding them.
Gene Palmer, 57, a corrections officer for 27 years, was suspended without pay from his job, the New York State Department of Corrections and Community Supervision said.
He is accused of bringing hacksaw blades and a screwdriver bit to the inmates, hidden in frozen hamburger meat supplied by Joyce Mitchell, 51, a training supervisor in the prison tailor shop.
She also has been charged in connection with the escape.
Palmer also let the men slip behind their cell walls onto a prison catwalk to hide contraband and alter electrical wiring so they could cook in their cells, according to court documents.
Matt was convicted in the 1997 torture, murder and dismemberment of his boss in Tonawanda, New York, and was sentenced to 25 years to life.
Sweat was serving a life sentence after his conviction in the shooting death of a Broome County Sheriff's deputy on 4 July, 2002.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:21:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Numerous arrests follow Kuwait mosque bombing</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/711038-kuwait-mosque-bomb/</Link>
        <Description>Kuwait's interior ministry has detained amongst others the owner of a vehicle which a suicide bomber used to get to a Shia Muslim mosque where he blew himself up, killing 27 and wounding 200 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saturday 27 June 2015 20.21
27 people were killed during Friday prayers at Kuwait City's Grand Mosque
Kuwait's interior ministry has detained amongst others the owner of a vehicle which a suicide bomber used to get to a Shia Muslim mosque where he blew himself up, killing 27 and wounding 200 people.
The self-styled Islamic State group claimed responsibility for the country's worst militant attack yesterday, one of threeon three continentsapparently linked to group.
In Tunisia, a gunman killed 38 people including Western tourists on a beach, and in France a decapitated body was found after an attacker rammed his car into a gas container, triggering an explosion.
The Kuwati interior ministry said it was now looking for the driver who vanished shortly after yesterdays blast.
A security source said "numerous arrests" had been made in connection with the bombing, which government officials said was intended to stir enmity between Kuwait's Sunni majority and Shia minority.
Two Iranian nationals were among those killed, a foreign ministry spokeswoman said.
A mass funeral for most of those killed will be held at Kuwait City's Grand Mosque later today and a day of national mourning has been declared.
Shia are between 15% and 30% of the population of Kuwait, a mostly Sunni country where members of both communities live side by side with little apparent friction.
"We will cut the evil hand that interferes with our homeland's security," Interior Minister Sheikh Mohammed al Khaled al Sabah was quoted as saying by KUNA.
Kuwait has stepped up security to the highest level at state-run oil conglomerate Kuwait Petroleum Corp (KPC) and its affiliates, KUNA also reported.
Islamic State named the bomber as Abu Suleiman al-Muwahed and said on social media that he had targeted a "temple of the apostates" - a term the group uses to refer to Shia, whom it regards as heretics.
Source: Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:27:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teenager killed in Dublin road collision</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/710996-rta-dublin/</Link>
        <Description>A teenage boy has died after he was struck by a car in Dublin last night.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saturday 27 June 2015 20.27
Boy was taken to the Mater Hospital where he was later pronounced dead
A teenage boy has died after he was struck by a car in Dublin last night.
The 16-year-old was seriously injured when he was hit by the car close to the junction of the Tolka Valley Road and St Helenas Road in Finglas at around 11.30pm.
He was taken to the Mater Hospital where he died in the early hours of this morning.
The driver and a passenger in the car were both uninjured.
The road had been closed for a technical examination but has since reopened.
Garda have appealed for any witnesses to contact Finglas Garda Station on 01 - 6667500, the Garda Confidential Line 1800 666111 or any Garda Station.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:18:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hondurans call for president to stand down</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/711032-honduras/</Link>
        <Description>Thousands of Hondurans have taken to the streets to demand the resignation of President Juan Orlando Hernandez over an ongoing corruption scandal.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saturday 27 June 2015 23.18
Protesters are demanding the resignation of President Hernandez
Thousands of Hondurans have taken to the streets to demand the resignation of President Juan Orlando Hernandez over an ongoing corruption scandal.
The crowd, estimated at around 50,000 people, sounded horns and carried candle-lit torches, demanding the creation of an anti-corruption commission and rejecting dialogue with the president.
Many of the protesters carried banners and held anti-government signs with slogans such as "Honduras is ours" and "This is no president, he's a criminal."
The protesters crowded onto the Tegucigalpas Suyapa Boulevard in a march to the presidential palace, which was guarded by police and soldiers.
The demonstration marked the fifth Friday in which protesters have hit the streets calling for Mr Hernandez to go.
The opposition charge that the president received about $90 million out of more than $300 million they say was skimmed from Honduras's public health system for his 2013 election campaign.
Mr Hernandez has denied wrongdoing and drastically played down the amount.
On Tuesday the president called for a dialogue on forming an organization to combat corruption and impunity, but the protesters have rejected the proposal.
Mr Hernandez was not in the country for the march, but was instead in Guatemala for a meeting of Central American leaders.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:18:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eurozone readies for Greek default</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/710991-greece-economy/</Link>
        <Description>Greece's European partners shut the door on extending a credit lifeline to Athens, leaving it facing a default that could push it out of the euro after the leftist government rejected tough lender demands and put their bailout deal to a referendum.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
In a formal statement, they also implicitly urged Greece to impose capital controls to stabilize its banking system.
The rejection of an extension piled huge pressure on Greek banks, which depend on central bank support to remain afloat, with long lines forming in front of cash machines as people rushed to pull their money out while the banks were still operating normally.
After its surprise decision to call a referendum on the bailout, Athens asked for an extension of Greece's bailout programme beyond Tuesday, the day it must pay 1.6 billion to the International Monetary Fund or default.
But the other 18 members of the euro zone unanimously rejected the request, freezing Greece out of further discussions with the European Central Bank and the IMF on how to deal with the fallout from a historic breach in the EU's 16-year-old currency.
The swift rejection was a startling demonstration of the degree to which Mr Tsipras had alienated the rest of the currency bloc with a final-hour announcement that upended five months of intense talks.
The Eurogroup of finance ministers shut Greece's Yanis Varoufakis from a meeting in Brussels and issued a statement without him, accusing Athens of breaking off negotiations unilaterally.
"The current financial assistance arrangement with Greece will expire on 30 June, 2015, as well as all agreements related to the current Greek programme," it said, making clear its refusal of a grace period to hold the vote.
Mr Varoufakis said the refusal to provide an extension "will certainly damage the credibility of the Eurogroup as a democratic union of partner member states".
"I'm very much afraid that that damage will be permanent."
The Greek parliament met to approve the referendum, with pro-European opposition parties uniting in condemning the decision and fuelling speculation that Mr Tsipras' left wing government may have to resign if voters back the bailout in the 5 July referendum.
Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos was expected to meet former conservative Prime Minister Antonis Samaras on Sunday.
The offer from creditors requires Greece to cut pensions and raise taxes in ways that Mr Tsipras has long argued would deepen one of the worst economic crises of modern times in a country where a quarter of the workforce is already unemployed.
Caught between fears of economic collapse and defiance of the demands from international creditors, many Greeks expressed shock, although opinion polls published in Sunday newspapers pointed to a majority in favour of accepting the bailout terms.
However voters in other euro zone states -- including the bloc's economic powerhouse Germany, other southern states which have suffered austerity in return for EU cash and poor eastern countries with living standards much lower than Greece  have lost patience.
Solution to Greek debt still possible - Michael Noonan
Finance Minister Michael Noonan has indicated it may still be possible to reach a deal between Greece and its creditors.
Minister Noonan said there is still time to cut a deal.
He said he did not have any fears over the euro as,he said, the currency was in a very strong position.
He said he has sympathy for the Greek people and said he would like to see progress made, "even at this late stage."
When asked if he thought Greece should hold a referendum as planned on the bailout deal, Minister Noonan said that was a matter for the Greeks to decide.
'Greece should remain in the euro despite difficulties' -Michel Sapin
Many questions remained over the referendum, which is being called over the terms of a bailout offer that may no longer be on the table.
But with fears growing that the foundations of the eurozone could be fatally weakened if Greece were forced out, French Finance Minister Michel Sapin insisted that Paris, at least, was still prepared to talk.
"The 18 countries, apart from Greece, all said clearly that Greece was in the euro and should remain in the euro whatever the difficulties of the moment," he said.
Although European officials have repeatedly insisted that financial firewalls built during the eurozone debt crisis of the past six years would limit the impact of any "Grexit", the longer-term effects are completely unknown.
Jeroen Dijsselbloem, the Dutch finance minister and chair of the Eurogroup, said Greek lawmakers should think about whether the referendum was wise before agreeing to hold it, essentially appealing directly to the Greek parliament to defy Mr Tsipras when it votes on approving the measure later today.
Underlining the mutual incomprehension that has marked months of often angry exchanges between the Syriza government and its European partners, Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis was still holding out hopes of a deal.
"In these crucial moments, the Greek government is fighting for there to be a last-minute deal by Tuesday," he said after the euro zone had rejected further talks and said it would cutoff financial support from 30 June.
He added the government would be prepared to recommend that voters backed the deal if lenders agreed to improve the terms.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:11:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Irish couple may have died in Tunisia attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/710988-tunisia-attack/</Link>
        <Description>Gardaí in Westmeath are liaising with the family of a couple in their 50s from the Athlone area who are believed to have died in a terrorist attack on a beach in Tunisia yesterday.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
One Irish person has been confirmed so far among the 38victims killed yesterday afternoon when a gunman opened fire at a beach resort inSousse.
Lorna Carty , a mother of two,from Robinstown in Co Meath isbelieved to have been on the beach when the attack began.
Shewas in the resort with her husband Declan, who was uninjured, but said to be "absolutely distraught".
Minister for ForeignAffairs CharlieFlanagan has said it will takea period of time to complete a full and formal identification of the victims of the attack.
He said the Irish Ambassador to Spainand Consulareworking closely with the authorities in Tunisia.
Meanwhile, the number of Britons confirmed to have died in the attack has risen to 15.
One Belgian and one German national have also been confirmed dead.
A further 39 people are said to have been wounded in the attack, which has been claimed by the so-called Islamic State group.
Tunisian Prime Minister Habib Essidsaid reserve troops would be called up to reinforce security at "sensitive sites... and places that could be targets of terrorist attacks" after the massacre, the second against tourists in Tunisia this year.
The "exceptional plan to better secure tourist and archaeological sites" will include "deploying armed tourist security officers all along the coast and inside hotels from 1 July," he added.
He also announced that a national anti-terrorism congress would be held in September and that financial rewards would be given to anyone who comes forward with information leading to the capture of any terrorists.
The Department of Foreign Affairs has advised Irish people planning on travelling to Tunisia or who may already be in the country to follow the advice of the Tunisian authorities and maintain contact with tour organisers.
Anyone who may have concerns about family or friends in Tunisia should contact 01-4082000.
Irish embassy staff, including Irish Ambassador to Spain David Cooney, who is also accredited with Tunisia,arrived in Sousse late Fridaynight to provide consular assistance to citizens caught up in the attack.
In a statement, Meath GAA has confirmed that allmatches and training involving Dunderry and Kilmessan have been cancelled until further notice following the killing of Ms Carty in Tunisia.
Her son Simon is part of the Meath senior panel and was a member of the county's U-21 team, while Ms Carty was very involved in the GAA and with her local club Dunderry.
The Leinster SFC semi-final match between Meath and Westmeath in Croke Park tomorrow will go ahead as scheduled.
Glanbia chairman Henry Corbally expressed sympathy to the Carty family.
"This is a terrible tragedy to afflict a highly respected and popular farming family.
"On behalf of all members of Glanbia, I wish to express my deepest sympathy to Lornas husband Declan and their children Simon and Hazel."
The gunman wasa 23-year-old student who disguised himself as a tourist and began firing at holidaymakers on a beach using a Kalashnikov he had hidden in a beach umbrella.
The student, identified as Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani, was reportedly laughing as he carried out the massacre and deliberately selected western tourists, before being shot dead by police.
'Four hours of hell'
Meanwhile, Irish holidaymakers who returned on Friday nightfrom Tunisia described scenes of chaos during the attack at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel.
Many described a large explosion as well as gunfire andpraised hotel staff for helping them.
Marian King from Lucan, who was staying in the hotel, said the last four hours of their holiday had turned into hell.
Speaking at Dublin airport after the Aer Lingus flight from Monastir arrived home she said she and her family had managed to get into a hotel bedroom when the shooting started.
"People were running down the corridors screaming to be let into bedrooms". She described hearing more shooting and hiding in the bathroom for about two hours until after it had it subsided.
Anthony and Betty Tunstead from Glasnevin Avenue in Dublin were part of a group of four who cut their holiday short to come home last night.
MsTunstead described screaming and chaos as the shooting started.
"We went into one room and kept there for a while. I came back out and here's a boyo in the lobby with a machine gun.
"We didnt make eye contact because he was looking to see where he was jumping off the parapet. He didn't see me."
Ms Tunstead said had it been a different day they might not have escaped alive. She said they normally met up with a couple from Meath and would have been sitting with them had they not been about to move hotel.
The group she was with expressed concern for another Irish couple they had been with at the hotel who they believed had been caught up in the shooting, and who they had not heard from.
Cathy Piper from Wicklow was having a beer on the beach when the attack began around noon and says she saw an attacker.
"I saw him from a distance - a guy dressed in black walking along the beach.
She followed a staff member in a side door to safety. "The hotel staff were great. They ran to the creche to get the kids out."
Patricia Sheehan from Dungarvan who was in a hotel 2km from the scene said she contacted the Irish authorities in Dublin, and they kept in contact with her through the day.
"We didnt have any male members of our family with us so we felt a little bit unsafe. I was trying to put people in the complex at ease and keep them up to date," she said.
Denis Purcell from Glasnevin described having to comfort an English man whose fiance was killed. "We were around him talking to him.
"He was devastated trying to find out was she brought to a hospital. It was killing him to think she was still lying inside the hotel."
Mr Purcell said the Tunisian prime minister visited the hotel.
"There was more security for the prime minister than came to the hotel after the explosions," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
