<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="rte">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:33:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>27 killed in attack on tourist hotels in Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710815-tunisia-attack/</Link>
        <Description>At least 27 people have died in an attack on two tourist hotel near the Tunisian coastal town of Sousse, about 150km south of the capital, Tunis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 13.33
Local police moved tourists and locals to a safe area (File picture)
At least 27peoplehave died in an attack on twotourist hotels near the Tunisian coastal town of Sousse, about 150kmsouth of the capital, Tunis.
An interior ministry official has said that the foreigners are among the dead.
Gunshots were fired in the vicinity of the Marhaba Sousse Hotel, which is popular with Irish holidaymakers.
It isunderstood that one gunman entered the hotel at around noon and opened fire.
A security source at the scene said the body of a gunmanarmed with a Kalashnikov assault rifle lay where police had shot him dead.
Ministry spokesman Mohamed Ali Aroui told Mosaique radio that two hotels were attacked.
Local police moved tourists and locals to a safe area.
The Department of Foreign Affairs is liaising with Irish diplomatic staff in the region.
The Department is aware of an incident in Sousse, Tunisia. If you have any concerns for family members there, please call 01-4082000
Dublin woman caught up in attack
A Dublin woman in the Tunisian resort of Sousse described what she saw when the attack happened.
Speaking to RT's News At One, Elizabeth O'Brien said: "I thought it was fireworks and then I thought 'Oh my God' it sounds like gunfire.
"I ran to the sea to my children and grabbed our things and, as I was running towards the hotel, the waiters and the security on the beach started shouting 'Run, run, run'.
"We ran to our room, which is like a little bungalow, so we are actually trapped in our room, because we have no contact the phone here doesn't work to call reception.
"The consul from Madrid who is over Tunisia as well said it is a terrorist attack in the hotel next door.
"She told me to stay put, my travel agent said to go to the reception to speak to the rep, but I'm afraid, so I'm stuck here in the room with my two sons not knowing what's going on.
"The agent said the attack was isolated to the hotel next door. The consul told me it was a terrorist attack.
"I just ran as soon as I heard the noise, I don't know what's happening now I'm sort of cut off from the world."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:38:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hollande says factory attack a 'terrorist' act</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710748-france-attack/</Link>
        <Description>A head covered in Arabic writing was found at a US gas company in southeast France this morning, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 12.38
1 of 3
French police and firefighters secure the entrance of the factory
Several explosive devices were at the factory (Pic: Dauphine Libere)
A decapitated body was found near the factory (Pic: Dauphine Libere)
A head covered in Arabic writing was found at a US gas company in southeast France this morning, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.
Speaking from a European Union summit in Brussels, French President Francois Hollande described it at a terrorist attack and said all measures would be taken to stop any future attacks on a country still reeling from Islamist assaults in January.
One suspect had been arrested and was already known to French intelligence sources, Mr Hollande said.
"Two individuals deliberately rammed a car into the gas containers to trigger an explosion," a police source said.
Suspected accomplices have also been detained.     
It was not known whether the victim, so far the only known fatality in the incident that also injured two people, was decapitated before or after the car smashed into the building, or whether the victim had been on site at the time of the attack, or killed elsewhere.
"The attack was of a terrorist nature since a body was discovered, decapitated and with inscriptions," Mr Hollande told the news conference.
Police sources earlier said the decapitated body was found at the site, along with a flag bearing Islamist inscriptions.
Local newspaper Le Dauphine said the head covered in Arabic writing was found on a fence.
The French public prosecutor said its anti-terrorist section had been deployed to investigate.
France, which has deployed aircraft to the international coalition fighting Islamic State insurgents in Iraq, has long been named on Islamist sites as a primary target for attacks.
In April, Prime Minister Manuel Valls said no fewer than five attacks had been thwarted in the country since the Charlie Hebdo killings in January.
Then, Islamist gunmen killed 17 people in the offices of the Charlie Hebdo satirical weekly and a Jewish food store.
Noting that hundreds of French nationals are in Syria where they risked being radicalised by Islamist fighters, Mr Valls said "never has the threat been so high".
The site belonged to Air Products, a US industrial gases and chemicals company, according to a spokeswoman for Air Liquide, a French company in the same sector.
It was immediately sealed off by police and emergency services.
The chairman and CEO of Air Products is Seifi Ghasemi, who in 2011 testimony to a US Senate committee described himself as Iranian-born.
Mainly Shia Iran is a sworn enemy of Sunni-dominated Islamic State. 
No group claimed responsibility for the attack and the motive was unknown.
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve was at the site in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, around 30km southeast of the city of Lyon.
French media said the government had ordered security to be stepped up around sensitive sites in the surrounding Rhone-Alpes region.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:30:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Court backs refusal to hold Finucane inquiry</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710711-pat-finucane/</Link>
        <Description>The High Court in Belfast has backed British Prime Minister David Cameron's refusal to hold a public inquiry into the 1989 murder of human rights lawyer Pat Finucane.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Friday 26 June 2015 11.30
Pat Finucane was shot dead in front of his wife and their three children in their Belfast home in 1989
The High Court in Belfast has backed British Prime Minister David Cameron's refusal to hold a public inquiry into the 1989 murder of human rights lawyer Pat Finucane.
Mr Finucanes death remains a lightning rod for anger over state collusion with pro-British paramilitaries.
The lawyer, who represented leading republicans in court, was shot dead in front of his family at his north Belfast by loyalists believed to have been acting in collusion with British security forces.
This morning, a judicial review rejected an appeal by Mr Finucane's family for a public inquiry into the shooting, saying Mr Cameron's 2011 decision not to hold one was lawful.
Mr Cameron instead commissioned an independent investigation, whose report was published in 2012.
The 2012 report severely criticised members of the British intelligence services and army and the Northern Irish police for colluding in the killing and covering it up.
The solicitor's family has long campaigned for a full independent public inquiry, but Mr Cameron insisted such an exercise would not shed any more light on the events.
He instead commissioned a review of the case papers by QC Desmond de Silva.
Mr de Silva's report detailed shocking levels of state involvement.
It included spreading malicious propaganda that Mr Finucane was sympathetic to the IRA; one or possibly more police officers proposing him as a target to loyalists; and the mishandling of state agents inside the UDA who were involved in the murder.
While Mr de Silva found no evidence of an overarching conspiracy by the authorities to target the 38-year-old lawyer, he said the actions of a number of state employees had "furthered and facilitated" the UDA shooting while there had also been efforts to thwart the subsequent criminal investigation.
As he accepted the report's findings in the House of Commons in December 2012, Mr Cameron reiterated an apology to the Finucane family and also pledged that the government would examine the review in detail to identify potential lessons.
Mr Finucane was shot dead in front of his wife and their three children inside their north Belfast home in February 1989.
The judicial review focused on a commitment made by the UK government at Weston Park in 2001 during peace process negotiations with the Government.
The Weston Park talks resulted in Canadian judge Peter Cory being asked to examine the grounds for public inquiry in a number of controversial Troubles deaths.
The British government said such inquiries would be implemented if the judge recommended that course of action.
Judge Cory subsequently did recommend public inquiries for a number of killings, including Mr Finucane's.
But while the government ordered inquiries into the other deaths, it did not give the green light for one in the Finucane case.
Speaking following the judgment,Minister for Foreign AffairsCharlie Flanagan said:"I note this morning's judgment in the judicial review and will be studying it closely. The Irish Government's position remains unchanged. 
"We continue to believe that an independent public inquiry into the murder of Pat Finucane, in line with the political commitments made by the British and Irish governments at Weston Park in 2001, should be honoured.
"This is a matter which the Government has consistently raised with the British Government. I raised it most recently with Secretary of State for Northern Ireland Theresa Villiers on 19 May, and the Taoiseach discussed the case with Prime Minister Cameron when they met in London last week.
"My thoughts at this time are with Geraldine Finucane and all the Finucane family, who have campaigned so tirelessly for more than a quarter of a century in pursuit of the full truth in the case of Pat Finucane, including the role of collusion in his murder."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:45:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece offered billions in funding to agree deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/business/2015/0626/710721-greece-euro-zone/</Link>
        <Description>The leaders of Germany and France have offered to release billions in frozen aid, in a last-minute push to talk Greece into contentious pension reforms in exchange for vital funding for Athens' until November.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The creditors laid out terms in a document that went to Greece yesterday and was seen by Reuters news agency today.
It said Greece could have 15.5bn in EU and IMF funding in four installments to see it through to the end of November, including 1.8bn by Tuesday as soon as the Athens parliament approved the plan.
The total is slightly more than Greece needs to service its debts over the next six months but contains no new money.
A French source said Ms Merkel and Mr Hollande discussed outstanding differences on reforms Greece needs to accept - centred on pension reform, labour law and increasing VAT - as well as an extension to Athens' bailout programme and financing.
The German and French leaders both said Saturday's emergency meeting of euro zone finance ministers would be decisive to seal a deal before Greece has to make a key IMF repayment for which the government has said it lacks the money.
"Saturday's meeting is crucial because we are on the eve of a date, June 30, when the Greek authorities have to meet a payment obligation," Mr Hollande told a news conference.
"It's also crucial because there are parliaments that have to meet if there's a deal," he added.
The Eurogroup ministers will meet at 4pm Irish time on Saturday and Greece will be asked whether it accepts a revised offer from the European Commission, the European Central Bank and the International Monetary Fund, a euro zone official said.
Greece's commitment to euro zone 'absolute' - Varoufakis
Earlier,Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis saidGreece has a moral responsibility to reach agreement not only for his country but for the euro zone also.
Mr Varoufakis was speaking toRT's Morning Irelandas talks between the Greek government and international creditors remain deadlocked.
He said it was not a game of guessing chances and that Greece was obliged to find a viable solution for the benefit of the whole of the euro zone.
He said it is up to the institutions to now "come to the party".
Mr Varoufakissaid Greece are "debtors,representatives of the social economy in recession for the last seven years."
He said the Irish people knew very well about international creditors.
He said it was important for people to understand that the negotiations were being conducted between the member states and the international creditors - not among the member states themselves.
He said the Government had been kept in the dark about what Greece had offered and that if TaoiseachEnda Kennyand Minister for Finance Michael Noonanknew the details of the offer,theywould change theirperspective.
"If your finance minister and I were to sit down and I were to explain my proposals....Michael Noonan would agree that they are very reasonable" he said.
Mr Varoufakis described as "absolute" Greece's commitment to remain in the euro zone, adding that Greece had bent over backwards to accommodate what he described as the "strange demands of creditors".
He also said that he will not accept any debt solution he considers to beunviable.
He said Greece was asking to take debt from the pocket of the ECB and put it in the pocket of ESM in order to "even out a very spiky debt repayment schedule, so as to make it easier for us to make the repayments for the benefit of the creditors."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:38:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supermac's in trademark battle with McDonald's</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/business/2015/0626/710800-supermacs-mcdonalds-registration-battle/</Link>
        <Description>Fast food chain Supermac's has stepped up its battle with McDonald's to have its company name registered across Europe with Managing Director Pat McDonagh personally handing in a submission in Spain today.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Friday 26 June 2015 12.38
McDonald's lodged a 41-page objection over Supermac's plans to the office that oversees trademarks and designs in the EU
Fast food chain Supermac's has stepped up its battle with McDonald's to have its company name registered across Europe with Managing Director Pat McDonagh personally handing in a submission in Spain today.
Mr McDonagh travelled to Alicante to deliver a submission to the Office for Harmonisation in the Internal Market (OHIM), following moves by McDonald's to stop the Supermac's trademark being registered throughout Europe.
Supermac's operates over 100 outlets in Ireland and Mr McDonagh, a former schoolteacher who opened the first premises in Ballinasloe in Co Galway in 1978, said the company has received requests to open in 15 cities across Europe.
However, expansion plans have met with opposition from McDonald's, with the American fast-food giant lodging a 41-page objection to the OHIM, which oversees trademarks and designs.
Mr McDonagh has now responded to that objection by delivering Supermac's submission today.
"I am optimistic that common sense will prevail. Supermac's has traded successfully alongside McDonald's in Ireland and Northern Ireland for over 30 years and I don't believe this could be any different in other countries," said Mr McDonagh, who is in the process of opening eight new outlets in Ireland this year.
He based the name of the new business in 1978 on his nickname from his schholdays in Carmelite College in Moate, when he became known as 'Supermac' in deference to the Newcastle United and England footballer Malcolm MacDonald.
"I am confident that the true facts of Supermac's case have been presented clearly to the Office for Harmonisation in the Internal Market today. Supermac's has long been regarded as a steadily growing business throughout its 37 years in existence.
"We are responding to demands coming from fifteen cities internationally for the opening of Supermac's restaurants," he added.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:34:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>166 IBRC loan accounts paid rate of less than 1%</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/business/2015/0626/710750-ibrc-interest-rates/</Link>
        <Description>New data shows that a total of 166 Irish Bank Resolution Corporation commercial loans accounts were charged an interest rate of less than 1%.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 11.34
Accounts charged less than 1% interest were mainly related to distressed loans
New data shows that a total of 166 Irish Bank Resolution Corporation commercial loans accounts were charged an interest rate of less than 1%.
In a written reply to Fianna Fil finance spokesman Michael McGrath, the Finance Minister said IBRC's Special Liquidators confirmed that accounts with a rate of less than 1% were mainly related to distressed loans.
This was where the loan was restructured or where the borrower was in the liquidation or administration and the prospect of any future recovery was "remote".
Today's data from the Finance Minister also shows that 920 accounts at the bank were charged a rate of between 1-1.99% on their loans. These loans amounted to 399m.
The largest number of loans at the former Anglo Irish Bank - 2,729 - were charged interest rates of between 2-2.99% on loans worth a total of 7.232 billion.
920 saw rates of between 1-1.99% on loans worth 8.658 billion, while a further 1,568 were charged at rates between 3-3.99% on loans totalling 4.894 billion.
392 IBRC customers paid interest rates of 4-4.99%, while 271 paid rates of 5-5.99%.
Another 132 customers paid rates of between 6 and 6.99%, 67 paid interest rates of 7-7.99% while a total of 66 paid interest rates of over 8% on their loans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:59:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Couples win right to challenge NI gay marriage ban</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710732-gay-marriage-northern-ireland/</Link>
        <Description>Two couples have cleared the first legal hurdle in their bid to challenge a ban on gay marriage in Northern Ireland.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 12.59
Thousands attended a march for marriage equality in Belfast earlier this month (Pic: Amnesty International)
Two same-sex couples seeking to overturn a ban on gay marriage in Northern Ireland have welcomed a judicial decision to let their case proceed.
A judge in Belfast High Court granted them leave to judicially review the refusal to legalise same sex marriage in the region.
Grainne Close and Shannon Sickles and Chris and Henry Flanagan-Kane are taking the joint action.
They were, respectively, the first and second couples in the UK to enter into a civil partnership after Northern Ireland became the first part of the UK to make that option available to same-sex couples in December 2005.
The Northern Ireland Assembly has rejected a proposal calling for the introduction of gay marriage on four occasions since, with unionists opposed to the move using a contentious voting mechanism to effectively veto it.
Neither couple was in court today when Mr Justice Treacy granted leave for a judicial review but their solicitor, Mark O'Connor, spoke on their behalf afterwards.
"On behalf of our clients we are delighted we have been able to get over the first hurdle in relation to the judicial process in that the judge today has granted leave for us to bring this judicial review," he said.
"We are thankful that the judge has made that decision today. We believe that religious policy and religious views should not be affecting public policy before the courts today and thankfully the judge today appears to have accepted there is an arguable case to answer for the (Stormont) departments and hopefully we will have success in the future in relation to this matter," Mr OConnor added.
Following the "Yes" vote in May's referendum on same-sex marriage in the Republic, Northern Ireland is now set to be the only part of the UK or Ireland where civil marriage is denied to gay couples.
Earlier this month, about 20,000 campaigners marched in Belfast city centre demanding a change in the law.
The case has been listed for a mention hearing in September.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:22:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Motion to protect Poolbeg chimneys deferred</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710803-poolbeg-chimneys-dublin/</Link>
        <Description>Efforts to have Dublin's Poolbeg chimneys listed as a protected structure are to be deferred to allow the ESB to carry out preservation work and further tests.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 12.22
Councillors have been told that the ESB would need planning permission to have the chimneys demolished
Efforts to have Dublin's Poolbeg chimneys listed as a protected structure are to be deferred to allow the ESB to carry out preservation work and further tests.
Labour councillor Dermot Lacey, who led the attempt to have the chimneys listed, saidhe will defer a motion that was due to be voted on by Dublin City councillors.
The ESB recently announced a 250,000 ten-year maintenance programme, which included repainting and steel capping to stop further deterioration.
ESB's Communications Manager Bernadine Maloney saidfurther tests will have to be carried out to assess the structural integrity of the chimneys.
A recent report to councillors from the Heritage Council stated that the chimneys are an "iconic" and "integral" part of the Dublin skyline with many references in popular culture.
There has not been any official recommendation on whether they should be added to the Record of Protected Structures.
The report also stated that brickwork had deteriorated because of moisture coming into the chimneys and that some of the outer concrete had become dislodged.
Confirming that a motion to have the chimneys listed will be deferred, Cllr Lacey said he believes the ESB is committed to saving them.
Councillors have been told that the ESB would have to apply for planning permission to have them demolished.
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:32:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU migrant deal reached, Kenny returns to summit</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710710-migrants/</Link>
        <Description>Taoiseach Enda Kenny has returned to the EU leaders summit today after a fractious overnight session which focused on how to respond to the migrant crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 12.32
Last night a voluntary scheme of 60,000 migrants per country was reached
TaoiseachEnda Kennyhas returned to the EU leaders summit today after a fractious overnight session which focused on how to respond to the migrant crisis. 
The scale of the problem has been charted by the UN which says 63,000 migrants arrived in Greece by sea in 2015 so far, with a further62,000 arriving in Italy.
The European Commission had been pushing for a mandatory quota for each member state, but it ended-up being a voluntary plan due to strong opposition from Poland and other Baltic countries.
Last night during a seven hour debate it was agreedmigrants fleeing war and poverty in North Africa and the Middle East would be shared out, based on a voluntary scheme of 60,000.
An exclusion granted for Hungary, which earlier described the plan as absurd, as well as for Bulgaria, one of the EU's poorest countries. 
There are 40,000 Syrian and Eritrean asylum seekers now in Italy and Greece and another20,000 people outside the EU.      
"It was a very intensive debate," German Chancellor Angela Merkel told reporters after the meeting ended.
Shedescribedthe migrant crisis "as the biggest challenge I have seen in European affairs in my time as chancellor".
Expressing his frustration, Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker described the plan as one of "modest ambition" and said at one point in the meeting he had told EU leaders "I don't give a damn" about objections to the plan's underlying methodology.
"We have to find out if the system works. It doesn't matter if it is voluntary or mandatory, it is whether it can help 60,000 refugees," Mr Juncker told a news conference in the early hours of this morning. 
However, the EU's chief executive had been hoping to set a precedent for Europe-wide action that limited national opt-outs. 
During the summit dinner, Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi rebuked his fellow leaders for their reluctance to support a plan that was meant as an emergency response to the tragedy of 2,000 migrant deaths in the Mediterranean year but has been overshadowed by divisions, particularly in eastern Europe.
"If we think Europe is only about budgets, it is not the Europe we thought of in 1957 in Rome," Mr Renzi said, referring to the European Union's founding treaty.
The summit became so tense that a speech by British Prime Minister David Cameron served as an interlude to cool tempers, with the much awaited address to pitch for a new deal for Britain in the European Union reduced to barely ten minutes.
The mood was a long way from the unity showed by EU ministers in April immediately after the deaths of 900 migrants off the Libyan coast in a single weekend.
While the political deal was a breakthrough, implementing the plan still faces hurdles. The criteria to share migrants among member states must be decided by the end of July.
Such factors as the size of a member state's economy and population must be considered.
"There's much, much more argument to come," said one senior EU diplomat. "I don't yet see the full way forward."
The criteria system replaces unpopular proposals for mandatory quotas on each country, which Poland, the Czech Republic, Slovakia, Hungary and others fought against, arguing their ex-Communist economies still lacked the capacity to cope.
The debate has also strained the EU's commitment to its Schengen agreement on passport-free travel.
This week, Austria threatened to re-impose controls on its border with Hungary and Britain called for more security around the French port of Calais.
Britain and Spain want a bigger focus on returning migrants to their countries of origin.
Analysis: Europe Correspondent Paul Cunningham
The European Commission hasbeen pressing, and pressing very hard, for a mandatory deal  for each member state to be given a quota.
However,the ECwas pressed hard by countries in the Baltics, particularly countries like Poland who wanted a voluntary deal.
There were seven hours of talks, they were described as "fractious", "very heated", and at the end of it, it was decided it would be voluntary  countries would opt in to see what they take.
The deal which was agreed last night has noteven be printed, so still it is very early stages.
After it is printed,it will go to EU Justice Ministers in July who will complete the plan. Then we will have some idea how it works.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:48:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>DA denies Irish pressure led to balcony inquiry</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710708-berkeley/</Link>
        <Description>The Office of the District Attorney for Berkeley in California has denied that it was pressurised by the Irish community to launch a formal investigation into the balcony collapse after local authorities said their involvement was over.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
In an interview with RT News, Ms O'Malley also said her office would be looking closely at previous lawsuits that had been taken against the developers and contractors who had built the Library Gardens apartment complex.
In relation to criticism about how the authorities had handled the investigation into the balcony collapse to date, Ms O'Malley said that her office had been monitoring the situation from the outset and decided to commence this investigation once the City of Berkeley local authority and police department had announced their involvement was over.
Her office confirmed there had been a lot of communication with members of the Irish community but there had been "no pressure" to launch an investigation as a result.
It is understood that legal representatives of some of those involved in the balcony collapse had contacted the DA's office in recent days and that there had also been communication on behalf of the Government following the news that the Berkeley authorities would not be pursuing the matter further.
The DA also said they would be closely examining the outcome of other lawsuits against the builders and water-proofing contractors and would investigate what action they had taken in other properties as a result of these lawsuits.
She said her investigation would be "thorough and exhaustive" and she was not setting a time-limit on it, although the statute of limitations for gross criminal negligence was three years from the date of the crime.
She said this was "an unusual case" and it was not something that a municipal police force like the Berkeley PD would normally handle.
The Berkeley city authorities had not carried out forensic or laboratory examinations on the wooden joists that had held the balcony in place, she said, but added that her department would.
She said she did not know what they would find during the investigation, adding there was a chance that there would be no grounds to bring a criminal prosecution.
She said that the investigation would be "going systematically from the very beginning right up until the tragedy happened".
She said they would start with how the construction occurred, pointing out that there were responsibilities not just to file plans with the local government but that inspectors also came to the site to make sure the builders were following the codes and had permits.
Ms O'Malley said they will be examining the practices of the developer and builders.
District Attorney O'Malley said it was interesting that there had been previous lawsuits filed against the developer - Segue Construction - for "similar types of situations" and that there had "certainly" been "some construction issues".
She said they would examine whether the outcome of these lawsuits served to put the developer or the contractors "on notice" that "what they were doing was dangerous", and that "they were creating a dangerous situation that could result in someone's death or serious injury".
Questions have also arisen surrounding the chain of custody of the collapsed balcony and the one itfell onto underneath, which was subsequently removed from the property as it was found to also have significant dry-rot and was considered a "collapse hazard".
At a Berkeley City press conference on Tuesday, officials said that they had already given the balconies and other related material back to the owner.
This would potentially cause an issue now that the DA has launched a full-scale criminal investigation.
However, Ms O'Malley confirmed today that the collapsed balcony remains in the possession of the Berkeley Police Department.
She said that the second balcony had been released by the Berkeley City local authority and made available to the owner, however before it was collected from the building where it was being held, individuals from the District Attorney's office had gone to that location and taken possession of the balcony.
It was now being moved, she said, from that locked facility to another secure location where the DA's Sheriff's Department would guard it.
Ms O'Malley also confirmed that her office had already contacted some of the injured people and the families of those who had been killed to inform them of the investigation and to discuss how her office could help with resources.
She said that she had a special victim-witness division in her office - the first of its kind in the US - and it was focused on working with those directly involved with this tragedy.
She said they would give them as much information as they wanted.
Ms O'Malley said that the hearts of those in her office were grieving with the families, especially as both she and her chief assistant Kevin Dunleavy had "strong ties to Ireland".
Her family members are originally from Mayo and Clare, Mr Dunleavy's are from Clare and Leitrim.
As District Attorney for Alameda County, she said would do everything they could for them and said she would "guarantee" that she would conduct a "thorough and exhaustive" investigation to determine whether not they could make a case and prove it in a court of law and hold those accountable who had caused the deaths and injuries.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:41:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suicide bomber kills at least 13 in Kuwait mosque</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710819-kuwait-mosque-attack/</Link>
        <Description>A suicide bomber has attacked a Shiite mosque in Kuwait, killing at least 13 and wounding dozens, officials and witnesses said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 13.41
The attack is the first such bombing targeting Kuwaiti Shiite Muslims
A suicide bomber has attacked a Shiite mosque in Kuwait,killing at least 13 and wounding dozens, officials and witnesses said.
Medics have confirmed that at least 13 people have beenkilled and 25 have been hospitalised.
Eight people are reported to be in critical conditions.
No one has claimed responsibility for the blast, but the so-called Islamic State group said it carried out recent bombings Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia and Yemen.
The blast hit the Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City during the main weekly prayers, security officials and witnesses said.
The country'sofficialnews agency KUNA confirmed that there were "dead and wounded," but did not provide details.
A security official said "it is a suicide bombing."
Witnesses gave a similar account, saying a suicide bomber entered the mosque during the weekly noon prayers.
The area has been cordoned off by police.
The attack is the first such bombing targeting Kuwaiti Shiite Muslims, who make up around one-third of the country's native population of 1.3 million people.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:35:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alleged misuse of political funds in NI probed</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710740-northern-ireland-political-party-funding/</Link>
        <Description>Police in Northern Ireland are investigating alleged misuse of public funding for a political party.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 09.35
Assembly authorities have been notified of the investigation
Police in Northern Ireland are investigating alleged misuse of public funding for a political party.
Two men, aged 41 and 43, have been interviewed by police and will now be reported to the Public Prosecution Service.
PSNI chief superintendent Peter Farrar said the allegations were in connection to "potential fraud and theft" by a "small number of individuals" relating to money available under the Financial Assistance to Political Parties Fund.
"A number of items have been seized as part of on-going police inquiries," he said.
"Authorities at the Assembly have been advised of the police investigation."
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:54:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>DNA samples to be taken from bodies found in Meath</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710709-disappeared-remains-meath/</Link>
        <Description>Work resumes this morning on the recovery of human remains found in Co Meath yesterday during the search for members of the so-called Disappeared - people abducted, murdered and buried in secret by the IRA.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 11.54
1 of 2
Last night it emerged that there are at least two bodies in a grave uncovered in
Kevin McKee disappeared in 1972
Work resumes this morning on the recovery of human remains found in Co Meath yesterday during the search for members of the so-called Disappeared - people abducted, murdered and buried in secret by the IRA.
The remains were discovered during a search for Joe Lynskey, who disappeared over 40 years ago.
However, last night it emerged that there are at least two bodies in the grave.
Coghalstown is about 10km north of Navan.
Forty years ago the area was wild bog land, but it is now mainly farmland.
Since March,the Commission for the Location of Victims Remains has been excavating in the area looking for the remains of Mr Lynskey.
The former Cistercian monk disappeared in 1972 as a result of an internal IRA feud.
Yesterday, human remains were found and initially it was believed they were those of Mr Lynskey.
However, it emerged last night that more than one body is in the uncovered grave.
This means the remains may well be those of Seamus Wright and Kevin McKee, who disappeared from Belfast a few weeks after Mr Lynskey, and were murdered and buried in the same area.
Lead Forensic Scientistand Investigator with Commission ,Geoff Knupfer,has said this islikely to be the case.
He said it was a huge relief that the bodies 'remained intact'.
Mr Knupfer said the bodies were found lying on top of each other.
He said he believed they may have originally been buried about a metre underground.
Mr Knupferadded that if it turns out that the remains are not those of Mr Lynskey, the search will continue for him in this location.
It may be several weeks before the bodies can be identitfied as post-mortem examinations and DNA analysis have to be carried out.
Family members of Seamus Wright and Kevin McKeehave arrived at the site.
Commenting on the discovery of the two bodiesMinister for JusticeFrances Fitzgerald said she hoped "the suffering of the families of some of those who were Disappeared over the course of the Troubles in Northern Ireland will now be eased".
In a statement Minister Fitzgerald said the Commission will continue to undertake the "humanitarian task" of working to find the "remains of those who have yet to be found".
Both the Commission and Sinn Fin president Gerry Adams have renewed their calls for those with information about other Disappeared to come forward.
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:32:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Call for more inspections of private rentals</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710715-rental-inspections/</Link>
        <Description>Local authority figures obtained by RTÉ show just 6% of private rental property across the country were inspected last year.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 26 June 2015 07.32
'Paul' says when it rains he just waits for water to come through his ceiling
Local authority figures obtained by RT show just 6% of private rental property across the country were inspected last year.
There are currently around 303,000 rental properties, with just 17,700 of these inspected in 2014.
More than 50% of the accommodation inspected failed to meet minimum standards set out in the housing regulations.
In one example, Paul has been living for three years in accommodation that is in a state of disrepair and has been deemed a fire hazard by Dublin City Council.
He said: "Dublin City Council has been out to examine the conditions of the house and the environmental health officer said the housing conditions are atrocious. There is damp, mould, the ceiling is ready to fall in," he says.
"There is water coming down over the light so that's very serious. Dublin City Council was out to inspect that they have the report on that.
"Any time it goes to rain the first thing you're looking at is the light, it's just a matter of when that's going to go up on fire."
His landlord was given three months to repair the house but that time expired last week and no work has been carried out.
Paul says that if he is forced to vacate his property he will not be able to afford the soaring cost of rent in Dublin.
"My main concern now is that I feel I'm going to be left homeless after this".
"I've never lived in conditions like this even in my student days so as it stands now a middle-class working person is the new homeless," he says.
Local authority figures show that in Dublin 63% of dwellings inspected failed, in Cork city 26% of properties inspected did not meet the standards required, while in Kerry 32% of rented properties inspected failed.
Some of the county councils contacted by RT said they were not in a position to categorise the figures into minor and serious breaches of the regulations.
Dublin city was among the councils that did provide detailed figures, which showed that out of 3,500 inspections, 930 dwellings did not reach regulatory requirements and of these 65 legal actions were initiated.
In Waterford 90% of failures resulted from lack of proper smoke alarms and/or fire blankets, while in 10% of cases there were damp and mould issues.
Out of a total of 387 cases in Roscommon four of the breaches were categorised as serious while in Galway and Kilkenny most of the failures were due to minor breaches of regulations.
Housing charity Thresholds Chief Executive, Bob Jordan, has raised concerns about the low level of inspections.
"There is huge anomalies within these figures... for instance if we take the example of Cavan carrying out 800 inspections compared with Galway City Council, which really is one of the centres of the private rented sector, and theyre carrying out less than 150.
"So there's a real issue about the number of inspections that are been carried out.
"I think the other issue is around the quality of these inspections. The fact that Donegal carried out just under 600 inspections and found no properties to be substandard, Tipperary - 200 again found nothing.
"Nobody believes there is no sub-standard properties in those counties so there's a real question about what they're actually going out and looking at," he said.
Mr Jordan is calling for a certification scheme to ensure rented accommodation is up to standard: "I think the issue is this approach where local authorities inspected private rented properties was set up at a time when we had a very small private rented sector.
"Now one in five households live in the private rented sector and clearly local authorities in the main are not up to carrying out these inspections. So what we are saying is that the boot should be put on the other foot," he said.
"The responsibility should be on the landlord to prove that their property is up to scratch before a tenant moves in and that it would be the job of the local authorities that landlords have those certs because with the best will in the world local authorities are not going to get around to every single property."
However, the Residential Landlords Association is against a certification scheme - which it says would create another layer of bureaucracy for landlords.
"We're one of the most highly-regulated rented sectors now in western Europe. We're governed by a wide range of legislation and of course the private rented tenancies board is the overarching supervisory body of the rented sector.
"It's expensive for landlords to comply with regulations it is expensive for them to register with the PRTB as well as all of the other tax obligations they have."
He says the standard of rented accommodation in Ireland is high by international standards.
"I served on two international bodies and we routinely carried out comparative analysis of the standards and regulations applying to rented property in other jurisdictions and there is no question but we have been very high here.
"The figures listed by the local authorities don't surprise me but what is worth bearing in mind is that they include a wide range of issues bearing from the very minor to some quite serious."
"Many things that have been listed for improvement would be like dampness in a room or a fire blanket to be supplied but when told by the local authority to comply landlords are given three months to comply and by in large most of them do," Mr McNamara added.
Related Files
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:15:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama to give eulogy for victim of church shooting</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710766-south-carolina-funeral/</Link>
        <Description>US President Barack Obama is expected to deliver the eulogy for the pastor that died in the mass shooting in South Carolina.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Friday 26 June 2015 12.15
The president will be accompanied by both First Lady Michelle Obama and Vice President Joe Biden to the funeral
US President Barack Obama is expected to deliver the eulogy for the pastor that died in the mass shooting in South Carolina.
Reverend Clementa Pinckney was a pastor at the Charlestons Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church where the shooting took place.
He was among the nine people who died when a gunman opened fire during Bible study.
The eight other victims were named as Susie Jackson, 87; Reverend Daniel Simmons, 74; Ethel Lance, 70; Myra Thompson, 59;Cynthia Hurd, 54; DePayne Middleton-Doctor, 49; Sharonda Coleman Singleton, 45; and Tywanza Sanders, 26.
The first of the victims funerals took place yesterday, when Ethel Lance and Sharonda Coleman-Singleton were laid to rest.
The church is the oldest African Methodist Episcopal church in the southeastern US and was founded by slaves.
The presidentwill be accompanied by both First Lady Michelle Obama and Vice President Joe Biden to Reverend Pinckneys funeral in Charleston.
All three knew Reverend Pinckney personally.
During his presidency, President Obama has spoken at six memorial services for victims of mass shootings, in Texas, Arizona, Colorado and Connecticut.
Speaking at the White House last week, he said: "I've had to make statements like this too many times. Communities like this have had to endure tragedies like this too many times."
The president repeated his calls for tougher gun laws, a controversial issue in the US where the constitution guarantees the right to own guns.
The mass shootinghas sparked a dialogue across the southern states over the legacy of slavery and its symbols, centering on the Civil War-era battle flag of the Confederacy.
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley and other Republicans have called for the Confederate flag to be removed from the State House grounds.
Some major retailers are removing merchandise with Confederate images from stores and websites.
The Department of Justice has opened a hate crime investigation into the shooting.
A 21-year-old white man, Dylann Roof, has been arrested in connection with the shooting. He faces nine murder charges and one gun charge.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:03:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama interviews Attenborough on climate change</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0626/710712-barack-obama-david-attenborough/</Link>
        <Description>US President Barack Obama has turned interviewer for the BBC, in a special programme with naturalist David Attenborough.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Friday 26 June 2015 07.03
Barack Obama told David Attenborough: 'I have been a huge admirer of your work for a very long time'
US President Barack Obama has turned interviewer for the BBC, in a special programme with naturalist David Attenborough.
Mr Obama and Mr Attenborough discuss climate change in the interview, to be aired on Sunday.
Climate change is one of Mr Obama's top issues for his remaining time in office.
"I have been a huge admirer of your work for a very long time," Mr Obama told Mr Attenborough.
It is the latest in a series of unusual media appearances for Mr Obama, who has been keen to tap almost any avenue that reaches as many people as possible to get his message out.
Last week, Mr Obama was interviewed by comedian Marc Maron for a viral podcast known as "WTF".
Earlier this year, he talked to green-lipstick-wearing comedian GloZell Green and other YouTube celebrities with huge followings.
To reach young people he wanted to sign up for Obamacare, his signature health care insurance program, he talked to comedian Zach Galifianakis for the web series "Between Two Ferns".
Mr Attenborough, 89, has been making television documentaries for 60 years.
The BBC has called him "the godfather of natural history TV".
Mr Obama's interview with Attenborough about climate change was taped on 8 May, and will air on BBC, BBC America and 20 other broadcasters around the world, a White House official said.
It comes as Mr Obama's administration is finalising rules to curb carbon emissions from power plants.
Mr Obama has pushed world leaders to agree to new targets at a summit later this year in Paris.
Mr Obama told Mr Attenborough that kids are "much more environmentally aware" than adults, citing his daughters Malia, 16, and Sasha, 13, as examples.
"They do not dispute, for example, the science around climate change," Mr Obama said in the clip.
Mr Attenborough agreed that adults lose the fascination with nature that is common among children.
"A five-year-old, turning over a stone and seeing a slug, and says, 'What a treasure!' Kids understand the natural world," Mr Attenborough said.
. @POTUS . David Attenborough. Talking climate change. Watch a sneak peek of their interview: http://t.co/SaiaqQzAqN https://t.co/e8bNWiIXgQ
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:02:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tests on BSE cow confirm it was an isolated case</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0625/710650-bse-cow-results/</Link>
        <Description>The Department of Agriculture has said final tests on the recent suspected case of BSE found in a cow in Co Louth have confirmed that it was an isolated case in a single animal.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The department also saidthe cow's mother and grandmother had also been tested and they too were found to be clear of the disease.
In addition, the department confirmed the integrity of the commercial feed supply chain to the farm on which the BSE cow was found.
It said between 2009 and 2010 more than 3,800 animal feed inspections and almost 2,500 feed samples were taken, including 52 from suppliers to the farm infected.
In all cases, the tests on the feeds were found to be clear of all signs of processed animal proteins and all tested negative for meat and bone meal.
The department will now inform the EU Commission and the World Animal Health Organisation of the findings of its tests.
It says it expects the health agency will reassign the BSE control risk status to Ireland as a result of this confirmation.
Reacting to the results IFA President Eddie Downey said consumers can be re-assured about the robustness of the food safety controls in place in Ireland.
He said:This and the high quality of Irish food has rightly reassured export markets from all over the world.
Meanwhile, ICSA President Patrick Kent warned that today's confirmation of a BSE case must not be used as an excuse to drive down price.
Farmers have seen a welcome tightening of prices in recent days, and meat processors cannot use this result, an isolated one-off case, as a stick to hammer farmers with," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:03:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three men charged over murder of biker in Limerick</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0625/710644-limerick-murder-charge/</Link>
        <Description>Three men have been charged in connection with the investigation into the fatal shooting of 51-year-old biker Andrew O'Donoghue at Mountfune, Murroe, Co Limerick last week.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Both men were granted free legal aid and remanded in custody to appear in court by video link on 30 June next.
A third man  50-year-old Dermot McKenna of Hillview Park, St Patricks Road in Limerick  was charged with possession of a shotgun and recklessly discharging it at an apartment in Castletroy on the day after the murder.
Garda allege this incident is connected with the murder and was carried out in retaliation for Mr O'Donoghues murder.
Two other men, aged in their late 40s, arrested in connection with the investigation have been released without charge and a file is being prepared for the Director of Public Prosecutions.
Mr ODonoghue was shot in the head at a bikers club outside Murroeon Saturday afternoon, when a man in a car pulled up and shot him.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:03:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Berkeley tragedy will be 'thoroughly' investigated</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0625/710662-berkeley-balcony-investigation/</Link>
        <Description>The Alameda County District Attorney has promised the families of those killed and injured in the Berkeley balcony collapse that the case will be "thoroughly and exhaustively" investigated.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Seven other students were injured in the incident.
Speaking at a press conference at her office,Ms O'Malley said the tragedy had devastated the Greater Bay Area and Ireland.
She said the DA's office would be the lead agency in this criminal investigation.
Ms O'Malley said she would be investigating whether there was cause to bring charges of criminal negligence in relation to the balcony collapseand whether there was enough evidence to prove those charges beyond reasonable doubt in a court of law.
She said she had 66 investigators at her disposal and she would also bring in outside experts.
She said her office would also be working with agencies from the State of California.
She said the City of Berkeley hada limited scope in terms of the investigationit had carried out but she could guarantee the families of those killed and those who were injured that she would carry out a complete investigation.
Ms O'Malley said she was happy that the city authority and the police department would be supporting her investigation.
In terms of evidence she said that the collapsed balcony was in police possession and the balcony from the floor beneath was in a secure location guarded by sheriffs.
She said there was no timeline on the investigation butany charges of criminal negligence needed to be brought within three years of the crime.
Despite having declared their examinations to be finished, the City of Berkeley local authority and the police department are now co-operating with the District Attorney's formal investigation.
The City of Berkeley local authority announced on Tuesday that its investigation into the tragic balcony collapse at the Library Gardens apartment complex had concluded. 
Its inspectors, it said, were satisfied that extensive dry rot was the sole cause of the failure of the wooden joists holding the balcony in place.
Meanwhile, the funeral of Lorcn Miller took place today while the funerals of Niccolai Schuster and Olivia Burke took place yesterday andEoghan Culligan and Eimear Walsh were laid to rest on Tuesday in Dublin.
The funeral mass forAshley Donohoe, a cousin of Olivia Burke, was held in California last weekend.
Two of the seven students injured in the balcony collapse have beendischarged from hospital. Two of the injuredremain in a critical condition in hospital in California.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:00:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eurogroup talks end with no deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0625/710475-greece-talks/</Link>
        <Description>EU leaders spent two hours of unscheduled talks on the Greek debt crisis at their summit in Brussels yesterday, however, there was no breakthrough.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Despite hours of talks between the Greek Prime Minister and international creditors, another meeting of the eurozone finance ministers, and two hours of talks with EU leaders, Greece is no closer to securing a deal on its debt.
EU officials said Mr Tsipras urged his fellow EU leaders to take responsibility and not leave Greece's fate in the hands of the International Monetary Fund, but they refused to intervene and argued the talks must continue to be conducted by finance ministers.
Later today Greek negotiators will resume contacts with the EU, IMF and ECB in a bid to narrow the points of differences on issues such as pensions, VAT and government spending.
If successful, eurozone finance ministers are prepared to return to Brussels on Saturday.
The head of the eurozone finance ministers group, Jeroen Dijsselbloem, tried to strike a note of optimism when he said: "The door is still open for the Greek side to come with new proposals."
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis told reporters: We'll continue until we find a solution."
However, time is rapidly running out for these negotiations, and tempers are fraying.
Greece could default as early as Tuesday if it does not have the money to replay 1.6bn to the IMF.
Speakingon arrival in Brussels for theEU summit, Taoiseach Enda Kenny said: "Clearly you are in the closing hours of making decisions here. It's in the red sector."
Asked whether Ireland, in principle, would support the continuing Greek demand for debt relief, the Taoiseach replied simply: "No."
Giving his view on yet another suspension of the eurozone finance ministers meeting this afternoon, Mr Kenny said it appeared there was "a complication about putting credible papers on the table.
"It is very important that the propositions, which are tabled, make economic sense and that they are financially sustainable and that they are fair."
Citing Ireland's example in negotiations with international creditors, the Taoiseach said: ".. we did not increase income tax; we did not increase VAT; and we did not increase PRSI. But we putup alternatives to those measure that were proposed."
Mr Kenny argued this Irish policy was put in place " in order to keep a pro-growth policy, and make our country competitive, and grow our economy, and provide jobs for our people."
Taking issue with the Greek proposals for higher taxes on people and companies, Mr Kenny said: "It's difficult to see the beneficial effect of measures that increase the tax on labour; that increase income tax; and that increase PRSI. These are not in the interest of pro-growth.'
He added: "Obviously that's what the [Finance Minister] discussions are about. But I think there is a frustration among the Minister for Finance that they don't have figures they can work off; and suggest better proposals that might be better in growing the economy of Greece and providing jobs for their people."
An Irish Government official clarified that the Taoiseach "continues to support debt reprofiling for Greece", in anydeal with its international lender.
The official cited Ireland's promissory note deal was an example of debt reprofiling "that can ease the burden of debt on taxpayers and give a small economy the space to grow".
Analysis: Europe CorrespondentPaul Cunningham
The hope is a deal can be concluded before eurozone Finance Ministers meet at lunchtime, but no one has any great confidence this new deadline will be met.
Yesterday, there was a cautious welcome to Greeces proposals but there were difficulties as far as some of the countries did not see it the same way. One person to look to is the German Finance Minister, and when he came to Brussels he said not much progress had been made.
It also appears that the IMF in particularhad major concerns on Greeces tax take measures.
The IMF is concerned that theyve heard previous promises from Greece and Greece before and tax collection has not worked out well.
The IMF does not believe Greece will raise enough in taxes to meet their targets and thats why the IMF is insisting on more cuts. However, for Syriza thats just not going to work  thats why the talks are deadlocked and thats why the Greek government say they remain firm in their positions.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:32:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ECB to maintain emergency credit line to Greece</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711122-greece-economy/</Link>
        <Description>The European Central Bank said it would keep its emergency cash lifeline to Greece at current levels, while closely monitoring financial markets and "the potential implications for the monetary policy stance".</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Meanwhile, Greece's finance minister has denied saying the government preferred the imposition of capital controls, saying the move would be incompatible with the concept of a monetary union, a statement from his ministry said.
BBC Radio earlier quoted Yanis Varoufakis saying Athens would consider imposing capital controls tonight in addition to losing the country's banks tomorrow.
Mr Varoufakis insisted that Greece's exit from the eurozone is not inevitable.
He said the bailout crisis was a "dark hour" for Europe, but the country had a "clear conscience" over its actions.
Greece's Financial StabilityCouncil is conveningthis afternoon to discuss the situation in the country's banking system, a source said.
The council comprises Mr Varoufakis, his deputy Dimitris Mardas, Central Bank Governor Yiannis Stournaras, the head of the Greek Banks Association, the chairman of the HFSF bank bailout fund and the head of the Capital Markets Commission.
      
Long lines formed in front of ATMs yesterdayas people rushed to pull their money out while the banks were still operating normally.
Huge pressure has been piling up on Greek banks after talks between Athens and its creditors for a cash-for-reforms deal collapsed.
Mr Varoufakis also said that German Chancellor Angela Merkel "holds the key" to resolving his country's crisis, and stressed that the government remains open to further talks with international creditors.
He told Germany's Bild newspaper that EU leaders must act and "and among them she, as the representative of the most important country, holds the key in her hand. I hope she uses it."
Ms Merkel has invited leaders from all the major German parties to a crisis meeting in Berlin tomorrow to discuss the Greece crisis.
A senior German official saidthe chairmen and parliamentary leaders of all the parties represented in the German parliament, including the opposition Greens and Left, had been invited to attend the meeting.
ECB should not cut support - Valls
Earlier, France's Prime Minister said the ECBshould not cut off support to Greek banks even if the country misses a 30 June deadline for debt repayments it cannot afford to make.
"The European Central Bank is independent, but I don't doubt it will assume its responsibilities," Manuel Valls said in an interview broadcast on Europe 1 radio.
"I don't think it can cut off support, to put it another way."
Mr Valls also sounded a warning to Greek voters that a "no" vote in the upcoming referendum on a proposed debt deal could amount to a decision to leave the euro zone.
"The Greek people must be able to decide lucidly," Mr Vallssaid.
"If there's a negative vote, there is a real risk ...of exiting the euro zone."
Greece has called a 5 July referendum so thatvoters can decide on whether to accept new, tougher bailout terms that the government itself opposes.
Austria's Finance Minister has said a Greek exit from the euro would only be possible if Greece got the permission of other member countries.
"Greece would have to file a request to do so. The other EU countries would have to approve the request.
"Only then could Greece leave the eurozone," saidHans Jorg Schelling in an interview with Austrian newspaper Die Presse.
It's clear that one country can under no circumstances blackmail the European Commission and the euro countries," Mr Schelling said.
Yesterday, eurozone finance ministers refused to extend the bailout, blaming the Greek government for unilaterally ending talks with creditors and announcing a surprise referendum.
In turn, the Greek government criticised the European Union for failing to live up to its founding principles of solidarity and equality and trying to impose a debt plan which would hurt the poorest and only deepen the country's economic crisis.
Eurozone finance ministers expressed confidence in the euro and its ability to withstand economic shocks, but conceded the single currency bloc is heading into uncharted waters. 
The Greek parliament approved thereferendum by a majority vote late last night, according to the assembly's count.
In a speech prior to the vote, Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras said he was confident that "the Greek people will say an emphatic no to the ultimatum" by the country's EU-IMF creditors, but "a big yes to European solidarity".
He also expressed confidence that "in the aftermath of this proud no, the negotiating power of the country (with the country's creditors) will be strengthened".
The Greeks, according to the text of the proposed referendum, must say "yes" or "no" to the measures submitted by the country's EU-IMF creditors to the government Friday at one of the final rounds of negotiations that have been going on since late February. 
Source: AFP/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:38:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three Irish confirmed dead in Tunisia attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711121-tunisia-attack/</Link>
        <Description>A couple from Athlone in Co Westmeath are confirmed to have died in Friday's terror attack in Tunisia, bringing to three the number of Irish people killed.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The couplehave one daughter.
Mr Hayes was a school bus inspector with Bus ireann and had worked at the company for 20 years, beginning as a bus driver in Galway.
The companyextended its sympathy to the couple's family, andfriends as well as Mr Hayes' colleagues.
Garda and officials from the Department of Foreign Affairs are liaising with the family.
The third Irish victim is Lorna Carty, a mother-of-two from Robinstown in Co Meath.
She was on holidayin the popular beach resort of Sousse with her husband Declan when the attack happened.
Minister for Foreign Affairs Charlie Flanagan urged people travelling to Tunisia to exercise extreme caution.
"I'm not in the business of imposing travel bans but I would say to people be extremely vigilant and extremely cautious in implementing any holiday plans in the region and keep in close contact with the tour operators and the police authorities."
Tour companies have already evacuated thousands of holidaymakers from Tunisia following the attack in which 38 people died, the majority of whom were British.
Tunisia's tourism minister called the attack a "catastrophe" and authorities vowed to toughen security, drafting in army reserves and arming tourism police at beaches and hotels.
Sousses tourism commissioner said more than 3,000 foreign tourists had left the town yesterday, including around 2,200 British and nearly 600 Belgians.
The British Foreign Office confirmed that 15 Britons had died in the attack, which was carried out by a lone gunman.
Among the British citizens killed was Joel Richards, 22, who played for James Connolly Gaelic Football Club in Birmingham and was also actively involved in Birmingham County FA Youth Council.
Sad to learn that one of those killed in Tunisia was Joel Richards, who played Gaelic Football for the James Connolly club in Birmingham.
 Daniel Mulhall (@DanMulhall) June 28, 2015
1/3 James Connollys GFC is devastated to learn of the death of one of our players, Joel Richards, during the horrific attack in Tunisia.
 Connollys GFC (@Connollys_Gaa) June 27, 2015
Mr Richards' uncle, 46-year-old Adrian Evans and his 78-year-old grandfather Patrick Evans, were also killed in the attack.
His 16-year-old brother Owen survived.
Lincolnshire Photographer Carly Lovett, 24, was killed as were Sue Davey and her partner Scott Chalkley from Staffordshire.
Another British couple, Jim and Ann McQuire from Cumbernauld, are also among the dead.
Tunisian studentSaif Rezgui opened fire on the beach of the Imperial Marhaba hotel before making his way to the pool and hotel before being shot dead by police.
Tunisian authorities said Rezgui was not on any watchlist of known potential militants.
But one source said he appeared to have been radicalised over the last six months by Islamist militant recruiters.
The self-styled Islamic State group later claimed responsibility for the attack.
It identified the gunman asAbu Yahya al-Qayrawani - a "soldier of the caliphate".
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have gone to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighbouring Libya, where some have set up training camps and vowed to return to attack their homeland.
Traveller safety 'paramount' - Sunway
A spokeswoman for Irish tour operator Sunway saidit istrying to contact as many of its customers as possible, including a large number who no longer want to travel to Tunisia.
Sunway said while it is still flying to Tunisia, traveller safety is paramount and it will be guided by the Department of Foreign Affairs.
The 177 people due to travel to Tunisia next Friday are being offered a full refund or a change of destination depending on availability.
Tanya Airey confirmed a high proportion wanted to change their destination and Friday's flight to Monastir is being kept under review.
For departures from 10 July, passengers can cancel for a fee, stay with Tunisia, or be offered a chance to switch to another destination.
There will be no full refunds for departures from 10 July.
Sunway is also facilitating those traveled to Tunisia despite the attack with 59 of the 177 booked on Fridays flight deciding not to go to Tunisia.
"We are holding welcome meetings for them at hotels," Ms Airey said, adding that many of the hotels are at another resort around half an hour away from Sousse where the attack occurred.
Sunway only deals with a proportion of Irish holidaymakers to Tunisia.
Many others are travelling with English companies who are taking direction from the British Foreign office.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:08:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ervia unions to refer bonus payments to LRC</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711169-irish-water/</Link>
        <Description>Ervia's group of unions has referred the company's decision not to pay controversial bonuses awards to Irish Water workers, to the Labour Relations Commission.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sunday 28 June 2015 14.08
Workers say they have earned their bonuses and are entitled to them
Ervia's group of unions has referred the company's decision not to pay controversial bonuses awards to Irish Water workers, to the Labour Relations Commission.
Workers at the company insist they have earned the bonuses and are now entitled to receive them.
The issue of bonus payments at the new water utility has been politically sensitive since details of the performance related awards became public last year.
Details included the fact that some staff who are deemed to "need improvement" can still benefit from a pay award.
The controversy prompted Minister for the Environment Alan Kelly to say at the time that he did not want to see a "bonus culture" emerge at Irish Water.
RT's This Week understands that unions and management at Irish Water's parent company Ervia will attend a conciliation conference at the LRC on 13 July, on the dispute.
The bonus payments were introduced as part of a new pay model at Ervia (then known as Bord Gais ireann) in 2013.
Irish Water inherited the new pay model when it was established as a utility under Ervia two years ago.
No performance related awards have been paid out at Irish Water yet but they were due to be paid earlier this year to cover work done in 2014.
However, company management informed the unions that this would not go ahead.
Ervia has repeatedly defended the pay model saying that it had brought considerable savings when compared to the previous increment-based pay model at Bord Gais.
It also rejected descriptions of the performance awards as being comparable to a traditional 'bonus' and instead they have described it as a 'pay-at-risk' element of pay.
In a statement, Ervia confirmed that the group of unions had referred the dispute to the LRC in recent weeks and that a conciliation conference had been scheduled for 13 July.
Speaking on This Week, Adrian Kane of SIPTU said Irish Water workers were angry that they were not being paid their performance related awards - and that it appeared to them that the decision was made at board level without a clear or consistent rationale being given for the non-payment of the bonus awards.
He said the performance-related awards were a key element of the pay model negotiated between the unions and the company back in 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:06:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>LÉ Eithne rescues 593 migrants off Libya coast</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711173-le-eithne-migrants/</Link>
        <Description>Almost 600 migrants have been rescued from six separate inflatable vessels by Irish naval vessel LÉ Eithne off the coast of Libya.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sunday 28 June 2015 14.06
L Eithne involved in rescue of almost 3,000 people since its deployment in May
Almost 600 migrants have been rescued from six separate inflatable vessels by Irish naval vessel L Eithne off the coast of Libya.
The rescue operation began at 4am Irish time around 50 nautical miles northwest of Tripoli when 101 people were taken from a rubber craft.
Five other rescue operations were also carried out and 593 people, including 92 women and five children, were taken on board L Eithne by 1pm.
L Eithne has rescued 2,729 people since its deployment on 16 May to assist Italian authorities in search and rescue operations in Mediterranean.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:09:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Appeal to trace man missing from Co Tipperary</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711152-john-ryan-appeal/</Link>
        <Description>An appeal has been issued to trace 30-year-old John Ryan who has been missing from Co Tipperary since 7 June.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Sunday 28 June 2015 11.09
John Ryan was last seen driving his car at the Cliffs of Moher in Liscannor on 7 June
An appeal has been issued to trace a 30-year-old man missing from Co Tipperary since 7 June.
John Ryan is missing from Faranaderry in Templemore and was last seen at the Cliffs of Moher, Liscannor driving his car.
He is described as 1.77m (5'10") tall, of slim build with short brown hair and green eyes.
Mr Ryan was wearing a light grey zip hoodie, black t-shirt, blue jeans and white runners when last seen.
Garda say they are concerned for his welfare and have asked anyone with information on his whereabouts to contact Ennistymon Garda Station on 065 7072180, the Garda Confidential Line 1800 666111 or any Garda station.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:25:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Driver killed in Belgium school tour bus crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711149-belgium-crash/</Link>
        <Description>A Northern Ireland bus company vehicle with 34 children on board overturned and crashed on a motorway in Belgium this morning, killing a driver.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The children, from Brentwood School in Essex, areaged between 11 and 13 and wereaccompanied by six teachers.
They were travelling to Cologne in Germany when the crashoccurred ona stretch of the E40 motorway near the Belgian coast.
Aspokesman from Richmond Coaches, of Ballinderry Road, Lisburn, Co Antrim, confirmed that one of its vehicles had been involved in the crash.
He said what had happened was "a tragedy" and the company was co-operating with the authorities.
He said the company's thoughts were with everyone involved.
Brentwood School said in a statement that two senior members of staff have travelled to Belgium.
It said all the pupils "walked off the coach and several pupils and teachers have been taken to local hospitals. One pupil is in intensive care receiving treatment for a head injury".
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:09:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>519 injured in Taiwan dance party fire</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711136-taiwan-fire/</Link>
        <Description>More than 500 people have been injured in a fire at a Taiwan water amusement park, with around 180 listed as being in intensive care.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
Authorities have banned the use of the powder until the investigation is completed.
"The next few days will be a critical time for the injured," Taiwan Premier Mao Chi-kuo said, adding that 410 people were still in hospital, with 194 being treated for serious injuries.
In the immediate aftermath of the explosion, rescuers treated hundreds of people, most of them aged between 20 and 30, wearing wet swimsuits and lying on inflatable plastic doughnuts.
Television showed images of people running from sky-high flames.
No deaths have been reported.
One 18-year-old girl had burns to 80% of her body, according to local media reports.
Soldiers, army vehicles and medical services joined the rescue effort, while hospitals in four municipal precincts, along with Taipei, are treating victims.
The amusement park has been closed temporarily.
Taipei has sweltered in temperatures exceeding 30C in recent weeks. 
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:11:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canadian police investigate French attack photo</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711127-france-attack/</Link>
        <Description>Canadian authorities are working with French police to help find the recipient of a photograph purportedly taken by an Islamist suspected of decapitating his boss in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The message was sent to a Canadian number, but investigators said they were still working to determine the final recipient, as the number used could be a relay to another phone in another location.
Authorities are questioning Mr Salhi about the attack, during which he also drove his van into a warehouse packed with dangerous gases in an apparent bid to blow up the factory and himself.
A source close to the investigation said Mr Salhi has admitted killing his boss, 54-year-old Herve Cornara.
Canadian officials did not give details about how they are helping the French, but police powers allow them to trace calls or locate a phone by its number.
"A government's first duty is to ensure the safety of its citizens," the spokesman said.
French police found the head of Mr Cornara, manager of the transport firm that employed Mr Salhi, attached to a fence at the plant owned by USgroup Air Products, framed by black and white flags bearing Islamic slogans.
The body of Mr Cornaraalso bore signs of strangulation suggesting that he may have been killed at an unknown location prior to his decapitation.
      
Investigators searching Mr Salhi'shome in Saint-Priest, near Lyon, seized a laptop, a tablet computer and a fake pistol but found no trace of explosives or radical propaganda.
      
"We don't know whether we're dealing with a fundamentalist who just lost it or a real terrorist," asource said.
Canada has seen the radicalisation of some of its citizens, with about 100 people thought to have gone to Syria to join the Islamic State group.
Politicians recently endorsed a new anti-terror law that boosts powers of Canada's spy agency amid concerns of attacks within the country.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:12:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man critical after Dublin stabbing</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711125-dublin/</Link>
        <Description>A man is in a critical condition after a stabbing incident in Dublin city centre last night.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sunday 28 June 2015 15.12
The man is being treated at St James's Hospital
A man is in a critical condition after a stabbing incident in Dublin city centre last night.
The incident occurred at around 8pm in Fleet Street in Temple Bar.
It is understood the man was stabbed in the face.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:37:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>MERS death toll in South Korea rises to 32</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711129-south-korea-mers/</Link>
        <Description>The death toll in an outbreak of MERS in South Korea has risen to 32 as the virus's mortality rate continued to rise even as the pace of the outbreak appeared to slow.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sunday 28 June 2015 08.37
A little girl wears a face mask as the death toll in MERS outbreak continues to rise
The death toll in an outbreak of MERS in South Korea has risen to 32 as the virus's mortality rate continued to rise even as the pace of the outbreak appeared to slow.
A 55-year-old man died yesterday of Middle East Respiratory Disease, the health ministry said, putting the latest mortality rate at 17.5%.
That is up from 15% a week ago and 10% two weeks ago, though still lower than World Health Organisation figures which put the mortality rate for the disease at around 36%.
The man was diagnosed on 9 June after contracting the virus at Samsung Medical Centre in Seoul - where about 90 patients, visitors and medical staff had been infected.
The total number of infections remained unchanged at 182 and 15 patients were in critical condition, the health ministry said.
A total of 91 patients have recovered and been released from hospital, including one yesterday.
A total of 2,562 people were under quarantine either at state facilities or at home.
The outbreak started on 20 May when a 68-year-old man was diagnosed after returning from a trip to Saudi Arabia.
Since then the potentially deadly virus - for which there is no vaccine - has spread at an unusually rapid pace in the Asia's fourth-largest economy, becoming the largest outbreak outside Saudi Arabia.
South Korea's government is facing criticism for failing to stop the outbreak.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:01:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Double boxing gold for Ireland at European Games</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/sport/other-sport/2015/0627/711003-magees-lose-out-in-baku-badminton-doubles-final/</Link>
        <Description>Ireland have claimed two gold medals at the European Games with Katie Taylor winning the women's lightweight title, and Michael O'Reilly securing the men's middleweight crown in Baku.</Description>
        <MainBody>Double boxing gold for Ireland at the European Games as Katie Taylor and Michael O'Reilly prevail at Baku 2015
By Tadhg Peavoy | Updated: Saturday, 27 Jun 2015 23:01 | Comments
Katie Taylor won all four rounds of the lightweight final Sam and Chloe Magee have bowed out at the last-four stage of the badminton mixed doubles
European Games, Baku, Azerbaijan
Boxing
Ireland have claimed two gold medals at the European Games with Katie Taylor winning the women's lightweight title, and Michael O'Reilly securing the men's middleweight crown, at the Crystal Hall, Baku.
28-year-oldTaylor won gold with a unanimous decision against Frances Estelle Mossely in a performance of consummate class, prevailing 40-36, 40-36, 39-37to claim an 18th major international title.
Laois man O'Reilly saw off Azeri boxer Xaybula Musalov, also on a unanimous decision,29-28, 29-28, 29-28, in a fight that oozed athleticismand power from both men.
22-year-old O'Reilly took the first round, lostthe second, and appearedto be behind in the third, before a superb closing 90 seconds from the Irishmansecured the top prize.
Boom! Said it from Day 1 that Michael Oreilly would win gold and he's just gone and done it! Thats 2 golds 1 silver and 1 bronze ?? #teamire
 Paddy Barnes (@paddyb_ireland) June 27, 2015
Bray womanTaylor adds the European Games title to hercurrent Olympic, world, European and EU crowns, once more cementing her unrivalled status as female boxings biggest star.
Taylor and Mossely had previously met in the European Championships decider in 2014, and the EU Championships finalin 2013, with Taylor winning both fights against the Frenchwoman.
The opening roundin Baku was very close, with both fighters battling hard for control of the centre of the ring. Taylor edged it 2-1 with some powerful combinations and right hooks, while Mossely replied withleft jabs and hooks to excellent effect.
The second round was perhaps somewhat generously given to Taylor on a 3-0 call from the judges, despite Mossely looking to have had the better of the scoring punches as she advanced furiously on Taylor, with the Olympic champion fighting on the counter for those two minutes.
Mossely came out in the third needing something special and landed some powerful lefts but Taylor managed to land solid left hooks and rights to ensure another 3-0 verdict from the judges, putting the bout out of sight.
The fourth round saw Taylor hammer Mossely with combinations in the opening 30 seconds, before Mossely responded with a superb pair of lefts to the Irishwomans jaw, but with just 15 seconds to go the fight was well beyond Mosselys reach. Once more the judges went with Irishwomanin the fourth to give Taylor a clean sweep, four-round unanimous victory.
The judges scored the bout 3-0 overall,40-36, 40-36 and39-37 in Taylor's favour.
OReilly came into the ring shortly before 4pm Irish time, looking to double Ireland's gold tally within the space of two hours and was immediatelycaught withfour lefts, as well as a right hook,by hisAzeri opponentMusalov in the opening round.
But the Laois man was far busier throughout the three minutes,landing combinations with both hands. The neutral might have given it to the host nation fighter, but the judges went 3-0 for OReilly.
The second round saw OReilly back off and let the Azeri come on to him. That resulted in Musalov landing a number of lefts, and although OReilly managed to counter wellhe lost the round 3-0.
That made it a awinner-takes-all scenario in the third round, with both fighters poised at 19 points apiece. The Azeri dominated with powerful right hooks for the first 90 seconds, but the second 90 was more impressive from OReilly, as he upped the gears and pumped combinations and uppercuts to turn it around and win the round 3-0 and the fight on a unanimous decision.
There was also good news forBelfast's Sean McComb. The Irishmans semi-final conqueror, Azeri fighter Albert Selimov, won lightweight gold today against Frances Sofiane Oumiha.
Thatwinguarantees McComb a place in the World Championships in Qatar in Octoberas the semi-final loser to the eventual champion.
Badminton
Irish mixed doubles duo Sam and Chloe Magee have lost their European Games mixed doubles semi-final clash at the European Games in Baku, Azerbaijan.
The top seeds lost in straight games21-12, 23-21, to the French duo ofGaetanMittelheisser and Audrey Fontaine,in a match lasting 38 minutes.
The Magees take home a bronze as there is no third-place play-off.
It is Sam's second bronze of the Games after collecting a bronze with his brother Joshua in the men's doubles yesterday.
Swimming
Emma Reid failed to make the 50m butterfly final after finishing eighth in her semi-final in a time of 28.04, over half a second behind heat winner Caroline Pilhatsch of Poland.
Reidhad earlier made the semis with atime of 28:16 and fifth place in her heat, which made herjoint 14th-fastest qualifier.
Reid's compatriots Danielle Hill and Niamh Kilgallen didn't make the cut, however, with overall placingsof 37th and 42nd respectivelyleaving them well outside the qualification spots.
Andrew Moore, James Brown and Benjamin Doyleall swam in the 400m individual medley heats, but none of the trio made the final, with finishesof seventh, fifthand sixth respectivelyplacing them30th, 31st and 33rd overall and out of the qualification spots for the final.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:07:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tens of thousands attend Pride Parade in Dublin</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/711057-tens-of-thousands-attend-pride-parade-in-dublin/</Link>
        <Description>Tens of thousands of people attended Dublin's annual Pride Parade in the city centre, the first event of its kind since the passing of the same-sex marriage referendum.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saturday 27 June 2015 23.07
1 of 2
Tens of thousands marched across Dublin city centre
This is the first Pride Parade since the passing of the referendum on same-sex marriage
Tens of thousands of people attended Dublin's annual Pride Parade in the city centre , the first paradeof its kind since the passing of the same-sex marriage referendum.
Organisers have said it was the biggest turnout in the history of the event.
The march was led by a float with a banner that read, "the future is equal", while many participants waved rainbow flags.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:06:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Polls indicate drop in support for Labour and SF</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/711065-red-c-poll/</Link>
        <Description>Support for the Labour party and Sinn Féin has fallen in two latest opinion polls.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fianna Fil are up one point to 20%.
Sinn Fin stands at 18%, a drop of three points.
The biggest shift in support is the five point increase for Independents and smaller parties.
That group is on 27% according to this poll.
A separate nationwide Sunday Independent/Millward Brown also indicates support for Labour andSinn Fin has declined.
Excluding those who were undecided,Fine Gael stand at 29%, up four points from the last comparable poll in April, Labour are down two points to6%,Fianna Fil stand at 23% up four points,Sinn Fin stands at 21% down three points andindependents and smaller parties stand at 21%, down two points.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:03:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Katie Taylor: I want to be the greatest</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/sport/boxing/2015/0627/711056-katie-taylor-i-want-to-be-the-greatest/</Link>
        <Description>Ireland's Olympic champion Katie Taylor said she wanted to go down as the greatest female boxer of all time after she added a European Games gold medal to her glittering list of titles on Saturday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Katie Taylor: I want to be the greatest
Updated: Saturday, 27 Jun 2015 18:03 | Comments
Comments
Katie Taylor stands to attention for Amhrn na bhFiann as Olympic Council of Ireland, and European Games, president Pat Hickey (second left) looks on
Ireland's Olympic champion Katie Taylor said she wanted to go down as the greatest female boxer of all time after she added a European Games gold medal to her glittering list of titles on Saturday.
      
The 28-year-old lightweight, Olympic, five-times world and six-times European champion, registered a unanimous points victory over Frenchwoman Estelle Mossely to claim her country's first gold medal in Baku, and her 18th major international title.
      
"I want to go down in the history books as one of the greatest female boxers of all time and I think I'm on the right path," Taylor, one of the highest-profile athletes at the continental games, told reporters at the Crystal Hall.
      
"It's definitely [mission accomplished]. I am European Games champion now as well as Olympic champion, European champion and world champion.
      
"I've got every single major title out there so it's great to add this one to the list," she added.
      
"When you're so consistent people have to stand up and take notice. I don't think people recognise or praise consistency enough."
"I want to go down in the history books as one of the greatest female boxers of all time and I think I'm on the right path" - Katie Taylor
Saturday's victory was not without its concerns, however, and though Taylor looked strong throughout, the 22-year-old Mossely landed a number of damaging punches.
      
Taylor was also tested in a tense semi-final victory against Azerbaijan's Yana Alekseevna in a weight division that is increasingly competitive.
      
Victory in the inaugural multi-sport continental games was the 18th major title of her illustrious career but Taylor said her desire to remain the dominant fighter in the division had not dwindled.
      
"I'm as hungry now as I ever was, maybe even more hungry," Taylor, whose medal was presented by compatriot and president of the European Olympic Committees (EOC) Patrick Hickey, added.
      
"I just want to continue to improve and add to that list (of titles). There's a lot of people on the way up who want to take my place so it's up to me to continue to improve.
      
"It's great just to continue to produce great performances and collect these gold medals all the time. Europe is the strongest continent for boxing. I think it was a great showcase for women's boxing."
Taylor's compatriot Michael O'Reilly beat Azerbaijan's Xaybula Musalov on Saturday to win the men's middleweight title and secure Ireland's second gold and sixth medal overall. 
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:20:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New York prison escapee shot dead by police</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/710993-prisoners-new-york/</Link>
        <Description>One of two prisoners who broke out of a maximum security prison in New York three weeks ago has been shot dead by police.</Description>
        <MainBody>"You never want to see anyone lose their life, but I would remind people that Mr Matt was an escaped murderer from a state prison," New York Governor Andrew Cuomo said at a news conference.
"Mr Matt killed two people that we know about."
Authorities said they have no evidence to confirm the whereabouts of the second escapee but have no reason to believe he was not with Matt recently and still in the area.
Malone is about 43km northwest of the Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, where the convicts staged their elaborate escape and were discovered missing on 6 June.
The manhunt has involved as many as 1,100 law enforcement officers.
Police started focusing the search in the Malone area, just south of the Canadian border, when two burglaries were reported this week at backwoods cabins, and items believed to have been dropped by Matt were found, said Joseph D'Amico, superintendent of the New York State Police.
Authorities were alerted to a third break-in near Malone yesterday.
When officers arrived at that cabin, they confronted Matt in the woods outside, Supt D'Amico said, and warned him to drop the firearm he was holding.
When Matt failed to comply, the Border Patrol agents shot and killed him, even though the escapee fired no shots of his own, the superintendent said. He declined to elaborate further.
In making their escape three weeks ago, Matt and Sweat cut through the walls of their adjoining cells and sneaked along a catwalk to a steam pipe, then crawled through it and climbed out of a manhole outside the prison walls.
Two prison workers have been charged with aiding them.
Gene Palmer, 57, a corrections officer for 27 years, was suspended without pay from his job, the New York State Department of Corrections and Community Supervision said.
He is accused of bringing hacksaw blades and a screwdriver bit to the inmates, hidden in frozen hamburger meat supplied by Joyce Mitchell, 51, a training supervisor in the prison tailor shop.
She also has been charged in connection with the escape.
Palmer also let the men slip behind their cell walls onto a prison catwalk to hide contraband and alter electrical wiring so they could cook in their cells, according to court documents.
Matt was convicted in the 1997 torture, murder and dismemberment of his boss in Tonawanda, New York, and was sentenced to 25 years to life.
Sweat was serving a life sentence after his conviction in the shooting death of a Broome County Sheriff's deputy on 4 July, 2002.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:21:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Numerous arrests follow Kuwait mosque bombing</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/711038-kuwait-mosque-bomb/</Link>
        <Description>Kuwait's interior ministry has detained amongst others the owner of a vehicle which a suicide bomber used to get to a Shia Muslim mosque where he blew himself up, killing 27 and wounding 200 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saturday 27 June 2015 20.21
27 people were killed during Friday prayers at Kuwait City's Grand Mosque
Kuwait's interior ministry has detained amongst others the owner of a vehicle which a suicide bomber used to get to a Shia Muslim mosque where he blew himself up, killing 27 and wounding 200 people.
The self-styled Islamic State group claimed responsibility for the country's worst militant attack yesterday, one of threeon three continentsapparently linked to group.
In Tunisia, a gunman killed 38 people including Western tourists on a beach, and in France a decapitated body was found after an attacker rammed his car into a gas container, triggering an explosion.
The Kuwati interior ministry said it was now looking for the driver who vanished shortly after yesterdays blast.
A security source said "numerous arrests" had been made in connection with the bombing, which government officials said was intended to stir enmity between Kuwait's Sunni majority and Shia minority.
Two Iranian nationals were among those killed, a foreign ministry spokeswoman said.
A mass funeral for most of those killed will be held at Kuwait City's Grand Mosque later today and a day of national mourning has been declared.
Shia are between 15% and 30% of the population of Kuwait, a mostly Sunni country where members of both communities live side by side with little apparent friction.
"We will cut the evil hand that interferes with our homeland's security," Interior Minister Sheikh Mohammed al Khaled al Sabah was quoted as saying by KUNA.
Kuwait has stepped up security to the highest level at state-run oil conglomerate Kuwait Petroleum Corp (KPC) and its affiliates, KUNA also reported.
Islamic State named the bomber as Abu Suleiman al-Muwahed and said on social media that he had targeted a "temple of the apostates" - a term the group uses to refer to Shia, whom it regards as heretics.
Source: Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:27:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teenager killed in Dublin road collision</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/710996-rta-dublin/</Link>
        <Description>A teenage boy has died after he was struck by a car in Dublin last night.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saturday 27 June 2015 20.27
Boy was taken to the Mater Hospital where he was later pronounced dead
A teenage boy has died after he was struck by a car in Dublin last night.
The 16-year-old was seriously injured when he was hit by the car close to the junction of the Tolka Valley Road and St Helenas Road in Finglas at around 11.30pm.
He was taken to the Mater Hospital where he died in the early hours of this morning.
The driver and a passenger in the car were both uninjured.
The road had been closed for a technical examination but has since reopened.
Garda have appealed for any witnesses to contact Finglas Garda Station on 01 - 6667500, the Garda Confidential Line 1800 666111 or any Garda Station.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:18:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hondurans call for president to stand down</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/711032-honduras/</Link>
        <Description>Thousands of Hondurans have taken to the streets to demand the resignation of President Juan Orlando Hernandez over an ongoing corruption scandal.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saturday 27 June 2015 23.18
Protesters are demanding the resignation of President Hernandez
Thousands of Hondurans have taken to the streets to demand the resignation of President Juan Orlando Hernandez over an ongoing corruption scandal.
The crowd, estimated at around 50,000 people, sounded horns and carried candle-lit torches, demanding the creation of an anti-corruption commission and rejecting dialogue with the president.
Many of the protesters carried banners and held anti-government signs with slogans such as "Honduras is ours" and "This is no president, he's a criminal."
The protesters crowded onto the Tegucigalpas Suyapa Boulevard in a march to the presidential palace, which was guarded by police and soldiers.
The demonstration marked the fifth Friday in which protesters have hit the streets calling for Mr Hernandez to go.
The opposition charge that the president received about $90 million out of more than $300 million they say was skimmed from Honduras's public health system for his 2013 election campaign.
Mr Hernandez has denied wrongdoing and drastically played down the amount.
On Tuesday the president called for a dialogue on forming an organization to combat corruption and impunity, but the protesters have rejected the proposal.
Mr Hernandez was not in the country for the march, but was instead in Guatemala for a meeting of Central American leaders.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:18:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eurozone readies for Greek default</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/710991-greece-economy/</Link>
        <Description>Greece's European partners shut the door on extending a credit lifeline to Athens, leaving it facing a default that could push it out of the euro after the leftist government rejected tough lender demands and put their bailout deal to a referendum.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
In a formal statement, they also implicitly urged Greece to impose capital controls to stabilize its banking system.
The rejection of an extension piled huge pressure on Greek banks, which depend on central bank support to remain afloat, with long lines forming in front of cash machines as people rushed to pull their money out while the banks were still operating normally.
After its surprise decision to call a referendum on the bailout, Athens asked for an extension of Greece's bailout programme beyond Tuesday, the day it must pay 1.6 billion to the International Monetary Fund or default.
But the other 18 members of the euro zone unanimously rejected the request, freezing Greece out of further discussions with the European Central Bank and the IMF on how to deal with the fallout from a historic breach in the EU's 16-year-old currency.
The swift rejection was a startling demonstration of the degree to which Mr Tsipras had alienated the rest of the currency bloc with a final-hour announcement that upended five months of intense talks.
The Eurogroup of finance ministers shut Greece's Yanis Varoufakis from a meeting in Brussels and issued a statement without him, accusing Athens of breaking off negotiations unilaterally.
"The current financial assistance arrangement with Greece will expire on 30 June, 2015, as well as all agreements related to the current Greek programme," it said, making clear its refusal of a grace period to hold the vote.
Mr Varoufakis said the refusal to provide an extension "will certainly damage the credibility of the Eurogroup as a democratic union of partner member states".
"I'm very much afraid that that damage will be permanent."
The Greek parliament met to approve the referendum, with pro-European opposition parties uniting in condemning the decision and fuelling speculation that Mr Tsipras' left wing government may have to resign if voters back the bailout in the 5 July referendum.
Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos was expected to meet former conservative Prime Minister Antonis Samaras on Sunday.
The offer from creditors requires Greece to cut pensions and raise taxes in ways that Mr Tsipras has long argued would deepen one of the worst economic crises of modern times in a country where a quarter of the workforce is already unemployed.
Caught between fears of economic collapse and defiance of the demands from international creditors, many Greeks expressed shock, although opinion polls published in Sunday newspapers pointed to a majority in favour of accepting the bailout terms.
However voters in other euro zone states -- including the bloc's economic powerhouse Germany, other southern states which have suffered austerity in return for EU cash and poor eastern countries with living standards much lower than Greece  have lost patience.
Solution to Greek debt still possible - Michael Noonan
Finance Minister Michael Noonan has indicated it may still be possible to reach a deal between Greece and its creditors.
Minister Noonan said there is still time to cut a deal.
He said he did not have any fears over the euro as,he said, the currency was in a very strong position.
He said he has sympathy for the Greek people and said he would like to see progress made, "even at this late stage."
When asked if he thought Greece should hold a referendum as planned on the bailout deal, Minister Noonan said that was a matter for the Greeks to decide.
'Greece should remain in the euro despite difficulties' -Michel Sapin
Many questions remained over the referendum, which is being called over the terms of a bailout offer that may no longer be on the table.
But with fears growing that the foundations of the eurozone could be fatally weakened if Greece were forced out, French Finance Minister Michel Sapin insisted that Paris, at least, was still prepared to talk.
"The 18 countries, apart from Greece, all said clearly that Greece was in the euro and should remain in the euro whatever the difficulties of the moment," he said.
Although European officials have repeatedly insisted that financial firewalls built during the eurozone debt crisis of the past six years would limit the impact of any "Grexit", the longer-term effects are completely unknown.
Jeroen Dijsselbloem, the Dutch finance minister and chair of the Eurogroup, said Greek lawmakers should think about whether the referendum was wise before agreeing to hold it, essentially appealing directly to the Greek parliament to defy Mr Tsipras when it votes on approving the measure later today.
Underlining the mutual incomprehension that has marked months of often angry exchanges between the Syriza government and its European partners, Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis was still holding out hopes of a deal.
"In these crucial moments, the Greek government is fighting for there to be a last-minute deal by Tuesday," he said after the euro zone had rejected further talks and said it would cutoff financial support from 30 June.
He added the government would be prepared to recommend that voters backed the deal if lenders agreed to improve the terms.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:11:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Irish couple may have died in Tunisia attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0627/710988-tunisia-attack/</Link>
        <Description>Gardaí in Westmeath are liaising with the family of a couple in their 50s from the Athlone area who are believed to have died in a terrorist attack on a beach in Tunisia yesterday.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
One Irish person has been confirmed so far among the 38victims killed yesterday afternoon when a gunman opened fire at a beach resort inSousse.
Lorna Carty , a mother of two,from Robinstown in Co Meath isbelieved to have been on the beach when the attack began.
Shewas in the resort with her husband Declan, who was uninjured, but said to be "absolutely distraught".
Minister for ForeignAffairs CharlieFlanagan has said it will takea period of time to complete a full and formal identification of the victims of the attack.
He said the Irish Ambassador to Spainand Consulareworking closely with the authorities in Tunisia.
Meanwhile, the number of Britons confirmed to have died in the attack has risen to 15.
One Belgian and one German national have also been confirmed dead.
A further 39 people are said to have been wounded in the attack, which has been claimed by the so-called Islamic State group.
Tunisian Prime Minister Habib Essidsaid reserve troops would be called up to reinforce security at "sensitive sites... and places that could be targets of terrorist attacks" after the massacre, the second against tourists in Tunisia this year.
The "exceptional plan to better secure tourist and archaeological sites" will include "deploying armed tourist security officers all along the coast and inside hotels from 1 July," he added.
He also announced that a national anti-terrorism congress would be held in September and that financial rewards would be given to anyone who comes forward with information leading to the capture of any terrorists.
The Department of Foreign Affairs has advised Irish people planning on travelling to Tunisia or who may already be in the country to follow the advice of the Tunisian authorities and maintain contact with tour organisers.
Anyone who may have concerns about family or friends in Tunisia should contact 01-4082000.
Irish embassy staff, including Irish Ambassador to Spain David Cooney, who is also accredited with Tunisia,arrived in Sousse late Fridaynight to provide consular assistance to citizens caught up in the attack.
In a statement, Meath GAA has confirmed that allmatches and training involving Dunderry and Kilmessan have been cancelled until further notice following the killing of Ms Carty in Tunisia.
Her son Simon is part of the Meath senior panel and was a member of the county's U-21 team, while Ms Carty was very involved in the GAA and with her local club Dunderry.
The Leinster SFC semi-final match between Meath and Westmeath in Croke Park tomorrow will go ahead as scheduled.
Glanbia chairman Henry Corbally expressed sympathy to the Carty family.
"This is a terrible tragedy to afflict a highly respected and popular farming family.
"On behalf of all members of Glanbia, I wish to express my deepest sympathy to Lornas husband Declan and their children Simon and Hazel."
The gunman wasa 23-year-old student who disguised himself as a tourist and began firing at holidaymakers on a beach using a Kalashnikov he had hidden in a beach umbrella.
The student, identified as Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani, was reportedly laughing as he carried out the massacre and deliberately selected western tourists, before being shot dead by police.
'Four hours of hell'
Meanwhile, Irish holidaymakers who returned on Friday nightfrom Tunisia described scenes of chaos during the attack at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel.
Many described a large explosion as well as gunfire andpraised hotel staff for helping them.
Marian King from Lucan, who was staying in the hotel, said the last four hours of their holiday had turned into hell.
Speaking at Dublin airport after the Aer Lingus flight from Monastir arrived home she said she and her family had managed to get into a hotel bedroom when the shooting started.
"People were running down the corridors screaming to be let into bedrooms". She described hearing more shooting and hiding in the bathroom for about two hours until after it had it subsided.
Anthony and Betty Tunstead from Glasnevin Avenue in Dublin were part of a group of four who cut their holiday short to come home last night.
MsTunstead described screaming and chaos as the shooting started.
"We went into one room and kept there for a while. I came back out and here's a boyo in the lobby with a machine gun.
"We didnt make eye contact because he was looking to see where he was jumping off the parapet. He didn't see me."
Ms Tunstead said had it been a different day they might not have escaped alive. She said they normally met up with a couple from Meath and would have been sitting with them had they not been about to move hotel.
The group she was with expressed concern for another Irish couple they had been with at the hotel who they believed had been caught up in the shooting, and who they had not heard from.
Cathy Piper from Wicklow was having a beer on the beach when the attack began around noon and says she saw an attacker.
"I saw him from a distance - a guy dressed in black walking along the beach.
She followed a staff member in a side door to safety. "The hotel staff were great. They ran to the creche to get the kids out."
Patricia Sheehan from Dungarvan who was in a hotel 2km from the scene said she contacted the Irish authorities in Dublin, and they kept in contact with her through the day.
"We didnt have any male members of our family with us so we felt a little bit unsafe. I was trying to put people in the complex at ease and keep them up to date," she said.
Denis Purcell from Glasnevin described having to comfort an English man whose fiance was killed. "We were around him talking to him.
"He was devastated trying to find out was she brought to a hospital. It was killing him to think she was still lying inside the hotel."
Mr Purcell said the Tunisian prime minister visited the hotel.
"There was more security for the prime minister than came to the hotel after the explosions," he said.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
