<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="sbs North America News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 03:51:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canadian nabbed for chair balloon flight</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47e7df66/sc/6/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A70Ccanadian0Enabbed0Echair0Eballoon0Eflight/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A Canadian man has been arrested for flying on a chair, strapped to more than a 100 helium-filled balloons, over the city of Calgary.</Description>
        <MainBody>7 Jul 2015 - 9:40pm
Canadian nabbed for chair balloon flight
A Canadian man has been arrested for flying on a chair, strapped to more than a 100 helium-filled balloons, over the city of Calgary.
Source:
A man has been arrested for flying over the Canadian city of Calgary on a chair, strapped to more than a 100 helium-filled balloons, in a scene straight out of the computer-animated film Up.
Calgary police said Daniel Boria, 26, was arrested and charged with mischief causing danger to life.
In a press conference on Monday, the police said Boria used a parachute to land, spraining his ankle in the process.
Boria was released on a $US1,200 ($A1,600) bail and will appear before a judge on July 13.
Police said the incident was a publicity stunt for his cleaning products company.
According to the Calgary Sun daily, the chair used by Boria was found some 65km south of Calgary.
Speaking to the newspaper, Boria said he didn't know what height he managed to reach, but at one point he was flying over a Boeing 747 aeroplane.
"It was the most surreal experience you can ever imagine," he exclaimed.
Boria's stunt on Sunday coincided with the celebration of the Calgary Stampede, considered the world's largest rodeo event and attended by a million people annually.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed Jul 08 01:40:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama shows a looser side on Twitter</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47e5e50c/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cobama0Eshows0Elooser0Eside0Etwitter/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US President Barack Obama is taking to Twitter to muse about sports, pop culture, even Supreme Court rulings - at all hours of the day.</Description>
        <MainBody>7 Jul 2015 - 5:44pm
Obama shows a looser side on Twitter
US President Barack Obama is taking to Twitter to muse about sports, pop culture, even Supreme Court rulings - at all hours of the day.
Source:
0
Forget the prime-time interviews or the formal, choreographed news conferences.
The White House has used Twitter to promote the president's views for years, but mostly in a highly scripted manner, with tweets composed by press aides and released at strategic times.
Only occasionally would Obama post to Twitter himself, identifying a bona fide presidential tweet by appending his initials.
Now Obama is composing his own tweets almost daily, weighing in on issues of the day from any location, without the filter of his press office.
He's been tweeting with increased frequency since inaugurating his personal twitter account, (at)POTUS, earlier this summer.
"Hello, Twitter! It's Barack. Really!" Obama wrote in May.
"Six years in, they're finally giving me my own account."
So how, exactly, does a president tweet?
Obama, who has been known to use an iPad and a Blackberry, can send tweets from a variety of secure devices, according to the White House.
Obama gives his team a heads up before he tweets, and his staff says he sometimes agrees to tweet about topics his aides suggests.
In the six weeks since Obama kicked off the account, he's already amassed more than three million followers.
He follows only 66 Twitter users - mostly sports teams, federal agencies and top government officials.
He briefly set a record for the attracting a million followers faster than any other Twitter user.
But Obama's record was quickly broken by Caitlyn Jenner.
Josh Earnest, the White House press secretary, says Obama was enthusiastic about having the chance to use venues like Twitter to communicate with people.
"He's really taken to the idea," Earnest said.
A LOOK AT SOME OF OBAMA'S RECENT TWEETS:
GAY MARRIAGE
Obama's first reaction to the Supreme Court's historic ruling legalising gay marriage nationwide came not in a press release or a Rose Garden appearance, but through his Twitter account.
"Today is a big step in our march toward equality," Obama tweeted on June 26.
"Gay and lesbian couples now have the right to marry, just like anyone else."
HOLY GUACAMOLE
When an enthusiastic debate broke out on Twitter this month about including peas in guacamole, Obama took to Twitter to say he had no appetite for the added ingredient.
He responded to the pea-laden recipe in The New York Times during a "Twitter town hall" - a medium the White House has been trying out in which the president takes questions from Americans directly on Twitter.
"Respect the NYT, but not buying peas in guac," the president wrote, offering his personal recipe: "Onions, garlic, hot peppers. Classic."
BRING IN THE BAND
After Obama tweeted that he'd spent his morning listening to the new album from The Black Keys, the rock band tweeted back asking if they could use Air Force One for their upcoming gigs.
A few hours later - at 8pm on a weeknight - Obama tweeted his response to the band: "It's not mine; just a loaner. Maybe you can come play at the White House sometime instead?"
No word on whether the group will be rocking out at 1600 Pennsylvania Ave.
NO. 1 FAN
Obama congratulated the American team and midfielder Carli Lloyd for their victory on Sunday night in the Women's World Cup.
"What a win for Team USA!" Obama wrote, adding: "Your country is so proud of all of you. Come visit the White House with the World Cup soon."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 21:14:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dalai Lama celebrates 80th birthday in US</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47e42d88/sc/11/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cdalai0Elama0Ecelebrates0E80Ath0Ebirthday0Eus/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Dalai Lama has celebrated his 80th birthday in the United States.</Description>
        <MainBody>Dalai Lama celebrates 80th birthday in US
The Dalai Lama has celebrated his 80th birthday in the United States.
Source:
0
The 14th Dalai Lama, spiritual leader of Tibetan Buddhism, has turned 80 surrounded by admirers at a public summit in southern California.
The Dalai Lama, whose name is Tenzin Gyatso, celebrated on Monday at the Global Compassion Summit, a three-day conference in the cities of Anaheim and Irvine.
The monk spent the day as the guest of honour at public discussion panels on the subjects of climate change action and "wisdom, vision and experience" at the University of California, Irvine.
He was lauded by admirers from Nobel laureate Jody Williams to singer Gloria Estefan and applauded by the more than 5000 people in the audience.
At the conference's start the day before, thousands of fans sang Happy Birthday as the spiritual leader blew out candles on a towering golden cake, then cut himself a slice.
His birthday wish was "the same as all beings. I wish to live a happy life," he said on Sunday, according to his website.
"My life is dedicated to the well-being of others. If humanity is happy, then I'll be happy, because each of us is dependent on others," the Dalai Lama said.
Organisers began the celebration on Sunday, to mark the birthday in his birthplace of Tibet.
The Dalai Lama has lived in exile in Dharamsala, India, since 1959.
The Central Tibetan Authority, Tibet's government in exile, celebrated his birthday there according to the Tibetan calendar, on June 21.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:16:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boston Marathon bomber files for new trial</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47e2062f/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cboston0Emarathon0Ebomber0Efiles0Enew0Etrial/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Lawyers for Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev have applied for a new trial, saying it is "required in the interests of justice".</Description>
        <MainBody>7 Jul 2015 - 8:00am
Boston Marathon bomber files for new trial
This courtroom sketch shows Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, right, stands before US District Judge George O'Toole Jr. as he addresses the court during his sentencing on June 24, 2015
Lawyers for Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev have applied for a new trial, saying it is "required in the interests of justice".
Source:
0
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev has filed a motion for a new trial, less than two weeks after he was formally sentenced to death for the 2013 attack.
Tsarnaev's lawyers filed a preliminary motion for a new trial on Monday for his conviction and death sentence. The motion did not contain any details on what grounds they plan to argue, saying only that a new trial is "required in the interests of justice."
The 21-year-old Tsarnaev was convicted of 30 charges in the bombing, which killed three people and injured more than 260.
The same jury recommended the death penalty, and a federal judge on June 24 sentenced him to death.
Tsarnaev's lawyers call the motion a "placeholder" until they can file a more detailed motion next month.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:09:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Oreos go thin for &amp;#039;sophisticated&amp;#039; air</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47e20630/sc/23/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A70Coreos0Ego0Ethin0Esophisticated0Eair/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Oreo Thins are being added to Mondelez International's permanent lineup as the company goes for a "grown-up" snack.</Description>
        <MainBody>7 Jul 2015 - 6:04am
Oreos go thin for 'sophisticated' air
Oreo Thins are being added to Mondelez International's permanent lineup as the company goes for a "grown-up" snack.
Source:
0
Oreos are getting a skinny new look, and its maker says the new cookie is a "sophisticated" snack for grown-ups that isn't meant to be twisted or dunked.
Mondelez International Inc says it will add Oreo Thins to its permanent lineup in the US starting next week.
The cookies look like regular Oreos and have a similar cookie-to-filling ratio, except that they're slimmer.
That means four of the cookies contain 140 calories, compared with 160 calories for three regular Oreos.
And since they're for adults, Oreo says they weren't designed to be twisted open or dunked.
"If people want to do that, it's clearly up to them," said Janda Lukin, senior director of Oreo for North America at parent company Mondelez International.
In explaining what exactly made them more grown-up, she said that if regular Oreos are like pancakes, then Oreo Thins would be like crepes.
Although the original Oreos started in the US in 1912, Americans won't be the first to taste the Thins.
The slimmer cookies were rolled out last year in China to address the company's tumbling cookie sales in the country.
Lukin said the slimmer cookies helped win back "lapsed users" in China, or younger women who wanted something that wasn't quite as rich. In the first eight months, she said Oreo Thins generated $US40 million ($A53 million) in sales.
Mondelez CEO Irene Rosenfeld has noted the success of the Thins in China and says the company will make them available "around the world".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 15:58:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hillary Clinton accuses China of hacking US computers</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d646e5/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A50Chillary0Eclinton0Eaccuses0Echina0Ehacking0Eus0Ecomputers/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>U.S. Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton accused China on Saturday of stealing commercial secrets and "huge amounts of government information," and of trying to "hack into everything that doesn't move in America."</Description>
        <MainBody>5 Jul 2015 - 7:58am
Hillary Clinton accuses China of hacking US computers
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Rodham Clinton speaks during a campaign event, Friday, July 3, 2015, in Hanover, N.H. (AP Photo/Elise Amendola)
U.S. Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton accused China on Saturday of stealing commercial secrets and "huge amounts of government information," and of trying to "hack into everything that doesn't move in America."
Source:
Reuters
5 Jul 2015 - 7:58 AM UPDATED5Jul2015-7:58AM
Clinton's language on China appeared to be far stronger thanthat usually used by President Barack Obama's Democraticadministration.
Speaking at a campaign event in New Hampshire, Clinton saidshe wanted to see China's peaceful rise.
"But we also have to be fully vigilant, China's military isgrowing very quickly, they're establishing militaryinstallations that again threaten countries we have treatieswith, like the Philippines because they are building oncontested property," said Clinton, who was secretary of statefrom 2009 to 2013.
"They're also trying to hack into everything that doesn'tmove in America. Stealing commercial secrets ... from defensecontractors, stealing huge amounts of government information,all looking for an advantage," she said.
Clinton is the front-runner to win the Democraticnomination for the November 2016 presidential election.
Asked about the remarks, a White House official declined tocomment.
In the most recent case involving suspicions of Chinesehacking, Obama administration officials have said China is thetop suspect in the massive hacking of a U.S. government agencythat compromised the personnel records of at least 4.2 millioncurrent and former government workers.
China has denied hacking into the computers of the U.S.Office of Personnel Management.
Iran and Putin
Clinton also addressed the current talks over Iran's nuclearprogram and had strong words for Tehran.
She said that even if a deal is reached with Iran, Tehran's"aggressiveness will not end" and it will remain a principalstate sponsor of terrorism.
Clinton said she hoped that "a strong verifiable deal" wouldbe reached at talks in Vienna between world powers and Iran.
But she added that even with an agreement, "They willcontinue to be the principal state sponsor of terrorism. Theywill continue to destabilize governments in the region andbeyond. They will continue to use their proxies like Hezbollah. And they will continue to be an existential threat to Israel."
The United States, other world powers and Iran have set aJuly 7 deadline to reach a deal to curb Tehran's nuclear programin exchange for a lifting of sanctions that have crippled Iran'seconomy.
At the campaign event, Clinton also said the United Stateshas to be "much smarter" about how it deals with RussianPresident Vladimir Putin's territorial ambitions.
She said Putin's moves to expand Russia's boundaries, suchas the annexation of Crimea last year, posed a challenge for theUnited States but she touted her experience as America's chiefdiplomat.
She noted that because of NATO members' agreement to protectfellow members, had Ukraine been a member of NATO when Crimeawas annexed, "that would have caused us to have to respond."
She added on Putin: "I've dealt with him. I know him. He'snot an easy man ... But I don't think there is any substituteother than constant engagement."
Reporting by Amanda Becker; Writing by Eric Beech; Editing byFrances Kerry and Tomasz Janowski.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 15:15:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Girl killed by jumping fish in Florida</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d662cb/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A50Cgirl0Ekilled0Ejumping0Efish0Eflorida/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A leaping sturgeon has struck and killed a five-year-old girl in a boat on Florida's Suwanne River.</Description>
        <MainBody>5 Jul 2015 - 7:24am
Girl killed by jumping fish in Florida
A leaping sturgeon has struck and killed a five-year-old girl in a boat on Florida's Suwanne River.
Source:
0
A five-year-old Florida girl riding in a boat has died after a sturgeon leapt from the Suwannee River and struck her.
Wildlife officials said Jaylon Rippy died after being struck on Thursday night. Her mother and nine-year-old brother were also injured and taken to a Gainesville hospital. Their condition was not known.
The Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission said it was the first fatality recorded from a sturgeon strike on the Suwannee River. Four people have been injured by jumping sturgeon this year.
The fish are known for leaping more than two metres above the water. They can grow up to 2.4 metres long, weigh up to 90kg and can cause serious injuries.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 23:02:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wheelchair man charged with US bank theft</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d310ce/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Cwheelchair0Eman0Echarged0Eus0Ebank0Etheft/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A man in a wheelchair, who is said to have robbed a New York bank, was recognised from police images when he went to a hospital two days after the theft.</Description>
        <MainBody>4 Jul 2015 - 4:18pm
Wheelchair man charged with US bank theft
A man in a wheelchair, who is said to have robbed a New York bank, was recognised from police images when he went to a hospital two days after the theft.
Source:
0
A New York City man in a wheelchair has been arrested two days after he pocketed $US1212 ($A1585) in a daytime bank robbery, authorities say.
Kelvin Dennison, 23, was picked up by officers at a hospital two days after he rolled into a Santander Bank branch in Queens on Monday afternoon and claimed to be armed, police said.
"Give me all you have," he told a teller, according to court papers. "I have a gun."
The teller then passed him the cash before he pushed himself out of the bank and then fled down the street in his wheelchair, police said.
Authorities released an image of a man in a wheelchair leaving the bank taken from a store's surveillance camera.
When Dennison went to a Queens hospital two days later, someone recognised him and called police, prosecutors said.
Authorities didn't say why Dennison went to the hospital.
When he was questioned by investigators, Dennison told them he was in a wheelchair after being injured in a shooting, a spokeswoman for the Queens district attorney's office told the New York Times.
Dennison was charged with robbery and is being held on $US15,000 bail.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 19:17:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alligator kills swimmer in southern US</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d294a7/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Calligator0Ekills0Eswimmer0Esouthern0Eus/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US police say an alligator has killed a man in Texas.</Description>
        <MainBody>Alligator kills swimmer in southern US
(Stock/AAP)
US police say an alligator has killed a man in Texas.
Source:
A US man has been killed after being attacked by an alligator while he was swimming in a Texas bayou, news reports say.
The 28-year-old man ignored warning signs posted along the edge of the water, the reports said.
He was attacked immediately after jumping into the water, KFDM television in Beaumont, Texas reported, quoting eye-witnesses.
A female companion who had gone swimming with him tried to pull the screaming man out of the water.
She was uninjured.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 18:54:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Truth commission on US invasion of Panama</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d26182/sc/11/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Ctruth0Ecommission0Eus0Einvasion0Epanama/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A truth commission will examine the 1989 US invasion of Panama, the country's foreign minister says.</Description>
        <MainBody>4 Jul 2015 - 3:07pm
Truth commission on US invasion of Panama
A relative of victims of the US invasion to Panama in 1989 adjusts a little flag as he visits a cemetery in Panama City
A truth commission will examine the 1989 US invasion of Panama, the country's foreign minister says.
Source:
0
A truth commission will examine the US invasion of Panama, which took place more than 25 years ago and toppled military dictator General Manuel Noriega.
The commission will look at victims of the military operation launched by the United States at the end of 1989, Panama Foreign Minister Isabel Saint Malo said.
The number of people estimated killed in operation Just Cause is more than 3000, including numerous civilians.
But the exact number of victims and their identities isn't known because many bodies were buried in mass graves.
After a long period of co-operation with the US, Noriega fell out of favour with the country toward the end of the 1980s because of his ties with the Medellin drug cartel and human rights abuses.
Noriega, 81, spent more than two decades in prison in the US and France on drug trafficking and money laundering charges.
He is serving out the last years of his sentence in Panama.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 18:33:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mexico close to releasing vigilante leader</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d2a3fe/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Cmexico0Eclose0Ereleasing0Evigilante0Eleader/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Mexican authorities may soon release a founder of the vigilante movement who fought against a powerful drug cartel in the western state of Michoacan.</Description>
        <MainBody>4 Jul 2015 - 10:36am
Mexico close to releasing vigilante leader
Mexican authorities may soon release a founder of the vigilante movement who fought against a powerful drug cartel in the western state of Michoacan.
Source:
0
Mexican authorities say they are near to freeing Jose Manuel Mireles, a founder of the self-defence movement that rose up to fight an entrenched drug cartel in the western state of Michoacan.
The Attorney General's office says it is withdrawing an appeal to a petition filed by Mireles' lawyer to free him, essentially allowing his release.
Mireles, who became the face of the vigilante movement, has been held for a year after being arrested in an armoured vehicle carrying weapons and drugs.
His arrest came around the time that he refused to co-operate with the federal government's conversion of self-defence groups to rural police.
Michoacan's vigilante movement began in February 2013 after farmers and ranchers grew tired of the Knights Templar drug cartel's reign of kidnapping, murder and extortion.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 17:24:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NZ entrant takes on US hot dog comp rivals</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d259e1/sc/13/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Cnz0Eentrant0Etakes0Eus0Ehot0Edog0Ecomp0Erivals/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>New Zealander Nela Zisser says she can out-eat her rivals in the US July Fourth hot dog eating contest.</Description>
        <MainBody>4 Jul 2015 - 2:28pm
NZ entrant takes on US hot dog comp rivals
Brooklyn Borough President Eric Adams watches Joey Chestnut, left, and Matt Stonie, right, during a news conference to promote the upcoming Nathan's Famous Fourth of July Hot-Dog Eating Contest  Friday, July 3, 2015, at Brooklyn Borough Hall in New York. (AP Photo/Frank Franklin II)
New Zealander Nela Zisser says she can out-eat her rivals in the US July Fourth hot dog eating contest.
Source:
0
Four avid eaters, including a New Zealander, have hit the scales ahead of the United States' annual July Fourth hot dog eating contest at Coney Island's Nathan's Famous.
Reigning champion Joey Chestnut joined past winners at the weigh-in on Friday ahead of the 99-year-old Independence Day boardwalk tradition.
The hot dogs will be served on Saturday morning.
Chestnut tipped the scales at a hearty 230 pounds (104.33kg) while Michelle Lesco ranked the lightest competitor at 112 pounds (50.80kg).
New Zealand native Nela Zisser says she can out-eat her male counterparts. She previously won a pizza-eating contest.
The event also featured a ceremonial stare down between the competitors.
Chestnut broke a world record in 2013 when he scoffed down 69 soggy dogs in 10 minutes.
As an eight-year champion, he holds the Mustard Yellow International Belt after eating 61 hot dogs at last year's contest.
This year, he'll face off against former champ Takeru Kobayashi.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 17:22:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Mormon leader Boyd K Packer dies at 90</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d259e3/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A40Cus0Emormon0Eleader0Eboyd0Ek0Epacker0Edies0E90A/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Mormon leader Boyd K Packer has died at the age of 90, a church spokesman says.</Description>
        <MainBody>4 Jul 2015 - 9:50am
US Mormon leader Boyd K Packer dies at 90
This April 6, 2014, file photo, shows President Boyd K. Packer, of the Quorum of Twelve Apostles, of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, addressing the 184th Annual General Conference of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, in Salt Lake City.  (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer, File)
Mormon leader Boyd K Packer has died at the age of 90, a church spokesman says.
Source:
0
Mormon leader Boyd K Packer, president of the faith's highest governing body, has died at the age of 90.
Packer died on Friday afternoon at his home in Salt Lake City from natural causes, church spokesman Eric Hawkins said in a statement.
Packer was next in line to become president of the Salt Lake City-based Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.
He had been a member of the church's Quorum of the Twelve Apostles since 1970.
The group is modelled after Jesus Christ's apostles and serves under the church president and his two councillors.
He is the second member of quorum to die in recent months. L Tom Perry died on May 30 from cancer.
Replacements for both of them are expected in the coming months, possibly at the church's conference in October.
Quorum member Russell M Nelson, 90, now becomes the leader who would take Mormon President Thomas S Monson's place.
Monson is 87 years old and church officials have said he's feeling the effects of his age.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 23:07:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Body of US prison escapee released</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47d207e4/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cbody0Eus0Eprison0Eescapee0Ereleased/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The body of Richard Matt, who escaped from a US prison and was shot dead while on the run, has been released to a funeral home.</Description>
        <MainBody>4 Jul 2015 - 6:42am
Body of US prison escapee released
The body of Richard Matt, who escaped from a US prison and was shot dead while on the run, has been released to a funeral home.
Source:
0
The body of a convicted murderer who broke out of prison and was fatally shot after three weeks on the run has been released to a funeral home as his fellow escapee continued his recovery at a hospital under heavy guard.
Richard Matt's body was being transported from a northern New York state hospital to a funeral home before being taken about six hours away to Tonawanda, in western New York, said the director of the Heald Funeral Home in Plattsburgh on Thursday.
Matt's estranged son in the Buffalo area had said he would claim the body, but could not be reached for comment.
Matt escaped from the Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora on June 6 with David Sweat, another convicted killer.
Matt was shot dead on June 26, while Sweat was shot and captured on June 28 and is listed in fair condition at an Albany hospital.
The escape by Sweat and Matt launched a massive 23-day man hunt amid the rugged northern New York terrain involving more than 1100 law enforcement officers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 20:11:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US woman&amp;#039;s measles death first since 2003</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47cb3fdf/sc/14/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cus0Ewomans0Emeasles0Edeath0Efirst0E20A0A3/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A woman who died from measles in the US had a compromised immune system and lacked some common symptoms of the disease, officials say.</Description>
        <MainBody>3 Jul 2015 - 12:18pm
US woman's measles death first since 2003
A woman who died from measles in the US had a compromised immune system and lacked some common symptoms of the disease, officials say.
Source:
0
A woman in Washington state died from measles in the Spring, the first measles death in the US since 2003 and the first in the state since 1990, health officials said.
The woman lacked some of the measles' common symptoms, such as a rash, so the infection was not discovered until an autopsy, Washington State Department of Health spokesman Donn Moyer said on Thursday.
It is the 11th case of measles in Washington state this year, Moyer said, following an outbreak of measles at Disneyland in California late last year.
The Disneyland outbreak sparked an intense debate around America about mandating vaccinations for schoolchildren, which some parents oppose, and eventually sickened more than 140 people across the country and in Mexico and Canada.
Measles is highly contagious and spreads when an infected person breathes, coughs or sneezes, however, death is extremely rare, Moyer said.
Officials didn't say whether the woman was vaccinated, but they did note she had a compromised immune system.
They withheld her age to protect her identity but said she was not elderly.
The woman was hospitalised for several health conditions in the Spring at a facility in Clallam County, which covers the northern part of the Olympic Peninsula.
She was there at the same time as a person who later developed a rash and was contagious for measles, Moyer says and it was then she was most likely exposed.
An autopsy concluded the cause of death was pneumonia due to measles.
"This tragic situation illustrates the importance of immunising as many people as possible to provide a high level of community protection against measles," Moyer said.
"People with compromised immune systems cannot be vaccinated against measles. Even when vaccinated, they may not have a good immune response when exposed to disease; they may be especially vulnerable to disease outbreaks."
The last active case of measles in Washington was reported in late April.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 18:38:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US park bison gore woman, injure teen</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47cac098/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cus0Epark0Ebison0Egore0Ewoman0Einjure0Eteen/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A 68-year-old woman and a 19-year-old woman are the latest victims from Bison attacks in the popular Yellowstone National Park.</Description>
        <MainBody>3 Jul 2015 - 10:42am
US park bison gore woman, injure teen
A 68-year-old woman and a 19-year-old woman are the latest victims from Bison attacks in the popular Yellowstone National Park.
Source:
0
Bison in Yellowstone National Park have gored a woman and tossed a teenager into the air in the latest run-ins with the massive animals during tourist season.
The National Park Service says a bison gored a 68-year-old woman on Wednesday on a trail near Yellowstone Lake.
She was taken to a hospital, but her condition wasn't immediately known.
On June 23, a bison tossed a 19-year-old off-duty park concession employee who was off trail.
She was treated and released from a hospital for minor injuries.
In other encounters, the animals have gored a 16-year-old girl and tossed an Australian tourist in the air, both of whom suffered serious injuries.
Yellowstone prohibits people from getting within 25 metres of bison or other large animals and within 100 metres of bears and wolves.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 17:33:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Backlash after sister of Charleston accused seeks donations for wedding</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47cacdec/sc/42/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cbacklash0Eafter0Esister0Echarleston0Eaccused0Eseeks0Edonations0Ewedding/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>An online campaign by Dylann Roof's sister asking for donations to cover the cost of postponing her wedding has backfired.</Description>
        <MainBody>Backlash after sister of Charleston accused seeks donations for wedding
"The Charleston Massacre took place and our lives were changed forever."
An online campaign by Dylann Roof's sister asking for donations to cover the cost of postponing her wedding has backfired.
Source:
SBS
3 Jul 2015 - 9:33 AM UPDATED3Jul2015-10:14AM
Amber Roof and her fianc were set to marry on June 21, four days after her brother gunned down nine people at a church in Charleston, South Carolina.
"The Charleston Massacre took place and our lives were forever changed," Roof wrote on the GoFundMe page set up this week. "The media abused our privacy and published all of our wedding information and destroyed our dream day. Destroying the first day of Michael and my life together."
Mr Roof was hoping to raise around $6,500 (5000 USD) to cover "lost wedding costs, to pay bills, and to send us on our dream honeymoon." She also pledged to donate 10 per cent of the proceeds to Emanuel AME church - the scene of her brother's crime.
"We would like the chance to start our lives on a positive note," Roof wrote on her page. "Therefore, we have decided to start a Go Fund Me account. We know money cannot replace the wedding we lost and our perfect day, however it will help us to create new memories and a new start with our new family."
However, she removed the campaign after it sparked backlash.
As of midday Thursday, the "Fresh Start For Michael and Amber" campaign had raised around $2000 (1,600 USD), and provoked mixed responses.
"I can't imagine what you are going through. I too have a selfish brother that has ruined a few of my special days. A situation like this could have easily been me since my brother has threatened to kill my father on several occasions. Prayers for you and your husband. I hope you can overcome the actions of your brother and know they don't reflect on you," wrote Megan P, along with a $10 donation.
"THE NERVE OF YOU!!!" read another comment. "If its just about getting married then go to the court house. But how dare u set up a gofundme under these circumstances."
GoFundMe Media cofirmed Amber Roof would still have access to all the funds raised.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 17:33:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Backlash after sister of Charleston gunman seeks donations for wedding</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47cab8bf/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cbacklash0Eafter0Esister0Echarleston0Egunman0Eseeks0Edonations0Ewedding/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>An online campaign by Dylann Roof's sister asking for donations to cover the cost of postponing her wedding has backfired.</Description>
        <MainBody>Backlash after sister of Charleston accused seeks donations for wedding
"The Charleston Massacre took place and our lives were changed forever."
An online campaign by Dylann Roof's sister asking for donations to cover the cost of postponing her wedding has backfired.
Source:
SBS
3 Jul 2015 - 9:33 AM UPDATED3Jul2015-10:14AM
Amber Roof and her fianc were set to marry on June 21, four days after her brother gunned down nine people at a church in Charleston, South Carolina.
"The Charleston Massacre took place and our lives were forever changed," Roof wrote on the GoFundMe page set up this week. "The media abused our privacy and published all of our wedding information and destroyed our dream day. Destroying the first day of Michael and my life together."
Mr Roof was hoping to raise around $6,500 (5000 USD) to cover "lost wedding costs, to pay bills, and to send us on our dream honeymoon." She also pledged to donate 10 per cent of the proceeds to Emanuel AME church - the scene of her brother's crime.
"We would like the chance to start our lives on a positive note," Roof wrote on her page. "Therefore, we have decided to start a Go Fund Me account. We know money cannot replace the wedding we lost and our perfect day, however it will help us to create new memories and a new start with our new family."
However, she removed the campaign after it sparked backlash.
As of midday Thursday, the "Fresh Start For Michael and Amber" campaign had raised around $2000 (1,600 USD), and provoked mixed responses.
"I can't imagine what you are going through. I too have a selfish brother that has ruined a few of my special days. A situation like this could have easily been me since my brother has threatened to kill my father on several occasions. Prayers for you and your husband. I hope you can overcome the actions of your brother and know they don't reflect on you," wrote Megan P, along with a $10 donation.
"THE NERVE OF YOU!!!" read another comment. "If its just about getting married then go to the court house. But how dare u set up a gofundme under these circumstances."
GoFundMe Media cofirmed Amber Roof would still have access to all the funds raised.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 17:22:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Air strike kills IS leader in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47caa513/sc/6/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cair0Estrike0Ekills0Eleader0Esyria/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Pentagon says the death of an Islamic State leader in Syria will impact the group's ability to integrate foreign fighters into the Syria/Iraq conflict.</Description>
        <MainBody>3 Jul 2015 - 11:24am
Air strike kills IS leader in Syria
IS leader who recruited fighters for the group has been killed in a coalition air strike in Syria. (AAP)
The Pentagon says the death of an Islamic State leader in Syria will impact the group's ability to integrate foreign fighters into the Syria/Iraq conflict.
Source:
0
A senior Islamic State leader who recruited funds and fighters and procured weapons for the jihadists has been killed in a coalition air strike in Syria.
Tariq bin Tahar al-Awni al-Harzi was killed in the northern city of Shaddadi on June 16, Pentagon spokesman Navy Captain Jeff Davis said in a statement on Thursday.
His brother Ali, an IS recruiter and person of interest in the 2012 Benghazi attack, was killed by an air strike in Iraq a day earlier.
The Pentagon says Harzi was "responsible for moving people and material into Syria and Iraq" and also raised funds to recruit fighters and facilitate travel.
In addition, he supported the Islamic State group by procuring and shipping weapons from Libya to Syria, where the militants have taken large swathes of territory.
He also aided with suicide attacks.
The Pentagon says his death is a significant blow to the Islamic State group.
"His death will impact ISIL's ability to integrate foreign terrorist fighters into the Syrian and Iraqi fight as well as to move people and equipment across the border between Syria and Iraq," Davis said, using an alternative acronym for the group.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 06:29:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Shots at Washington Navy Yard</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47c64045/sc/35/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A70C0A20Cshots0Ewashington0Enavy0Eyard/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>An official says shots have been reported on the Washington Navy Yard campus and a lockdown is under way.</Description>
        <MainBody>US Navy Yard on lockdown, report of gunman
Shots have been reported in a building on the Washington Navy Yard campus. (AAP)
The Washington Navy Yard is in lockdown amid reports of a shooter in the facility, but the US Navy says it can't confirm an incident has taken place.
Source:
0
The Navy Yard in Washington has been put in lockdown amid unconfirmed reports of an active gunman on the military facility, the scene of a deadly shooting two years ago.
A Navy officer who was inside the complex told CNN people scrambled for cover after hearing someone shout to get out of the building and stay away from the cafeteria.
But Lieutenant Commander Scott Williams said he heard no shots or saw any signs of a struggle.
"We heard someone scream, get out of the building, stay away from the cafeteria and we saw everyone running for the exits or adjoining offices," he said on Thursday.
The Navy, which told people at the site to shelter in place, said via Twitter that no "incident can be confirmed as of yet".
"NavyYard Lockdown/shelter continues. No further info at this time. More to follow," it said.
Police cars converged on the scene in southeast Washington, and television images showed a huge traffic jam outside the complex.
Authorities stepped up security outside the White House, closing the pedestrian mall that runs along Pennsylvania Avenue and the adjoining Lafayette Square.
The Navy Yard was the scene of a September 2013 shooting that saw a lone gunman fatally shoot 12 people before being killed himself in a shootout with police.
The Navy Yard houses offices of the US Navy and is the headquarters for a number of naval operations.
The incident comes with the US on heightened alert ahead of the July 4 national holiday.
The FBI, Department of Homeland Security and National Counterterrorism Center have warned the public of an increased risk of attack during Independence Day weekend.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
