<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="sbs North America News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 07:28:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Person shot at San Francisco gay pride</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47a28695/sc/38/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C280Cperson0Eshot0Esan0Efrancisco0Egay0Epride/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A man has been shot in the US at a gay pride event in San Francisco.</Description>
        <MainBody>Person shot at San Francisco gay pride
A person has been shot at a San Francisco pride event. (AP Photo/Noah Berger)
A man has been shot in the US at a gay pride event in San Francisco.
Source:
A bystander has been shot at a gay pride event in San Francisco when an argument between several young men turned violent.
Officer Carlos Manfredi says several people were detained for questioning after the shooting on Saturday evening.
The shooting triggered a chaotic scene as dozens of people ran screaming as officers carrying handguns rushed to the scene.
Manfredi says a 64-year-old man who was caught in the crossfire got shot in the arm. He's hospitalised in stable condition.
Four shots were heard in a witness video posted online.
Manfredi says the argument had nothing to do with the gay pride event.
A concert that was part of the weekend-long gay pride celebration across the city was ending around the time of the shooting.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 18:46:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US plane crash victims identified</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47a1bfc8/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C280Cus0Eplane0Ecrash0Evictims0Eidentified/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The nine people who were killed in a sightseeing plane crash in Alaska, have been identified.</Description>
        <MainBody>28 Jun 2015 - 1:08pm
US plane crash victims identified
Eight cruise ship passengers killed in a sightseeing plane crash in Alaska, have been identified. (AAP)
The nine people who were killed in a sightseeing plane crash in Alaska, have been identified.
Source:
0
A recovery crew has reached a remote site in southeast Alaska where a sightseeing plane crashed, killing all nine people aboard.
Chris John of the Ketchikan Volunteer Rescue Squad said on Friday that the aircraft was sitting at a steep angle and three members from his organisation had to secure it so they could safely work to recover the bodies.
Eight cruise ship passengers and the pilot died when the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop went down on Thursday in Misty Fjords National Monument near Ketchikan.
The cause of the crash remained under investigation.
Authorities tentatively identified the victims as Hal Cheney, 71, and Mary Doucette, 59, of Lodi, California; Glenda Cambiaso, 31, and Hugo Cambiaso, 65, of North Potomac, Maryland; June Kranenburg, 73, and Leonard Kranenburg, 63, of Medford, Oregon; Margie Apodaca, 63, and Raymond Apodaca, 70, of Sparks, Nevada; and the pilot, Bryan Krill, 64 of Hope, Idaho.
The plane crashed on a cliff above a lake in steep, muddy and slippery terrain, John said. The fuselage was largely intact but the wings and tail were separated or heavily deformed, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 10:12:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama delivers eulogy for shooting victim</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/479cdf7b/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C270Cobama0Edelivers0Eeulogy0Eshooting0Evictim/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US President Barack Obama has delivered the eulogy for one of the victims of the Charleston church massacre, calling for stricter gun controls.</Description>
        <MainBody>27 Jun 2015 - 2:00pm
Obama delivers eulogy for slain preacher
Barack Obama has paid homage to a black pastor killed during a mass shooting in a Charleston church. (AAP)
US President Barack Obama has delivered the eulogy for the pastor slain with eight others in a Charleston church, ending it by singing Amazing Grace.
Source:
0
US President Barack Obama has led an impassioned funeral service for a popular black minister and politician killed in a church massacre in the US state of South Carolina.
Touching on the themes of racism, poverty and injustice that persist for African Americans in the United States, Obama said the killing of Reverend Clementa Pinckney - a personal friend - and eight others in a church was a call to grace.
The alleged killer did not know he was "being used by God", he said on Friday.
"Blinded by hatred, the alleged killer could not see the grace surrounding Reverend Pinckney and that Bible study group," Obama told thousands gathered in the arena of the College of Charleston.
"The alleged killer could have never anticipated the way the families of the fallen would respond when they saw him in court in the midst of unspeakable grief, with words of forgiveness," Obama said.
Behind him stood dozens of purple-and-black-robed ministers of the African Methodist Episcopal church.
The song Amazing Grace was the theme of his 40-minute eulogy, which the president ended by singing the traditional hymn, leading thousands of voices through the verse.
He called on his listeners to "prove" themselves worthy of this grace by waking up "to the way past injustices continue to shape the present", by considering what "causes so many of our children to hate".
And he said "God's grace" would be expressed by doing something about the fact that 30 people are cut down every day by gun violence.
Pinckney and the eight other black worshippers were slaughtered last week at the historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston.
Their alleged white killer had joined the prayer and Bible service for an entire hour before standing up and shooting them.
Pinckney's funeral service is the third of the nine funerals to follow the killings. Thousands started lining up early in the morning for the service.
Pinckney, 41, was a senator in the South Carolina legislature and had been one of the earliest supporters of Obama's presidential bid. The two met in 2007 as Obama was getting his campaign off the ground.
His ancestors had been preachers and civil rights activists, and Pinckney followed in their footsteps, "in the pulpit by 13, pastor by 18, public servant by 23", Obama noted.
The killings shocked the nation, coming on the heels of a year-long series of killings of unarmed black suspects by white police officers.
But while those killings fractured communities and spawned violent riots, the killings of the nine in Charleston not only pulled people together in Charleston, they also provoked a deep soul-searching across the old South.
Black politicians, rights activists and conservative Republicans pointed to the Confederate flag that still flew in an unofficial capacity at the state capital - alongside the American and official state flags - as a persistent reminder to African Americans of the South's history of slavery and "of systematic oppression and racial subjugation", Obama said.
Within days after the deaths, the flag started being pulled off the virtual and real shelves of Walmart, Sears, eBay and Amazon.com, and even the gift shops of some national parks.
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley called for its removal from the state capital, and the state of Mississippi launched a move to remove its embedded image from its official state flag.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 10:12:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Funeral for Charleston victim begins</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/479bb9d8/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C270Cfuneral0Echarleston0Evictim0Ebegins/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The funeral for one of the victims of the Charleston church shooting has begun in South Carolina, with President Barack Obama to deliver the eulogy.</Description>
        <MainBody>27 Jun 2015 - 2:00pm
Obama delivers eulogy for slain preacher
Barack Obama has paid homage to a black pastor killed during a mass shooting in a Charleston church. (AAP)
US President Barack Obama has delivered the eulogy for the pastor slain with eight others in a Charleston church, ending it by singing Amazing Grace.
Source:
0
US President Barack Obama has led an impassioned funeral service for a popular black minister and politician killed in a church massacre in the US state of South Carolina.
Touching on the themes of racism, poverty and injustice that persist for African Americans in the United States, Obama said the killing of Reverend Clementa Pinckney - a personal friend - and eight others in a church was a call to grace.
The alleged killer did not know he was "being used by God", he said on Friday.
"Blinded by hatred, the alleged killer could not see the grace surrounding Reverend Pinckney and that Bible study group," Obama told thousands gathered in the arena of the College of Charleston.
"The alleged killer could have never anticipated the way the families of the fallen would respond when they saw him in court in the midst of unspeakable grief, with words of forgiveness," Obama said.
Behind him stood dozens of purple-and-black-robed ministers of the African Methodist Episcopal church.
The song Amazing Grace was the theme of his 40-minute eulogy, which the president ended by singing the traditional hymn, leading thousands of voices through the verse.
He called on his listeners to "prove" themselves worthy of this grace by waking up "to the way past injustices continue to shape the present", by considering what "causes so many of our children to hate".
And he said "God's grace" would be expressed by doing something about the fact that 30 people are cut down every day by gun violence.
Pinckney and the eight other black worshippers were slaughtered last week at the historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston.
Their alleged white killer had joined the prayer and Bible service for an entire hour before standing up and shooting them.
Pinckney's funeral service is the third of the nine funerals to follow the killings. Thousands started lining up early in the morning for the service.
Pinckney, 41, was a senator in the South Carolina legislature and had been one of the earliest supporters of Obama's presidential bid. The two met in 2007 as Obama was getting his campaign off the ground.
His ancestors had been preachers and civil rights activists, and Pinckney followed in their footsteps, "in the pulpit by 13, pastor by 18, public servant by 23", Obama noted.
The killings shocked the nation, coming on the heels of a year-long series of killings of unarmed black suspects by white police officers.
But while those killings fractured communities and spawned violent riots, the killings of the nine in Charleston not only pulled people together in Charleston, they also provoked a deep soul-searching across the old South.
Black politicians, rights activists and conservative Republicans pointed to the Confederate flag that still flew in an unofficial capacity at the state capital - alongside the American and official state flags - as a persistent reminder to African Americans of the South's history of slavery and "of systematic oppression and racial subjugation", Obama said.
Within days after the deaths, the flag started being pulled off the virtual and real shelves of Walmart, Sears, eBay and Amazon.com, and even the gift shops of some national parks.
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley called for its removal from the state capital, and the state of Mississippi launched a move to remove its embedded image from its official state flag.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 10:02:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deformed mutt named World&amp;#039;s Ugliest Dog</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/479ec829/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C270Cdeformed0Emutt0Enamed0Eworlds0Eugliest0Edog/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A 10-year-old pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix with a hunchback and a "bubbly personality" has been named the World's Ugliest Dog in an annual contest.</Description>
        <MainBody>27 Jun 2015 - 6:06pm
Deformed mutt named World's Ugliest Dog
Quasi Modo wins top honors in the World's Ugliest Dog Contest at the Sonoma-Marin Fair on Friday. (AP)
A 10-year-old pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix with a hunchback and a "bubbly personality" has been named the World's Ugliest Dog in an annual contest.
Source:
0
A 10-year-old mutt named Quasi Modo, whose spinal birth defects have left him a bit hunchbacked, is the winner of the annual World's Ugliest Dog contest.
The pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix and his owner took the $US1,500 ($A1,938.99) prize on Friday night, besting 25 other dogs competing in the contest that applauds imperfection, organisers said.
Quasi Modo was abandoned at an animal shelter before being adopted by a veterinarian in Loxahatchee, Florida, according to his biography posted on the contest's website.
"My appearance can be a little unsettling to some (I have had grown men jump on top of their cars to get away from me because they thought I was a hyena or Tasmanian devil) but once they get to know me I win them over with my bubbly personality," his biography said.
Two Chinese crested and Chihuahua mixes named Sweepee Rambo and Frodo took the second- and third-place prizes, respectively.
An eight-year-old Chihuahua named Precious received the "spirit award," honouring a dog and owner who have overcome obstacles and/or are providing service to the community.
Precious, who is blind in one eye, is trained to monitor smells related to low blood sugar levels and alert her owner, a disabled veteran, of the problem, her biography said.
The contest, held at the Sonoma-Marin Fairgrounds in Petaluma, California, is in its 27th year.
The dogs are scored by a three-judge panel in several categories, including special or unusual attributes, personality and natural ugliness.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 22:20:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US plane crashes with 8 tourists on board</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/479677b3/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Cus0Eplane0Ecrashes0E80Etourists0Eboard/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A sightseeing plane carrying eight passengers from a cruise liner has crashed on to a cliff face in the US state of Alaska.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nine die in US tourist plane crash
Alaska, USA (AAP/Mary Evans/Ardea/M. Watson)
Attempts to recover the bodies of nine people who died in the crash of a sightseeing plane on an Alaska cliff face will resume Friday.
Source:
0
All nine people aboard a sightseeing plane have been killed after it crashed in southeast Alaska, authorities say.
Clint Johnson, head of the National Transportation Safety Board's Alaska office, confirmed weather is preventing the recovery of bodies Thursday evening off a cliff about 30 kilometres northeast of Ketchikan.
Attempts to recover the bodies will resume Friday.
The plane was carrying eight cruise ship passengers and a pilot.
It went missing Thursday afternoon and was crashed against the granite rock face of an Alaska cliff.
Holland America said the passengers from its MS Westerdam were sightseeing on a float plane owned by Ketchikan-based Promech Air.
The Westerdam departed Seattle June 20 for a seven-day cruise through southeastern Alaska.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:12:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama delivers eulogy for slain preacher</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/479d6206/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C270Cobama0Edelivers0Eeulogy0Eslain0Epreacher/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US President Barack Obama has delivered the eulogy for the pastor slain with eight others in a Charleston church, ending it by singing Amazing Grace.</Description>
        <MainBody>27 Jun 2015 - 2:00pm
Obama delivers eulogy for slain preacher
Barack Obama has paid homage to a black pastor killed during a mass shooting in a Charleston church. (AAP)
US President Barack Obama has delivered the eulogy for the pastor slain with eight others in a Charleston church, ending it by singing Amazing Grace.
Source:
0
US President Barack Obama has led an impassioned funeral service for a popular black minister and politician killed in a church massacre in the US state of South Carolina.
Touching on the themes of racism, poverty and injustice that persist for African Americans in the United States, Obama said the killing of Reverend Clementa Pinckney - a personal friend - and eight others in a church was a call to grace.
The alleged killer did not know he was "being used by God", he said on Friday.
"Blinded by hatred, the alleged killer could not see the grace surrounding Reverend Pinckney and that Bible study group," Obama told thousands gathered in the arena of the College of Charleston.
"The alleged killer could have never anticipated the way the families of the fallen would respond when they saw him in court in the midst of unspeakable grief, with words of forgiveness," Obama said.
Behind him stood dozens of purple-and-black-robed ministers of the African Methodist Episcopal church.
The song Amazing Grace was the theme of his 40-minute eulogy, which the president ended by singing the traditional hymn, leading thousands of voices through the verse.
He called on his listeners to "prove" themselves worthy of this grace by waking up "to the way past injustices continue to shape the present", by considering what "causes so many of our children to hate".
And he said "God's grace" would be expressed by doing something about the fact that 30 people are cut down every day by gun violence.
Pinckney and the eight other black worshippers were slaughtered last week at the historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston.
Their alleged white killer had joined the prayer and Bible service for an entire hour before standing up and shooting them.
Pinckney's funeral service is the third of the nine funerals to follow the killings. Thousands started lining up early in the morning for the service.
Pinckney, 41, was a senator in the South Carolina legislature and had been one of the earliest supporters of Obama's presidential bid. The two met in 2007 as Obama was getting his campaign off the ground.
His ancestors had been preachers and civil rights activists, and Pinckney followed in their footsteps, "in the pulpit by 13, pastor by 18, public servant by 23", Obama noted.
The killings shocked the nation, coming on the heels of a year-long series of killings of unarmed black suspects by white police officers.
But while those killings fractured communities and spawned violent riots, the killings of the nine in Charleston not only pulled people together in Charleston, they also provoked a deep soul-searching across the old South.
Black politicians, rights activists and conservative Republicans pointed to the Confederate flag that still flew in an unofficial capacity at the state capital - alongside the American and official state flags - as a persistent reminder to African Americans of the South's history of slavery and "of systematic oppression and racial subjugation", Obama said.
Within days after the deaths, the flag started being pulled off the virtual and real shelves of Walmart, Sears, eBay and Amazon.com, and even the gift shops of some national parks.
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley called for its removal from the state capital, and the state of Mississippi launched a move to remove its embedded image from its official state flag.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:12:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thousands await Obama&amp;#039;s eulogy</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/479bec20/sc/8/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C270Cthousands0Eawait0Eobamas0Eeulogy/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Thousands of mourners have turned out for the funeral of one of the victims of the Charleston church shooting, with Barack Obama to deliver the eulogy.</Description>
        <MainBody>27 Jun 2015 - 2:00pm
Obama delivers eulogy for slain preacher
Barack Obama has paid homage to a black pastor killed during a mass shooting in a Charleston church. (AAP)
US President Barack Obama has delivered the eulogy for the pastor slain with eight others in a Charleston church, ending it by singing Amazing Grace.
Source:
0
US President Barack Obama has led an impassioned funeral service for a popular black minister and politician killed in a church massacre in the US state of South Carolina.
Touching on the themes of racism, poverty and injustice that persist for African Americans in the United States, Obama said the killing of Reverend Clementa Pinckney - a personal friend - and eight others in a church was a call to grace.
The alleged killer did not know he was "being used by God", he said on Friday.
"Blinded by hatred, the alleged killer could not see the grace surrounding Reverend Pinckney and that Bible study group," Obama told thousands gathered in the arena of the College of Charleston.
"The alleged killer could have never anticipated the way the families of the fallen would respond when they saw him in court in the midst of unspeakable grief, with words of forgiveness," Obama said.
Behind him stood dozens of purple-and-black-robed ministers of the African Methodist Episcopal church.
The song Amazing Grace was the theme of his 40-minute eulogy, which the president ended by singing the traditional hymn, leading thousands of voices through the verse.
He called on his listeners to "prove" themselves worthy of this grace by waking up "to the way past injustices continue to shape the present", by considering what "causes so many of our children to hate".
And he said "God's grace" would be expressed by doing something about the fact that 30 people are cut down every day by gun violence.
Pinckney and the eight other black worshippers were slaughtered last week at the historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston.
Their alleged white killer had joined the prayer and Bible service for an entire hour before standing up and shooting them.
Pinckney's funeral service is the third of the nine funerals to follow the killings. Thousands started lining up early in the morning for the service.
Pinckney, 41, was a senator in the South Carolina legislature and had been one of the earliest supporters of Obama's presidential bid. The two met in 2007 as Obama was getting his campaign off the ground.
His ancestors had been preachers and civil rights activists, and Pinckney followed in their footsteps, "in the pulpit by 13, pastor by 18, public servant by 23", Obama noted.
The killings shocked the nation, coming on the heels of a year-long series of killings of unarmed black suspects by white police officers.
But while those killings fractured communities and spawned violent riots, the killings of the nine in Charleston not only pulled people together in Charleston, they also provoked a deep soul-searching across the old South.
Black politicians, rights activists and conservative Republicans pointed to the Confederate flag that still flew in an unofficial capacity at the state capital - alongside the American and official state flags - as a persistent reminder to African Americans of the South's history of slavery and "of systematic oppression and racial subjugation", Obama said.
Within days after the deaths, the flag started being pulled off the virtual and real shelves of Walmart, Sears, eBay and Amazon.com, and even the gift shops of some national parks.
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley called for its removal from the state capital, and the state of Mississippi launched a move to remove its embedded image from its official state flag.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:27:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds Obamacare</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47940f8d/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Csupreme0Ecourt0Eupholds0Eobamacare/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The US Supreme Court has upheld a key portion of President Barack Obama's healthcare law in a 6-3 decision.</Description>
        <MainBody>US top court backs Obamacare
US President Barack Obama. (AAP)
The US Supreme Court has upheld a key portion of President Barack Obama's healthcare law in a 6-3 decision.
Source:
0
The US Supreme Court has upheld a disputed portion of President Barack Obama's landmark health care reform, in a major legacy-building victory for his administration.
By a margin of six to three, the judges ruled in favour of allowing the federal government to subsidise health insurance by giving tax credits to consumers nationwide.
A triumphant Obama quickly hailed the ruling, calling it a win for "hard-working Americans all across this country".
"This law is working and it's going to keep doing just that," he said.
Opponents of the Affordable Care Act - better known as Obamacare - had argued that it was unconstitutional for the federal government to subsidise insurance in this way in states that refused to set up their own insurance exchanges.
The narrow question before the court was whether some seven million people who signed up for Obamacare via the government's website were actually entitled to tax subsidies that make the coverage affordable.
But the high court ruled that the law should stand, with two usually conservative justices joining the four generally liberal members of the panel to overturn the challenge.
In a ruling read out by Chief Justice John Roberts, the bench argued that it was clear that the original law had been intended to permit federal subsidies in all states.
Failure to do so would have condemned the law to a "death spiral" by destabilising the insurance market in states with federally run exchanges, Justice Sonia Sotomayor had said in March.
"It thus stands to reason that Congress meant for those provisions to apply in every state as well... tax credits are available to individuals in States that have a federal exchange," the ruling said.
Republicans have mounted several legislative attacks on the law in parallel to the legal assaults and this is the second time in three years that the court has saved it.
For Obama, the ruling marked a major victory that cements his signature domestic policy achievement.
"Five years in, this is no longer about a law. This is not about the Affordable Care Act as legislation or Obamacare as a political football. This is health care in America," the president said in the White House Rose Garden.
But Republicans have reacted angrily.
"Republicans will continue to fight tooth and nail to repeal this oppressive law," declared Senator John Cornyn, the party's number two leader in the senate.
"Today's decision doesn't change the fact that Obamacare has been a disaster for the millions of hardworking American families who have seen their health care costs skyrocket or lost their insurance entirely."
Several Republican contenders in the 2016 presidential race to succeed Obama also slammed the ruling.
White House hopeful, Jeb Bush, called it a "fatally flawed law" and added: "This decision is not the end of the fight against Obamacare."
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton meanwhile tweeted: "Yes! SCOTUS affirms what we know is true in our hearts &amp; under the law: Health insurance should be affordable &amp; available to all."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:27:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds Obama health care</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47940572/sc/24/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Csupreme0Ecourt0Eupholds0Eobama0Ehealth0Ecare/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The US Supreme Court has upheld a key portion of President Barack Obama's healthcare law in a 6-3 decision.</Description>
        <MainBody>US top court backs Obamacare
US President Barack Obama. (AAP)
The US Supreme Court has upheld a key portion of President Barack Obama's healthcare law in a 6-3 decision.
Source:
0
The US Supreme Court has upheld a disputed portion of President Barack Obama's landmark health care reform, in a major legacy-building victory for his administration.
By a margin of six to three, the judges ruled in favour of allowing the federal government to subsidise health insurance by giving tax credits to consumers nationwide.
A triumphant Obama quickly hailed the ruling, calling it a win for "hard-working Americans all across this country".
"This law is working and it's going to keep doing just that," he said.
Opponents of the Affordable Care Act - better known as Obamacare - had argued that it was unconstitutional for the federal government to subsidise insurance in this way in states that refused to set up their own insurance exchanges.
The narrow question before the court was whether some seven million people who signed up for Obamacare via the government's website were actually entitled to tax subsidies that make the coverage affordable.
But the high court ruled that the law should stand, with two usually conservative justices joining the four generally liberal members of the panel to overturn the challenge.
In a ruling read out by Chief Justice John Roberts, the bench argued that it was clear that the original law had been intended to permit federal subsidies in all states.
Failure to do so would have condemned the law to a "death spiral" by destabilising the insurance market in states with federally run exchanges, Justice Sonia Sotomayor had said in March.
"It thus stands to reason that Congress meant for those provisions to apply in every state as well... tax credits are available to individuals in States that have a federal exchange," the ruling said.
Republicans have mounted several legislative attacks on the law in parallel to the legal assaults and this is the second time in three years that the court has saved it.
For Obama, the ruling marked a major victory that cements his signature domestic policy achievement.
"Five years in, this is no longer about a law. This is not about the Affordable Care Act as legislation or Obamacare as a political football. This is health care in America," the president said in the White House Rose Garden.
But Republicans have reacted angrily.
"Republicans will continue to fight tooth and nail to repeal this oppressive law," declared Senator John Cornyn, the party's number two leader in the senate.
"Today's decision doesn't change the fact that Obamacare has been a disaster for the millions of hardworking American families who have seen their health care costs skyrocket or lost their insurance entirely."
Several Republican contenders in the 2016 presidential race to succeed Obama also slammed the ruling.
White House hopeful, Jeb Bush, called it a "fatally flawed law" and added: "This decision is not the end of the fight against Obamacare."
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton meanwhile tweeted: "Yes! SCOTUS affirms what we know is true in our hearts &amp; under the law: Health insurance should be affordable &amp; available to all."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:27:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama hails health care ruling victory</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/4792e8cf/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Cobama0Ehails0Ehealth0Ecare0Eruling0Evictory/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The US Supreme Court has upheld a key portion of President Barack Obama's health care law, a decision the president hailed as a win for Americans.</Description>
        <MainBody>US top court backs Obamacare
US President Barack Obama. (AAP)
The US Supreme Court has upheld a key portion of President Barack Obama's healthcare law in a 6-3 decision.
Source:
0
The US Supreme Court has upheld a disputed portion of President Barack Obama's landmark health care reform, in a major legacy-building victory for his administration.
By a margin of six to three, the judges ruled in favour of allowing the federal government to subsidise health insurance by giving tax credits to consumers nationwide.
A triumphant Obama quickly hailed the ruling, calling it a win for "hard-working Americans all across this country".
"This law is working and it's going to keep doing just that," he said.
Opponents of the Affordable Care Act - better known as Obamacare - had argued that it was unconstitutional for the federal government to subsidise insurance in this way in states that refused to set up their own insurance exchanges.
The narrow question before the court was whether some seven million people who signed up for Obamacare via the government's website were actually entitled to tax subsidies that make the coverage affordable.
But the high court ruled that the law should stand, with two usually conservative justices joining the four generally liberal members of the panel to overturn the challenge.
In a ruling read out by Chief Justice John Roberts, the bench argued that it was clear that the original law had been intended to permit federal subsidies in all states.
Failure to do so would have condemned the law to a "death spiral" by destabilising the insurance market in states with federally run exchanges, Justice Sonia Sotomayor had said in March.
"It thus stands to reason that Congress meant for those provisions to apply in every state as well... tax credits are available to individuals in States that have a federal exchange," the ruling said.
Republicans have mounted several legislative attacks on the law in parallel to the legal assaults and this is the second time in three years that the court has saved it.
For Obama, the ruling marked a major victory that cements his signature domestic policy achievement.
"Five years in, this is no longer about a law. This is not about the Affordable Care Act as legislation or Obamacare as a political football. This is health care in America," the president said in the White House Rose Garden.
But Republicans have reacted angrily.
"Republicans will continue to fight tooth and nail to repeal this oppressive law," declared Senator John Cornyn, the party's number two leader in the senate.
"Today's decision doesn't change the fact that Obamacare has been a disaster for the millions of hardworking American families who have seen their health care costs skyrocket or lost their insurance entirely."
Several Republican contenders in the 2016 presidential race to succeed Obama also slammed the ruling.
White House hopeful, Jeb Bush, called it a "fatally flawed law" and added: "This decision is not the end of the fight against Obamacare."
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton meanwhile tweeted: "Yes! SCOTUS affirms what we know is true in our hearts &amp; under the law: Health insurance should be affordable &amp; available to all."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:27:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Supreme Court upholds Obama health care</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/4792915c/sc/24/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Cus0Esupreme0Ecourt0Eupholds0Eobama0Ehealth0Ecare/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The US Supreme Court has upheld a key portion of President Barack Obama's healthcare law in a 6-3 decision.</Description>
        <MainBody>US top court backs Obamacare
US President Barack Obama. (AAP)
The US Supreme Court has upheld a key portion of President Barack Obama's healthcare law in a 6-3 decision.
Source:
0
The US Supreme Court has upheld a disputed portion of President Barack Obama's landmark health care reform, in a major legacy-building victory for his administration.
By a margin of six to three, the judges ruled in favour of allowing the federal government to subsidise health insurance by giving tax credits to consumers nationwide.
A triumphant Obama quickly hailed the ruling, calling it a win for "hard-working Americans all across this country".
"This law is working and it's going to keep doing just that," he said.
Opponents of the Affordable Care Act - better known as Obamacare - had argued that it was unconstitutional for the federal government to subsidise insurance in this way in states that refused to set up their own insurance exchanges.
The narrow question before the court was whether some seven million people who signed up for Obamacare via the government's website were actually entitled to tax subsidies that make the coverage affordable.
But the high court ruled that the law should stand, with two usually conservative justices joining the four generally liberal members of the panel to overturn the challenge.
In a ruling read out by Chief Justice John Roberts, the bench argued that it was clear that the original law had been intended to permit federal subsidies in all states.
Failure to do so would have condemned the law to a "death spiral" by destabilising the insurance market in states with federally run exchanges, Justice Sonia Sotomayor had said in March.
"It thus stands to reason that Congress meant for those provisions to apply in every state as well... tax credits are available to individuals in States that have a federal exchange," the ruling said.
Republicans have mounted several legislative attacks on the law in parallel to the legal assaults and this is the second time in three years that the court has saved it.
For Obama, the ruling marked a major victory that cements his signature domestic policy achievement.
"Five years in, this is no longer about a law. This is not about the Affordable Care Act as legislation or Obamacare as a political football. This is health care in America," the president said in the White House Rose Garden.
But Republicans have reacted angrily.
"Republicans will continue to fight tooth and nail to repeal this oppressive law," declared Senator John Cornyn, the party's number two leader in the senate.
"Today's decision doesn't change the fact that Obamacare has been a disaster for the millions of hardworking American families who have seen their health care costs skyrocket or lost their insurance entirely."
Several Republican contenders in the 2016 presidential race to succeed Obama also slammed the ruling.
White House hopeful, Jeb Bush, called it a "fatally flawed law" and added: "This decision is not the end of the fight against Obamacare."
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton meanwhile tweeted: "Yes! SCOTUS affirms what we know is true in our hearts &amp; under the law: Health insurance should be affordable &amp; available to all."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 07:20:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nine die in US tourist plane crash</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47967c66/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Cnine0Edie0Eus0Etourist0Eplane0Ecrash/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Attempts to recover the bodies of nine people who died in the crash of a sightseeing plane on an Alaska cliff face will resume Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nine die in US tourist plane crash
Alaska, USA (AAP/Mary Evans/Ardea/M. Watson)
Attempts to recover the bodies of nine people who died in the crash of a sightseeing plane on an Alaska cliff face will resume Friday.
Source:
0
All nine people aboard a sightseeing plane have been killed after it crashed in southeast Alaska, authorities say.
Clint Johnson, head of the National Transportation Safety Board's Alaska office, confirmed weather is preventing the recovery of bodies Thursday evening off a cliff about 30 kilometres northeast of Ketchikan.
Attempts to recover the bodies will resume Friday.
The plane was carrying eight cruise ship passengers and a pilot.
It went missing Thursday afternoon and was crashed against the granite rock face of an Alaska cliff.
Holland America said the passengers from its MS Westerdam were sightseeing on a float plane owned by Ketchikan-based Promech Air.
The Westerdam departed Seattle June 20 for a seven-day cruise through southeastern Alaska.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Apple removing games with Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47954938/sc/28/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Capple0Eremoving0Egames0Econfederate0Eflag/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Apple says it is in the process of removing all games which feature the Confederate flag from its App Store.</Description>
        <MainBody>26 Jun 2015 - 10:54am
Apple removing games with Confederate flag
Apple says it is in the process of removing all games which feature the Confederate flag from its App Store.
Source:
0
Apple has begun removing games from its online app store that feature the Confederate flag.
The move comes days after Apple chief executive Tim Cook called on people to honour the victims of the Charleston, South Carolina, church shooting by eradicating racism and the symbols that feed it.
Apple said in a statement that apps are being removed that use the flag in "offensive or mean-spirited ways", in violation of guidelines.
Other apps depicting the flag in educational or historical contexts are not being removed.
The company is working with developers to get games that have been removed back in the store after changes are made.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:50:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Google&amp;#039;s self-driving cars hit the roads</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/4795493b/sc/23/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Cgoogles0Eself0Edriving0Ecars0Ehit0Eroads/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Google's bubble-shaped prototype cars built from the ground up are driving themselves around the streets near their developers' HQ.</Description>
        <MainBody>0
Google says its self-driving prototype cars have taken to streets in the Silicon Valley where it has its headquarters.
It comes after Google's internal testing of the bubble-shaped vehicle over the past year and more extensive experience with technology adapted for existing cars.
"We want to understand what it really means to have self-driving vehicles in the world - both how people in the community perceive and interact with them, and what the practical realities are for us in operating and maintaining them," Google said in a released statement on Thursday.
Prototype cars built from the ground up to get around safely without human drivers join Google's fleet of Lexus vehicles augmented with sensors and other computing gadgetry to manage autonomously on roads.
The prototypes will have "safety drivers" who can take over using manual controls if needed, according to Google.
"We've had 20-plus Lexus vehicles driving on Mountain View city streets for the last few years, but the arrival of our new self-driving vehicle prototypes marks the start of a new phase of our project," Google said.
The Google car uses the same technology as its fleet of Lexus 4WDs which has logged some 1.6 million kilometres.
In Google's home town of Mountain View, speeds will be limited to 40km/h "and during this next phase of our project we'll have safety drivers aboard with a removable steering wheel, accelerator pedal, and brake pedal that allow them to take over driving if needed," according to the head of the project.
Google has defended the safety record of its self-driving cars, saying that they were not at fault in any of the dozen or so accidents in which they've been involved.
Most of the collisions involved self-driving cars being hit in the rear by vehicles driven by people, according to the internet titan.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:21:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Key countries want UN tribunal for MH17</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47953a5b/sc/24/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Ckey0Ecountries0Ewant0Eun0Etribunal0Emh17/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Australia won't comment that the key countries affected by the downing of MH17 last year want a UN tribunal to prosecute those responsible.</Description>
        <MainBody>26 Jun 2015 - 9:26am
Key countries want UN tribunal for MH17
Australia won't comment that the key countries affected by the downing of MH17 last year want a UN tribunal to prosecute those responsible.
Source:
0
The five countries investigating last year's shooting down of a Malaysia Airlines plane over Ukraine are calling for an international tribunal to prosecute those responsible.
A UN diplomat says Australia, Malaysia, Ukraine, the Netherlands and Belgium "want the Security Council to establish a UN tribunal that would prosecute those responsible".
Last week, their legal experts were in New York to meet with the council's legal advisers, the diplomat said.
Another diplomat said the legal experts presented a draft statute to establish a tribunal and a draft UN resolution that would authorise it.
Both diplomats spoke on condition of anonymity because discussions have been private.
Australian Foreign Minister Julie Bishop would not confirm that the five countries were pushing for a UN tribunal, although she said she was aware of media reports around the proposals.
She said Australia was committed to working with the broader international community to secure justice for the families of the victims.
"The means for achieving this are currently being discussed by relevant countries and it would not be appropriate to go into details at this time," she said.
Malaysia's UN ambassador, Ramlan Ibrahim, told reporters on Thursday, "The subject has been moved over to capitals to review.
"We hope" to take up a draft resolution in the council in July, he said. "We can only hope for the best."
Diplomats said Russia, a veto-wielding council member, holds the key to the adoption of a resolution.
Ramlan said Malaysia has had preliminary discussions with Russia "but it's too early to say" whether Moscow will support a resolution.
Flight MH17 was shot down over rebel-held eastern Ukraine in July last year, killing all 298 on board, including 38 from Australia.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:54:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US jail guard denies knowing escape plan</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/479459ea/sc/3/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Cus0Ejail0Eguard0Edenies0Eknowing0Eescape0Eplan/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US police are continuing their search for two convicted killers, while a prison guard charged over their escape claims to have no knowledge of their plan.</Description>
        <MainBody>26 Jun 2015 - 6:58am
US jail guard denies knowing escape plan
US police are continuing their search for two convicted killers, while a prison guard charged over their escape claims to have no knowledge of their plan.
Source:
0
A US prison guard charged in connection with the escape of two killers admitted providing them with tools, paint, frozen hamburger meat and access to a catwalk electrical box, but claims he never knew they planned to bust out, authorities say.
As the search for the convicts entered its 20th day, Gene Palmer, 57, awaited arraignment on Thursday on charges of promoting prison contraband, tampering with evidence and official misconduct. He was freed on $US25,000 bail after his arrest Wednesday night.
Palmer is the second Clinton Correctional Facility employee to be charged since two convicted murderers, Richard Matt and David Sweat, cut their way out of the maximum-security prison in far northern New York, close to the Canadian border, on June 6.
A prison tailor shop instructor Joyce Mitchell, 51, is charged with helping them break out.
But in contrast to the allegations against Mitchell, Palmer said he was an unwitting helper.
"I did not realise at the time that the assistance provided to Matt or Sweat made their escape easier," he told authorities in a signed statement.
District Attorney Andrew Wylie said that based on Palmer's statements and a polygraph test, investigators have no reason to believe he was knowingly involved in the escape.
In the statement, Palmer admitted providing Matt with paint and paintbrushes. On four occasions over eight months, he supplied Sweat with needle-nose pliers and a screwdriver.
He said he gave Sweat access to the catwalk later used in the escape to change the wiring on electrical boxes as "a favour" to make it easier for them to cook in their cells.
And a week before the escape, he delivered to Matt a pound of frozen ground beef in a package left by Mitchell.
Palmer told investigators that he agreed to help the pair in return for information about some illegal acts the other inmates were engaged in.
Wylie said Mitchell told investigators she smuggled hacksaw blades, a screwdriver and other tools into the prison by hiding them in the frozen meat.
She then put the meat in a refrigerator in the tailor shop, and Palmer took the meat to Sweat and Matt, who were housed in a section where inmates are allowed to cook their meals, according to the district attorney.
Wylie said Thursday that investigators have no proof Palmer, who will plead not guilty, knew hacksaw blades were embedded in the meat.
Authorities say the inmates cut through the steel wall at the back of their cells, crawled down a catwalk, broke through a brick wall, cut their way into and out of a steam pipe and then emerged from a manhole outside the prison.
About 1,100 law enforcement on Thursday continued their search for the escaped convicts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:15:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US report looks at Aust human rights</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47940f8c/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Cus0Ereport0Elooks0Eaust0Ehuman0Erights/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Each year the US government releases a human rights report card for nations and Australia's asylum seeker policies were put under the spotlight.</Description>
        <MainBody>26 Jun 2015 - 7:52am
US report looks at Aust human rights
Each year the US government releases a human rights report card for nations and Australia's asylum seeker policies were put under the spotlight.
Source:
0
Australia's human rights challenges include asylum seeker policies, domestic violence on women and children and discrimination against indigenous people, a US government report has found.
Australia, compared to other nations, fares relatively well in the Country Reports on Human Rights Practices report released annually by the US State Department.
The report points to the UN High Commissioner for Refugees Zeid Ra'ad Al Hussein's speech last year stating Australia's policies were "leading to a chain of human rights violations, including arbitrary detention and possible torture" for asylum seekers following their return to home countries.
It also cites reports and arrests for anti-Semitism in Australia, examples of government corruption, age discrimination and the Western Australian Inspector of Custodial Services description of conditions at the Roebourne Regional Prison in Western Australia as "intolerable and inhumane".
"The main human rights challenges reported were domestic violence against women and children, particularly in indigenous communities; discrimination against indigenous people; and policies affecting asylum seekers, including lengthy detention and austere detention center conditions for some attempting to reach the country by sea," the US report's chapter on Australia states.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:27:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US top court backs Obamacare</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/47942537/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C260Cus0Etop0Ecourt0Ebacks0Eobamacare/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The US Supreme Court has upheld a key portion of President Barack Obama's healthcare law in a 6-3 decision.</Description>
        <MainBody>US top court backs Obamacare
US President Barack Obama. (AAP)
The US Supreme Court has upheld a key portion of President Barack Obama's healthcare law in a 6-3 decision.
Source:
0
The US Supreme Court has upheld a disputed portion of President Barack Obama's landmark health care reform, in a major legacy-building victory for his administration.
By a margin of six to three, the judges ruled in favour of allowing the federal government to subsidise health insurance by giving tax credits to consumers nationwide.
A triumphant Obama quickly hailed the ruling, calling it a win for "hard-working Americans all across this country".
"This law is working and it's going to keep doing just that," he said.
Opponents of the Affordable Care Act - better known as Obamacare - had argued that it was unconstitutional for the federal government to subsidise insurance in this way in states that refused to set up their own insurance exchanges.
The narrow question before the court was whether some seven million people who signed up for Obamacare via the government's website were actually entitled to tax subsidies that make the coverage affordable.
But the high court ruled that the law should stand, with two usually conservative justices joining the four generally liberal members of the panel to overturn the challenge.
In a ruling read out by Chief Justice John Roberts, the bench argued that it was clear that the original law had been intended to permit federal subsidies in all states.
Failure to do so would have condemned the law to a "death spiral" by destabilising the insurance market in states with federally run exchanges, Justice Sonia Sotomayor had said in March.
"It thus stands to reason that Congress meant for those provisions to apply in every state as well... tax credits are available to individuals in States that have a federal exchange," the ruling said.
Republicans have mounted several legislative attacks on the law in parallel to the legal assaults and this is the second time in three years that the court has saved it.
For Obama, the ruling marked a major victory that cements his signature domestic policy achievement.
"Five years in, this is no longer about a law. This is not about the Affordable Care Act as legislation or Obamacare as a political football. This is health care in America," the president said in the White House Rose Garden.
But Republicans have reacted angrily.
"Republicans will continue to fight tooth and nail to repeal this oppressive law," declared Senator John Cornyn, the party's number two leader in the senate.
"Today's decision doesn't change the fact that Obamacare has been a disaster for the millions of hardworking American families who have seen their health care costs skyrocket or lost their insurance entirely."
Several Republican contenders in the 2016 presidential race to succeed Obama also slammed the ruling.
White House hopeful, Jeb Bush, called it a "fatally flawed law" and added: "This decision is not the end of the fight against Obamacare."
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton meanwhile tweeted: "Yes! SCOTUS affirms what we know is true in our hearts &amp; under the law: Health insurance should be affordable &amp; available to all."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 15:08:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Senate okays TPP negotiations</title>
        <Link>http://sbs.feedsportal.com/c/34692/f/637533/s/478bb17a/sc/7/l/0L0Ssbs0N0Bau0Cnews0Carticle0C20A150C0A60C250Cus0Esenate0Eokays0Etpp0Enegotiations/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The huge Trans-Pacific Partnership trade pact remains alive after US President Barack Obama aligned himself with usual enemies in US Congress.</Description>
        <MainBody>US, Australia keen to finalise trade deal
President Barack Obama  (AAP)
Politicians in Canberra and Washington remain cautious even as US President Barack Obama's Republican foes backed him to fast-track a Pacific trade deal.
Source:
The mega trade pact between the US, Australia, New Zealand and nine other Pacific Rim nations remains alive, after being just a heartbeat, or one vote, from possible death.
US President Barack Obama secured fast-track authority for the Trans-Pacific Partnership in Washington on Wednesday.
The US Senate voted 60-38 after weeks of backroom deals.
To secure the win, Mr Obama aligned himself with his habitual combatants, Republican Party members in congress, and upset many of his Democrat allies, unions and environmentalists.
Australia and other member nations, fearing the US may not be part of the TPP because of interference from the US Congress, breathed a sigh of relief and announced they were keen to hammer out the final details.
"This would pave the way for the relevant ministers from the respective countries to come together in the near future with the aim of concluding these long-running negotiations," Australian Trade Minister Andrew Robb told AAP.
The past month brought tense moments in the White House and congress, with Democrats revolting against Mr Obama and torpedoing an earlier version of the fast-track bill in the House of Representatives.
On Tuesday, a procedural vote for fast-track in the US Senate passed by just one vote.
Fast-track protects the TPP from being altered and delayed by amendments when it is brought back to congress for final approval.
With fast-track, congress can approve or reject, but not alter, the bill.
Democrats, bruised from the battle, have vowed to stand in the way of the TPP when it is sent to congress for review and approval later this year, if it is deemed not good for Americans.
Apart from some partial leaks, most of the TPP remains secret.
"We all recognise that the next debate will be over (TPP) itself and all members, on both sides of this debate, will shine a bright light on the provisions of TPP," House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi, a Democrat, said.
Politicians in Australia are also cautious.
Independent senator Nick Xenophon fears the deal will be a "one-way street" and bad news for Australia.
"It is not so much a partnership, but an assault on Australian sovereignty," he told reporters in Canberra.
Senate crossbencher David Leyonhjelm has some concerns about the deal's impact on intellectual property rights, patents and copyright.
China is not included in the TPP and Mr Obama has said the pact will prevent China from writing the rules in the Asia-Pacific - the world's fastest-growing region.
The TPP is planned between the US, Australia, New Zealand, Brunei, Canada, Chile, Japan, Malaysia, Mexico, Peru, Singapore and Vietnam.
The nations represent 40 per cent of the world economy.
"We had plenty of bumps along the road," Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell, a Republican and frequent Obama antagonist, said.
"Frankly, a few big potholes too.
"But we worked across the aisle to get through all of them."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
