<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="sciencedaily">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:31:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Impulsivity linked to binge eating</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/PSO__Tqooac/150528163143.htm</Link>
        <Description>Do you get impulsive when you're upset? If so, this could be putting you at risk for binge eating. The more impulsive you are, the more likely it is you'll binge eat when experiencing negative feelings.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:31:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Physicists precisely measure interaction between atoms and carbon surfaces</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/TwmLwC6xaAI/150528163141.htm</Link>
        <Description>Physicists have conducted the most precise and controlled measurements yet of the interaction between the atoms and molecules that comprise air and the type of carbon surface used in battery electrodes and air filters -- key information for improving those technologies.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:31:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News may influence racial bias</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/9s48S0U4z58/150528163135.htm</Link>
        <Description>A recent study suggests that long-term exposure to news may negatively influence racial bias towards social groups.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:31:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As people non-consciously categorize others by political affiliation, they ignore race, but not age or gender</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/smIF4-R3rkk/150528163131.htm</Link>
        <Description>Beatles versus Rolling Stones. Ironman versus the Incredible Hulk. Deep dish versus thin crust. Such differences of opinion among family and friends rarely end in serious squabbles. Let the conversation turn to political parties, however, and lively disagreements can become downright ugly. Why is it that even among the people we care about most, differences in political affiliation often result in awkwardness and discomfort, and pushed far enough, can feel like a threat to the entire relationship?</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:31:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Even when we're resting, our brains are preparing us to be social</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ShOP_wddP94/150528163129.htm</Link>
        <Description>Our brains are wired to prepare us, during quiet moments, to be socially connected to other people, neuroscientists report. Facebook is aligned with the state of our brains at rest -- which can explain why it's such a popular activity when we want to take a break.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:30:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Melanoma rates dramatically increasing in children and young adults</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/0cQwPS4ihbc/150528163042.htm</Link>
        <Description>The incidence of melanoma, a deadly form of skin cancer, has increased by more than 250% among children, adolescents and young adults since 1973, according to new research.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:36:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Magnetism can control heat, sound</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Wna-LH3qVqk/150528153621.htm</Link>
        <Description>Elemental particles that transmit both heat and sound -- known as acoustic phonons -- also have magnetic properties and can, therefore, be controlled by magnets, even for materials thought to be 'nonmagnetic,' such as semiconductors. This discovery 'adds a new dimension to our understanding of acoustic waves,' according to a landmark study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:35:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How comets were assembled</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/gUuL6vp4DtE/150528153528.htm</Link>
        <Description>Rosetta's target 'Chury' and other comets observed by space missions show common evidence of layered structures and bi-lobed shapes. With 3D computer simulations an astrophysicist was able to reconstruct the formation of these features as a result of gentle collisions and mergers.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:35:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nivolumab treatment in melanoma patients has manageable safety profile</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/1ka5axfJV2g/150528153517.htm</Link>
        <Description>The monoclonal antibody nivolumab has shown promise as a therapeutic agent, particularly by improving the survival rates of melanoma patients. Medical researchers have presented data from a retrospective analysis of the safety of nivolumab in 4 ongoing phase I-III studies in melanoma patients.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:52:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chronic myelomonocytic leukemia: JAK2 inhibitor ruxolitinib has promising efficacy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ELrp_TpHBt8/150528145212.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists are reporting on the first phase 1 study of the JAK2 inhibitor ruxolitinib in CMML patients.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:29:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Implicit social biases made to drop away during sleep</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/tLF6EEsBQ3U/150528142903.htm</Link>
        <Description>Can we learn to rid ourselves of our implicit biases regarding race and gender? A new study indicates that sleep may hold an important key to success in such efforts. Building on prior research, investigators aimed to find out whether learning to alter habitual reactions to other people could be enhanced during sleep.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:28:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Scientists retrieve lost memories using optogenetics</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/OGWJTLAf-78/150528142815.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have found that memories that have been 'lost' as a result of amnesia can be recalled by activating brain cells with light. They reactivated memories that could not otherwise be retrieved, using a technology known as optogenetics.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:28:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How sleep helps us learn and memorize</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/IkwU4aSkUAE/150528142809.htm</Link>
        <Description>Sleep is important for long lasting memories, particularly during this exam season. New research suggests that sleeping triggers the synapses in our brain to both strengthen and weaken, which prompts the forgetting, strengthening or modification of our memories in a process known as long-term potentiation.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:09:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dinosaurs were likely warm-blooded</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/KeRIXhnndIo/150528140937.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dinosaurs grew as fast as your average living mammal, according to a new research article. The article is a re-analysis of a widely publicized 2014 Science paper on dinosaur metabolism and growth that concluded dinosaurs were neither ectothermic nor endothermic -- terms popularly simplified as 'cold-blooded' and 'warm-blooded' -- but instead occupied an intermediate category.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:01:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vulnerability found in some drug-resistant bacteria</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/1xuv0Hlq7f0/150528140110.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new study analyzing the physical dynamics of all currently mapped structures in an important group of antibiotic-destroying enzymes has found a common structural feature: the physical coordination of a set of flexible components. The apparently universal nature of this complex structural dynamic implies that it is critical to the antibiotic destroying properties of the enzyme and points to the possibility of finding a way to chemically disable the enzymes and bacterial antibiotic resistance, experts say.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:01:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New rapid-deployment plasma protocol effectively treats trauma patients quicker in the ER</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/idAFyVlyyIc/150528140108.htm</Link>
        <Description>Traumatic injury is the leading cause of death among people under age 45, but if trauma physicians could deliver plasma to these injury victims within minutes of their arrival in the emergency room, more of them would stand a better chance of survival.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:01:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sexual intrigue in nematodes: In battle of the sexes, a single night with a New York male is enough to kill</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/rBz6OJ-rx2w/150528140105.htm</Link>
        <Description>Men and women often enter relationships with different long-term goals. In the animal world, differences in approaches to reproductive success can lead to sexual conflict. In a new study, scientists show that sexual conflicts can evolve rapidly in natural populations, driven by competition among males for mating success.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:45:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Donuts, math, and superdense teleportation of quantum information</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/FZ_4DdZTggw/150528124519.htm</Link>
        <Description>Quantum teleportation has been achieved by a number of research teams around the globe since it was first theorized in 1993, but current experimental methods require extensive resources and/or only work successfully a fraction of the time. Now, by taking advantage of the mathematical properties intrinsic to the shape of a donut -- or torus, in mathematical terminology -- a physicists have made great strides by realizing 'superdense teleportation.'</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:45:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New technique for isolating sunlight scattering could help illuminate Universe's birth</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/aNZgtFUOEHU/150528124517.htm</Link>
        <Description>Astrophysicists have developed a new method for calculating the effect of Rayleigh scattering on photons, potentially allowing researchers to better understand the formation of the Universe.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:45:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ancient DNA sheds light on how past environments affected ancient populations</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/fhZZqyFgUbw/150528124515.htm</Link>
        <Description>For the first time, a study shows that epigenetic marks on DNA can be detected in a large number of ancient human remains, which may lead to further understanding about the effects of famine and disease in the ancient world.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:45:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Protecting women from multiple sclerosis</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/U8vDqDt01IE/150528124513.htm</Link>
        <Description>An innocent mistake made by a graduate student in a lab who accidentally used male mice instead of female mice during an experiment, has led scientists to a novel discovery that offers new insight into why women are more likely than men to develop autoimmune diseases such as multiple sclerosis.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:44:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Walnut twig beetle's origin, spread revealed in genetic studies</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/sdV7zVEGAzc/150528124411.htm</Link>
        <Description>Even though the walnut twig beetle is likely native to Arizona, California, and New Mexico, it has become an invasive pest to economically and ecologically important walnut trees throughout much of the Western and into the Eastern United States. Through genetic testing, researchers have characterized the beetle's geographic distribution and range expansion.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:44:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Metformin use associated with reduced risk of developing open-angle glaucoma</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/fWm4Dfkmy-0/150528124407.htm</Link>
        <Description>Taking the medication metformin hydrochloride was associated with reduced risk of developing the sight-threatening disease open-angle glaucoma in people with diabetes, according to a study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:44:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Estimating the global burden of cancer in 2013; 14.9 million new cases worldwide</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YivaaDEz7dM/150528124405.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers from around the world have worked together to try to measure the global burden of cancer and they estimate there were 14.9 million new cases of cancer, 8.2 million deaths and 196.3 million years of a healthy life lost in 2013, according to new research.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:44:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brain circuit that controls decisions that induce high anxiety identified</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/8Fn5TeRlygs/150528124403.htm</Link>
        <Description>Some decisions arouse far more anxiety than others. Among the most anxiety-provoking are those that involve options with both positive and negative elements, such choosing to take a higher-paying job in a city far from family and friends, versus choosing to stay put with less pay.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:42:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Scientists see a natural place for 'rewilded' plants in organic farming</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/dfzaekKi4z0/150528124208.htm</Link>
        <Description>One key element of organic agriculture is that it rejects unpredictable technologies, such as genetic engineering. But what if adding a gene from undomesticated plants to bring back a natural trait isn't unpredictable? Researchers present a case for using precise genetic engineering technologies to 'rewild' crops in a way that would make organic farming more efficient, and thus more profitable.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:42:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New tool to study an important anti-cancer, immunosuppressive target</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/CZuOqGgzeig/150528124206.htm</Link>
        <Description>The chemical rapamycin is used clinically as an immunosuppressant and as an anti-cancer agent that works by inactivating a protein named TOR (Target Of Rapamycin). This protein is essential for the growth of normal cells, but is hyperactive in tumor cells. To be able to carry out its various growth-related tasks, TOR needs to assemble into one of two larger protein complexes named TORC1 and TORC2. Curiously, whereas TORC1 is inhibited by rapamycin.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:42:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Genetic analysis of the American eel helps explain its decline</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-6nh4wn75eU/150528124204.htm</Link>
        <Description>The numbers of American eels in freshwater areas have been decreasing rapidly but scientists have been puzzled as to why the fish can't recolonize. Now, a new look at eel genetics finds that there are differences between eels that feed in freshwater and eels that feed in brackish environments that were previously thought to be genetically interchangeable.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:42:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Long life: Balancing protein and carb intake may work as well as calorie restriction</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/9BFm1lWgkyE/150528124202.htm</Link>
        <Description>Cutting calories through dietary restriction has been shown to lower cholesterol, improve insulin sensitivity, and even prolong life in mammals. Now, new research shows that, at least in mice, low protein, high carbohydrate diets can provide benefits similar to those obtained with calorie restriction.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ethiopian and Egyptian genomes help map early humans' route out of Africa</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/CpUQOB1pHCM/150528124200.htm</Link>
        <Description>Although scientists are confident that all modern human populations can trace their ancestry back to Africa, the route taken out of Africa is still unclear. New genomic analyses of people currently living in Ethiopia and Egypt indicate that Egypt was the major gateway out of Africa and that migration followed a northern rather than a southern route. The findings add a crucial piece of information to help investigators reconstruct humans' evolutionary past.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:41:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Controlling typhoid bacterium key to prevent gallbladder cancer in India and Pakistan</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/bY9hGEkijA4/150528124158.htm</Link>
        <Description>Controlling bacterial infections responsible for typhoid fever could dramatically reduce the risk of gallbladder cancer in India and Pakistan, according to study. The findings establish the causal link between bacterial infection and gallbladder cancer, explaining why this type of cancer is rare in the West but common in India and Pakistan, where typhoid fever is endemic. Public policy changes inspired by this research could have an immediate impact, experts say.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:41:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Smart flies can match odd scents to sweet treats based on time of day</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/SXF_sEwr_HI/150528124154.htm</Link>
        <Description>Flies might be smarter than you think. New research shows fruit flies know what time of day it is. What's more, the insects can learn to connect different scents with the sweet reward of sugar, depending on the hour: menthol in the morning and mushrooms in the afternoon.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:41:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Scientists discover key to what causes immune cell migration to wounds</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/JjTgfawvcIY/150528124152.htm</Link>
        <Description>Immune cells play an important role in the upkeep and repair of our bodies, helping us to defend against infection and disease. Until now, how these cells detect a wounded or damaged site has largely remained a mystery. New research has identified the triggers which lead these cells to react and respond in cell repair.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:40:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Public raises alarm about ineffectiveness of some Montagu's harrier conservation measures</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/qZffmBk-aYQ/150528124023.htm</Link>
        <Description>A citizen science program reveals the protection measures for the Montagu's harrier in the cereal crop season in France to be ineffective if nests are not protected to decrease predation after harvesting. A new study proposes fencing off the nests as a way of mitigating the damage and optimizing conservation efforts in different areas.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:40:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Health factors influence ex-prisoners' chances of returning to jail</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/f-asYwsfM5Q/150528124021.htm</Link>
        <Description>Ex-prisoners with a history of risky drug use, mental illness or poverty are more likely to end up back behind bars. Those who are obese, are chronically ill or have attempted suicide are more likely to remain in the community. These are some of the findings from an exploratory study into health-related factors that could be used to predict whether a person released from prison will end up in custody again.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:39:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Acquiring 'perfect' pitch may be possible for some adults</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/MZIM0Wa0ITA/150528123917.htm</Link>
        <Description>If you're a musician, this sounds too good to be true: psychologists have been able to train some adults to develop the prized musical ability of absolute pitch, and the training's effects last for months.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:38:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wastewater treatment may be creating new antibiotics</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/5DraCp76agA/150528123858.htm</Link>
        <Description>For years, scientists have been aware of the potential problems of antibiotics being present in wastewater, and new research is showing that treatments to clean wastewater may actually be creating new antibiotics and further contributing to the development of antibiotic resistance in the environment.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:38:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sleep quality influences cognitive performance of autistic, neurotypical children</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/INlqc9TLC3o/150528123855.htm</Link>
        <Description>One night of poor sleep significantly decreases performance on intelligence tests in children with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) and also in neurotypical children (without ASD). The researchers observed the EEG measures of 13 autistic children and 13 neurotypical children (children with a mean age of 10 years old without an intellectual deficiency or sleep problem and who were not on medication) and found that disruptions in protective brain waves during sleep are associated with lower results on verbal IQ tests.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:38:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New target for treating drug-resistant melanoma found</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/WMMoYbsUZjE/150528123853.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new study explains why some melanoma tumors are resistant to BRAF inhibitor treatment. Melanoma is the deadliest form of skin cancer, killing more than 8,000 people in the U.S. each year. Approximately 50 percent of melanoma tumors are driven by mutations in the BRAF gene, and patients with these tumors are prescribed BRAF inhibitors.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:38:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Researchers unravel a link between a genetic mutation and autistic behaviors, then find a way to undo it</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Zupd1rMN0Ck/150528123851.htm</Link>
        <Description>The mechanisms behind a genetic mutation that produces certain autistic behaviors in mice has been identified by researchers, as well as therapeutic strategies to restore normal behaviors.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:38:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bladder cells regurgitate bacteria to prevent UTIs</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/1_Wxfeo5Wro/150528123847.htm</Link>
        <Description>Bladder cells have a highly effective way to combat E. coli bacteria that cause urinary tract infections (UTIs), researchers have found. They do to the bacteria what we could do to having indigestion problems: vomiting to rid the stomach of harmful substances.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:11:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pangolin trade: Experts urge reforms to CITES</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-IQIw93XU70/150528111118.htm</Link>
        <Description>New research by conservationists suggests that in order to manage trade-threatened species more effectively the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora needs to act more upon the economic reality of wildlife trade.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:11:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>High rates of MRSA transmission found between nursing home residents, healthcare workers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ZU_ah6h03oc/150528111115.htm</Link>
        <Description>Healthcare workers frequently contaminate their gloves and gowns during every day care of nursing homes residents with drug resistant Staphylococcus aureus or MRSA, according to a new study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:11:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Spinning a new version of spider silk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/iJZIaQR43gI/150528111112.htm</Link>
        <Description>After years of research decoding the complex structure and production of spider silk, researchers have now succeeded in producing samples of this exceptionally strong and resilient material in the laboratory. The new development could lead to a variety of biomedical materials -- from sutures to scaffolding for organ replacements -- made from synthesized silk with properties specifically tuned for their intended uses.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:41:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ombitasvir/paritaprevir/r in hepatitis C: Indication of added benefit in certain patients</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/rneVPQ6mqvU/150528104114.htm</Link>
        <Description>The new drug combination showed an advantage in three of a total of 16 patient groups, particularly regarding virologic response. The extent of added benefit remains unclear, however.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:41:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Astronomy: Link between mergers and supermassive black holes with relativistic jets</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/GyyVaxozx1w/150528104112.htm</Link>
        <Description>In the most extensive survey of its kind ever conducted, a team of scientists have found an unambiguous link between the presence of supermassive black holes that power high-speed, radio-signal-emitting jets and the merger history of their host galaxies. The results lend significant weight to the case for jets being the result of merging black holes.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:39:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Study cites federal policy as key to primary care access and nurse practitioner workforce development</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/LWqqTtJZb8U/150528103943.htm</Link>
        <Description>With demand for primary care expected to increase sharply over the next five years– due to passage of the Affordable Care Act (ACA), population growth and aging – the role of advanced-practice nurses or nurse practitioners (NPs) is also increasing. But a new study illustrates how federal policies influence the NP workforce and practice, and how misalignment of those policies with state mandates can affect workforce supply and patient access to care.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:39:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Treatment for genetically caused emphysema effective, experts say</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/VLdnu06GJUg/150528103940.htm</Link>
        <Description>A landmark clinical study provides convincing evidence that a frequently overlooked therapy for genetically-caused emphysema is effective and slows the progression of lung disease. Alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency is an inherited disorder that can cause emphysema even without exposure to tobacco smoke.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:39:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Not making enough money? Check your attitude</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/JbOnUaQKCN0/150528103937.htm</Link>
        <Description>Holding cynical beliefs about others may have a negative effect on your income according to research using survey data from the United States and Europe. The reviews looked at cynicism (as measured by responses to a questionnaire) in national surveys of Americans (1,146 and 497 participants respectively) and income level at a later date. In both studies, a high level of cynicism was associated with lower income.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:26:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Roadside air can be more charged than under a high-voltage power line</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-Tn3f_rR4tY/150528092642.htm</Link>
        <Description>More charged particles in urban environments come from motor vehicle emissions than anything else which makes living beside a busy road with lots of diesel-driven vehicles worse for your health than living under high voltage power lines, experts say.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:26:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A sight for sore eyes: Visually training medical students to better identify melanomas</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YYV7x6GtgnQ/150528092640.htm</Link>
        <Description>New research is helping to improve the ability of medical students and health professionals to detect early forms of skin cancer. The study concludes that traditional teaching methods can be improved substantially by training health professionals to put a greater focus on the visual aspects of the task, as opposed to an emphasis on learning the physiology and anatomy of skin lesions.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="51">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:42:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Super-efficient light-based computers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/qqwDjD5Gz8A/150528084202.htm</Link>
        <Description>Infrared light passes through silicon the way visible light passes through glass. Just as a prism bends visible light to reveal the rainbow, different silicon structures can bend infrared light in useful ways. It is theoretically possible to replace wires with silicon fibers. Why bother: to transmit lots more data while using lots less energy.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="52">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Large but unexplained variations in paracetamol-induced liver failure among European countries</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-brzjoiRc80/150528084200.htm</Link>
        <Description>A 50-fold between-country difference in rates of paracetamol-induced acute liver failure that leads to liver transplant has been revealed by a study that compared patient data from seven countries at the request of the European Medicines Agency: France, Greece, Ireland, Italy, Netherlands, Portugal and the UK.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="53">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:41:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Unexpected brain structures tied to creativity, and to stifling it</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/bdIpoiolEvk/150528084158.htm</Link>
        <Description>A surprising link has been found between creative problem-solving and heightened activity in the cerebellum, a structure located in the back of the brain and more typically thought of as the body's movement-coordination center.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="54">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:38:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Birds, not just mammals, copy yawns</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/sQJrIVipD6k/150528083830.htm</Link>
        <Description>Have you ever caught yourself yawning right after someone else did? The same happens to budgies. Biologists have just noted that contagious yawning also occurs between members of a bird species. Contagious yawning was previously thought only to occur between humans, domestic dogs, chimpanzees and a type of rodent aptly called the high-yawning Sprague-Dawley rat.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="55">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:38:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Innovative components pave way for cheaper wind energy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/n1wc49Kmc88/150528083826.htm</Link>
        <Description>Wind turbines began cropping up across the landscapes of Spain and Germany in the 1990s'. These two countries have the highest wind energy production in the EU. But according to the Global Wind Energy Council, the global installed power capacity in Europe -- which is 134,007 MW -- has been surpassed by Asia with 141,964 MW, at the end of 2014. The wind power industry is arguably the most mature -- and fastest developing -- among renewable energies. But, there is still considerable room for improvement to compete with other sources of electricity.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="56">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:38:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Big Bang aftermath: Ancient stars from birth of the universe</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Xt55UtsYVZI/150528083824.htm</Link>
        <Description>Astronomers have discovered three "cosmic Methusalems" from the earliest years of the universe. These unusual stars are about 13 billion years old and experts assign them to the first generations of stars after the "dark ages." The chemical qualities of these extremely rare stellar bodies enable new insights into the events that must have led to the origins of the stars. The first stars have been assumed to be high-mass and to shine especially brightly. However, the latest observations point to hitherto unknown phenomena in the young universe, allowing for the emergence of much smaller stars.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="57">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:38:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Importance of using the right rubber for the job</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Zghu8k2C1is/150528083820.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have discovered that when it comes to rubbers, textured surfaces, and reproduction, more fluid formulations have greater reliability than those that are thick and sticky.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="58">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:38:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Extreme global warming of Cretaceous period punctuated with significant global cooling</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/gurOZOxz7Xg/150528083818.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have reconstructed the climatic development of the Arctic Ocean during the Cretaceous period, 145 to 66 million years ago. At that time the poles were devoid of ice and average temperatures of up to 35 degrees Celsius prevailed in the oceans. Yet new research shows there was a severe cold snap during the geological age known for its extreme greenhouse climate. What sparked the abrupt global cooling?</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="59">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:36:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Underwater robot swarms use collective cognition to perform tasks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/6D0VLP1nGWk/150528083639.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have created underwater robot swarms that function like schools of fish, exchanging information to monitor the environment, searching, maintaining, exploring and harvesting resources in underwater habitats. The project developed autonomous robots that interact with each other and exchange information, resulting in a cognitive system that is aware of its environment.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
</site>
