<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="sciencedaily">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:18:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Multiple pathways progressing to Alzheimer's disease</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/hqrouZfQmVQ/150625161845.htm</Link>
        <Description>The amyloid cascade hypothesis of Alzheimer's disease (AD) posits that sticky aggregations or plaques of amyloid-beta peptides accumulate over time in the brain, triggering a series of events that ultimately result in the full-blown neurodegenerative disorder. The hypothesis has been a major driver of AD research for more than 20 years. However, in a new study, researchers suggest the picture is not so clear-cut, reporting that early indicators or biomarkers of AD development are not fixed in a specific sequence.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:16:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A person's diet, acidity of urine may affect susceptibility to UTIs</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/4jwN4zo0b00/150625161623.htm</Link>
        <Description>The acidity of urine — as well as the presence of small molecules related to diet — may influence how well bacteria can grow in the urinary tract, a new study shows. The research may have implications for treating urinary tract infections, which are among the most common bacterial infections worldwide.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:15:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As siblings learn how to resolve conflict, parents pick up a few tips of their own</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/7WKePZoZdZc/150625161514.htm</Link>
        <Description>When children participated in a program designed to reduce sibling conflict, both parents benefited from a lessening of hostilities on the home front. But mothers experienced a more direct reward. As they viewed the children's sessions in real time on a video monitor and coached the kids at home to respond as they'd been taught, moms found that, like their kids, they were better able to manage their own emotions during stressful moments.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:15:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brain scan can predict who responds best to certain treatment for OCD</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/noTX3685hLg/150625161512.htm</Link>
        <Description>A certain detail from patients' brain scans could help clinicians identify which people are more likely to relapse after cognitive-behavioral therapy -- and why. Tens of millions of Americans -- an estimated 1 to 2 percent of the population -- will suffer at some point in their lifetimes from obsessive-compulsive disorder, a disorder characterized by recurrent, intrusive, and disturbing thoughts (obsessions), and/or stereotyped recurrent behaviors (compulsions).</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:15:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tracking genetic arms race between humans, mosquitoes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/eDfTlFwi6Zc/150625161510.htm</Link>
        <Description>Individual populations of mosquitoes are under strong evolutionary pressure from humans and their environment, a new study shows.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:14:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supercomputer model shows planet making waves in nearby debris disk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/GG77IvNbC8U/150625161445.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new supercomputer simulation of the planet and debris disk around the nearby star Beta Pictoris reveals that the planet's motion drives spiral waves throughout the disk, a phenomenon that causes collisions among the orbiting debris. Patterns in the collisions and the resulting dust appear to account for many observed features that previous research has been unable to fully explain.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:14:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blue and fin whale distribution in waters off Southern California</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/W_1C8IfSKsY/150625161438.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new study indicates a steady population trend for blue whales and an upward population trend for fin whales in Southern California.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:14:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Most of America's poor have jobs, study finds</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/0Jktnx_4UJE/150625161435.htm</Link>
        <Description>Sociologists evaluated 129 existing methods for defining the 'working poor' and propose one method as a unified definition. Their estimate is that 10 percent of all working households are poor. That's lower than some federal estimates, but it also means that a majority of poor Americans have jobs.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:54:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Giant axonal neuropathy: Researchers develop innovative gene transfer-based treatment approach</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/wrX1CfVhQXo/150625145432.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have developed an innovative, experimental gene transfer-based treatment for children with giant axonal neuropathy (GAN). This extremely rare genetic disorder causes children to gradually lose the ability to balance themselves, move their muscles and to feel certain sensations. Most children born with GAN do not survive beyond their early 20s because of progressive impairment of their ability to breath.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:53:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lax rules put Congo's forests, key carbon reserve, at risk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/EJ_p56pR3Jo/150625145322.htm</Link>
        <Description>Without new conservation efforts, the Democratic Republic of Congo could lose up to 20 percent of its forests, unleashing a 60 percent increase in carbon emissions from one of the largest carbon reserves in the world, a new study shows.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:53:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Compound in magnolia may combat head and neck cancers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/FJ7seoeGrgY/150625145320.htm</Link>
        <Description>As one of the compounds in magnolia extract, honokiol has been used for centuries in traditional Chinese and Japanese medicine to treat anxiety and other conditions. More recently, scientists have been revealing its cancer-fighting properties.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:53:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Synthetic biology used to engineer new route to biochemicals</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/WHgp0rpVy6s/150625145317.htm</Link>
        <Description>Chemists create a new pathway that allows E. coli bacteria to feed on sugar and acetate to make isobutyl coA, a raw material for fuels and chemicals.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Some snowy forestlands cool climate better without trees</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/WcvKt6SgiMU/150625145246.htm</Link>
        <Description>Forests worldwide are increasingly used to store carbon as a way to slow climate change, but a new study finds that some wooded areas may be more valuable without trees, allowing the cleared landscape to reflect rather than absorb the sun's energy. In other words, it's better to have snow-covered ground act as a natural mirror if you want to use some forest lands to cool the climate.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chloroplast tubes play a key role in plants' immune defense</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/8WO_leswCfk/150625145244.htm</Link>
        <Description>When plant cells are infected with pathogens, networks of tiny tubes called stromules grow from the chloroplasts to the cell's nucleus and trigger programmed cell death and innate immune responses.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New approach holds promise for earlier, easier detection of colorectal cancer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-8xCjlJnhBI/150625145242.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new, sensitive electrochemical technique capable of detecting colorectal cancer in tissue samples has been developed by chemists -- a method that could one day be used in clinical settings for the early diagnosis of colorectal cancer.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Top scientists call for improved incentives to ensure research integrity</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/uKrYU_nePME/150625145238.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientific controversies, from problems replicating results - such as with the now debunked association between autism and MMR vaccines -- to researcher misconduct and sensationalism, have led to speculation of 'trouble at the lab,' as the Economist put it. Top scientists have now examine ways to return to high scientific standards.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Faster internet? Electrical engineers break power and distance barriers for fiber optic communication</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/nJPrIfZL_uc/150625145236.htm</Link>
        <Description>Photonics researchers have increased the maximum power -- and therefore distance -- at which optical signals can be sent through optical fibers. This advance has the potential to increase the data transmission rates for the fiber optic cables that serve as the backbone of the Internet, cable, wireless and landline networks. The new study presents a solution to a long-standing roadblock to increasing data transmission rates in optical fiber.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Earth's daily rotation period encoded in an atomic-level protein structure</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/M1vt7sfpNQU/150625145232.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have demonstrated that Earth's daily rotation period (24 hours) is encoded in the KaiC protein at the atomic level, a small, 10 nm-diameter biomolecule expressed in cyanobacterial cells.The results of this joint research will help elucidate a longstanding question in chronobiology: How is the circadian period of biological clocks determined?</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:48:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Corals are already adapting to global warming, scientists say</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/INxvA_bMZBE/150625144850.htm</Link>
        <Description>Some coral populations already have genetic variants necessary to tolerate warm ocean waters, and humans can help to spread these genes, scientists have found.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:39:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Low scores on memory and thinking tests may signal Alzheimer's 18 years prior to disease</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/23-pBPKQqS0/150625143929.htm</Link>
        <Description>Errors on memory and thinking tests may signal Alzheimer's up to 18 years before the disease can be diagnosed, a new study suggests.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:39:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Backward-moving glacier helps scientists explain glacial earthquakes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/W2MInT2SlsA/150625143926.htm</Link>
        <Description>The relentless flow of a glacier may seem unstoppable, but a team of researchers from the United Kingdom and the U.S. has shown that during some calving events -- when an iceberg breaks off into the ocean -- the glacier moves rapidly backward and downward, causing the characteristic glacial earthquakes which until now have been poorly understood.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:39:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stem-like progenitor cell that exclusively forms heart muscle</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ryryoXhCMGU/150625143922.htm</Link>
        <Description>Future therapies for failing hearts are likely to include stem-like cells and associated growth factors that regenerate heart muscle. Scientists have just taken an important step towards that future by identifying a stem-like “progenitor” cell that produces only heart muscle cells.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:37:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Genetic discovery uncovers key tool for morphine production in poppies</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/TnwXx5zHTmM/150625143714.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have made a key genetic discovery in poppies, paving the way for more effective painkillers.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:36:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Solving the next step in the mystery of prions</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/gS9mv4pmWds/150625143650.htm</Link>
        <Description>Working towards the ultimate goal to develop therapeutics to treat diseases such as Alzheimer's, Parkinson's, ALS, and BSE (Mad Cow Disease), scientists are investigating the physical principles underlying the formation of misfolded protein aggregates. The aggregates of misfolded proteins -- proteins that clump together in the 'wrong' structure -- feature prominently in these fatal degenerative diseases.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:11:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Smartphone app may prevent dangerous freezing of gait in Parkinson's patients</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/u_E0rilEV4g/150625131150.htm</Link>
        <Description>CuPID is striving to provide personalized rehabilitation for patients with Parkinson's disease who experience gait disturbances. It is a home-based personalized rehabilitation tool in the form of a smartphone app that harnesses wearable sensors, audio biofeedback, and external cuing to provide intense motivational training tailored to each patient.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:11:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Study highlights 'important safety issue' with widely used MRI contrast agents</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/jhkBpL_umHw/150625131148.htm</Link>
        <Description>New results in animals highlight a major safety concern regarding a class of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) contrast agents used in millions of patients each year. The study adds to concerns that repeated use of specific "linear"-type gadolinium-based contrast agents (GBCAs) lead to deposits of the heavy-metal element gadolinium in the brain.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:11:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Artificial blood to assist in mosquito control research</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/40R-74p34S4/150625131146.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists continue to advance research on controlling one of the world's most notorious species of pests, the mosquito.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:09:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cancer drug makes fruit flies live longer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YtDLBilxswA/150625130909.htm</Link>
        <Description>Adult fruit flies given a cancer drug live 12 percent longer than average, according to a study researching healthy aging. The drug targets a specific cellular process that occurs in animals, including humans, delaying the onset of age-related deaths by slowing the aging process.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:09:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What controls blood flow in the brain?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/C4VTcxjiTgg/150625130907.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists present the strongest evidence yet that smooth muscle cells surrounding blood vessels in the brain are the only cells capable of contracting to control blood vessel diameter and thus regulate blood flow. This basic anatomical understanding may also have important implications for phenomena observed in stroke and migraines.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:09:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Calcium uptake by mitochondria makes heart beat harder in fight-or-flight response</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/JGAFOvtD_L4/150625130903.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a life-threatening situation, the heart beats faster and harder, invigorated by the fight-or-flight response, which instantaneously prepares a person to react or run. Now, a new study shows that the uptick in heart muscle contractility that occurs under acute stress is driven by a flood of calcium into mitochondria -- the cells' energy-producing powerhouses.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:09:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Songbirds have a thing for patterns</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/uY_ug2RDJRY/150625130900.htm</Link>
        <Description>You might think that young children would first learn to recognize sounds and then learn how those categories of sounds fit together into words. But that isn't how it works. Rather, kids learn sounds and words at the same time. Now, researchers present evidence from European starlings showing that songbirds learn their songs in much the same way.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:03:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Potential drug lessens neurodegeneration in Parkinson's disease model</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/35mJl48Kh1s/150625130316.htm</Link>
        <Description>The first test in a mammalian model of a potential new class of drugs to treat Parkinson’s disease shows abatement of neurodegeneration in the brains of test rats and no significant toxicities.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:02:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Functional class helps predict mortality risk after surgery</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/dDG-XX7FzAM/150625130259.htm</Link>
        <Description>Information on functional status—whether or not a person can carry out routine daily tasks independently—improves the ability to predict risk of death in patients undergoing surgery, according to a study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:02:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New drug squashes cancer's last-ditch efforts to survive</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/W5y3VLI5K98/150625130257.htm</Link>
        <Description>As a tumor grows, its cancerous cells ramp up an energy-harvesting process to support its hasty development. This process, called autophagy, is normally used by a cell to recycle damaged organelles and proteins, but is also co-opted by cancer cells to meet their increased energy and metabolic demands. A compound that stops this cellular recycling process has now been developed by scientists.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:02:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New close-up view of key part of ebola virus life cycle</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YywzpxstHpM/150625130255.htm</Link>
        <Description>A key part of the Ebola virus life cycle has been revealed at a higher resolution than ever before. The research sheds light on how Ebola virus assembles--and how researchers might stop the often-fatal infection.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:02:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three simple rules govern complex brain circuit in fly</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ljIxcchc_Hc/150625130253.htm</Link>
        <Description>Think the nest of cables under your desk is bad? Try keeping the trillions of connections crisscrossing your brain organized and free of tangles. A new study reveals this seemingly intractable job may be simpler than it appears.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:02:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Scientists pinpoint mutations responsible for ineffectiveness of 2014-2015 flu vaccine</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/OmJpaHiWHmw/150625130251.htm</Link>
        <Description>Viruses like influenza have the ability to mutate over time, and given that the flu vaccines administered during the 2014-2015 season were largely ineffective at preventing the spread of the flu, it appears the virus that recently circulated had taken on mutations not accounted for when last year's vaccine was developed. Now, researchers have identified specific mutations that influenza recently acquired to escape the current vaccine design.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:01:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Analyzing genes according to evolutionary profile</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/222NIIti4-o/150625130121.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have developed a new Internet tool that will allow any investigator, physician or patient to analyze genes according to their evolutionary profile and find associated genes. The tool combines genomics and informatics to enables the rapid, cost-free identification of genes responsible for diseases, by inputting results from genetic mapping studies concerning suspected genes, and identifying connections to known genes with association to diseases.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Investigating parent-child visitation in prison</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/wHfZ5wg3uTY/150625130000.htm</Link>
        <Description>It's not 'cupcakes and lollipops' for most children who visit a parent in prison, with two-thirds reported to have negative experiences including fear, anger, anxiety, and related reactions, according to a study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:59:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New class of compounds shrinks pancreatic cancer tumors, prevents regrowth</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Q0RSHHH1tPM/150625125958.htm</Link>
        <Description>A chemical compound that has reduced the growth of pancreatic cancer tumors by 80 percent in treated mice has been developed by researchers. The compound, called MM41, was designed to block faulty genes. It appears to do this by targeting little knots in their DNA, called quadruplexes, which are very different from normal DNA and which are especially found in faulty genes.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:59:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Researchers stretch a thin crystal to get better solar cells</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/WLWOUY7ONuE/150625125956.htm</Link>
        <Description>An interdisciplinary team has made a semiconductor crystal with a variable band gap. Among other potential uses, this variable semiconductor could lead to solar cells that absorb more energy from the sun by being sensitive to a broader spectrum of light.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:59:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A good appetizer could make your main course less enjoyable</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Ot3PKxeGLL4/150625125953.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new study outlines how a good appetizer can make people enjoy the main course less, and a mediocre appetizer can make them enjoy the main course more.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:31:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>microRNA may provide therapy against pancreatic cancer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/V5mXPg4mNrM/150625113102.htm</Link>
        <Description>Cancer researchers have found that a particular microRNA may be a potent therapeutic agent against pancreatic cancer. The need for new therapies for pancreatic cancer patients is great as only 7 percent of people with the disease survive more than 5 years after diagnosis. According to the National Cancer Institute, there will be an estimated 48,960 new cases of pancreatic cancer and 40,560 deaths from the disease in 2015.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:31:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Women on the U.S. $10? These eight women could fill the bill</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Tb1-oB4CUGw/150625113100.htm</Link>
        <Description>Some notable but lesser-known women in American history might be overlooked as possibilities for the soon-to-be redesigned 10 dollar bill.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:30:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Children with severe head injuries are casualties of wars in Iraq, Afghanistan</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/g1UqvhDHlRQ/150625113056.htm</Link>
        <Description>During the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, U.S. combat support hospitals treated at least 650 children with severe, combat-related head injuries, according to a new report.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:29:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>E2F4 signature can predict progression of bladder cancer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/nuQbJSoDSdM/150625112908.htm</Link>
        <Description>Investigators harnessed genomic data to discover that the previously identified E2F4 signature in breast cancer can be utilized to predict prognosis and response to therapy in bladder cancer.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:20:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bad news and good news for birds nesting at reservoirs</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/1xUWtTXnEgk/150625112014.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a six-year study at Arrow Lakes Reservoir in British Columbia, researchers found that while some nests failed due to flooding as the reservoir filled up in the spring, the higher water levels actually provided benefits for the nests that survived. Their results show that overall, nesting in the reservoir's riparian areas did not reduce nest success.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:20:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eating in the absence of hunger: A recipe for expanding waistline</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/X4H6jomnYBI/150625112012.htm</Link>
        <Description>Snacking when you're not hungry can cause weight gain as much as overly large portion sizes and energy-rich foods, a researcher reports.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:20:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chimps are sensitive to what is right and wrong</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/qeu_1wHyqVA/150625112010.htm</Link>
        <Description>How a chimpanzee views a video of an infant chimp from another group being killed gives a sense of how human morality and social norms might have evolved. A new study provides the first evidence that chimpanzees, like humans, are sensitive to the appropriateness of behaviors, especially those directed toward infants.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:20:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Breakthrough graphene production could trigger revolution in artificial skin development</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/1uOwmtN5B1k/150625112008.htm</Link>
        <Description>A pioneering new technique to produce high-quality, low cost graphene could pave the way for the development of the first truly flexible 'electronic skin,' that could be used in robots.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:13:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Past water patterns drive present wading bird numbers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/5PFrMHVMEUw/150625111320.htm</Link>
        <Description>Wading bird numbers in the Florida Everglades are driven by water patterns that play out over multiple years according to a new study. Previously, existing water conditions were seen as the primary driving factor affecting numbers of birds, but this research shows that the preceding years' water conditions and availability are equally important.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="51">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:13:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Experimental treatment sends deadly leukemia into remission</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/BzN22L67W_E/150625111318.htm</Link>
        <Description>An experimental new treatment approach for a rare, deadly leukemia can send the disease into remission even in patients for whom the standard therapy has failed, a pilot study has found. The study is 'proof of principle' the cutting-edge approach could be used to treat many other cancers as well.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="52">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:13:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Starfish that clone themselves live longer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/8w0lizFEh1I/150625111315.htm</Link>
        <Description>Starfish that reproduce through cloning avoid aging to a greater extent than those that propagate through sexual reproduction.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="53">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:13:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pilot program in pediatric long-term care facility halves topical antibiotic use</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/gEXWmPgLuUw/150625111312.htm</Link>
        <Description>A pilot antibiotic stewardship program at a pediatric long-term care facility brought about a 59 percent decrease in use of a topical antibiotic and an 83 percent decrease in orders for antibiotics without proper documentation during a six-month period, according to a new study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="54">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:13:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Infection preventionists may spend more time collecting data than protecting patients</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/8qyxPOKBZT4/150625111309.htm</Link>
        <Description>Collecting and reporting hospital infection data to federal health agencies takes more than five hours each day, at the expense of time needed to ensure that frontline healthcare personnel are adhering to basic infection prevention practices such as hand hygiene, according to a recent case study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="55">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:13:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How companies can reduce sovereign risk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/2JVavWN7hts/150625091306.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a new study of five-year spreads on credit default swap contracts for more than 2,000 U.S. and international firms, a finance researcher found that strong property rights and transparency are key in securing a stable financial future for companies amid a widespread rise in sovereign risk around the globe.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="56">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:12:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New way of understanding police authority, power</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/IdE-wMT9EMw/150625091229.htm</Link>
        <Description>The police aim at maintaining law and order and social peace, and to achieve it they can make use of authority and power in a coercive way, through repression, prohibition or control, but they can also make use of this authority and power to manage conflicts and seek amicable settlements between the parties. A study claims the opportunities offered by police mediation, which operation is still attached to a great dose of "lawlessness”. In this sense, the research shows legal arguments, which clearly support the legal framework of police mediation and compliance with the reporting principles of voluntariness, freely availability and confidentiality governing any field of mediation.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="57">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:11:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Recycled water, salt-tolerant grass a water-saving pair</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/kHKZ-kRbIPU/150625091159.htm</Link>
        <Description>Plants need water. People need water. Unfortunately, there's only so much clean water to go around -- and so the effort begins to find a solution. One strategy is to use treated wastewater, containing salt leftover from the cleaning process, to water large areas of turf grass. Researchers have found ways to breed salt-tolerant turf that can withstand this irrigation.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="58">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:11:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Antarctic life: Highly diverse, unusually structured</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/mQGlMN3U_zI/150625091157.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a comprehensive assessment of Antarctic biodiversity scientists have revealed the region is more diverse and biologically interesting than previously thought. The team noted several unusual ways in which patterns of biodiversity are produced in the region. Geothermal, heated areas, such as volcanoes, have played an important role as refuges from icy, glacial conditions on land. At sea, wind has an especially significant effect on diversity. Windier areas have more seabird species.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="59">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:11:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Writing program with student interaction creates sense of purpose for seniors</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/BvwLzPLniaM/150625091153.htm</Link>
        <Description>A unique program combining a life review writing workshop with conversations between seniors and college students enhances the sense of meaning in life for older adults living independently, finds a new study.</Description>
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Orange is the new red</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YxaL9vQqFsY/150627081238.htm</Link>
        <Description>A photoprotective mechanism in cyanobacteria is triggered by an unprecedented, large-scale movement from one location to another of the carotenoid pigment within the Orange Carotenoid Protein, researchers have discovered.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Opening a new route to photonics</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/61AMNyp9gRM/150627081226.htm</Link>
        <Description>A technique for effectively controlling pulses of light in closely packed nanoscale waveguides -- an essential requirement for ultrahigh density, ultracompact integrated photonic circuitry -- has been developed by a group of researchers.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why June 30 will get an extra second</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/GqNqNbo6NoA/150627081224.htm</Link>
        <Description>The day will officially be a bit longer than usual on Tuesday, June 30, 2015, because an extra second, or 'leap' second, will be added.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Natural wilderness areas need buffer zones to protect from human development</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/aPXw9nE-bFs/150627081222.htm</Link>
        <Description>Despite heavy development, the United States still has millions of acres of pristine wild lands. Coveted for their beauty, these wilderness areas draw innumerable outdoor enthusiasts eager for a taste of primitive nature. But researchers say these federally protected nature areas have a problem: Their boundaries have become prime real estate.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Building a better semiconductor</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/s7TGzc-g2kQ/150627081220.htm</Link>
        <Description>Research could someday lead to the development of new and improved semiconductors. Scientists detail how they developed a method to change the electronic properties of materials in a way that will more easily allow an electrical current to pass through.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New strategies, solutions to fight pediatric asthma</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/KgqR0yMbYoM/150627081218.htm</Link>
        <Description>Low flu vaccination rates, medication compliance and limited access to primary care providers have contributed to the high pediatric asthma rates in California, researchers conclude. This new study details several issues affecting asthma care and offers a number of public policy strategies that could help remedy these shortcomings.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Potential new class of cancer drugs developed in lab</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/t1e-XTKbi48/150627081216.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new class of drug developed targets the Warburg effect to cut off cancer's energy supply, and researchers say that it has the potential to stop most kinds of cancer in its tracks.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Calcium channel essential for deep sleep identified</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/rrjMAdqYC4E/150627081214.htm</Link>
        <Description>A specific calcium channel plays a crucial role in deep, slow-wave sleep, scientists have discovered. This is a key step toward understanding both normal and abnormal waking brain functions.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eco-friendly oil spill solution developed</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/DUkWApYIEkE/150627081212.htm</Link>
        <Description>An eco-friendly biodegradable green 'herding' agent that can be used to clean up light crude oil spills on water has been developed by researchers. Derived from the plant-based small molecule phytol abundant in the marine environment, the new substance would potentially replace chemical herders currently in use, they say.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Children with asthma likely born in area with high air pollution</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/5eUPRK-5Ay4/150627081210.htm</Link>
        <Description>Children who develop asthma in Toronto are more likely to have been born in a neighborhood that has a high level of traffic-related air pollution, new research suggests.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why are seabirds abandoning their ancestral nesting grounds in the Gulf of California?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ACppKLqO3tQ/150627081208.htm</Link>
        <Description>Warming oceanographic conditions and fishing pressure are driving nesting seabirds away from their ancestral breeding ground in Mexico into California harbors, a group of researchers has found.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:10:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fewer tiger subspecies, better protection?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/HBrTSjMlKjU/150627081055.htm</Link>
        <Description>New scientific research could help to protect tigers (Panthera tigris) from extinction. The findings indicate that tigers should be classified as only two subspecies – up to now nine subspecies were previously recognized. This will have a significant impact on species conservation since management efforts and breeding programs can now be organized in a simpler, more flexible and effective way.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:10:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Coil for the next upgrade of the Large Hadron Collider passes tests</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/4sQyMY9zDY8/150627081026.htm</Link>
        <Description>A group collaborating across four American laboratories completed the first successful tests of a superconducting coil in preparation for the future high-luminosity upgrade of the Large Hadron Collider, or HL-LHC. These tests indicate that the magnet design may be adequate for its intended use.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:10:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fatalistic beliefs may prevent Appalachian women from completing HPV vaccination series</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/DOT3zaHJ1V0/150627081022.htm</Link>
        <Description>Could a fatalistic attitude toward cervical cancer serve as a barrier to prevention of the disease? A recent study suggests a link between fatalistic beliefs and completion of the human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccine series among a sample of young Appalachian Kentucky women.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:07:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Better heat exchangers using garbage bags</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Z5vTKLa5nHQ/150626130716.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers are making better heat exchangers for industrial use using the same plastic as in garbage bags.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:06:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The peaks and valleys of silicon</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/OOc7JUwhTV0/150626130651.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have created a new method for generating a 2D semiconducting material that could one day replace silicon in electronics. The demand for a silicon material aided the discovery of graphene, a single layer of graphite -- which won the Nobel Prize in Physics in 2010. Since this time, scientists and engineers have developed many two-dimensional (2D) material innovations -- layered materials with the thickness of only one atom or a few atoms. One such layered 2D material is black arsenic phosphorus.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:06:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Scientists identify 'decoy' molecule that may sharply reduce risk of flu death</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/febxzrVAtiQ/150626130649.htm</Link>
        <Description>The flu virus can be lethal. But what is often just as dangerous is the body's own reaction to the invader. The immune counterattack can end up harming the body's own tissues, causing deadly damage. Now, a researcher has, for the first time, uncovered new details about how this response plays out. And he has identified a 'decoy' molecule that can rein in this runaway inflammatory response.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:57:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Having a stroke? Where you are makes a huge difference in your treatment</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/aH3n8aExkQo/150626125725.htm</Link>
        <Description>It looks like a crazy quilt spread over the continent. But a new map of emergency stroke care in America shows just how much of a patchwork system we still have for delivering the most effective stroke treatment. And thousands of people a year may end up unnecessarily disabled as a result.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:56:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Helium ‘balloons’ offer new path to control complex materials</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/3g8QigeSawc/150626105651.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have developed a new method to manipulate a wide range of materials and their behavior using only a handful of helium ions.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:56:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Light fixture kills bacteria safely, continuously</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Q6tuTr0MI8I/150626105627.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new light fixture uses Continuous Environmental Disinfection technology to continuously kill harmful bacteria linked to hospital acquired infections (HAIs). The technology behind the Indigo-Clean™ inactivates a wide range of micro-organisms that are known causes of HAIs, including MRSA (Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus), C.difficile and VRE (Vancomycin-resistant Enterococcus).</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:51:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Analysis shows increased carbon intensity from Canadian oil sands</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Q8CLrYubmjs/150626105141.htm</Link>
        <Description>Gasoline and diesel refined from Canadian oil sands has a higher carbon impact than fuels derived from conventional domestic crude sources, a new study concludes.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:51:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pet owners reluctant to face up to their cats' kill count</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/9v9ehLibRuA/150626105139.htm</Link>
        <Description>Pet owners are reluctant to face up to their cats' kill count, a new study suggests. Cat owners fail to realize the impact of their cat on wildlife according to new research.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:51:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Most of amateur athletes undergoing hypoxic training are not advised by specialists</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/MGQ1kUk5ezw/150626105137.htm</Link>
        <Description>Physical performance after periods of hypoxic training -- in low-oxygen conditions -- has become a matter of growing controversy within the scientific community. An international study compared professional and amateur athletes' knowledge and understanding of this type of training According to the results, just 25 percent of amateurs are assessed and monitored by specialists.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:57:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Solving Saturn’s 2-billion-year age problem</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/_lLPdaX1J04/150626095705.htm</Link>
        <Description>Experiments at Sandia's Z machine have provided data may help explain why Saturn is two billion years younger than Jupiter on some computer simulations, supporting a prediction first made in 1935.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:56:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Project to 3-D print houses begun</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/53b7uwybrEY/150626095604.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists are developing a technology to make full-scale 3D prints of cellulose based material. It is not a matter of small prints – the objective is to make houses.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:55:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>3-D heart printed using multiple imaging techniques</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/03qL4okA19Y/150626095528.htm</Link>
        <Description>Congenital heart experts have successfully integrated two common imaging techniques to produce a three-dimensional anatomic model of a patient's heart. This is the first time the integration of computed tomography (CT) and three-dimensional transesophageal echocardiography (3DTEE) has been used in this way. A proof-of-concept study also opens the way for these techniques to be used in combination with a third tool -- magnetic resonance imaging (MRI).</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:55:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>High blood pressure linked to reduced Alzheimer's risk, meds may be reason</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/6uU8dplOVGE/150626095526.htm</Link>
        <Description>People with a genetic predisposition to high blood pressure have a lower risk for Alzheimer's disease, new research suggests. However, authors conclude the connection may have more to do with anti-hypertension medication than high blood pressure itself.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:55:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Action spectrum of sun skin damage documented</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/t0OY2SIYYRQ/150626095523.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have documented for the first time the DNA damage that can occur to skin across the full range of ultraviolet radiation from the sun providing an invaluable tool for sun-protection and the manufacturers of sunscreen.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:55:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Inactivity reduces people's muscle strength</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/eEG1WISgSdY/150626095520.htm</Link>
        <Description>It only takes two weeks of not using their legs for young people to lose a third of their muscular strength, leaving them on par with a person who is 40-50 years their senior, new research shows.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:55:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Daily bathing of pediatric patients with antiseptic cuts bloodstream infections by 59 percent</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/MGOq689zsmI/150626095518.htm</Link>
        <Description>Daily bathing of pediatric patients with disposable cloths containing 2 percent chlorhexidine gluconate reduced central line-associated bloodstream infections by 59 percent and saved approximately $300,000 in one hospital over a six-month period, according to a new study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:55:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Attractive female flies harmed by male sexual attention</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/cRMqVAm3yvI/150626095516.htm</Link>
        <Description>Too much male sexual attention harms attractive females, according to a new study on fruit flies. The study showed that male harassment of females hampered the species' ability to adapt to new environmental conditions.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:55:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Braking mechanism identified for cell growth pathway linked to several cancers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/hI5AKBVZT8I/150626095513.htm</Link>
        <Description>A self-regulating loop in the Hippo pathway, a signaling channel garnering increased attention from cancer researchers due to its role in controlling organ size, cell proliferation and cell death, has been identified by researchers.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:42:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>RNASEH1 mutations impair mtDNA replication, cause adult-onset mitochondrial encephalomyopathy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YWUWcfl_FE8/150626084259.htm</Link>
        <Description>Next Generation Sequencing (NGS) technology offers an incredible opportunity for the rapid and relatively low-cost characterization of individual genomes, giving us a chance to make a substantial leap ahead in the molecular dissection of all mitochondrial disorders in humans.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:42:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Darwinian fisheries: Shrinking fish sizes in exploited stocks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/63JnKJkoCxg/150626084257.htm</Link>
        <Description>An experimental study with size-selectively harvested zebrafish that began in 2006 reveals that size-selective harvesting causes changes in key life-history traits, leading to low maximum body size and poor reproductive output.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:41:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bronze Age humans' diet and arrival of new crops in Iberian Peninsula</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/3pPGm0VV8CI/150626084135.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have studied human skeletal remains from the Cova do Santo collective burial cave in northwestern Spain. Remains found in the Sil river valley -- in the province of Ourense -- reveal a vegetable-based diet with little meat or fish.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:41:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Key protein may affect risk of stroke</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/5_YK8e6lVmc/150626084131.htm</Link>
        <Description>Studies on mice reveal that a special protein in the brain's tiniest blood vessels may affect the risk of stroke. Scientists are learning how the blood-brain barrier develops and what makes the capillaries in the brain different from small blood vessels in other organs.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:41:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Graphene: Magnetic sensor 100 times more sensitive than silicon equivalent</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Ve9B5DpWMbY/150626084129.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have created a graphene-based magnetic sensor 100 times more sensitive than an equivalent device based on silicon.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:41:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Endogenous proteins as anti-inflammatory agents</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/7F7p2v3axY0/150626084127.htm</Link>
        <Description>In autoimmune diseases and immune pathologies such as rheumatoid arthritis, psoriasis or organ rejection, inflammatory processes take place in the body, triggered by its own immune system. New research is concentrating on a special protein that is thought to play an important role in controlling excessive immune reactions.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:41:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Unexpectedly little black-hole monsters rapidly suck up surrounding matter</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/xl_ZMuTrFtk/150626084124.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have found evidence that enigmatic objects in nearby galaxies -- called ultra-luminous X-ray sources (ULXs) -- exhibit strong outflows that are created as matter falls onto their black holes at unexpectedly high rates. The strong outflows suggest that the black holes in these ULXs must be much smaller than expected. Curiously, these objects appear to be "cousins" of SS 433, one of the most exotic objects in our own Milky Way Galaxy. The team's observations help shed light on the nature of ULXs, and impact our understanding of how supermassive black holes in galactic centers are formed and how matter rapidly falls onto those black holes.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:39:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More endangered pygmy sloths in Panama than previously estimated</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/HdF4cPJo0ZY/150626083921.htm</Link>
        <Description>Pygmy sloths wander inland in addition to inhabiting the mangrove fringes of their island refuge. A researchers now suggests that the population size of the pygmy sloth has been underestimated; a new, higher estimate for the number of sloths on Panama's Escudo de Veraguas Island points to how little is known about the species, and it underscores the need to conserve the sloths' isolated home.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:39:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iron: A biological element?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/51pdl6d9MDU/150626083919.htm</Link>
        <Description>Think of an object made of iron: An I-beam, a car frame, a nail. Now imagine that half of the iron in that object owes its existence to bacteria living two and a half billion years ago. That's the upshot of a new study. Its findings have meaning for fields as diverse as mining and the search for life in space.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:39:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Want to be seen as more loving and a better cook?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/UoroZXZ3WTg/150626083917.htm</Link>
        <Description>Do you want to be seen as a better cook and a more loving parent? It's as easy as serving a vegetable at dinner, according to recent research. Families are most likely to consume vegetables at dinner time, yet only about 23% of dinners contain a full serving of vegetables, the study discovered.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:39:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Exercising early in life yields rewards in adult years</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/IvWFRx6FX90/150626083915.htm</Link>
        <Description>What impact can exercise done early in life have on the propensity for exercising during the adult years? Researchers did experiments on mice in the lab to find out. They found that early-age exercise in mice has positive effects on adult levels of voluntary exercise in addition to reducing body mass -- results that may have relevance for the public policy debates concerning the importance of physical education for children.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:38:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Spiral arms cradle baby terrestrial planets</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/jo1Z_-U9Dog/150626083812.htm</Link>
        <Description>New work offers a potential solution to a longstanding problem in the prevailing theory of how rocky planets formed in our own Solar System, as well as in others. The snag he's untangling: how dust grains in the matter orbiting a young protostar avoid getting dragged into the star before they accumulate into bodies large enough that their own gravity allows them to rapidly attract enough material to grow into planets.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:38:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Long-acting antipsychotic medication may improve treatment for schizophrenia</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/sw_Hc1-fIQU/150626083810.htm</Link>
        <Description>An injectable drug given every two weeks works better than a daily pill for those who have been recently diagnosed with schizophrenia, a study shows.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:38:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pet care can help improve adolescents' Type 1 diabetes management, pediatricians find</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/vx6A_swqskk/150626083808.htm</Link>
        <Description>Pediatric diabetes researchers found that incorporating routine pet care into a child's diabetes self-care plan can significantly improve monitoring of the disease, resulting in lower blood glucose levels.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:38:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Researchers uncover epigenetic switches that turn stem cells into blood vessel cells</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/X2wmCBZvCrk/150626083806.htm</Link>
        <Description>A molecular mechanism that directs embryonic stem cells to mature into endothelial cells -- the specialized cells that form blood vessels -- has been discovered by researchers. Understanding the processes initiated by this mechanism could help scientists more efficiently convert stem cells into endothelial cells for use in tissue repair, or for engineering blood vessels to bypass blockages in the heart.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:38:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Head Start program played anti-segregation role in the Deep South</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/G7MCVWewc5c/150626083802.htm</Link>
        <Description>A federal preschool program did more than improve educational opportunities for poor children in Mississippi during the 1960s. The program also gave a political and economic boost to the state's civil rights activists, according to a historian.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:38:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Waging war on Australia's nastiest parasite: Scientists map blowfly genome</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-AsKgtI6cvY/150626083800.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have decoded the Australian sheep blowfly genome, adding ammunition to the battle against one of the nation's most insidious pests. This blowfly is responsible for about $280 million in losses to Australia's sheep industry each year from flystrike.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:37:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Medically complex patients with Type 2 diabetes could benefit from seeing a specialist soon</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/f571rZ7daMc/150626083756.htm</Link>
        <Description>People recently diagnosed with Type 2 diabetes and who have other serious chronic health issues have less heart disease and lower death rates if they see an endocrinologist within one year of diagnosis, new research suggests.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European rule changes on cross border pet transport may heighten rabies risk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/QjlVF7mV9Zw/150626083445.htm</Link>
        <Description>Recent changes to regulations on the transport of pets across Europe may have increased the threat of introducing rabies from rescue dogs into countries considered free of the disease, suggests research.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="51">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>SSRI antidepressants taken for menopausal symptoms may boost bone fracture risk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/oTZexd1Dp_A/150626083441.htm</Link>
        <Description>The class of antidepressants known as SSRIs (selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors), taken to curb menopausal symptoms, may boost bone fracture risk, suggests new research.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="52">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Online computer game can help shed weight, reduce food intake</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/UqKHPvMVFVw/150626083439.htm</Link>
        <Description>A simple new computerized game could help people control their snacking impulses and lose weight. Psychologists report that participants lost an average of 0.7kg and consumed around 220 fewer calories a day whilst undergoing the week of training.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="53">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rapid Ebola diagnostic successful in field trial</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/fteLWrapH2Y/150626083437.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new test can accurately diagnose Ebola virus disease within minutes, providing clinicians with crucial information for treating patients and containing outbreaks.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="54">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rats 'dream' paths to a brighter future</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/pL2X6iws3j8/150626083433.htm</Link>
        <Description>When rats rest, their brains simulate journeys to a desired future such as a tasty treat. Researchers monitored brain activity in rats, first as the animals viewed food in a location they could not reach, then as they rested in a separate chamber, and finally as they were allowed to walk to the food. The activity of specialized brain cells involved in navigation suggested that during the rest the rats simulated walking to and from food that they had been unable to reach.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="55">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Hydrothermal siphon' drives water circulation through seafloor</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/vcnSxIf5SEc/150626083431.htm</Link>
        <Description>Vast quantities of ocean water circulate through the seafloor, flowing through the volcanic rock of the upper oceanic crust. A new study explains what drives this global process and how the flow is sustained. About 25 percent of the heat that flows out of Earth's interior is transferred to the oceans through this process.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="56">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Emergency visits for childhood food allergy on rise in Illinois</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/7NJhctkkWlM/150626083429.htm</Link>
        <Description>Emergency room visits and hospitalizations of children with severe, potentially life-threatening food allergy reactions increased nearly 30 percent in Illinois over five years, reports a new study. Hispanic children, who previously had the lowest cases of food allergies, had the biggest increase with a 44 percent rise. This study shows severe food allergies are beginning to impact children of all races and income. It is no longer primarily a disease of children who are white and/or from higher income families.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="57">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>High-performance microscope displays pores in the cell nucleus with greater precision</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/RLX-TUDYj3s/150626083426.htm</Link>
        <Description>The transportation of certain molecules into and out of the cell nucleus takes place via nuclear pores. For some time, detailed research has been conducted into how these pores embedded in the nuclear envelope are structured. Now, for the first time, biochemists have succeeded in elucidating the structure of the transportation channel inside the nuclear pores in high resolution using high-performance electron microscopes.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="58">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:07:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tests vs. Fests: Students in 'learning celebrations' rather than exams scored higher and enjoyed themselves</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/2wnjZdem5cw/150625170753.htm</Link>
        <Description>A sociologist who reshaped "test day" in his class -- transforming it with balloons, streamers, treats and music -- found that students in "learning celebrations" scored higher than students who took standard-style exams in previous semesters.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="59">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:07:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New strategies for combatting chronic kidney disease, other long-term conditions</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/GUFjpWkk8JM/150625170751.htm</Link>
        <Description>New strategies for using electronic health records (EHRs) to treat patients with chronic kidney disease have been outlined by investigators. Their recommendations may help clinicians and hospitals better manage individual patients with chronic conditions and identify groups of patients most likely to benefit from different treatment strategies.</Description>
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
</site>
