<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="sciencedaily">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:57:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supernovas help 'clean' galaxies</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/CYpjyZdT2n4/150526155720.htm</Link>
        <Description>Astronomers have found that the black holes located at the cores of galaxies launch fountains of charged particles, which can stir up gas throughout the galaxy and temporarily interrupt star formation. But unless something intervenes, the gas will eventually cool and start forming stars again.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:48:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Study suggests using excess stress to kill therapy resistant breast cancer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/njFiLiwHsks/150526144843.htm</Link>
        <Description>Maxing out the inherently stressed nature of treatment-resistant breast cancer cells thwarts their adaptive ability to evolve genetic workarounds to treatment, according to a study. Looking at tumor progression as essentially an evolutionary process, researchers highlight the feasibility of maximizing cell stress by inhibiting adaptive pathways to cause cell death.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:48:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Astrophysicist provides new fluid dynamics insights</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/RX4tAflXEII/150526144809.htm</Link>
        <Description>New calculations by a theoretical astrophysicist provide tools that open a door to exploring the history of events in astrophysical flows and in plasma fusion devices.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:48:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New foam technology to lead advances in medical devices and protective equipment</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/JZhJZqxL_K4/150526144806.htm</Link>
        <Description>A unique, high performance foam has been developed that can be used to make safer athletic gear and medical equipment, among other things. The developers anticipate an immediate benefit to the medical device and protective equipment industries while the collaborative project for the development of the new prosthetic sock is underway.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:06:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New chip makes testing for antibiotic-resistant bacteria faster, easier</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/1jc2OTQd6K4/150526140607.htm</Link>
        <Description>We live in fear of 'superbugs': infectious bacteria that don't respond to treatment by antibiotics, and can turn a routine hospital stay into a nightmare. Now, researchers have designed a diagnostic chip to reduce testing time of antibiotics from days to one hour, allowing doctors to pick the right antibiotic the first time.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:06:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Advance in quantum error correction</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Sr4GxzbDUTc/150526140603.htm</Link>
        <Description>Protocol corrects virtually all errors in quantum memory, but requires little measure of quantum states.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:06:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Babies can think before they can speak</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/RdF_mk5yGV8/150526140601.htm</Link>
        <Description>Analogical ability -- the ability to see common relations between objects, events or ideas -- is a key skill that underlies human intelligence and differentiates humans from other apes. While there is considerable evidence that preschoolers can learn abstract relations, it remains an open question whether infants can as well. In a new study, researchers found infants are capable of learning the abstract relations of same and different after only a few examples.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:05:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Historian mapping out a new view of the Medieval world</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/cdJoUv98AU8/150526140524.htm</Link>
        <Description>Maps show us the way and identify major landmarks – rivers, towns, roads and hills. For centuries, they also offered a perspective on how societies viewed themselves in comparison to the rest of the world. New research looks at maps from the medieval and early-modern Muslim world.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:24:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Clinical trial reduces stress of cancer caregivers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/gcvDdX1WpBs/150526132401.htm</Link>
        <Description>A randomized control trial demonstrates an intervention that successfully reduces the stress of caregivers in the context of cancer patients treated with stem cell transplantation. The study enrolled 148 caregivers of allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell (Allo-HSCT) patients.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:23:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Honesty can keep companies' stock prices up during hard times</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/EZBc1lRCo94/150526132359.htm</Link>
        <Description>Honesty is the best policy, and a new study finds that companies can benefit when they publicly accept the blame for poor performance. Just taking responsibility, however, is not the entire solution, say authors of the report. When companies accepted the blame, they also had to explain how they were going to fix the problem.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:23:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Infusions of donor bone marrow cells help children with inherited skin blistering</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/MDBbrJabTAY/150526132355.htm</Link>
        <Description>Promising results from a trial of a new stem-cell based therapy for a rare and debilitating skin condition suggest that the therapy, involving infusions of stem cells, provide pain relief and to reduce the severity of this skin condition for which no cure currently exists.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:23:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New findings about mechanisms underlying chronic pain reveal novel therapeutic strategies</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/B6z21XjT7eg/150526132353.htm</Link>
        <Description>A critical role for a class of cells present in the brain and spinal cord, called microglia, has been discovered for those in pain. Researchers have found microglia to neuron signaling to be crucial in the development of pain hypersensitivity after injury, but also for one of the paradoxical effects morphine and other opioids sometimes produce, called hyperalgesia, which is an increase in pain sensitivity.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:22:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A push to open doors to care for the homebound</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/--5rbBKIyls/150526132239.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new study examines a nearly invisible population of shut-ins for ways to treat the infirm, assist the rest. Researchers looked at the community-dwelling Medicare population, which they estimate to be about 2 million people in the United States. They explain that most older adults want to age at home, but with the ability to come and go as they wish. Being homebound means being trapped, unable to leave without considerable help.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:49:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Squeezed quantum cats' and 'stable cats' for quantum computers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/FNPr4av2dM0/150526124922.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have reached deep into their bag of tricks to create so-called 'squeezed Schrodinger cats.' These quantum systems could be extremely useful for future technologies.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:49:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New urine test could reduce need for blood samples</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ATafUEUUGd8/150526124904.htm</Link>
        <Description>If you've been to the doctor, you probably know what to do when you're handed a plastic cup and shown to the bathroom. Most patients hand over the sample and give little thought to what happens when it's shipped to the lab for analysis. Researchers have developed a new testing method that they believe will reduce costs, get faster results and lower the volume of urine needed for a sample.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:49:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Changes in forest structure affect bees, other pollinators</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/76h7oRrPG6M/150526124902.htm</Link>
        <Description>Over the past century, many forests have shifted from open to closed canopies. The change in forest structure could be contributing to declines in pollinator species, especially native bees, according to a new study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:49:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ER doctors stress need for good communications with police</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/2oiLsW0mCK8/150526124900.htm</Link>
        <Description>Not surprisingly, differences of opinion arise from time to time over a health care worker's duty to protect patient privacy and the police need to conduct a criminal investigation. A good working relationship with police is therefore essential for the smooth operation of a busy Emergency Department, experts say.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:48:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Co-operative tools: Intelligent handheld robots</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/hv4pnfqhyUk/150526124858.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have developed and started studying a novel concept in robotics -- intelligent handheld robots.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:48:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Genomic data reveals emergence in Africa of drug resistant strain of typhoid</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ultq8-FWIFQ/150526124856.htm</Link>
        <Description>The emergence of a novel strain of Typhoid fever in Malawi, Africa has been revealed by scientists. Research suggests that the H58-strain, which is likely to have emerged in Asia approximately thirty years ago, is now rapidly spreading across Africa, where it has been introduced on several separate occasions. A key feature of this strain appears to be its ability to acquire resistance to commonly available antibiotics.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:48:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Neuroscientists reveals autism's 'noisy' secret: 3-D simulator reveals inner workings of the autistic brain</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/KnZVrAGV0oQ/150526124854.htm</Link>
        <Description>Strapped into a motion-enabled simulator and wearing 3-D glasses, 36 adolescent volunteers recently experienced what it was like to 'travel' through a field of virtual stars. The experiments provided new and convention-busting data about how sensory stimuli are processed by the brains of individuals with Autism Spectrum Disorder.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:48:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Severe ozone depletion avoided</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/HobDLwpmB38/150526124811.htm</Link>
        <Description>We are already reaping the rewards of the Montreal Protocol, researchers say, with the ozone layer in much better shape than it would have been without the UN treaty. Although the Montreal Protocol came into force in 1987 and restricted the use of ozone-depleting substances, atmospheric concentrations of these harmful substances continued to rise as they can survive in the atmosphere for many years. Concentrations peaked in 1993 and have subsequently declined, the researchers say.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:48:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Soy supplements don't improve asthma, study concludes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/bRkXaLONEDw/150526124809.htm</Link>
        <Description>Despite previous findings suggesting a link between soy intake and decreased asthma severity, a new placebo-controlled study shows soy supplements do not improve lung function for patients with asthma. The paper highlights the importance of focusing on overall health -- not just one food -- to manage disease and the importance of performing well-designed studies.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:47:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Better fine motor skills with delayed cord clamping</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/JLc6Uv3YFiE/150526124728.htm</Link>
        <Description>The importance of the umbilical cord for both the fetus and for newborn infants was demonstrated by researchers several years ago, in a study that received great international acclaim. In a follow-up study, the researchers have now been able to show an association between delayed cord clamping (DCC) and children's fine motor skills at the age of four years, especially in boys.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:47:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New technique speeds nanoMRI imaging</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/aeHRw6OaQGM/150526124726.htm</Link>
        <Description>NanoMRI is a scanning technique that produces nondestructive, high-resolution 3-D images of nanoscale objects, and it promises to become a powerful tool for researchers and companies exploring the shape and function of biological materials such as viruses and cells in much the same way as clinical MRI today enables investigation of whole tissues in the human body.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:45:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Where there's a will … well, there's another way</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/C2k5lcbWL9s/150526124557.htm</Link>
        <Description>There’s more than one way to gain a sense of control. The traditional view of a life in control is one in which an individual has taken actions to ensure success in both the near and long terms. “Secondary control,” has been given short shrift in both the scientific literature and the attitudes of Western societies. Secondary control can be described as a mindset in which one accepts and adapts to the fact that much of life can’t be bent to human will.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:45:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hospice use linked to fewer depressive symptoms for surviving spouses</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/fEtnhrPYeiw/150526124555.htm</Link>
        <Description>Spouses of patients receiving hospice for three or more days more frequently reported reduced depression symptoms, compared to surviving spouses of patients who did not receive hospice, a new report concludes.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:38:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Study finds association between exposure to aflatoxin and gallbladder cancer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/SjRzoOodR3Q/150526123845.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a small study in Chile that included patients with gallbladder cancer, exposure to aflatoxin (a toxin produced by mold) was associated with an increased risk of gallbladder cancer. In Chile, gallbladder cancer is a leading cause of cancer death in women. Exposure to aflatoxin, a liver carcinogen, is associated with gallbladder cancer in primates.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:38:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Study examines association of genetic variants with cognitive impairment</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/hfSo2l0EkoY/150526123843.htm</Link>
        <Description>Individually rare but collectively common intermediate-size copy number variations may be negatively associated with educational attainment, according to a study. Copy number variations (CNVs) are regions of the genome that differ in the number of segments of DNA.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:38:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Subclinical hyperthyroidism associated with an increased risk of hip and other fractures</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/6IGvJCPH9qs/150526123839.htm</Link>
        <Description>In an analysis that included more than 70,000 participants from 13 studies, subclinical hyperthyroidism was associated with an increased risk for hip and other fractures including spine. Subclinical hyperthyroidism is a low serum thyroid-stimulating hormone concentration in a person without clinical symptoms and normal thyroid hormone concentrations on blood tests.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:38:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New kind of wood chip: Biodegradable computer chips made from wood</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/NUBEAlVSoHI/150526123835.htm</Link>
        <Description>Portable electronics -- typically made of non-renewable, non-biodegradable and potentially toxic materials -- are discarded at an alarming rate in consumers' pursuit of the next best electronic gadget. In an effort to alleviate the environmental burden of electronic devices, scientists have develop a surprising solution: a semiconductor chip made almost entirely of wood.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:38:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Starved for fire, Wisconsin's pine barrens disappear</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/KEFuPuVFUps/150526123833.htm</Link>
        <Description>A century spent treating wildfires as emergencies to be stamped out may have cost Central Wisconsin a natural setting that was common and thriving before the state was settled.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:38:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Who needs water to assemble DNA? Non-aqueous solvent supports DNA nanotechnology</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/3sNdsvRagMY/150526123831.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have now shown that they can assemble DNA nanostructures in a solvent containing no water. They also discovered that adding a small amount of water to their solvent increases the assembly rate and provides a new means for controlling the process. The solvent may also facilitate the production of more complex structures by reducing the problem of DNA becoming trapped in unintended structures.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:38:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tiny heart, big promise: Understanding how cells become coronary vessels may lead to advances in repairing heart damage</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/aR7HcoewQi4/150526123829.htm</Link>
        <Description>Studying zebrafish, investigators have discovered a new source for cells that can develop into coronary vessels and have identified the signaling protein, a chemokine called CXCL12, which guides this process.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Tue May 26 18:06:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Monitoring magnetospheres: Debunking theory behind massive stars</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/pbQg205QMTo/150526110616.htm</Link>
        <Description>Students researching magnetic, massive stars, have uncovered questions concerning the behavior of plasma within their magnetospheres.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Tue May 26 18:06:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nanotechnology identifies brain tumor types through MRI 'virtual biopsy' in animal studies</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/t2um8Q4UHaw/150526110613.htm</Link>
        <Description>A tiny drug-delivery system has been invented that can identify cancer cell types in the brain through 'virtual biopsies' and then attack the molecular structure of the disease. The results could be used to deliver nano-scale drugs that can distinguish and fight tumor cells in the brain without resorting to surgery, the authors say.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Tue May 26 18:06:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How DNA is organized in our cells</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/LMRFlsFwc_0/150526110610.htm</Link>
        <Description>A critical role for two proteins in chromatin structure has been uncovered by researchers. Their breakthrough helps explain how DNA is organized in our cells. This discovery could lead to a better understanding of what causes certain types of cancer, such as lymphoma.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Tue May 26 18:05:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Researchers solve another piece of the puzzle how forests can effect our climate</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/yWf9gVikoQE/150526110558.htm</Link>
        <Description>A first global scale study has estimated how forest emitted compounds affecting cloud seeds via formation of low-volatility vapors. According to the latest projections, terrestrial vegetation emits several million tons of extremely low-volatility organic compounds per year to the atmosphere. These oxidation products of compounds such as monoterpenes results in an increase of condensing vapors that can further form cloud condensation nuclei over the continents and thus has an influence on the cloud formation.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Tue May 26 18:05:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What is the most humane way to kill a cane toad?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/GAXARCfggWk/150526110555.htm</Link>
        <Description>Like many pests, cane toads are killed in their thousands in Australia every year, especially by community-based 'toad-busting' groups. New research has now revealed the most humane way to do it.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Tue May 26 18:05:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Therapy-resistant breast cancer mechanism revealed</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/UtTCUvRAHDY/150526110553.htm</Link>
        <Description>A cluster of defined, non-coding RNAs are mechanistically involved in endocrine therapy resistance in human breast cancer cells, new research has revealed. Furthermore, resveratrol, a kind of polyphenol, was found to repress these RNAs and inhibit the proliferative activity of breast cancer cells which had acquired resistance.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Tue May 26 18:05:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nearly indestructible virus yields tool to treat diseases</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/P9GnwXG2u8c/150526110549.htm</Link>
        <Description>By unlocking the secrets of a bizarre virus that survives in nearly boiling acid, scientists have found a blueprint for battling human disease using DNA clad in near-indestructible armor.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Tue May 26 18:02:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Evolution of the Antarctic ice sheet</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ZwmJ2P3tnpc/150526110224.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new light has been shed on the stability of the Antarctic ice sheet. It shows for the first time that ice rises (pinning points that keep the floating parts of ice sheets in place) are formed during the transition between glacial and interglacial periods, which significantly slows down the response of the ice sheet to climate change.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Tue May 26 17:09:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How will Congressmen vote? Just look at their social circles, study finds</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-Sp5NsWEl2Y/150526100951.htm</Link>
        <Description>US Congress members' social circles are more important in how they vote than their liberal or conservative beliefs or constituents' opinions, according to a new model of voting behavior.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Tue May 26 17:09:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Smartphone app predicts GPA</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-swle6xGpCI/150526100949.htm</Link>
        <Description>If you're a college student wondering how your study and party habits will affect your GPA, wonder no longer. Dartmouth researchers and their colleagues have built the first app that automatically predicts college students' grade point average based on their smartphone data.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Tue May 26 17:09:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Climate change debate fueled by 'echo chambers,' new study finds</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/b1TuiHgUzHc/150526100947.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new study demonstrates the highly contentious debate on climate change is fueled in part by how information flows throughout policy networks. Researchers found that 'echo chambers' -- social network structures where individuals with the same viewpoint share information with each other -- may help explain why, despite a well-documented scientific consensus on the causes of global changes in climate, half of US senators voted earlier this year against an amendment affirming that climate change is human-induced.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Tue May 26 17:09:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Study identifies Ebola virus's Achilles' heel</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/TchiADlv484/150526100917.htm</Link>
        <Description>The molecular "lock" that the deadly Ebola virus must pick to gain entry to cells has been identified by researchers. The findings, made in mice, suggest that drugs blocking entry to this lock could protect against Ebola infection.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:36:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How to get high-quality RNA from chemically complex plants</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Bo6_hPigtgc/150526093617.htm</Link>
        <Description>RNA extraction is a notoriously tricky and sensitive lab procedure, but new protocols are quicker, more effective, and more reliable than previous methods. The protocols are featured in bench-ready form with detailed notes and a troubleshooting guide tested extensively on a diverse selection of woody, aromatic, and aquatic plants.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:36:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Herpes offers big insights on coughing -- and potential new remedies</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/4x1vnQA4ekY/150526093615.htm</Link>
        <Description>Cough treatments could change dramatically after the herpes virus helped researchers discover that the respiratory tract links to two different parts of the nervous system.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:36:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Glancing at greenery on a city rooftop can markedly boost concentration levels</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/h7Wri-Mj8OU/150526093611.htm</Link>
        <Description>Glancing at a grassy green roof for only 40 seconds markedly boosts concentration, a new study concludes. The green roof provided a restorative experience that boosted those mental resources that control attention, researchers say.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:36:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two new, very large classes of RNAs found to be linked to cancer biomark</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/LdeaJrpRFBo/150526093606.htm</Link>
        <Description>Two new classes of RNAs have been identified that are closely associated with a protein known to be a prognostic biomarker for breast cancer and could play a role in progression of prostate cancer.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:35:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Communication made easier for children with cerebral palsy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/dzQAjd76KNI/150526093533.htm</Link>
        <Description>A European initiative has developed a new brain-computer interface system to enhance communication skills of people with cerebral palsy from childhood, improving the relationship with their environment and the expression of emotions.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:35:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Friendships start better with a smile</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/30uzNzSNEK4/150526093531.htm</Link>
        <Description>If you want to strike up a new relationship, simply smile. It works because people are much more attuned to positive emotions when forming new bonds than they are to negative ones such as anger, contempt or sadness. Don't try to fake it, however, because people can recognize a sincere smile a mile away, according to an American study that sheds light on how relationships are formed and maintained.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="51">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:34:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Low-altitude aerial images allow early detection of devastating avocado disease</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/zfeuyUvnEms/150526093441.htm</Link>
        <Description>The laurel wilt pathogen can severely damage Florida's avocado crop, which provides a $100 million-a-year economic impact on Florida. But the new camera images can give growers a jump-start on the disease.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="52">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:34:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Decoder ring' powers found in micro RNA</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/itwLsU6zDj4/150526093439.htm</Link>
        <Description>MicroRNA can serve as a "decoder ring" for understanding complex biological processes, a team of chemists has found. Their study points to a new method for decrypting the biological functions of enzymes and identifying those that drive diseases.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="53">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:34:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anti-pollution rules have uncertain effects</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/r8pkcu1hn78/150526093437.htm</Link>
        <Description>Air pollution regulations issued by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency are estimated to save thousands of lives annually. A new study, however, says these estimates are more uncertain than commonly believed.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="54">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:34:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Carbon nanothreads from compressed benzene</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/KvzLKInEdbw/150526093435.htm</Link>
        <Description>The thinnest possible linear thread that still retains a diamond-like structure was created by the extreme compression and decompression of the common chemical benzene. The threads may have outstanding mechanical and electronic properties. Further, the synthesis method opens up possible variations that could lead to new materials.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="55">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:32:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Green-mix' concrete: An environmentally friendly building material</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/I13TCXpWUVY/150526093237.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have developed an environment friendly version of building concrete called green-mix concrete.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="56">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:32:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Can a little loving kindness improve our mental health?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/51KzgHHO25w/150526093234.htm</Link>
        <Description>Mindfulness - an ancient Buddhist approach to meditation - is attracting increasing attention in the 21st century as a non-invasive treatment for stress and depression. But can it improve mental well-being in young people?</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="57">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:32:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Enhancing the productivity of yarn makers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/SfB-iOwqB8E/150526093232.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchershave developed a new yarn manufacturing technology that can increase productivity with less energy consumption.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="58">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:32:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ozone antiseptic shows potential for treating severe gum infections</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/h3B4My6bHWg/150526093230.htm</Link>
        <Description>A powerful new antiseptic agent, called ozone nanobubble water, holds promise for the treatment of periodontitis, or severe gum infections, according to new research.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="59">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:32:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mapping Singapore’s urban heat island phenomenon</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/g8i-rjtWaU4/150526093228.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers in Singapore are developing a microclimatic modelling tool to prevent further deterioration of the country’s urban heat island phenomenon.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
</site>
