<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="sciencedaily">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 01:32:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Typically disregarded brain lesions may warn of heightened stroke risk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/MD5_5e22Dfw/150706183247.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have found that very small brain lesions noted on brain imaging that would typically be disregarded by clinicians are associated with a heightened risk of stroke and death. The discovery about these tiny lesions -- areas of the brain where tissue may have been damaged by injury or disease -- may help physicians identify people at risk of stroke and death as early as middle age.</Description>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:18:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Multiple pathways progressing to Alzheimer's disease</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/hqrouZfQmVQ/150625161845.htm</Link>
        <Description>The amyloid cascade hypothesis of Alzheimer's disease (AD) posits that sticky aggregations or plaques of amyloid-beta peptides accumulate over time in the brain, triggering a series of events that ultimately result in the full-blown neurodegenerative disorder. The hypothesis has been a major driver of AD research for more than 20 years. However, in a new study, researchers suggest the picture is not so clear-cut, reporting that early indicators or biomarkers of AD development are not fixed in a specific sequence.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:16:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A person's diet, acidity of urine may affect susceptibility to UTIs</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/4jwN4zo0b00/150625161623.htm</Link>
        <Description>The acidity of urine — as well as the presence of small molecules related to diet — may influence how well bacteria can grow in the urinary tract, a new study shows. The research may have implications for treating urinary tract infections, which are among the most common bacterial infections worldwide.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:15:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As siblings learn how to resolve conflict, parents pick up a few tips of their own</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/7WKePZoZdZc/150625161514.htm</Link>
        <Description>When children participated in a program designed to reduce sibling conflict, both parents benefited from a lessening of hostilities on the home front. But mothers experienced a more direct reward. As they viewed the children's sessions in real time on a video monitor and coached the kids at home to respond as they'd been taught, moms found that, like their kids, they were better able to manage their own emotions during stressful moments.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:15:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brain scan can predict who responds best to certain treatment for OCD</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/noTX3685hLg/150625161512.htm</Link>
        <Description>A certain detail from patients' brain scans could help clinicians identify which people are more likely to relapse after cognitive-behavioral therapy -- and why. Tens of millions of Americans -- an estimated 1 to 2 percent of the population -- will suffer at some point in their lifetimes from obsessive-compulsive disorder, a disorder characterized by recurrent, intrusive, and disturbing thoughts (obsessions), and/or stereotyped recurrent behaviors (compulsions).</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:15:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tracking genetic arms race between humans, mosquitoes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/eDfTlFwi6Zc/150625161510.htm</Link>
        <Description>Individual populations of mosquitoes are under strong evolutionary pressure from humans and their environment, a new study shows.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:14:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supercomputer model shows planet making waves in nearby debris disk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/GG77IvNbC8U/150625161445.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new supercomputer simulation of the planet and debris disk around the nearby star Beta Pictoris reveals that the planet's motion drives spiral waves throughout the disk, a phenomenon that causes collisions among the orbiting debris. Patterns in the collisions and the resulting dust appear to account for many observed features that previous research has been unable to fully explain.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:14:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blue and fin whale distribution in waters off Southern California</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/W_1C8IfSKsY/150625161438.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new study indicates a steady population trend for blue whales and an upward population trend for fin whales in Southern California.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:14:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Most of America's poor have jobs, study finds</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/0Jktnx_4UJE/150625161435.htm</Link>
        <Description>Sociologists evaluated 129 existing methods for defining the 'working poor' and propose one method as a unified definition. Their estimate is that 10 percent of all working households are poor. That's lower than some federal estimates, but it also means that a majority of poor Americans have jobs.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:54:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Giant axonal neuropathy: Researchers develop innovative gene transfer-based treatment approach</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/wrX1CfVhQXo/150625145432.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have developed an innovative, experimental gene transfer-based treatment for children with giant axonal neuropathy (GAN). This extremely rare genetic disorder causes children to gradually lose the ability to balance themselves, move their muscles and to feel certain sensations. Most children born with GAN do not survive beyond their early 20s because of progressive impairment of their ability to breath.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:53:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lax rules put Congo's forests, key carbon reserve, at risk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/EJ_p56pR3Jo/150625145322.htm</Link>
        <Description>Without new conservation efforts, the Democratic Republic of Congo could lose up to 20 percent of its forests, unleashing a 60 percent increase in carbon emissions from one of the largest carbon reserves in the world, a new study shows.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:53:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Compound in magnolia may combat head and neck cancers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/FJ7seoeGrgY/150625145320.htm</Link>
        <Description>As one of the compounds in magnolia extract, honokiol has been used for centuries in traditional Chinese and Japanese medicine to treat anxiety and other conditions. More recently, scientists have been revealing its cancer-fighting properties.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:53:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Synthetic biology used to engineer new route to biochemicals</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/WHgp0rpVy6s/150625145317.htm</Link>
        <Description>Chemists create a new pathway that allows E. coli bacteria to feed on sugar and acetate to make isobutyl coA, a raw material for fuels and chemicals.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Some snowy forestlands cool climate better without trees</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/WcvKt6SgiMU/150625145246.htm</Link>
        <Description>Forests worldwide are increasingly used to store carbon as a way to slow climate change, but a new study finds that some wooded areas may be more valuable without trees, allowing the cleared landscape to reflect rather than absorb the sun's energy. In other words, it's better to have snow-covered ground act as a natural mirror if you want to use some forest lands to cool the climate.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chloroplast tubes play a key role in plants' immune defense</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/8WO_leswCfk/150625145244.htm</Link>
        <Description>When plant cells are infected with pathogens, networks of tiny tubes called stromules grow from the chloroplasts to the cell's nucleus and trigger programmed cell death and innate immune responses.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New approach holds promise for earlier, easier detection of colorectal cancer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-8xCjlJnhBI/150625145242.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new, sensitive electrochemical technique capable of detecting colorectal cancer in tissue samples has been developed by chemists -- a method that could one day be used in clinical settings for the early diagnosis of colorectal cancer.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Top scientists call for improved incentives to ensure research integrity</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/uKrYU_nePME/150625145238.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientific controversies, from problems replicating results - such as with the now debunked association between autism and MMR vaccines -- to researcher misconduct and sensationalism, have led to speculation of 'trouble at the lab,' as the Economist put it. Top scientists have now examine ways to return to high scientific standards.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Faster internet? Electrical engineers break power and distance barriers for fiber optic communication</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/nJPrIfZL_uc/150625145236.htm</Link>
        <Description>Photonics researchers have increased the maximum power -- and therefore distance -- at which optical signals can be sent through optical fibers. This advance has the potential to increase the data transmission rates for the fiber optic cables that serve as the backbone of the Internet, cable, wireless and landline networks. The new study presents a solution to a long-standing roadblock to increasing data transmission rates in optical fiber.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:52:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Earth's daily rotation period encoded in an atomic-level protein structure</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/M1vt7sfpNQU/150625145232.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have demonstrated that Earth's daily rotation period (24 hours) is encoded in the KaiC protein at the atomic level, a small, 10 nm-diameter biomolecule expressed in cyanobacterial cells.The results of this joint research will help elucidate a longstanding question in chronobiology: How is the circadian period of biological clocks determined?</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:48:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Corals are already adapting to global warming, scientists say</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/INxvA_bMZBE/150625144850.htm</Link>
        <Description>Some coral populations already have genetic variants necessary to tolerate warm ocean waters, and humans can help to spread these genes, scientists have found.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:39:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Low scores on memory and thinking tests may signal Alzheimer's 18 years prior to disease</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/23-pBPKQqS0/150625143929.htm</Link>
        <Description>Errors on memory and thinking tests may signal Alzheimer's up to 18 years before the disease can be diagnosed, a new study suggests.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:39:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Backward-moving glacier helps scientists explain glacial earthquakes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/W2MInT2SlsA/150625143926.htm</Link>
        <Description>The relentless flow of a glacier may seem unstoppable, but a team of researchers from the United Kingdom and the U.S. has shown that during some calving events -- when an iceberg breaks off into the ocean -- the glacier moves rapidly backward and downward, causing the characteristic glacial earthquakes which until now have been poorly understood.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:39:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stem-like progenitor cell that exclusively forms heart muscle</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ryryoXhCMGU/150625143922.htm</Link>
        <Description>Future therapies for failing hearts are likely to include stem-like cells and associated growth factors that regenerate heart muscle. Scientists have just taken an important step towards that future by identifying a stem-like “progenitor” cell that produces only heart muscle cells.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:37:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Genetic discovery uncovers key tool for morphine production in poppies</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/TnwXx5zHTmM/150625143714.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have made a key genetic discovery in poppies, paving the way for more effective painkillers.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:36:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Solving the next step in the mystery of prions</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/gS9mv4pmWds/150625143650.htm</Link>
        <Description>Working towards the ultimate goal to develop therapeutics to treat diseases such as Alzheimer's, Parkinson's, ALS, and BSE (Mad Cow Disease), scientists are investigating the physical principles underlying the formation of misfolded protein aggregates. The aggregates of misfolded proteins -- proteins that clump together in the 'wrong' structure -- feature prominently in these fatal degenerative diseases.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:11:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Smartphone app may prevent dangerous freezing of gait in Parkinson's patients</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/u_E0rilEV4g/150625131150.htm</Link>
        <Description>CuPID is striving to provide personalized rehabilitation for patients with Parkinson's disease who experience gait disturbances. It is a home-based personalized rehabilitation tool in the form of a smartphone app that harnesses wearable sensors, audio biofeedback, and external cuing to provide intense motivational training tailored to each patient.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:11:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Study highlights 'important safety issue' with widely used MRI contrast agents</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/jhkBpL_umHw/150625131148.htm</Link>
        <Description>New results in animals highlight a major safety concern regarding a class of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) contrast agents used in millions of patients each year. The study adds to concerns that repeated use of specific "linear"-type gadolinium-based contrast agents (GBCAs) lead to deposits of the heavy-metal element gadolinium in the brain.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:11:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Artificial blood to assist in mosquito control research</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/40R-74p34S4/150625131146.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists continue to advance research on controlling one of the world's most notorious species of pests, the mosquito.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:09:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cancer drug makes fruit flies live longer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YtDLBilxswA/150625130909.htm</Link>
        <Description>Adult fruit flies given a cancer drug live 12 percent longer than average, according to a study researching healthy aging. The drug targets a specific cellular process that occurs in animals, including humans, delaying the onset of age-related deaths by slowing the aging process.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:09:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What controls blood flow in the brain?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/C4VTcxjiTgg/150625130907.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists present the strongest evidence yet that smooth muscle cells surrounding blood vessels in the brain are the only cells capable of contracting to control blood vessel diameter and thus regulate blood flow. This basic anatomical understanding may also have important implications for phenomena observed in stroke and migraines.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:09:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Calcium uptake by mitochondria makes heart beat harder in fight-or-flight response</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/JGAFOvtD_L4/150625130903.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a life-threatening situation, the heart beats faster and harder, invigorated by the fight-or-flight response, which instantaneously prepares a person to react or run. Now, a new study shows that the uptick in heart muscle contractility that occurs under acute stress is driven by a flood of calcium into mitochondria -- the cells' energy-producing powerhouses.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:09:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Songbirds have a thing for patterns</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/uY_ug2RDJRY/150625130900.htm</Link>
        <Description>You might think that young children would first learn to recognize sounds and then learn how those categories of sounds fit together into words. But that isn't how it works. Rather, kids learn sounds and words at the same time. Now, researchers present evidence from European starlings showing that songbirds learn their songs in much the same way.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:03:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Potential drug lessens neurodegeneration in Parkinson's disease model</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/35mJl48Kh1s/150625130316.htm</Link>
        <Description>The first test in a mammalian model of a potential new class of drugs to treat Parkinson’s disease shows abatement of neurodegeneration in the brains of test rats and no significant toxicities.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:02:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Functional class helps predict mortality risk after surgery</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/dDG-XX7FzAM/150625130259.htm</Link>
        <Description>Information on functional status—whether or not a person can carry out routine daily tasks independently—improves the ability to predict risk of death in patients undergoing surgery, according to a study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:02:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New drug squashes cancer's last-ditch efforts to survive</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/W5y3VLI5K98/150625130257.htm</Link>
        <Description>As a tumor grows, its cancerous cells ramp up an energy-harvesting process to support its hasty development. This process, called autophagy, is normally used by a cell to recycle damaged organelles and proteins, but is also co-opted by cancer cells to meet their increased energy and metabolic demands. A compound that stops this cellular recycling process has now been developed by scientists.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:02:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New close-up view of key part of ebola virus life cycle</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YywzpxstHpM/150625130255.htm</Link>
        <Description>A key part of the Ebola virus life cycle has been revealed at a higher resolution than ever before. The research sheds light on how Ebola virus assembles--and how researchers might stop the often-fatal infection.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:02:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three simple rules govern complex brain circuit in fly</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ljIxcchc_Hc/150625130253.htm</Link>
        <Description>Think the nest of cables under your desk is bad? Try keeping the trillions of connections crisscrossing your brain organized and free of tangles. A new study reveals this seemingly intractable job may be simpler than it appears.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:02:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Scientists pinpoint mutations responsible for ineffectiveness of 2014-2015 flu vaccine</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/OmJpaHiWHmw/150625130251.htm</Link>
        <Description>Viruses like influenza have the ability to mutate over time, and given that the flu vaccines administered during the 2014-2015 season were largely ineffective at preventing the spread of the flu, it appears the virus that recently circulated had taken on mutations not accounted for when last year's vaccine was developed. Now, researchers have identified specific mutations that influenza recently acquired to escape the current vaccine design.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:01:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Analyzing genes according to evolutionary profile</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/222NIIti4-o/150625130121.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have developed a new Internet tool that will allow any investigator, physician or patient to analyze genes according to their evolutionary profile and find associated genes. The tool combines genomics and informatics to enables the rapid, cost-free identification of genes responsible for diseases, by inputting results from genetic mapping studies concerning suspected genes, and identifying connections to known genes with association to diseases.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Investigating parent-child visitation in prison</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/wHfZ5wg3uTY/150625130000.htm</Link>
        <Description>It's not 'cupcakes and lollipops' for most children who visit a parent in prison, with two-thirds reported to have negative experiences including fear, anger, anxiety, and related reactions, according to a study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:59:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New class of compounds shrinks pancreatic cancer tumors, prevents regrowth</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Q0RSHHH1tPM/150625125958.htm</Link>
        <Description>A chemical compound that has reduced the growth of pancreatic cancer tumors by 80 percent in treated mice has been developed by researchers. The compound, called MM41, was designed to block faulty genes. It appears to do this by targeting little knots in their DNA, called quadruplexes, which are very different from normal DNA and which are especially found in faulty genes.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:59:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Researchers stretch a thin crystal to get better solar cells</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/WLWOUY7ONuE/150625125956.htm</Link>
        <Description>An interdisciplinary team has made a semiconductor crystal with a variable band gap. Among other potential uses, this variable semiconductor could lead to solar cells that absorb more energy from the sun by being sensitive to a broader spectrum of light.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:59:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A good appetizer could make your main course less enjoyable</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Ot3PKxeGLL4/150625125953.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new study outlines how a good appetizer can make people enjoy the main course less, and a mediocre appetizer can make them enjoy the main course more.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:31:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>microRNA may provide therapy against pancreatic cancer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/V5mXPg4mNrM/150625113102.htm</Link>
        <Description>Cancer researchers have found that a particular microRNA may be a potent therapeutic agent against pancreatic cancer. The need for new therapies for pancreatic cancer patients is great as only 7 percent of people with the disease survive more than 5 years after diagnosis. According to the National Cancer Institute, there will be an estimated 48,960 new cases of pancreatic cancer and 40,560 deaths from the disease in 2015.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:31:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Women on the U.S. $10? These eight women could fill the bill</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Tb1-oB4CUGw/150625113100.htm</Link>
        <Description>Some notable but lesser-known women in American history might be overlooked as possibilities for the soon-to-be redesigned 10 dollar bill.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:30:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Children with severe head injuries are casualties of wars in Iraq, Afghanistan</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/g1UqvhDHlRQ/150625113056.htm</Link>
        <Description>During the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, U.S. combat support hospitals treated at least 650 children with severe, combat-related head injuries, according to a new report.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:29:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>E2F4 signature can predict progression of bladder cancer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/nuQbJSoDSdM/150625112908.htm</Link>
        <Description>Investigators harnessed genomic data to discover that the previously identified E2F4 signature in breast cancer can be utilized to predict prognosis and response to therapy in bladder cancer.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:20:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bad news and good news for birds nesting at reservoirs</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/1xUWtTXnEgk/150625112014.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a six-year study at Arrow Lakes Reservoir in British Columbia, researchers found that while some nests failed due to flooding as the reservoir filled up in the spring, the higher water levels actually provided benefits for the nests that survived. Their results show that overall, nesting in the reservoir's riparian areas did not reduce nest success.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:20:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eating in the absence of hunger: A recipe for expanding waistline</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/X4H6jomnYBI/150625112012.htm</Link>
        <Description>Snacking when you're not hungry can cause weight gain as much as overly large portion sizes and energy-rich foods, a researcher reports.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:20:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chimps are sensitive to what is right and wrong</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/qeu_1wHyqVA/150625112010.htm</Link>
        <Description>How a chimpanzee views a video of an infant chimp from another group being killed gives a sense of how human morality and social norms might have evolved. A new study provides the first evidence that chimpanzees, like humans, are sensitive to the appropriateness of behaviors, especially those directed toward infants.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:20:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Breakthrough graphene production could trigger revolution in artificial skin development</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/1uOwmtN5B1k/150625112008.htm</Link>
        <Description>A pioneering new technique to produce high-quality, low cost graphene could pave the way for the development of the first truly flexible 'electronic skin,' that could be used in robots.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:13:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Past water patterns drive present wading bird numbers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/5PFrMHVMEUw/150625111320.htm</Link>
        <Description>Wading bird numbers in the Florida Everglades are driven by water patterns that play out over multiple years according to a new study. Previously, existing water conditions were seen as the primary driving factor affecting numbers of birds, but this research shows that the preceding years' water conditions and availability are equally important.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="51">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:13:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Experimental treatment sends deadly leukemia into remission</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/BzN22L67W_E/150625111318.htm</Link>
        <Description>An experimental new treatment approach for a rare, deadly leukemia can send the disease into remission even in patients for whom the standard therapy has failed, a pilot study has found. The study is 'proof of principle' the cutting-edge approach could be used to treat many other cancers as well.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="52">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:13:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Starfish that clone themselves live longer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/8w0lizFEh1I/150625111315.htm</Link>
        <Description>Starfish that reproduce through cloning avoid aging to a greater extent than those that propagate through sexual reproduction.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="53">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:13:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pilot program in pediatric long-term care facility halves topical antibiotic use</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/gEXWmPgLuUw/150625111312.htm</Link>
        <Description>A pilot antibiotic stewardship program at a pediatric long-term care facility brought about a 59 percent decrease in use of a topical antibiotic and an 83 percent decrease in orders for antibiotics without proper documentation during a six-month period, according to a new study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="54">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:13:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Infection preventionists may spend more time collecting data than protecting patients</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/8qyxPOKBZT4/150625111309.htm</Link>
        <Description>Collecting and reporting hospital infection data to federal health agencies takes more than five hours each day, at the expense of time needed to ensure that frontline healthcare personnel are adhering to basic infection prevention practices such as hand hygiene, according to a recent case study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="55">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:13:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How companies can reduce sovereign risk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/2JVavWN7hts/150625091306.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a new study of five-year spreads on credit default swap contracts for more than 2,000 U.S. and international firms, a finance researcher found that strong property rights and transparency are key in securing a stable financial future for companies amid a widespread rise in sovereign risk around the globe.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="56">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:12:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New way of understanding police authority, power</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/IdE-wMT9EMw/150625091229.htm</Link>
        <Description>The police aim at maintaining law and order and social peace, and to achieve it they can make use of authority and power in a coercive way, through repression, prohibition or control, but they can also make use of this authority and power to manage conflicts and seek amicable settlements between the parties. A study claims the opportunities offered by police mediation, which operation is still attached to a great dose of "lawlessness”. In this sense, the research shows legal arguments, which clearly support the legal framework of police mediation and compliance with the reporting principles of voluntariness, freely availability and confidentiality governing any field of mediation.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="57">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:11:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Recycled water, salt-tolerant grass a water-saving pair</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/kHKZ-kRbIPU/150625091159.htm</Link>
        <Description>Plants need water. People need water. Unfortunately, there's only so much clean water to go around -- and so the effort begins to find a solution. One strategy is to use treated wastewater, containing salt leftover from the cleaning process, to water large areas of turf grass. Researchers have found ways to breed salt-tolerant turf that can withstand this irrigation.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="58">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:11:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Antarctic life: Highly diverse, unusually structured</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/mQGlMN3U_zI/150625091157.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a comprehensive assessment of Antarctic biodiversity scientists have revealed the region is more diverse and biologically interesting than previously thought. The team noted several unusual ways in which patterns of biodiversity are produced in the region. Geothermal, heated areas, such as volcanoes, have played an important role as refuges from icy, glacial conditions on land. At sea, wind has an especially significant effect on diversity. Windier areas have more seabird species.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="59">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:11:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Writing program with student interaction creates sense of purpose for seniors</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/BvwLzPLniaM/150625091153.htm</Link>
        <Description>A unique program combining a life review writing workshop with conversations between seniors and college students enhances the sense of meaning in life for older adults living independently, finds a new study.</Description>
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:12:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Orange is the new red</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YxaL9vQqFsY/150627081238.htm</Link>
        <Description>A photoprotective mechanism in cyanobacteria is triggered by an unprecedented, large-scale movement from one location to another of the carotenoid pigment within the Orange Carotenoid Protein, researchers have discovered.</Description>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:38:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two biomarkers linked to severe heart disease found</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/HM6CupxgVic/150706163825.htm</Link>
        <Description>A first-of-its-kind animal model to pinpoint two biomarkers that are elevated in the most severe form of coronary disease has been developed by scientists.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:38:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heart attack treatment hypothesis 'busted'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/rwkeOvwWKRI/150706163822.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have long had reason to hope that blocking the flow of calcium into the mitochondria of heart and brain cells could be one way to prevent damage caused by heart attacks and strokes. But in a study of mice engineered to lack a key calcium channel in their heart cells, scientists appear to have cast a shadow of doubt on that theory.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:37:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How dengue virus adapts as it travels, increasing chances for outbreaks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/dsJLT4bZhZQ/150706163738.htm</Link>
        <Description>A research group is the first to explain the mechanisms that the Dengue virus has developed to optimize its ability to cause outbreaks as it travels across the globe to new places and revisits old ones.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:37:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New blood pressure guidelines may lead to under treatment of older adults</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/zvzKdATDV90/150706163736.htm</Link>
        <Description>In 2014, the Joint National Committee released the eighth update to the blood pressure guidelines (JNC8P). These guidelines included a controversial decision to change the blood pressure goal that may lead to under treatment of adults 60 years of age or older. The JNC8P guidelines set a less stringent goal blood pressure of </Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:16:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Reducing stroke damage may be next for optical coherence tomography technology widely used in vision healthcare</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/f-ylkETK2Nk/150706161627.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new article reports on use of optical coherence tomography to obtain high-resolution images showing blood-flow dynamics in the brain before, during, and after stroke-like states. The information may ultimately enable clinicians to reduce stroke damage.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:16:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Killer sea snail a target for new drugs</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/qr-itLRpKoE/150706161623.htm</Link>
        <Description>Pain treatment researchers have discovered thousands of new peptide toxins hidden deep within the venom of just one type of Queensland cone snail. Researchers hope the new molecules will be promising leads for new drugs to treat pain and cancer.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:49:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New insights into the genetics of drug-resistant fungal infections</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/MUPPzAxYses/150706154902.htm</Link>
        <Description>A study offers new insights into how virulent fungi adapt through genetic modifications to fight back against the effects of medication designed to block their spread, and how that battle leaves them temporarily weakened. These insights may provide clues to new ways to treat notoriously difficult-to-cure fungal infections like thrush and vaginitis.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:49:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Perennial biofuel crops' water consumption similar to corn</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/OLqJfhEZG0k/150706154900.htm</Link>
        <Description>Converting large tracts of the Midwest's marginal farming land to perennial biofuel crops carries with it some key unknowns, including how it could affect the balance of water between rainfall, evaporation and movement of soil water to groundwater.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:32:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Restraint, confinement still an everyday practice in mental health settings</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/gWgeRDD1u64/150706143254.htm</Link>
        <Description>Providers of mental-health services still rely on intervention techniques such as physical restraint and confinement to control some psychiatric hospital patients, a practice that can cause harm to both patients and care facilities, according to a new study.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:32:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blacklegged tick populations have expanded via migration, biologists show</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Kv9tpJScg8w/150706143251.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a new study, biologists used genetic and phylogeographic analyses to determine the origin and recent migratory history of newly discovered tick populations in the Northeastern United States. Their findings indicate that the ticks moved into new areas from established populations, mainly through short-distance, local moves.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:32:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stress-fighting proteins could be key to new treatments for asthma</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/fcBosdpc9bI/150706143249.htm</Link>
        <Description>Investigators have discovered the precise molecular steps that enable immune cells implicated in certain forms of asthma and allergy to develop and survive in the body. The findings reveal a new pathway that scientists could use to develop more effective treatments and therapies for the chronic lung disorder.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:32:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Link found between autoimmune diseases, medications, dangerous heartbeat condition</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/m4dRPJsMj5c/150706143246.htm</Link>
        <Description>New research focuses on identifying the mechanism by which patients with various autoimmune and connective tissue disorders may be at risk for life-threatening cardiac events if they take certain anti-histamine or anti-depressant medications.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:57:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Protein implicated in osteosarcoma's spread acts as air traffic controller</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-req6FyFwuY/150706135709.htm</Link>
        <Description>The investigation of a simple protein has uncovered its uniquely complicated role in the spread of the childhood cancer, osteosarcoma. It turns out the protein, called ezrin, acts like an air traffic controller, coordinating multiple functions within a cancer cell and allowing it to endure stress conditions encountered during metastasis.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:57:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How to rule a gene 'galaxy': A lesson from developing neurons</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/HDaM9ovwihw/150706135706.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new study has found that many RNA messengers encoding neuronal proteins contain specialized sequences that can promote their destabilization in the presence of an RNA-binding protein called tristetraprolin, or TTP.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:37:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Uncovering the mechanism of our oldest anesthetic</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/ts-TQK-yEfs/150706123744.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have now revealed brainwave changes in patients receiving nitrous oxide, or "laughing gas." Nitrous oxide, commonly known as "laughing gas," has been used in anesthesiology practice since the 1800s, but the way it works to create altered states is has not been well understood.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:37:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Therapeutic nitric oxide generated from air with an electric spark</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/XXATU1mKLbM/150706123742.htm</Link>
        <Description>Treatment with inhaled nitric oxide can be life saving for newborns, children and adults with several dangerous conditions, but the availability of the treatment has been limited by the size, weight and complexity of equipment needed to administer the gas and the therapy's high price. Now a research team has developed a lightweight, portable system that produces nitric oxide from the air by means of an electrical spark.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:37:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ion channel mechanics yield insights into optogenetics experiments</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/AMfCd6THKco/150706123740.htm</Link>
        <Description>Optogenetics techniques, which allow scientists to map and control nerve cells using light stimulation, are being used to study neural circuits in the brain with unprecedented precision. This revolutionary technology relies on light-sensitive proteins such as channelrhodopsins, and researchers have now determined the molecular mechanism involved in the light-induced activation of one of these proteins.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:37:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crowd computing to improve water filtration</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Qt3xzDy_ijw/150706123738.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists propose a novel nanotechnology-based strategy to improve water filtration. The project was an experiment in crowdsourced computing -- carried out by over 150,000 volunteers who contributed their own computing power to the research.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:37:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Researchers develop world's most sensitive test to detect infectious disease, superbugs</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/nE11DKcsSb4/150706123736.htm</Link>
        <Description>Infectious diseases such as hepatitis C and some of the world's deadliest superbugs -- C. difficile and MRSA among them -- could soon be detected much earlier by a unique diagnostic test, designed to easily and quickly identify dangerous pathogens, experts report after developing the world's most sensitive detection test.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:37:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Surfing a wake of light</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/3UidIOAD4Do/150706123733.htm</Link>
        <Description>For the first time, Harvard researchers have created wakes of light-like waves moving on a metallic surface, called surface plasmons, and demonstrated that they can be controlled and steered. The creation and control of surface plasmon wakes could lead to new types of plasmonic couplers and lenses that could create two-dimensional holograms or focus light at the nanoscale.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:37:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fundamental beliefs about atherosclerosis overturned</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/uaZyCv0DqFQ/150706123730.htm</Link>
        <Description>Doctors' efforts to battle the dangerous atherosclerotic plaques that build up in our arteries and cause heart attacks and strokes are built on several false beliefs about the fundamental composition and formation of the plaques, new research shows. These new discoveries will force researchers to reassess their approaches to developing treatments and discard some of their basic assumptions about atherosclerosis, commonly known as hardening of the arteries.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:37:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Older patients with traumatic spinal cord injuries less likely to get surgery</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/LKC-4X0TyyE/150706123726.htm</Link>
        <Description>Older patients with traumatic spinal cord injuries are less likely to receive surgery compared with younger patients and they experience a significant lag between injury and surgery, according to new research.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:44:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Full sky map: Rings and loops in the stars</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/pq8RD88oEQ8/150706114443.htm</Link>
        <Description>A ring of dust 200 light years across and a loop covering a third of the sky: two of the results in a new map from the Planck satellite.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:44:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Faster detection of hidden objects by terahertz sensor</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/CjlK1XjfFUc/150706114441.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new type of sensor, that is much faster than competing technologies used to detect and identify hidden objects, has been developed by scientists.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:44:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Research breakthrough to treat girls-only epilepsy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/59VE_gCUWrA/150706114405.htm</Link>
        <Description>A breakthrough discovery is expected to help thousands of young girls worldwide who are suffering from a rare yet debilitating form of epilepsy, an international team led by a genetics expert reports.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:44:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fundamental observation of spin-controlled electrical conduction in metals</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/hu3VJMYH-Ww/150706114401.htm</Link>
        <Description>Ultrafast terahertz spectroscopy allows direct insight into the building block of modern magnetic memories.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:43:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>People over 65 with traumatic brain injuries hospitalized four times as often as younger people</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/B0AH4PQ3RlI/150706114357.htm</Link>
        <Description>A disproportionate number of people hospitalized in Canada with traumatic brain injuries are 65 years or older, a new study has found. While that age group represents only 14 per cent of the Canadian population, it accounted for 38 per cent of hospitalizations for TBI between 2006-07 and 2010-11.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:43:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Potential treatment option for children with Ewing's sarcoma</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/86b-4DhvyM8/150706114353.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new therapeutic alternative for children who suffer from a malignant pediatric tumor bone and soft tissue called Ewing's sarcoma has been discovered by a research consortium. Ewing's sarcoma is the second most common bone cancer and affects children and youth. Currently, if diagnosed early and there is no metastasis it can be cured in 80% of cases but between 25% and 30% of cases are diagnosed when it has metastasized and survival drops to 20%.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:42:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Producing biodegradable plastic just got cheaper, greener</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/TDDVFz4MLp4/150706114237.htm</Link>
        <Description>Biodegradable drinking cups or vegetable wrapping foil: the bioplastic known as polylactic acid (PLA) is already a part of our everyday lives. And yet, PLA is not yet considered a full alternative to traditional petroleum-based plastics, as it is costly to produce. Researchers now present a way to make the PLA production process more simple and waste-free.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:42:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New study again shows: More strokes with intracranial stents</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/NE8TBnNwAqE/150706114235.htm</Link>
        <Description>A new study confirms that iff, after a stroke, patients also have stents inserted into blood vessels of the brain, new strokes occur considerably more often.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:42:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pazopanib improves progression-free survival without impairing quality of life</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/3QGnhA1dZvw/150706114233.htm</Link>
        <Description>In patients with soft tissue sarcoma, whose disease had progressed during or after prior chemotherapy, pazopanib improved progression-free survival but did not change health-related quality of life, research shows. This observed improvement in progression-free survival without impairment of health-related quality of life was considered a meaningful result.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:42:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Grey squirrels are quick learners, study shows</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/2gYPHBszSU0/150706114231.htm</Link>
        <Description>They may be viewed by some as an invasive species or a commonplace pest of public parks, but a new study has shown that grey squirrels are actually quick learners capable of adapting tactics to improve efficiency and reap the best rewards.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:42:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tundra study uncovers impact of climate warming in the Arctic</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/tWdzhTpyAXw/150706114229.htm</Link>
        <Description>Significant changes in one of Earth's most important ecosystems are not only a symptom of climate change, but may fuel further warming, research suggests. One of the biggest studies to date of key vegetation in the Arctic tundra provides strong evidence that dramatic changes in the region are being driven by climate warming.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:42:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Transition from three to two dimensions increases conduction</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/chGneqbo37E/150706114225.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have for the first time described the behavior of electrons in a previously unstudied analogue of graphene, two-dimensional niobium telluride, and, in the process, uncovered the nature of two-dimensionality effects on conducting properties.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:42:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>tRNAs are segmented into fragments in a manner that depends on race, gender and population</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/Ig0muEdYh0E/150706114221.htm</Link>
        <Description>The study reports on a newly discovered category of tRNA fragments as well as shows that all tRNAs are rich sources of very diverse short molecules whose characteristics depend on a person's gender, population, and race and differ according to tissue and disease type.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:42:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Age-related cognitive decline tied to immune-system molecule</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/5DBQfSzpaGc/150706114219.htm</Link>
        <Description>A blood-borne molecule that increases in abundance as we age blocks regeneration of brain cells and promotes cognitive decline, new research shows. The molecule in question, known as beta-2 microglobulin, or B2M, is a component of a larger molecule called MHC I, which plays a major role in the adaptive immune system. A growing body of research indicates that the B2M-MHC I complex, which is present in all cells in the body except red blood cells and plasma cells, can act in the brain in ways not obviously related to immunity--guiding brain development, shaping nerve cell communication, and even affecting behavior.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:41:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Midlife changes in Alzheimer's biomarkers may predict dementia</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/hIrrNUPIHsk/150706114140.htm</Link>
        <Description>Studying brain scans and cerebrospinal fluid of healthy adults, scientists have shown that changes in key biomarkers of Alzheimer's disease during midlife may help identify those who will develop dementia years later, according to new research.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:41:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Protein suggests a new strategy to thwart infection</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/P-iUwHJGOLI/150706114138.htm</Link>
        <Description>The newfound ability of a protein of the intestines and lungs to distinguish between human cells and the cells of bacterial invaders could underpin new strategies to fight infections. A new article describes the knack of a human protein known as intelectin to distinguish between our cells and those of the disease-causing microbes that invade our bodies.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:41:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Autonomous taxis would deliver significant environmental and economic benefits</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/yGH8-sxyTSo/150706114135.htm</Link>
        <Description>Imagine a fleet of driverless taxis roaming your city, ready to pick you up and take you to your destination at a moment's notice. While this may seem fantastical, it may be only a matter of time before it becomes reality. And according to a new study such a system would both be cost-effective and greatly reduce per-mile emissions of greenhouse gases.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:41:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia with psychiatric, medical conditions</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/qkCBzo78j54/150706114133.htm</Link>
        <Description>Cognitive behavioral therapy is a widely used nonpharmacologic treatment for insomnia disorders and an analysis of the medical literature suggests it also can work for patients whose insomnia is coupled with psychiatric and medical conditions, according to an article.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:41:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Increased risk of complications, death during delivery for women with epilepsy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/MuHkTPIoo-w/150706114131.htm</Link>
        <Description>A small fraction of pregnancies occur in women with epilepsy but a new study suggests those women may be at higher risk for complications and death during delivery, in a new article.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:41:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Many physicians, clinicians work sick despite risk to patients, survey finds</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/eykGScSEbz8/150706114129.htm</Link>
        <Description>Many physicians and advanced practice clinicians, including registered nurse practitioners, midwives and physician assistants, reported to work while being sick despite recognizing this could put patients at risk, according to the results of a small survey.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:41:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Detecting more small cancers in screening mammography suggests overdiagnosis</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/wB6nIafS50Q/150706114127.htm</Link>
        <Description>Screening mammography was associated with increased diagnosis of small cancers in a study across U.S. counties but not with significant changes in breast cancer deaths or a decreased incidence of larger breast cancers, which researchers suggest may be the result of overdiagnosis, according to an article.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:41:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Risk of interbreeding due to climate change lower than expected</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/5UJzmPeUEcw/150706114125.htm</Link>
        <Description>A surprising study of North and South American mammals, birds and amphibians finds that only about 6 percent of closely related species whose ranges do not currently overlap are likely to come into contact by the end of this century.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:41:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Extra DNA acts as a 'spare tire' for our genomes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/wCPEITONmsM/150706114123.htm</Link>
        <Description>Carrying around a spare tire is a good thing -- you never know when you'll get a flat. Turns out we're all carrying around 'spare tires' in our genomes, too. Today researchers report that an extra set of guanines (or 'G's) in our DNA may function just like a 'spare' to help prevent many cancers from developing.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:38:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Significant reduction in serious crimes after juvenile offenders given emotional awareness training</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/upyvNg3Gml0/150706103836.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists believe that a simple two-hour emotional awareness course aimed at making young offenders less aggressive could hold the key to significantly reducing the seriousness of their future crimes.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:38:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Good quantum states and bad quantum states</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/6V_YS-5FBek/150706103834.htm</Link>
        <Description>It is impossible to obtain all information about a large quantum system consisting of hundreds or thousands of particles. A new technique allows to describe such systems in terms of 'continuous matrix product states.' With this approximation, the relevant information about a quantum system can be obtained by only a few measurements.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:38:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nanomedicine in the fight against thrombotic diseases</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/5F3qG9aMHlo/150706103831.htm</Link>
        <Description>Ischemic heart disease and stroke caused by thrombus formation are responsible for more than 17 million deaths per year worldwide. Now researchers announce new research that has been covering the use of nanocarriers and microbubbles in drug delivery for thrombotic disease.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:38:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fingolimod in relapsing remitting multiple sclerosis: Indication of added benefit in certain patients</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/m7pluGenR3s/150706103829.htm</Link>
        <Description>Based on new analyses conducted by the drug manufacturer, an advantage can be determined in two instead of only one patient group for the use of Fingolimod in relapsing remitting multiple sclerosis. There are now indications instead of a hint.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:24:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Aluminum clusters shut down molecular fuel factory</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/lEGiI5Vsh9M/150706092420.htm</Link>
        <Description>When aluminum atoms bunch up, porous materials called zeolites lose their ability to convert oil to gasoline. An international team of scientists created the first 3-D atomic map of a zeolite in order to find out how to improve catalysts used to produce fuel, biofuel and other chemicals.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="51">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:24:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rope-chewing technique an easy way to screen monkeys for disease</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/P6HXbWdbeoE/150706092417.htm</Link>
        <Description>What a piece of rope and strawberry jam have to do with preventing the spread of zoonotic disease.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="52">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:14:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Visualizing RNAi at work</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/YfDN_FBPHVA/150706091408.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have revealed the molecular mechanism of RNA interference (RNAi), the phenomenon by which the synthesis of a specific protein is inhibited, by real time observation of target RNA cleavage at the single-molecule level.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="53">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:13:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mechanism of biological multi-fuel engine</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/-Px_ZvZbokc/150706091351.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have constructed the atomic model structure of the protein complex that corresponds to the stator (stationary part of a motor that surrounds the rotating part of a motor) of the E. coli flagellar motor for the first time by molecular simulation based on previously published experimental data, and elucidated the mechanism by which ions, including hydrogen ions (protons), are transferred through the stator.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="54">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:13:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Geology: Slow episodic slip probably occurs in the plate boundary</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/HjgYfjKFiMU/150706091348.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have discovered slow-moving low-frequency tremors which occur at the shallow subduction plate boundary in Hyuga-nada, off east Kyushu. This indicates the possibility that the plate boundary in the vicinity of the Nankai Trough is slipping episodically and slowly (over days or weeks) without inducing a strong seismic wave.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="55">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:13:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Drug inhibits infection that causes watery diarrhea</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/69kTtc6lfL0/150706091345.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have demonstrated that heparin, a type of sulfated polysaccharide, inhibits infection with Cryptosporidium parvum, a protozoan that causes diarrhea in humans and other mammals. This will facilitate the development of anti-cryptosporidial agents.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="56">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:13:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Transcriptional mechanisms governing cartilage formation</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/yy08kCq1_lU/150706091343.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers have identified modes of Sox9 action during cartilage formation by analyzing big data on Sox9 location, chromatin state, and gene expression over the whole mouse genome. This finding will contribute to the understanding of cartilage diseases caused by genomic mutation and genome-based drug discovery for disease therapies.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="57">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:13:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New genomic aberrations of gastric cancer could pave the way for precision medicine</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/EuYeSZK9HCU/150706091340.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have discovered a relationship between Asian gastric cancers and the fusion of two genes.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="58">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:12:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Schools start mapping cosmic rays and solar wind</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/oetOhFcXfsk/150706091216.htm</Link>
        <Description>A satellite experiment to study cosmic rays and the solar wind that was devised by school students is now successfully collecting data in space. LUCID, the Langton Ultimate Cosmic ray Intensity Detector, uses particle detectors from CERN to study the radiation environment in low Earth orbit.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="59">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:00:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How cancer cells avoid shutdown</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/z-yWL5kDLJA/150706090051.htm</Link>
        <Description>Researchers unravel mechanisms by which a protein that promotes tumor growth is produced during stress. The specific protein concerned in the team's study is the protease cathepsin L, a certain enzyme. It is long known that high levels of this protease in breast cancers are associated with high metastasis rates and poor survival of the patients.</Description>
=======
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:07:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New strategies for combatting chronic kidney disease, other long-term conditions</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.sciencedaily.com/~r/sciencedaily/~3/GUFjpWkk8JM/150625170751.htm</Link>
        <Description>New strategies for using electronic health records (EHRs) to treat patients with chronic kidney disease have been outlined by investigators. Their recommendations may help clinicians and hospitals better manage individual patients with chronic conditions and identify groups of patients most likely to benefit from different treatment strategies.</Description>
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
</site>
