<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="scrippsobfeeds">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:39:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Florida teen defecates in squad car</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/deputies-florida-teen-intentionally-defecated-in-squad-car</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Deputies: Florida teen intentionally defecated in squad car
Associated Press
7:39 AM, May 1, 2015
Show Caption
Previous
Next
LARGO, Fla. (AP)  A teenager is suspected by sheriff's deputies of having intentionally defecated in a squad car following an arrest.
The Tampa Bay Times reports 18-year-old Katelyn Patricia Felegi was arrested Saturday afternoon after breaking into and damaging her ex-boyfriend's home. An officer said in a report Felegi was in the back of a marked cruiser when she intentionally removed her pants and defecated.
Deputies directed inmates to clean the car, which was out of commission for eight hours.
Felegi faces several charges including criminal mischief, burglary and simple domestic assault.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:53:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Motorcycle crash seriously injures Naples man</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/motorcycle-crash-on-us-41-seriously-injures-naples-man</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Motorcycle crash on U.S. 41 seriously injures Naples man
Daily News staff
6:33 AM, May 1, 2015
2 hours ago
Previous
Next
A motorcycle crash with a sport utility vehicle seriously injured a Naples man Thursday night on U.S. 41 in North Naples.
Wesley Mayhew, 46, was riding a Harley-Davidson motorcycle when an SUV turned in front of him about 11:45 p.m. near Pelican Bay. Mayhew, who was not wearing a helmet, was seriously injured in the crash and taken to Lee Memorial Hospital in Fort Myers, Florida Highway Patrol reports show.
Nadezda Gavrilova, who was driving a Range Rover northbound on U.S. 41, failed to yield the right of way to the southbound motorcyclist by turning left in front of him at the intersection of Laurel Oak Drive . Gavrilova, 40, of Naples, was cited for violation of right of way, but was not injured in the crash, FHP reports.
Both disabled vehicles had to be removed from the scene by tow trucks.
Copyright 2014 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:00:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Traffic enforcement locations in Collier, Lee</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/traffic/fridays-traffic-enforcement-locations-in-collier-lee-050115</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Friday's traffic enforcement locations in Collier, Lee
5:00 AM, May 1, 2015
Copyright Associated Press
NAPLES, Fla. - Here are today's traffic enforcement locations in Collier and Lee counties:
Collier County
The Collier County Sheriff's Office each day lists locations it could target for increased enforcement of traffic violations. In addition to their normal patrols, Collier deputies will target at least one of these locations with stepped up enforcement:
Naples Boulevard and Hollywood Drive  Aggressive driving
Immokalee Road and Gulf Coast High School  Aggressive driving
Pine Ridge Road at I-75 southbound exit  Aggressive driving
Lee County
The Lee County Sheriff's Office each day lists locations it could target for increased enforcement of traffic violations. In addition to their normal patrols, Lee deputies will target at least one of these locations with stepped up enforcement:
Iona Road, Fort Myers
Bass Road and Park Royal Dr., Fort Myers
San Carlos Blvd., Fort Myers Beach
Copyright 2014 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 04:00:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Collier animal shelter to be open all night</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/animal-shelter-to-host-adoption-marathon_29182216</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Animal shelter to host adoption marathon
Daily News staff
9:00 PM, Apr 30, 2015
9:18 PM, Apr 30, 2015
local news
Belle is a friendly, 2-year-old pit bull mix who loves to cuddle. Adoption fee for dogs is $85 at Collier County Domestic Animal Services from 11 a.m. to 6 p.m. Mondays through Saturdays at 7610 Davis Blvd., Naples. Information: 239-252-7387 or www.colliergov.net/pets 
Copyright Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:48:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Last Marines to leave Saigon describe war's end</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/world/last-us-marines-to-leave-saigon-describe-chaos-of-wars-end</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Last US Marines to leave Saigon describe chaos of war's end
Margie Mason, Associated Press
8:48 PM, Apr 30, 2015
Previous
Next
Former U.S. Marines Sgt. Kevin Maloney of Hollywood, Florida, left, and Lance Cpl. John Stewart of Nacogdoches, Texas, attend the unveiling ceremony of a plaque dedicated to their fallen comrades Cpl. Charles McMahon and Lance Cpl. Darwin Judge who were the last U.S. servicemen killed in the Vietnam War, at the U.S. Consulate in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, Thursday, April 30, 2015. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara)
Dita Alangkara
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Former U.S. Marine Sgt. Kevin Maloney of Hollywood, Florida, places a flower in front of the plaque dedicated to his fallen comrades Cpl. Charles McMahon and Lance Cpl. Darwin Judge who were the last U.S. servicemen killed in the Vietnam War, during its unveiling ceremony at the U.S. Consulate in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, Thursday, April 30, 2015. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara)
Dita Alangkara
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Former Marine Sgt. Kevin Maloney of Hollywood, Florida, holds a U.S. flag during the unveiling ceremony of a plaque dedicated to his fallen comrades Cpl. Charles McMahon and Lance Cpl. Darwin Judge who were the last U.S. servicemen killed in the Vietnam War, at the U.S. Consulate in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, Thursday, April 30, 2015. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara)
Dita Alangkara
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Former U.S Marines pose for a group photo during the unveiling ceremony of a plaque dedicated to their fallen comrades Cpl. Charles McMahon and Lance Cpl. Darwin Judge who were the last U.S. servicemen killed in the Vietnam War, at the U.S. Consulate in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, Thursday, April 30, 2015. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara)
Dita Alangkara
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Former Marine Sgt. John Ghilain of Malden, Massachusets, left, and Sgt. Kevin Maloney of Hollywood, Florida, hold U.S. flags during the unveiling ceremony of a plaque dedicated to their fallen comrades Cpl. Charles McMahon and Lance Cpl. Darwin Judge who were the last U.S. servicemen killed in the Vietnam War, at the U.S. Consulate in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, Thursday, April 30, 2015. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara)
Dita Alangkara
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
This undated photo provided by former U.S. Marines Master Gunnery Sgt. Juan Valdez shows Vietnamese climbing the wall of the U.S. Embassy in Saigon, Vietnam. On the 40th anniversary of the fall of Saigon, 13 Marines returned to dedicate a plaque to their two fallen brothers at the site of the old embassy, which is now the U.S. Consulate. (Juan Valdez via AP)
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
In this Tuesday, April 28, 2015 photo, former U.S. Marines Master Gunnery Sgt. Juan Valdez of Oceanside, California, holds a photo of himself, rear center, sitting on the last helicopter leaving the U.S. Embassy in Saigon on April 30, 1975, in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam. On the 40th anniversary of the fall of Saigon, 13 Marines returned to dedicate a plaque to their two fallen brothers at the site of the old embassy, which is now the U.S. Consulate. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara)
Dita Alangkara
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
In this Tuesday, April 28, 2015 photo, former U.S. Marines Sgt. Kevin Maloney, left, of Hollywood, Florida and Master Gunnery Sgt. Juan Valdez, of Oceanside, California, look at photos on Maloney's tablet in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam. On the 40th anniversary of the fall of Saigon, 13 Marines returned to dedicate a plaque to their two fallen brothers at the site of the old embassy, which is now the U.S. Consulate. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara)
Dita Alangkara
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
This April 30, 1975 photo provided by former U.S. Marines Master Gunnery Sgt. Juan Valdez shows Marines barricading themselves on the roof of the U.S. Embassy in Saigon, Vietnam. On the 40th anniversary of the fall of Saigon, 13 Marines returned to dedicate a plaque to their two fallen brothers at the site of the old embassy, which is now the U.S. Consulate. (Juan Valdez via AP)
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
HO CHI MINH CITY, Vietnam - As the Marines scrambled to the roof of the U.S. Embassy, they locked a chain-link gate on every other floor to slow the throng of panicked Vietnamese civilians sure to come behind them. They knew if the crowd pushed through to the top, they could easily be overrun by hundreds of people desperate to get a seat on one of the last helicopters out of Saigon.
The men barricaded the rooftop door using heavy fire extinguishers and wall lockers and waited nervously as Vietnamese outside rammed a fire truck through an embassy entrance. They could hear looting going on below and watched as cars were driven away and everything from couch cushions to refrigerators was carted out of the offices. They saw South Vietnamese soldiers strip off their uniforms and throw them into the street, fearing they would be shot on sight by the northern enemy.
It was still dark when the U.S. ambassador left the roof on a helicopter around 5 a.m. April 30, 1975. A message went out over the radio with his code name, "Tiger, Tiger, Tiger," followed by "Tiger out," to signal that the diplomat was en route to safety.
As the sun came up, the remaining Marines realized they had been forgotten. The pilots mistakenly believed that the call meant everyone had been evacuated. The Marines had no way to contact U.S. airmen ferrying Vietnamese allies and Americans to aircraft carriers offshore because their radio signals didn't carry that far.
The last U.S. servicemen in Vietnam were stuck alone atop the embassy, hoping someone would realize they were there before the city fell to rapidly advancing communist forces.
____
On the 40th anniversary of the fall of Saigon on Thursday, a group of Marines who were there that day returned to what is now Ho Chi Minh City for a memorial ceremony at the site of the old embassy, which is now the U.S. Consulate. They had been in charge of guarding the facility and the defense attache office beside Tan Son Nhut airport, and were tasked with helping to get the last Americans out.
The days leading up to the end of the Vietnam War were chaotic and exhausting. Northern enemy forces had been sweeping southward for weeks, capturing major South Vietnamese strongholds as they went. Everyone knew it was only a matter of time before the capital, Saigon, also fell. Rumors of a looming bloodbath gripped the city, and Americans along with their South Vietnamese allies were being evacuated on cargo planes from the airport.
Lance Cpl. John Stewart, now 58, of Nacogdoches, Texas, was assigned to take a bus through Saigon to pick up those eligible to leave. He was just 18 and had only been in the country a couple weeks, but he saw anger growing among those on the streets as people realized the end was near and the U.S. was pulling out its last remaining citizens. At one point a rocket hit near the bus and it was shaken by shrapnel, but no one was injured and the evacuation continued.
"We were having to pull people off or physically keep them from getting onto the buses," he said. "You couldn't blame them for wanting to get out, but it had gotten to the point where we could only take those that we absolutely had to. We couldn't take everybody. That's when your brain tells you this is really happening and we've reached the end, and hopefully we'll get out before the end gets here."
Stewart and the others were already shaken after a rocket attack killed two Marines  Cpl. Charles McMahon and Lance Cpl. Darwin Judge  early April 29 while they stood guard at the defense attache compound. They would be the last U.S. servicemen to die in a war that killed some 58,000 Americans, up to 250,000 South Vietnamese allies and an estimated 3 million North Vietnamese and civilians.
Thirteen of the original Marines on Thursday placed red roses in front of a plaque honoring them, saluting it on the old embassy grounds as taps played.
The bodies of McMahon and Judge were found by Sgt. Kevin Maloney, now 62 of Hollywood, Florida. But there was no time to mourn. Like Stewart, he had to help load buses.
While in the city, he locked eyes with a little boy with light brown hair. He was only supposed to pick up Americans, but he shoved the kid and his mother into one of the front seats anyway, knowing that the child was most likely the son of a GI. He still wonders whether they made it onto a plane and on to America, as many Vietnamese did after being evacuated.
Once the airport became too bombed out to continue operations there, helicopters were ordered to land at the embassy for the final flights.
Maloney was later moved there to help. He spent hours going over the wall to help pull Americans and allies from other countries out of the mob and into the compound so they could be airlifted. He grabbed their hands to hoisted them up, while beating back the Vietnamese. He left his pistol inside the compound, fearing someone might grab it from his holster and fire shots into the thousands of people.
The scene became so insane that Sgt. Don Nicholas, now 62, of Green, Ohio, was sent to the attache office to guard millions of U.S. dollars before the cash was burned and the compound blown up by the Americans to keep the enemy from raiding it and obtaining classified documents. He later stood watch at the embassy and was shocked when a Vietnamese man, desperate to get into the compound, ran a spike from the gate into his foot as he climbed over the wall. Others began offering "anything and everything" to get inside.
"Women were like, 'Take us in, we'll have sex with you. Here's gold. I have this money, here's jewels. Please just let me in!'" he said. "Within 48 hours, that's all I heard. People begging."
___
Once the Marines got word that they were to abandon their posts and prepare to evacuate, they moved up to the roof, where they could see parts of the city burning. Many had not slept in two or three days and were running only on adrenaline. No one knew what would happen when the Americans finally left and Saigon was overtaken by the enemy.
There were about 80 men crowded on the rooftop. One stood guard next to a small window where Vietnamese, who had forced their way inside and through all of the locked gates in the stairwell, were pressed  hoping and waiting more helicopters were coming for them to board.
A couple of hours passed. No choppers.
"They literally forgot about us," said Master Sgt. Juan Valdez, now 77, of Oceanside, California, who was the detachment commander. "Everybody was in their own thoughts. I was on one side thinking, 'What was going to happen next?' My worst thought was if they were able to direct artillery fire to (the airport), what was to keep them from directing artillery fire on the roof?"
The men passed around a bottle of whiskey and waited. Finally, they heard the whirring of helicopter blades. They stripped off their flak jackets, helmets and packs to save weight and stuffed as many people as possible into the final birds that landed. After one quick glace to make sure all of his men were gone, Valdez became the last man to board the last helicopter.
On the chopper out ahead of him, Sgt. Douglas Potratz, now 60, from Fullerton, California, watched Saigon burn.
"I felt sad because I felt like we had lost the war and so many lives had been spent on the war here," he said. "I felt like we were entrusted to keep the traditions going and to not let the country go to communism and we had failed, and I felt very low at that time. I felt like it was the end of the world."
The scenes of the women with wailing babies frantically begging to be saved outside the embassy walls haunted his dreams for years, but he said coming back four decades later with the same men he left with so long ago has helped him heal.
"When I saw that that the country had moved forward, it gave me a little peace in my mind and let me move forward mentally knowing that it wasn't frozen in time anymore," he said. "Things do progress. Things do move forward, and I could put the past away and have better memories instead of just bad memories about this country."

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:37:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deputies: Man hid in ex-girlfriend's closet</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/deputies-man-hid-in-exgirlfriends-closet_26124362</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Previous
Next
A 20-year-old Immokalee man has been hit with a slew of charges after deputies he stalked his ex-girlfriend. Hernan Gijon was charged Wednesday with burglary after the ex-girlfriends family members reported that he broke into their home and hid in a closet under some clothes.
Full story available to subscribers only.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:27:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Panther, wreck and car fire make for a rough day</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/interstate-75-commute-marred-by-threecar-crash-car-fire-and-florida-panther-roadkill-thursday_63632533</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Interstate 75 commute marred by three-car crash, car fire and Florida panther roadkill Thursday
Eric Staats
6:27 PM, Apr 30, 2015
7:59 PM, Apr 30, 2015
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
ESTERO, Fla. - Before the white Buick caught fire and the three cars crashed into one another, the man on his way to work at the Steak n Shake ran over the Florida panther.
Full story available to subscribers only.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:46:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deputies: Man ran grow house with child in home</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/deputies-man-ran-grow-house-with-10yearold-in-the-home_94413267</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Share Article
Subscribe to the Naples Daily News
Ready to subscribe to the Naples Daily News? Choose between a Premium or Digital subscription below.
Need Help? Call us at 1-888-878-6842.
Monday-Friday: 6am-6pm / Saturday: 7am-3pm / Sunday: 7am-2pm
Comments
Want to participate in the conversation? Log in or become a subscriber today.  Subscribers can read and comment on any story, anytime.  Non-subscribers will only be able to view comments on select stories.
Trending stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:10:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fifth Avenue bar seeks go-go dancers?</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-government/naples-club-seeks-gogo-dancers-city-officials-stop-them_79209784</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Naples club on Fifth Avenue seeks go-go dancers, city officials stop them
Aisling Swift
5:39 PM, Apr 30, 2015
9:45 PM, Apr 30, 2015
local news | local government | on todays 1a
Club 469 owner Tommaso Davide (left) and Manager Rick Meadows at Davide's bar at 469 Fifth Ave. S., the former Osetra Caviar and Champagne Bar. City Code Enforcement officials shut them down this week until they obtain all required permits and have a food supplier so food is served with the wine and beer. (Photo by Aisling Swift/Staff)
Aisling Swift
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
It was a Craigslist ad looking for go-go dancers for a bar and the map showed the location as Naples posh Fifth Avenue South, an unlikely place for scantily clad dancers.
Full story available to subscribers only.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:28:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NASA's Messenger crashes into Mercury</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/world/doomsday-at-mercury-nasa-craft-falls-from-orbit-into-planet</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Doomsday at Mercury: NASA craft falls from orbit into planet
Marcia Dunn, Associated Press
4:57 PM, Apr 30, 2015
5:28 PM, Apr 30, 2015
Previous
Next
This artist's rendering provided by NASA shows the MErcury Surface, Space ENvironment, GEochemistry, and Ranging (MESSENGER) spacecraft around Mercury. On Thursday, April 16, 2015, NASA announced that after years of orbiting the planet, the spacecraft will crash into the planet at the end of the month. (NASA/JHU APL/Carnegie Institution of Washington via AP)
Uncredited
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
In this undated photo provided by NASA, technicians with The Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics Laboratory in Titusville, Fla., prepare the MESSESNGER spacecraft for a move to a hazardous processing facility in preparation for loading the spacecraft's hypergolic propellants. (NASA via AP)
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
This artist's rendering provided by the Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics Laboratory shows the sunshade on the MErcury Surface, Space ENvironment, GEochemistry, and Ranging (Messenger) around the planet Mercury. The sunshade shields the spacecraft's instruments from heat and solar radiation. (Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics Laboratory via AP) Image converted using ifftoany
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:38:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Documentary on T-rex leads to pardon request</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/watercooler/documentary-on-t-rex-discovery-leads-to-pardon-request</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Documentary on T-rex discovery leads to pardon request
Kevin Burbach, Associated Press
4:38 PM, Apr 30, 2015
Previous
Next
In this June 26, 2013 photo provided by Black Hills Institute of Geological Research, Peter Larson excavates a Triceratops femur in a quarry near Newcastle, Wyoming. Larson has discovered thousands of fossils around the world and led the team that unearthed the largest and most complete Tyrannosaurus rex ever found. But there's one black mark on his record  a federal conviction that landed him in prison 20 years ago. (Timothy Larson/Black Hills Institute via AP)
Timothy Larson
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
In this May 5, 2013 photo provided by the Black Hills Institute of Geological Research, Inc., Peter Larson surveys a dig site before beginning an excavation near Newcastle, Wyoming. Larson has discovered thousands of fossils around the world and led the team that unearthed the largest and most complete Tyrannosaurus rex ever found. But there's one black mark on his record _ a federal conviction that landed him in prison 20 years ago. (Timothy Larson/Black Hills Institute via AP)
Timothy Larson
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
PIERRE, S.D. - Pete Larson has discovered thousands of fossils around the world, co-authored three books and led the team that unearthed the largest and most complete Tyrannosaurus rex ever found. But there's one black mark on his record: a federal conviction that landed him in prison almost 20 years ago.
His name could soon be cleared because of a documentary released last year at the Sundance Film Festival, which has brought his legal blemish back into the public eye and spurred South Dakota residents  and Larson himself  to push for President Barack Obama to give him a pardon.
"Dinosaur 13" details the discovery of "Sue," a Tyrannosaurus rex that was more than 90 percent complete when it was discovered in 1990 in South Dakota. Federal agents seized the fossil in 1992, alleging that Larson's Black Hills Institute of Geological Research and its employees took it from federal trust land.
While those charges never stuck, the federal government investigated the institute and brought more than 150 unrelated charges against its employees. Only Larson and two others were found guilty, and the paleontologist was sentenced to two years in federal prison for lying on customs documents about thousands of dollars used for fossil deals in Peru and Japan and illegally taking fossils from a national forest in Montana.
Larson's backers have argued for more than two decades that he was overzealously prosecuted. The movie's release has reignited that conversation, leading his supporters to push for the president to correct what they see as the government's mistake.
The South Dakota Legislature overwhelmingly passed a resolution this session that's been sent to Obama requesting a pardon for Larson. And Larson is working with an attorney on a formal pardon request  a move he hopes could clear his name and also allow him to travel to Canada, where he said more fossil work is be done.
"It's something very special for me personally to have this piece of paper that says I'm pardoned for these offenses," Larson said. "It's an important mile marker to reach. Like climbing Mt. Everest, or finding your first T-rex  or finding your 10th T-rex."
But not everyone thinks Larson's name should be cleared or that the documentary, which portrays the paleontologists in the mid-1990s trial in a fairly sympathetic light, should prompt a pardon.
The lone two lawmakers  out of 105  who opposed the resolution said they personally know people who were involved in the investigation, believe Larson's crime was serious and that the conviction was justified.
"It's possible that he was overzealously prosecuted but yet guilty of the crimes on which he was found guilty of," said Rep. Mark Mickelson, R-Sioux Falls.
Neither he nor fellow Republican Rep. Lee Schoenbeck, of Watertown, has seen the film.
"Unless it had a detailed review of the criminal investigation file, I probably wouldn't spend my time watching it," Schoenbeck said. "There is no chance that any legislators knew the details of that criminal case that would warrant them for voting for that resolution."
Rep. Mike Verichio, a Republican from Larson's home of Hill City, said he introduced the resolution after an outpouring of requests from constituents who had watched the documentary and thought Larson was unjustly imprisoned.
The film aired worldwide and played in tiny theatres across South Dakota last summer, from Mitchell to Hill City, where the geological institute is headquartered.
"There were people who really weren't aware of the background of the situation and how it happened and that seemed to be the catalyst right there," said Verichio, who has watched the film several times. "It built up a tremendous amount of support here."
It's unclear how Larson's pardon request and the support from the state of South Dakota will be received by the president. A White House spokesman said they don't usually comment on individual cases.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:29:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>When can you film cops? Rules aren't clear cut</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/rules-on-filming-cops-arent-clear-cut_76469535</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Subscribe to the Naples Daily News
Ready to subscribe to the Naples Daily News? Choose between a Premium or Digital subscription below.
Need Help? Call us at 1-888-878-6842.
Monday-Friday: 6am-6pm / Saturday: 7am-3pm / Sunday: 7am-2pm
Comments
Want to participate in the conversation? Log in or become a subscriber today.  Subscribers can read and comment on any story, anytime.  Non-subscribers will only be able to view comments on select stories.
Trending stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:22:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Did head blows push boxer to burglary?</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/did-blows-to-the-head-lead-boxer-to-burglary_24633282</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Did blows to the head lead boxer to burglary?
Jacob Carpenter
4:22 PM, Apr 30, 2015
7:40 PM, Apr 30, 2015
crime
ID Photo
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
With blistering hand speed and a streak of showmanship, Hector MachoCamachobecame a world-renowned championship boxer and notorious playboy during his heyday in the1980sand90s.
In the other corner, there wasCamachoslittle brother, Felix.
Felix also spent two decades in the ring, trying to fight his way out of an impoverished Harlem childhood. But Showtime, as Felix was known, never reached the same heights as his brother, disposing of 20 challengers and dropping six bouts.
Like many boxers, Felix didnt know when to throw in the towel. At age 44, he went six rounds at a Fort Myers ice skating rink against a 29-year-old. Family members said he was never the same after that.
Those years of pounding, of constant blows to the head, are what helped put FelixCamachoin prison for 15 years for burglary and theft, his lawyers say, and theyre also his only hope of getting out sooner.
Full story available to subscribers only.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 22:40:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Sanders differs from Clinton</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/elections/in-presidential-bid-sanders-differs-with-clinton</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>In presidential bid, Sanders differs with Clinton
David Espo, Associated Press
3:40 PM, Apr 30, 2015
Sen. Bernie Sanders, I-Vt., reacts as he as he is asked about running for president during a news conference on Capitol Hill in Washington, Wednesday, April 29, 2015. Sanders has made it official, telling The Associated Press in an interview that he's running for president. (AP Photo/Carolyn Kaster)
Carolyn Kaster
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
WASHINGTON - Day-old presidential contender Bernie Sanders said Thursday that questions about the Clinton Foundation's activities are fair game in the race for the Democratic nomination, and noted that Hillary Rodham Clinton has yet to take a position on contentious trade legislation and the proposed Keystone XL Pipeline.
At a news conference with the U.S. Capitol as a backdrop, the independent senator from Vermont said creating "an economy that works for all of our people" would be at the center of his campaign for the Democratic nomination. "The wealthiest people in the country and the largest corporations" must stop shipping jobs overseas and start paying their fair share of taxes, he said.
He spoke not long after filing papers for his launch and as his team came out with a new website. It says, "A political revolution is coming," and has a disclaimer that it is "paid for by Bernie 2016, not the billionaires."
Sanders said he remains a political independent, but drew a tweeted welcome to the race from Florida Rep. Debbie Wasserman Schultz, head of the Democratic National Committee. "Sanders has clearly demonstrated his commitment to the values we all share as members of the Democratic Party," she posted.
And Clinton tweeted: "I agree with Bernie. Focus must be on helping America's middle class. GOP would hold them back. I welcome him to the race."
He is the first major challenger to enter the race against Clinton, who launched her own bid for president earlier this month and is the heavily favored, early front-runner in the Democratic contest. Former Maryland Gov. Martin O'Malley and former Virginia Sen. Jim Webb are potential contenders, and ex-Rhode Island Gov. Lincoln Chafee recently said he intends to run.
On economic issues, Sanders' campaign platform coincides with positions taken by Sen. Elizabeth Warren, D-Mass., a fierce critic of large corporations, who has declined calls to enter the presidential race. He hopes to turn a lingering sense of economic insecurity on the part of millions of Americans into votes in primaries and caucuses that begin early next year.
Once known as a socialist mayor of Burlington, Vt., Sanders is a native of Brooklyn with an accent to match. The 73-year-old veteran lawmaker said he has never run a negative television commercial, implying he won't this time, either. Yet he said, "We're in this race to win," and pledged a vigorous debate on the issues with Clinton, a former first lady, senator and secretary of state.
Drawing a contrast with his rival  if politely  he said he opposed the Iraq war while in the Senate, a conflict that she voted to authorize as a New York senator.
He also said he is helping lead opposition to legislation that would strengthen President Barack Obama's hand in future trade talks, including a proposed 12-nation Trans-Pacific Partnership. He added he opposed legislation to permit construction of the proposed Keystone XL Pipeline that cleared Congress and was vetoed earlier in the year by Obama.
"We don't know what Hillary's stances are on all of the issues," Sanders added.
Clinton has supported previous trade deals, and the issue emerged as a key point of contention eight years ago when she and Obama both sought the presidency. She's expressed skepticism recently about the emerging Pacific agreement, saying it must protect U.S. workers, but has not taken a firm position on the deal and spoke in its favor when in Obama's Cabinet.
Sanders said questions about the Clinton Foundation are legitimate for the campaign ahead. The global charitable effort was set up by former President Bill Clinton after he left office. Critics have recently raised questions about possible connections between donations made by foreign governments and policies Hillary Clinton pursued while serving as secretary of state.
In addition, the acting head of the foundation said recently the organization expects to refile some of its past tax returns to correct errors.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 22:38:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'I know it' Spelling Bee sensation offers advice</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/scripps-national-spelling-bee-i-know-it-sensation-jacob-williamson-offers-advice</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Previous
Next
Last year, Jacob Williamson stood out to viewers of the televised Scripps National Spelling Bee for his intoxicating exhilaration  and sudden exit in round 10 after confidently misspelling kabaragoya.
I know it! he said.
But it was not to Bee.
I enjoyed the recognition while it was around but everything went back to normal eventually and Im fine with that, he said.
Because Williamson is 16 this year, hes no longer eligible to compete in the Scripps National Spelling Bee. He recently gave coaching a try, instructing two local children. But they appeared to be unprepared for the grueling regimen that it takes to go far, he said.
We got beat pretty bad at regionals. They didnt seem all that interested in it, to be honest, Williamson said. They got to be wanting to study and prepare on their own without me. They didn't seem to be willing enough.
In Williamsons final year of eligibility, he studied full time over his spring break  about eight hours per day.
I was going through the entire Webster dictionary cover to cover. I did that twice, he said. With enough preparation, anyone can go far, Williamson said.
Making it to the top takes time, effort and dedication. For beginning spellers, he advises going to SpellingBee.com and study the round three list. The site provides word clubs for regional winners, he said.
No matter how low your odds are, you should believe that you can do your best, Williamson said.
Its also important to learn the rules of each language. Thats why asking for the origin is so common.
Each individual language has its own rules, you know spellers ask the language of origin on stage, Williamson said. One of the most important things for a speller to do is to learn the rules and the word roots.
Though his first experience as a coach came with challenges, Williamson said he isnt giving up.
Im going to try again but Im only going to get with someone if theyre committed enough to study some on their own, Williamson said, And not totally rely on me for their success.
While viewers will miss out on Williamsons on-stage energy, he will be attending the Bee as a fan. Many of his friends still compete.
Williamson is now weighing his future, which is as bright as he is. Last month, he passed the test to enter MENSA International, the society for people with a high IQ.
Williamson, who is homeschooled, was recently accepted to online high schools by Stanford and George Washington University. Hes weighing each programs strengths to make a decision.
I like both for different reasons, he said. After that, off to college.
Gavin Stern is a national digital producer for the Scripps National Desk.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
