<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="scrippsobfeeds">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:37:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colorado speller's 1st national bee is her last</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/lakewood-spellers-first-national-bee-is-also-her-last</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Previous
Next
NATIONAL HARBOR, Md. - The stakes are high for 12-year-old Sylvie Lamontagne , who will compete in the Scripps National Spelling Bee for the first  and only  time since she started participating in the third grade.
Although many regional bees allow past winners to compete again, the Denver area does not. The national bee includes one speller who is making a fifth appearance and three who are here for a fourth year.
Theres a rule that you can only come here once, said Sylvie, who is still young enough to qualify, but cant compete again because a rule in the Colorado State Spelling Bee prevents past winners.
I want to enjoy this, but at the same time, it adds more pressure, she said.
For Sylvie, of Lakewood, Colo., it has been a long road to the national bee stage. She came in 26th place as a fifth-grader in the state bee, and moved up to 8th place last year.
This year, the Creighton Middle School seventh-grader finally won the state bee with the word sympatric, which means occupying the same geographic area.
Sylvie hopes her experience in previous bees has prepared her for whats to come.
If I get a word I havent studied, which is always a possibility, I slow down, she said. When I started competing, I rushed too much.
In one her first bees, Sylvie remembers misspelling the word zigzag, by starting the word withan s.
Now I use my finger to write out the word on hand, she said.
Sylvies dad, Jeff Lamontagne, helps her study the root of words and language patterns to improve the chances of making an educated guess when she comes across a word she doesnt know.
For me, this trip is about Sylvie. She has worked so hard and she only gets the one chance, he said.
All 285 spellers took a written spelling and vocabulary test Tuesday morning. Spellers take the stage for Round 2 at 8 a.m. Wednesday. Those who spell their words correctly spell again on stage in the afternoon. ESPN3 will televise the competition beginning at 8 a.m. and 1:15 p.m. EDT.
At about 5 p.m., bee officials will announce the names of a maximum of 50 spellers to advance to the semifinals. They are chosen based on the points they earn for correctly spelling words on stage and their scores on the written test. ESPN 2 will broadcast the semifinals beginning at 10 a.m. Thursday.
The finals will air Thursday at 8 p.m. EDT on ESPN. The winner takes home $35,000 in cash, a trophy and other prizes.
Reach reporterRebeca Piccardoat rebeca.piccardo @scripps.com or 202-408-1492. SHFWire stories are free to any news organization that gives the reporter a byline and credits the SHFWire. Like the Scripps Howard Foundation Wire interns on Facebook and follow us on Twitter .
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:06:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Locals describe devastation in Wimberley</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/weather/locals-describe-flooding-in-wimberley_87036816</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Locals describe devastation in Wimberley
Julie Garcia
5:56 PM, May 25, 2015
49 mins ago
Previous
Next
Debi Welsh, of Corpus Christi, Texas, picks up a lamp while helping clean up the remains of her family home that washed away, Monday, May 25, 2015, in Wimberley, Texas. Around a dozen people were reported missing in flash flooding from a line of storms that stretched from the Gulf of Mexico to the Great Lakes. (Jerry Lara/The San Antonio Express-News via AP)
Jerry Lara
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Gordon Welch surveys damage to the house his family has owned since 1964 along River Road next to the Blanco River in Wimberley, Texas, Sunday, May 24, 2015. Welch said that he and his wife watched the house get swept away by flood water. (Kelly West/Austin American-Statesman via AP)
Kelly West
Next
Sheri Emerick says she was lucky.
Emerick and her husband, Kurt, were visiting friends in Wimberley over the weekend when severe rains caused the Blanco River to rise about 35 feet within a few hours and flood or sweep away about 400 homes.
We have friends that have a home that is probably two miles north of the actual central park of Wimberley. Its a much more highly elevated area, about 700 feet above the river, the Portland resident said. We did not experience any flooding, but we did experience the very intense rainstorm. Lots of lightning and thunder with 60 mph winds.

Eight Corpus Christi residents who were visiting Wimberley for Memorial Day weekend are missing after they were swept away in a vacation home in the floodwaters late Saturday. There are 12 people missing total.
Wimberley was a charming little town, Emerick said.
The whole area is really beautiful in the Hill Country with a lot of creeks and rivers, she said. Many people go there and either rent houses or cabins or may own a second home there. Its a very popular vacation spot.
The day after the devastation, the Emericks saw damage in downtown Wimberley along the Blanco River and Cypress Creek.
Its really a tragedy, its just a beautiful part of the state, she said. Luckily, Im completely safe but our hearts go to the families.
Facing the Storm
When water collects quickly and has nowhere to go because of soil saturation, it can act as a solid rather than a liquid, said Mike Buchanan, a meteorologist with the National Weather Service.
There are very few things on Earth that can stop flowing water, Buchanan said. With over 40 feet of flowing water, nothing can withstand that. That is a tremendous force that is hard to imagine.
The abundant rain in Central and South Texas this spring has led to flooding conditions across the state. A persistent El Nio pattern is the main reason for much of the rainfall in the past six months, Buchanan said.
That river was only at about five feet and jumped to over 40-feet in a short amount of time, Buchanan said. All of the soils were saturated. Usually the water will infiltrate the soils, but when youre saturated, the water has nowhere else to go. It will run off into low spots  valleys, creeks and water crossings, but when it has no where else to go, there is a greater risk for flash flooding.
Because of Wimberleys hilly terrain, the area is conducive to flash flood conditions.
A lot of the time, rainfall here is very heavy (which can lead to) a flash flood in less than an hour. Its usually two- to four-inches an hour, which is sufficient for flash flooding in many communities.
Though Nueces County has experienced flash flooding and damaging floodwaters in its urban and rural areas recently, the possibility of a Wimberley-like disaster are not likely for the area, he said.
If water is falling on a hillside, it can run off quickly to a river valley which is what happened there, Buchanan said. Around here in Corpus, a lot of time, the water ponds and doesnt move fast.
It Keeps Coming
The American Red Cross has been activated statewide to aid in helping flood victims and evacuees. TexSar, a state search and rescue organization partnered with Nueces County Emergency Management, has teams in Central and South Texas searching for the 12 missing.
With severe weather still in the forecast for most of the middle and lower half of the state, flooding conditions are expected along the Guadalupe River in DeWitt and Victoria counties.
This is going to be a very wet season, said Danielle Hale, Nueces County Emergency Management Coordinator. I believe were going to be dealing with this for the long-term.
A Red Cross shelter will be set up at Cuero Intermediate School gymnasium for evacuees starting at 5 p.m. Monday.
Any time we have a major event, Safe and Well with the Red Cross is a great place to let friends and family know that youre OK, Hale said. The system is activated for the Texas flood event for people displaced as they go into shelters.
Hale, who knows the emergency management personnel in Hays County, said the search and rescue is their primary goal, then connecting families and surveying damage. The publics patience and cooperation is necessary and appreciated, she said.
Twitter: @Caller_Jules
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:02:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why grocery coupons stink these days</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/business/why-grocery-coupons-stink-these-days</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Why grocery coupons stink these days
Don't Waste Your Money
11:47 AM, May 18, 2015
45 mins ago
Previous
Next
Remember a few years back when couponing was all the rage, and even spawned some reality shows?
But coupon use is now dropping off sharply. Those couponing shows are disappearing faster than Honey Boo Boo.
And one reason, according to a new report, is that most of them are duds.
Many Shoppers Frustrated
You're not the only one who's gotten frustrated by today's grocery coupon offerings.
A report from the money saving website "Credit Donkey" says they don't always save you money, and can lead to unhealthy habits.
It says many of today's coupons...
Encourage junk food cravings.
Make you buy processed food.
Trigger impulse buys of things you don't need.
Make you buy two or three items, when you just wanted one.
Unless you run a restaurant, do you really need three bottles of ketchup?
Doesn't That Stink? 
But from the "doesn't that stink" file, the main reasons the couponing craze has been waning.
Coupon values are getting smaller (Many are just 25 cents off instead of 75 cents or $1)
Coupons doubling is disappearing (Kroger ended it in most markets 2 years ago)
Most coupons are for unpopular items, that are not selling well, instead of things like Tide and Cheerios.
Finally, stores are limiting the number of coupons you can use per trip.
Sure, you can still find some good coupons -- such as for laundry detergent or vitamins-- but they are fewer and fewer.
Alternatives to Couponing
Many stores are transitioning to digital coupons.
It's often worth signing up for a store's coupon offerings, sent directly to your phone or Inbox.
Also consider apps that give you rebates for buying certain items such as Ibotta or ReceiptHog .
Click here for my report on how to make money this way.
If your paper coupons are just for things you would never buy otherwise, then it may be a case of don't waste your money.
____________________
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:38:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rape, assault detailed as trial opens</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/prosecutors-open-trail-with-detail-of-rape-assault_97915456</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Prosecutors open trial with detail of rape, assault
Kristine Gill
6:38 PM, May 26, 2015
29 mins ago
Previous
Next
Jacob Carrel is admitted into court from a holding area Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at the Collier County Courthouse in Naples, Fla. Opening statements were heard in the trial involving Jacob Carrel, accused of attempted murder, rape and armed burglary from February 2013. Investigators said Carrel broke into a home, threatened a teenage girl, raped her and tried to break her neck. The woman fell unconscious and woke up covered in blood with stab wounds to her neck. Investigators said Carrel knew the womans brother. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Judge Frederick Hardt looks at photo evidence Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at the Collier County Courthouse in Naples, Fla. Opening statements were heard in the trial involving Jacob Carrel, accused of attempted murder, rape and armed burglary from February 2013. Investigators said Carrel broke into a home, threatened a teenage girl, raped her and tried to break her neck. The woman fell unconscious and woke up covered in blood with stab wounds to her neck. Investigators said Carrel knew the womans brother. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Jacob Carrel, center, sits with his defense team Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at the Collier County Courthouse in Naples, Fla. Opening statements were heard in the trial involving Jacob Carrel, accused of attempted murder, rape and armed burglary from February 2013. Investigators said Carrel broke into a home, threatened a teenage girl, raped her and tried to break her neck. The woman fell unconscious and woke up covered in blood with stab wounds to her neck. Investigators said Carrel knew the womans brother. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Previous
Next
Hours after leaving Golden Gate High School following a band event, the 16-year-old victim of a rape and attempted murder returned to her school, this time waiting to be airlifted to the hospital as she bled from a stab wound to her neck.
Prosecutors told jurors Tuesday that Jacob Carrel, a 25-year-old Golden Gate man, was responsible for the Feb. 7, 2013 attack.
He laid in wait for her to arrive, Assistant State Attorney Mara Marzano said.
Carrel was arrested after the crime and faces charges of burglary, sexual assault and attempted murder.
Related story: Golden Gate man charged with attempted murder, sexual assault in home attack
In her opening statements, Marzano described in detail how Carrel broke into the victims home where she lived with her father. He waited until the girl had gone to the bathroom before busting through the door. He raped the girl then told her he was worried she had seen his face and could identify him. Thats when Carrel twisted the girls neck, trying to break it. The attempt failed, Marzano said, and instead Carrel used a kitchen knife to slash the teens throat, taking her cellphone and leaving her for dead.
When the girl woke, she was naked and covered in her own blood. Weakened from the attack, she pulled a pair of boxers on, then wrapped a pair of pants around her neck wound and waited on the couch for her father to arrive.
The victim had recognized her attacker and remembered his shoes and tattoo. Following a conversation with her brother in the hospital, the two realized Carrel, a family acquaintance, was likely behind the attack.
She identified him, without hesitation, in both lineups, Marzano said.
DNA evidence from a rape kit and found on Carrel shoes will corroborate this story in the coming days of the trial, Marzano said.
But those statements dont tell the whole story, a public defender for Carrel said.
You were told Jacob Carrel laid in wait. What you may not hear is evidence as to why, Shannon Lynn Brown said. There was no evidence of any past history between (the victim) and Jacob.
Namely, the victim described her attacker as being shorter than her. Carrel, his attorney pointed out, is taller than the victim.
And despite the credentials of a witness scheduled to testify on DNA evidence in the case, none of Carrels DNA was ever found on the victim.
She will testify to statistics, Brown said.
Brown reminded the jurors that theyd taken an oath to reserve judgment until theyd heard all the evidence.
Jacob Carrel is not guilty, Brown said. And hes personally chosen you to decide that.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:29:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Self-defense or something else? Jury to decide</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/selfdefense-or-something-else-jury-will-decide-collier-mans-fate_38113086</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Self-defense or something else? Jury will decide Collier man's fate
Kristine Gill
6:29 PM, May 26, 2015
59 mins ago
Previous
Next
Defendant Javier Ortoll, left, looks on as members of the jury speak Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at the Collier County Courthouse in Naples, Fla. Opening statements were heard in the trial involving Ortoll, a 78-year-old wheelchair-bound landlord charged with murder. Investigators said Ortoll fatally shot 51-year-old Edward Melone during an argument about unpaid rent on Okeechobee Street, about a quarter-mile south of the Collier courthouse, where they both lived. Ortolls family has said it was self-defense after Melone reached into his van, while investigators said Melone was only retrieving a
Corey Perrine
Defense Attorney James Zonas, center, and Assistant State Attorney Lisa Mead, right, look on as the jury enters Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at the Collier County Courthouse in Naples, Fla. Opening statements were heard in the trial l involving Javier Ortoll, a 78-year-old wheelchair-bound landlord charged with murder. Investigators said Ortoll fatally shot 51-year-old Edward Melone during an argument about unpaid rent on Okeechobee Street, about a quarter-mile south of the Collier courthouse, where they both lived. Ortolls family has said it was self-defense after Melone reached into his van,
Corey Perrine
Judge Mike Carr talks as the defense and prosecution teams talk about three jurors exempt from duty because of a belief or knowledge of the case Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at the Collier County Courthouse in Naples, Fla. Opening statements were heard in the trial involving Javier Ortoll, a 78-year-old wheelchair-bound landlord charged with murder. Investigators said Ortoll fatally shot 51-year-old Edward Melone during an argument about unpaid rent on Okeechobee Street, about a quarter-mile south of the Collier courthouse, where they both lived. Ortolls family has said it was self-defense after
Corey Perrine
Judge Mike Carr is seen talking to the jury Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at the Collier County Courthouse in Naples, Fla. Opening statements were heard in the trial involving Javier Ortoll, a 78-year-old wheelchair-bound landlord charged with murder. Investigators said Ortoll fatally shot 51-year-old Edward Melone during an argument about unpaid rent on Okeechobee Street, about a quarter-mile south of the Collier courthouse, where they both lived. Ortolls family has said it was self-defense after Melone reached into his van, while investigators said Melone was only retrieving a dropped cellphone.
Corey Perrine
Defendant Javier Ortoll, looks on as members of the jury speak Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at the Collier County Courthouse in Naples, Fla. Opening statements were heard in the trial involving Ortoll, a 78-year-old wheelchair-bound landlord charged with murder. Investigators said Ortoll fatally shot 51-year-old Edward Melone during an argument about unpaid rent on Okeechobee Street, about a quarter-mile south of the Collier courthouse, where they both lived. Ortolls family has said it was self-defense after Melone reached into his van, while investigators said Melone was only retrieving a dropped
Corey Perrine
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:55:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Graduate of Distinction: Yanet Gomez</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/education/graduate-of-distinction-yanet-gomez-of-lely-high-school_69212123</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Graduate of Distinction: Yanet Gomez of Lely High School
John Osborne
5:55 PM, May 26, 2015
3 hours ago
education
Yanet Gomez
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
After moving to the United States from Cuba at age 11, Yanet Gomez decided to repeat fifth grade to help her overcome the language barrier.
Full story available to subscribers only.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:43:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bernie Sanders kicks off 2016 bid</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/elections/vermonts-bernie-sanders-kicks-off-2016-bid-from-clintons-left</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Vermont's Bernie Sanders kicks off 2016 bid from Clinton's left
Dave Gram and Ken Thomas, Associated Press
5:43 PM, May 26, 2015
In this photo taken May 20, 2015, Democratic Presidential candidate Sen. Bernie Sanders, I-Vt., poses for a portrait before an interview with The Associated Press in Washington. For Democrats who had hoped to lure Massachusetts Sen. Elizabeth Warren into a presidential campaign, independent Sen. Bernie Sanders might be the next best thing. Sanders, who is opening his official presidential campaign Tuesday in Burlington, Vermont, aims to ignite a grassroots fire among left-leaning Democrats wary of Hillary Rodham Clinton. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)
Jacquelyn Martin
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
BURLINGTON, Vt. - Vermont Sen. Bernie Sanders kicked off his longshot presidential campaign Tuesday with a pitch to liberals in the Democratic Party and others who want change from a "rigged economy" that favors the rich.
Sanders vowed to make income inequality, a campaign finance overhaul and climate change his leading issues as he takes on Hillary Rodham Clinton for the Democratic nomination.
"This type of rigged economy is not what America is supposed to be about," the self-described democratic socialist said in remarks prepared for his rally. The event came several weeks after Sanders announced his candidacy  this time, the plan was to hand out free ice cream before his crowd of supporters.
He says there is "something profoundly wrong" when so much of the nation's income goes to the top 1 percent of all earners.
"I know what I believe," Sanders said in a fundraising email hours before his event, pushing back against "the billionaire class" trying to buy the election. "That's why today marks the beginning of our political revolution."
Sanders is trying to ignite a grassroots fire among left-leaning Democrats wary of Clinton  a group that pined for months for Massachusetts Sen. Elizabeth Warren to get in the race. Some still do.
But while Warren remains committed to the Senate, repeatedly saying she won't run for the White House, Sanders is laying out an agenda in step with the party's progressive wing and Warren's platform  reining in Wall Street banks, tackling college debt and creating a government-financed infrastructure jobs program.
Clinton is in a commanding position by any measure, far in front of both Sanders and former Maryland Gov. Martin O'Malley, who is widely expected to get into the race Saturday.
Yet Sanders' supporters in New Hampshire say his local ties and longstanding practice of holding town hall meetings and people-to-people campaigning  a staple in the nation's first primary state  will serve him well.
"Toward the Vermont border it's like a love-fest for Bernie," said Jerry Curran, an Amherst, New Hampshire, Democratic activist who has been involved in the draft Warren effort. "He's not your milquetoast left-winger. He's kind of a badass left-winger."
Sanders, an independent in the Senate who often votes with the Democrats, has raised more than $4 million since announcing in late April that he would seek the party's nomination. He suggested in the interview that raising $50 million for the primaries was a possibility. "That would be a goal," he said.
Whether Sanders can tap into the party's Warren wing and influence Clinton's policy agenda remains unclear. But he has been on the forefront of liberal causes as Clinton has seemed to be tacking to the left.
He's joined with Warren to drive opposition to the Trans-Pacific Partnership trade proposal, arguing it would ship jobs overseas. Clinton has avoided taking a specific position on the trade deal.
He has introduced legislation to make tuition free at public colleges and universities, a major piece of Warren's agenda. Clinton's campaign has signaled that she intends to make debt-free college a major piece of her campaign.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:26:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Graduate of Distinction: Nedgie Paul of Palmetto</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/2015-palmetto-ridge-graduate-of-distinction-nedgie-paul_77377383</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Graduate of Distinction: Nedgie Paul of Palmetto Ridge High School
John Osborne
5:26 PM, May 26, 2015
3 hours ago
Negdie Paul
Douglas, Katherine
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
At age two, Nedgie Paul, along with her family, moved to the United States from Haiti in pursuit of the American dream.
Full story available to subscribers only.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:23:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Graduate of Distinction: Regine Francois</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/education/graduate-of-distinction-regine-francois-of-immokalee-high-school_05533921</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Graduate of Distinction: Regine Francois of Immokalee High School
John Osborne
5:23 PM, May 26, 2015
3 hours ago
Regine Francois
Nick Shirghio
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
By accumulating more than 60 college credits even before she completes high school and starring in a pair of varsity sports that require running shoes, it should come as no surprise that Regine Francois has been on the fast track for a while now.
Full story available to subscribers only.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:52:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Update: I-75 reopens following crash at mm 97</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/traffic/interstate-75-shut-down-in-both-directions-at-mile-marker-97-for-crash</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Next
Update:
As of 4:45 p.m., the Florida Highway Patrol says Interstate 75 is now open to traffic, following a single-vehicle crash around 4 p.m.
The crash shut down both directions of traffic near mile marker 97 for about 40 minutes Tuesday while one person was flown to Lee Memorial Hospital to be treated for traumatic injuries.
The crash happened when a Honda Civic rolled over in the median, according to Assistant Chief Nolan Sapp of the Greater Naples Fire-Rescue District.
As of 4:45 p.m., Greater Naples personnel were clearing the scene.

Earlier:
A crash in southbound lanes of Interstate 75 has shut down lanes of traffic in both directions near mile marker 97.
The crash was reported around 4 p.m. Tuesday. As of 4:30 p.m., Florida Highway Patrol troopers were shutting down the interstate in both directions.
Check back to naplesnews.com for updates.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:30:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Collier approves money for Freedom Memorial</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/collier-commits-525000-to-freedom-memorial-and-open-competitive-bids-next-week_36639400</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Collier commits $525,000 to Freedom Memorial, and open competitive bids next week
Greg Stanley
4:30 PM, May 26, 2015
4 hours ago
The Collier County Freedom Memorial sits incomplete in Fred W. Coyle Freedom Park on Wednesday, Feb. 4, 2015, in Naples. (David Albers/Staff)
David Albers
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
Collier County commissioners agreed on Tuesday to give $525,000 to the long unfinished Freedom Memorial on Golden Gate Parkway, which may be enough to complete the once languishing project.
The memorial already has raised $600,000 in private donations during a fundraising flurry over the last few months and another $100,000 in public money given by the Naples City Council.
Im going to cry when this is finished, said Jerry Sandford a public information officer for the North Collier Fire District who has been promoting the memorial since the beginning in 2003. This is a lot of Saturdays, Sundays and weekends. People are sick of seeing me. The light is much brighter now that were getting to the end of the tunnel.
The county will handle competitive bidding on the project and will start looking at construction bids next week. Barring any setbacks, the project could be completed by the end of the year, said Commissioner Georgia Hiller.
We might be able to have a New Years Eve party there, Hiller said.
The 13-foot-high battleship gray flag was started years ago, but never finished due to lack of funding. Only a 6-foot corner was completed. It will feature expensive red, white and blue granite pieces and honor the military, along with those killed in the 9/11 terrorist attacks and the police officers, firefighters and emergency workers who responded.
Commissioners had promised in February to set aside up to $600,000 to match any funds raised to complete the project.
Its fitting and proper to have this wonderful memorial, Commissioner Tim Nance said.
The project is expected to cost $1.2 million, but a final bill wont be known until a contractor is selected.
Commissioners also unanimously voted to give Arthrex, a North Naples medical device manufacturer, $165,000 in incentives for its planned expansion in Ave Maria. The incentive will wipe out all of the impact fees under the county governments control that the company would normally owe for the 55,000 square-foot facility.
The countys impact fees, which act as one-time taxes on new development used to offset the added strain on public services, have long been among the highest in the state.
The money wont be tied to the number of jobs created by Arthrex, but instead to the amount of money the company is investing in the new facility.
Until recently, any public incentives doled out by the county have been mostly tied to job numbers.
This is a great example of how capital infrastructure incentives are really, in my view, superior and the way to go, Nance said.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:06:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In the Know: Mission BBQ open, CrepeMaker closes</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/columnists/tim-aten-in-the-know/in-the-know-mission-bbq-opens-crepemaker-closes</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>4:00 PM, May 26, 2015
47 mins ago
Mission BBQ
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Mission BBQ
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Tim Aten
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Tim Aten
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
Mission BBQ opened May 11 in the former location ofBrattason U.S. 41 in south Fort Myers.
Missions mission is to serve those who serve America. The patriotic barbecue chain is dedicated to soldiers, firefighters, police officers and other first responders sworn to protect and serve.
Plus more on local eateries coming and going.
Full story available to subscribers only.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:00:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sights and sounds from Scripps Spelling Bee</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/sights-and-sounds-from-the-2015-scripps-national-spelling-bee</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>4:00 PM, May 26, 2015
Jeffery Thompson and Jonathon Schafer.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
Washington, D.C. - 285 spellers from eight countries will compete this year for the coveted title of champion at the88thannual Scripps National Spelling Bee.
Seventh-grader Jonathon Schafer, a student at Royal Palm Academy , correctly spelled the word, "radium" to win the Collier County Spelling Bee. Fort Myers Middle eighth-grader Jeffery Thompson correctly spelled escargot to win the Lee County Spelling Bee.
Follow Collier Citizen editor Jay Schlichter for social media updates during the week from the Bee.
The Bee will take place May 26 to 28 at the Gaylord National Resort and Convention Center in National Harbor, Maryland.
Are you having trouble seeing our live updates? Click here to view our ScribbleLive .

Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:52:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>3 burglars share tips in crime prevention video</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/watercooler/3-burglars-share-tips-of-trade-in-crime-prevention-video</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>3 burglars share tips of trade in crime prevention video
Andrew Welsh-Huggins, Associated Press
3:52 PM, May 26, 2015
This combination of booking photos provided by the Ohio Department of Rehabilitation and Correction shows: Adam Taylor, left, Joel David Hamlin, center, and William Coffman. The Columbus Police Department recruited the inmates with the help of the state prisons agency to produce an educational YouTube video for the public in which the offenders shared their how-to tips on how to prevent burglaries. (Ohio Department of Rehabilitation and Correction via AP)
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
COLUMBUS, Ohio - Police looking to educate the public about ways to prevent break-ins turned to the experts  a trio of convicted burglars.
The Columbus Police Department recruited the inmates with the help of the state prisons agency and produced a YouTube video in which the offenders share their how-to tips. Most of the suggestions are common-sense warnings about locking up, keeping blinds drawn and not storing valuables in cars.
A few recommendations stand out for originality: "Sometimes set it off so people know it's there. Don't just buy it and never set it off." That's William Coffman, of Franklin County, serving time for burglary and aggravated robbery, on advertising that your home alarm system works.
Or Hardin County burglar Joel Hamlin on the importance of putting valuables in a wall safe, not a small portable safe:
"Little safes? You can easily just grab that and take it on out," he said.
Or Adam Taylor, of Hamilton County, on why the elderly are often targeted: It's easier "to burglarize them and get away with it."
Columbus police and the Department of Rehabilitation and Correction filmed the inmates last year, put the pieces together over the past few months and recently posted the two-part, 24-minute video, called "From the Big House to Your House."
Police Cmdr. Bob Meader likens the impact to a child tuning out advice from a parent but heeding the same tips from a teacher or coach.
"For the police to say, 'Lock your doors, keep your garage door shut, leave the lights on on your porch,' is one thing," Meader said. "When you're hearing it from somebody that actually did it for a living? I think it adds some validity to it."
Criminals-turned-anti-crime consultants aren't new. In 1985, reformed burglar Ray Johnson published "Ray Johnson's Total Security: How You can Protect Yourself Against Crime."
In 2002, the Leonardo DiCaprio movie "Catch Me If You Can" told the real-life story of check forger Frank Abagnale Jr., who impersonated an airline pilot, a doctor and a lawyer before going to prison and then becoming an FBI consultant.
In the case of the three Ohio burglars, they agreed to cooperate in exchange for a letter to the parole board from Columbus police about their participation.
The exercise seemed to help the men process the impact they had on their communities, said Officer Norm Russell, who came up with the idea.
Hardin County prosecutor Bradford Bailey recalled Hamlin as a brazen addict who broke into wealthy people's homes in broad daylight. Charging documents from the day Hamlin was arrested describe him going house to house in February 2006 before fleeing from officers, tossing a bag into a river and throwing away other items as he ran.
Bailey isn't bothered by Hamlin's role in the video.
"We'll take any tips from the good guys, or we'll take them from the bad guys," Bailey said.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:23:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A guide to Greece's debt crisis</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/world/a-guide-to-greeces-debt-crisis-and-whats-at-stake</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>A guide to Greece's debt crisis and what's at stake
Elena Becatoros, Associated Press
3:23 PM, May 26, 2015
A tourist touches an ancient column of the archaeological site of Elefsina west of Athens, on Tuesday, May 26, 2015. Greece's finance minister insisted Tuesday that the cash-strapped country will soon reach an agreement with bailout creditors, that will enable it to make a debt payment to the International Monetary Fund on June 5 _ which it would be otherwise unable to pay. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Petros Giannakouris
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
ATHENS, Greece - Greece is out of cash to repay debts due as soon as next week.
The country and its creditors  other eurozone countries and the International Monetary Fund  have been locked in negotiations for months on what reforms the southern European country needs to take to get the final batch of loans from its international bailout.
Greece's government came to power in January on a promise to not make any more belt-tightening reforms, arguing they risk hurting the economy even more.
Without a deal to get more loans, Greece could be unable to repay a series of loans to the IMF in June, the first of which is due on the 5th. Missing those payments could destabilize the country's financial system and eventually push it out of the 19-country eurozone, a step that could shake the currency union and the global economy.
Here's a look at the situation.
___
WHAT IS BEING NEGOTIATED?
The talks now are about releasing the last 7.2 billion euro ($8 billion) loan out of Greece's overall 240 billion euro bailout program. Since Greece's rescue program started in May 2010, money has been disbursed in installments, with debt inspectors from the IMF, European Central Bank and European Commission reviewing the country's progress in reforms each time. Many of the reviews have run beyond their scheduled time, however, as creditors and successive Greek governments argued over the measures. This particular installment was supposed to have been disbursed last year.
___
WHY IS THIS SO URGENT?
Greece needs the money to repay its debts, many of which are repayments of the initial bailout loans. The country cannot borrow on international bond markets, like most countries, because investors are wary and demanding painfully high interest rates.
Greece has a heavy debt repayment schedule in the next three months, with 1.6 billion euros due to the IMF in June alone, with just over 300 million euros due June 5.
But having received no significant rescue loans since last August, it is now struggling to make ends meet by scraping together any cash it can find. The government recently ordered state enterprises, including kindergartens, municipalities, museums and embassies abroad, to transfer their reserve funds into a Bank of Greece account where they can be used by the state.
___
WHAT IF GREECE DOESN'T PAY THE IMF ON JUNE 5?
Missing an IMF repayment doesn't automatically mean Greece is in default. The IMF's rules say that would only be declared once a payment is one month overdue.
But failing to repay its debts could rock the country's markets and further hammer whatever confidence was left among investors and Greeks. Greece could have to put restrictions on money transfers and withdrawals to prevent panicked depositors from withdrawing their money in droves and bringing down the banking system. If, under such a scenario, Greece doesn't get any more help from its creditors, it could have to eventually abandon the euro so that it can print its own money and get its financial system going again.
So far, the government's has said it intends to honor all its domestic and international financial commitments. But some officials say it would need a bailout deal to be able to pay the IMF on June 5.
___
IF GREECE GETS THE 7.2 BILLION, HOW LONG WILL IT LAST?
Not more than a few months.
Beyond the 1.6 billion euros it owes the IMF in June, it owes a total of 6 billion euros to creditors in July, and another 3 billion euros to the ECB in August, according to Angus Campbell, senior analyst at FXPro. "This is going to be a long drawn out summer," he said.
This year Greece faces massive debt repayments  the most it has to deal with in a single year for the next four decades. The total amount for 2015, including treasury bills, reaches a total of about 30 billion euros, small amounts of which have already been repaid.
___
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN THAT MONEY RUNS OUT?
It is almost certain that Greece will need more financial help once the 7.2 billion euros are paid. What that will be is a matter of contention and speculation. Greece had long called for debt forgiveness for at least part of what it owes. In 2012, Greece restructured the debt held by private investors, with bondholders  including many Greek pension funds  seeing their holdings lose about three quarters of their value.
But talk of a third bailout for Greece is unpopular in Europe, where states have sunk billions of euros into the country in the form of cheap bailout loans. Countries like Spain, which have gone through economic trouble of their own, are loathe to write off billions in loans they gave to Greece.
Greece argues it doesn't want a third package of bailout loans but wants to discuss a "growth pact" that would see the country's economy return to growth and Greece stand on its own two feet again.
___
WHAT ARE THE STICKING POINTS IN THE TALKS?
The sticking points in the current negotiations appear to include labor issues, with Athens insisting it will not cut salaries and pensions any further and creditors saying it must reform its labor market. Another bone of contention seems to be how much of a primary surplus  the budget balance without debt repayments  Greece must produce in the next few years.
Greece also says it wants a deal on the 7.2 billion euros to be tied to a deal to help it financially after that money runs out.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
