<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="scrippsobfeeds">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:45:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Reporter learns how tough it is to be a cop</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/only-a-simulation-but-real-enough-for-reporter_34574429</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Only a simulation, but real enough for reporter
Kristine Gill
Naples Daily News reporter Kristine Gill participates in a Collier County Sheriff's Office training scenarios in Naples.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
Naples, Fla. - Sgt. Fletch Fuller zipped through a Power Point at breakneck speed, handed me a fake gun and said Youre hired.
Full story available to subscribers only.
Share Article
Subscribe to the Naples Daily News
Ready to subscribe to the Naples Daily News? Choose between a Premium or Digital subscription below.
Need Help? Call us at 1-888-878-6842.
Monday-Friday: 6am-6pm / Saturday: 7am-3pm / Sunday: 7am-2pm
Comments
Want to participate in the conversation? Log in or become a subscriber today.  Subscribers can read and comment on any story, anytime.  Non-subscribers will only be able to view comments on select stories.
Trending stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:45:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Collier charter deals with diversity questions</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/education/one-of-colliers-top-schools-drawing-criticism-for-its-racial-makeup_00100215</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
Collier Countys newest charter school, founded by two sitting school board members, has recently fielded attacks from people who say the school isnt diverse enough  and drawn passionate defenses from its leaders who say theyve done everything is their power to attract minority families.
At a school board meeting earlier this month, Collier resident Theron Trimble referred to the school as Mason Classical Academy for Middle Class White Students.
Local Republican politician Byron Donalds, who serves on the academys board, was sitting in the audience, waiting for his turn to defend the school from attacks he says are politically motivated.
Were sitting here in the Martin Luther King Administrative Building and I know Martin Luther King would not tolerate vicious and racist remarks, said Donalds, who is the husband of School Board member Erika Donalds. I do have a problem when there are racist remarks that are going to be levied against a school that I helped to create.
State law and contracts with the school district require that charter schools reflect the racial and ethnic demographics of the community they serve or of other schools in the district.
On Airport Pulling Road just south of Golden Gate Parkway, Mason Classical Academy teaches a student body that is 79 percent white, 14 percent Hispanic and 1 percent black. Mason Classical serves the highest percentage of white students in the county compared to other public and charter schools.
Collier County public schools are 36 percent white, 48 percent Hispanic and 12 percent black. A look at the demographics of the greater Naples area, Mason Classical Academys target population, paints a community that is 69 percent white, 22 percent Hispanic and 7 percent black.
Since Kelly Lichter and Erika Donalds got elected to the school board, the school they founded has faced tough scrutiny from the community  even in the midst of success.
Earlier this month, Mason Classical Academy outperformed every other school in the district when only 2 percent of its students landed in the list of Floridas low-performing third graders in the states reading and language arts exam. The district average was 20 percent.
Its critics say its not that the school is fighting and succeeding against the achievement gap  the fact that poor minority students still perform below their middle class white peers  but instead benefiting from it. Its defenders say the school has done everything within its means to create a diverse student body and that the critiques are politically driven.
This year in Collier County, this is what the achievement gap looks like: nearly all of the 15 schools with more low-performing third graders than the district average are also the schools with highest number of students receiving free and reduced lunches and the highest number of minority students.
It perpetuates the problem that we have in our society that still has certain amounts of segregation, said David Goldstein, a founder of the Coalition for Quality Public Education, a newly-created group which has criticized both Lichter and Erika Donalds.
Other schools have found a way to do it, he said of reflecting the communitys racial balance in their student populations.
Less than a mile away from Mason Classical Academy, on the other side of the street, Gulf Coast Charter Academys racial makeup more closely reflects that of the school district.
At this charter  for now the only other charter school that serves the greater Naples area  less than half of the student body is white, 34 percent are Hispanic and 15 percent are black.
The three other charters in Collier County serve niche communities and have student bodies that reflect those demographics: Immokalee Community School serves mostly Hispanics.
Marco Island Academys student body is 75 percent white, 20 percent Hispanic and 2 percent black; Marco Charter Middles student body is 63 percent white, 28 percent Hispanic and 4 percent black. The city of Marco Island is 90 percent white, 7 percent Hispanic and less than one percent black, according to 2013 census data.
In Florida, other school districts are grappling with racial imbalance in some of their charter schools. In Polk County, the school board denied a charters application to increase enrollment last month because of the schools racial imbalance.
At Polk Pre-Collegiate Academy, 81 percent of students are white, 11 percent are Hispanic and 4 percent are black. That school districts make up is 43 percent white, 31 percent Hispanic and 21 percent black. That school district has said it will issue a corrective action plan for that school, reports the Lakeland Ledger.
Lichter says that from the beginning, Mason Classical Academy leaders have made efforts to attract minority and low-income students. When the school began to actively recruit, founders held an informational meeting in Golden Gate City, which has a large Hispanic population, and more than 250 people showed.
Our meeting at Golden Gate City had the largest showing, Lichter said. It wasnt just in the white neighborhoods that we were having these meetings.
While Mason Classical Academy has attracted some students from that community, Erika Donalds said many who showed interest are limited because of transportation.
Mason Classical Academy, unlike Gulf Coast Academy and both charters in Marco Island, does not offer busing or any other form of transportation. Parents who choose to send their children to Mason Classical Academy must drop them off and pick them up.
David Hull, the schools principal, said the he has been working on ways to provide transportation, but right now, the school simply doesnt have the funds  even with partial reimbursement from the state for transportation costs.
Lichter said that another impediment are repeated denials from the district to lease the services to Mason Classical Academy.
In an email from late April provided to the Naples Daily News by the district, charter school coordinator Janice Messer told Hull that the district does not currently have the capacity in rolling stock or personnel to do this.
Both schools in Marco Island contract with the district for bus service, paying $1.70 per mile and around $30 per driver, per hour. Gulf Coast Academy purchased surplus buses from the district.
Messer said Collier Schools could provide some assistance in mapping routes and other logistics as part of the administrative assistance charter schools get from the district from the 5 percent fee they pay.
Lichter and Hull said theyll continue to explore ways to bring transportation, but say Mason Classical Academy, like other charters, is underfunded by the state and is constantly pinching pennies.
If these people want to see more minorities at our school, great. But they dont want to give up a penny for our charter school, Lichter said.
Beyond those efforts, school leaders say their hands are tied. They argue that Mason Classical Academy is a school of choice and all students are selected through a blind lottery.
We have minorities in our school but does it reflect the demographics of the county? No. At the end of the day, if people choose not to enroll their child, theres not much we can do, Byron Donalds said. At the end of the day, all you can do as a charter is market yourself to the community.

Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:30:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Records show housing authority diverted funds</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-government/records-show-housing-authority-diverted-funds_76226671</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Records show housing authority diverted funds
Maria Perez
local government
Esmeralda "Essie" Serrata
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
The Collier County Housing Authority, which spent funds earmarked for a federal housing project to pay for costs of an independent, mostly empty, housing subdivision, also diverted funds from the federal program to keep up a rental dormitory for single farmworkers in Immokalee, authority records show.
The public entity spent more than $530,000 obtained from renting 365 affordable homes financed by the U.S. Department of Agriculture to cover costs of operating the dormitory, Horizon Village, from 2010 through 2014, according to the authoritys financial documents. The 192-bed dormitory, which should be self-sustaining, lost money from 2010 through 2013.
Michael Botelho, USDA Rural Development area director, said revenues from their Rural Development program homes, which the housing authority rents to low-income farmworkers, can only be used to pay for costs that will show a benefit for the property residents.
The more than $500,000 diverted to Horizon Village is in addition to about $350,000 that, according to the authoritys preliminary estimates, were spent inappropriately out of the federal program to pay for costs of managing an independent group of 276 affordable homes in the fiscal year ended in September 2014.
The housing authority programs balances summary for fiscal year 2014 showed the amount owed by Horizon to the USDA program.
Esmeralda Serrata, the housing authoritys executive director for almost 13 years, was fired on May 26, after the USDA raised concerns about the expenses declared by the authority for its Rural Development program and requested more information.
The housing authority, an independent entity whose board members are appointed by the governor, manages affordable housing programs in the county, mostly funded by other public agencies, like USDA or the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, also known as HUD.
Farm Worker Village, which includes both USDA financed housing and the 276 independent affordable homes the authority rents, is the largest affordable rental housing community in Immokalee.
William McDaniel, chairman of the housing authoritys board of commissioners, said board members were aware that the Horizon Village program owed money to the Rural Development program, but didnt know that the expenditures were inappropriate. He said they were assured the funds would be repaid to the program when the authority sells the dormitory, if they get the authorization to do so.
McDaniel said their auditor never signaled anything wrong with the payments and Serrata never told them they were breaking USDA regulations.
We had an executive director who theoretically was very familiar with programs, rules, what can be done ...  McDaniel said.
Serrata couldnt be reached for comment on Friday.
Botelho said the auditor should have reported the inappropriate expenditures to cover costs of the independent operation.
Horizon Village opened in 2004 to offer single low-income farmworkers an affordable, better housing option than the cramped trailers where many live in Immokalee.
The initial $3.2 million grant for Horizon Village came from a $20 million emergency appropriation to the USDA. The appropriation followed a 30-day hunger strike by farmworkers in Immokalee that began in late 1997 and brought national attention their demands for higher pay and more affordable housing.
The state of Florida received $9.2 million of that money, and more than a third went to the dormitory.
The dormitory had total operating loses of over $290,000 from 2010 through 2013, but its operating income was positive  $7,011  in 2014.
The housing authority signed a sales contract in 2011 with Pacific Tomato Growers to sell the property for $1.6 million, about a third of what it cost to build it. The housing authority received $3.7 million in grants, and obtained a $228,000 state loan and a $500,000 private loan to build the facility, according to the housing authoritys documents. The premises current tax value is $2.2 million.
To sell the property without having to pay back the grants, the housing authority needs the approval of USDA and the Florida Department of Economic Opportunity.
McDaniel said Horizon Village operation had been losing money for many years. He said after three new board members were appointed  in 2013  the board became more active, met more frequently, and gave more direction. Horizon started to earn money, he said.
Financial documents from the housing authority show the local agency used an account where it deposited revenues of USDA financed housing  mainly tenants rents and USDA rental assistance to tenants who qualified  as a general operating account for the whole organization.
That account paid not only for the federal program costs, but also for common expenses of the authoritys different programs, and costs exclusive of other programs, such as salaries of employees who didnt work for the USDA housing program.
The revenues of the other authoritys operations, such as those that came from the management of the Section 8 federal program or the dormitory were kept in separate accounts. They had to reimburse the USDA program account for their expenses.
But Horizon Village account underpaid the USDA program operating account from fiscal year 2011 through fiscal year 2014, when the amount owed reached $530,826 in September 2014. Since then, the balance continued growing until May 31, a few days after Serrata was fired, when Horizon made a payment of $90,000 that got the balance down to $526,158.
Horizon also owed $30,412 to an educational nonprofit owned by the authority.
Botelho said the housing authority shouldnt be paying expenses unrelated to the program, such as salaries of employees who dont work for the federally-financed housing project, out of the general account for the USDA program, even they are later reimbursed.
He said the authority should have a general operating account for common expenses that cannot be separated, such as liability insurance, and every program should pay its prorated share of the costs.
The housing authority also kept paying costs of its independent housing operation, including its employees salaries, with the federal program funds after September 2014, according to the authoritys accounting documents and bills.
Meanwhile the organization spent $27,365 in February from revenues from that separate subsidized operation to buy a 2015 Ford Explorer to replace Serratas 2002 car, which she could use for personal purposes according to her contract.
In 2012, USDA had refused to allow the housing authority to retrieve USDA reserve funds to buy Serrata a new car.
It is unreasonable, atypical, unnecessary and does not provide a clear benefit to the residents for the project to provide the Executive Director with a vehicle to oversee the management of a 315 unit project, said a USDA letter signed by Botelho.
McDaniel said board members always thought expenses were being prorated adequately. He said the housing authority staff and fee accountant are now analyzing now how much was spent inappropriately and they may hire an external auditor to check that the amounts are correct.
Botelho said USDA will require more frequent budgets and reports from the housing authority and may require a third party auditor or the Office of the Inspector General to review the authoritys records.
---
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 04:02:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Aging with HIV presents challenges</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/health/as-people-with-hiv-live-longer-aging-presents-challenges_09953332</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>As people with HIV live longer, aging presents challenges
Lolly Bowean Chicago Tribune (TNS)
9:02 PM, Jun 27, 2015
Previous
Next
Greg Sanchez, who has been living with HIV for 30 years, displays his many medications stored in the bedroom of his Chicago home on Wednesday, June 3, 2015. Only one pill is for HIV; the rest are for conditions brought on by aging with the virus and years of taking medications to treat it, he says. (Antonio Perez/Chicago Tribune/TNS)
Antonio Perez
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Roy Ferguson, 63, who has lived with HIV for 18 years, is pictured at his Brookfield, Ill., home on Thursday, June 11, 2015. (Antonio Perez/Chicago Tribune/TNS)
Antonio Perez
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Several containers of medication are laid out beside the bed of Greg Sanchez, who has been living with HIV for 30 years, on Wednesday, June 3, 2015. (Antonio Perez/Chicago Tribune/TNS)
Antonio Perez
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
CHICAGO  Its been 30 years since Greg Sanchez was diagnosed with HIV, the human immunodeficiency virus that causes AIDS, and he keeps his more than two dozen bottles of pills and other medications on his wooden nightstand so he can get to them easily.
But he takes only a single pill for HIV. The rest of his prescriptions, a crowd of white-topped orange plastic bottles, are to treat the many ailments and conditions that he says are a result of aging with the virus, along with years of taking the sometimes toxic medications to treat it.
At 50, Sanchez has coronary artery disease, fibromyalgia and arthritis, among other illnesses. He suffers chronic pain in his knees and back and walks with a cane because of vertigo and neuropathy. Advancing bone disease has left him in need of hip surgery.
Im grateful to still be alive, but my body is probably about 20 years older than I actually am, said Sanchez, who lives in an apartment in Chicagos Rogers Park neighborhood filled with plants and photographs of loved ones. Im going to the doctors constantly. Sometimes its hard to put my finger on if it is the HIV, or if its just getting older.
Sometimes I feel like an old man.
In the decades since HIV emerged, it has evolved from a diagnosis with an almost certain death sentence to a chronic illness, one that medical advances have made manageable and less urgent. Now, those diagnosed while relatively young have lived into middle age and even longer with the disease. In some cases, they have lived with HIV for more than a quarter-century.
As these long-term survivors get older, though, some are finding their bodies wearing out, their internal organs battered by potent and sometimes toxic medications, the devastatingly permanent conditions that come with aging leaving their mark a lot faster.
Statistics suggest that more and more HIV and AIDS patients will experience aging that way, and that the urgency over the diseases killing prowess will give way to how it slowly takes a different toll on its patients. According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 26 percent of the estimated 1.2 million people living with HIV in 2011 were 55 or older. In 2013, 27 percent of the estimated 26,688 new AIDS diagnoses were in people 50 and older.
Those demographic changes are forcing a new conversation among health care professionals about how patients manage HIV and the other illnesses that come with growing older. Indeed, this is the first group to live so long with the virus, offering a first glimpse of what it is like to grow old with the disease, as well as a first test for doctors for how to treat it.
Some in that group are men like Sanchez, who was diagnosed in 1985, when the condition was far more deadly. The rest may have contracted the disease later in life. Either way, the inflammation HIV causes makes the body work harder and show symptoms of aging faster.
Few studies have examined age-related health problems among HIV patients and how to slow what looks like an accelerated aging process. One study at the University of California, Los Angeles suggests that HIV-positive blood samples showed signs of aging 14 years faster than the blood of healthy individuals. But researchers examining those samples still have more work to do to determine why, said Tammy Rickabaugh, an assistant researcher with the project at the schools AIDS Institute and Center for AIDS Research.
We definitely see from studies that HIV-infected people tend to have clinical conditions earlier: frailty, diabetes, high blood pressure, she said. Whats difficult to tease out is how much of that is because of the virus and how much of that is from drug treatment. We know the drugs have some effects.
At the Howard Brown Health Center, on Chicagos North Side, doctors and other health care providers have begun counseling young HIV patients on heart disease, diabetes, kidney and liver disease and cancers and are testing them for those conditions earlier. They advise them that if they overcome HIV, other issues are likely to arise, said Dr. Magda Houlberg, a chief clinical officer, internal medicine physician and geriatric expert at Howard Brown.
Some patients are exhausted because they have experienced chronic illness for so long and now they are growing old, Houlberg said. They think, Wow, this doesnt go away. I have all these other new things and I can only expect more things to come.
Roy Ferguson, 63, has lived with HIV for 18 years.
Three times, he was near death with pneumonia. In 2011, he went to the Hines VA Hospital thinking he would die, he said. Instead, he made it through the crisis.
Then it became clear that I was going to live, not die, he said. I thought, Now what do I do with myself? 
Ferguson worked for years as a field service technician installing equipment until he was downsized. He has emerged as an activist pushing for better access to medication and research for people infected with HIV. These days, he sticks with a disciplined two-hour workout regimen of pushups, squats and bench presses and can be obsessive about his diet. To keep an upbeat disposition, he works with HIV-positive military veterans and volunteers with the AIDS Foundation of Chicago.
Unlike Sanchez, he takes only five pills a day, three of them to manage HIV.
It helps to think of the benefits of aging, instead of giving in to fear, he said. Now Im prepared to live.
Its not just the physical problems that make aging with HIV a challenge. There is also a psychological toll: the guilt from having survived when so many others died. There is a fatigue, too, that can set in from dealing with so many ailments and taking so much medication.
Then there are those who didnt financially prepare because they didnt expect to live long enough to retire. Others find themselves debt-ridden from medical bills.
Even as an educator on HIV and aging who talks about the issue often, Brian Bongner said its different living through it. He was diagnosed in 1987, took medications that possibly damaged his organs and watched dozens of his friends succumb to AIDS-related illnesses.
I was told three different times by doctors that I would not go home from the hospital, he said. I was told I would never see 23.
Now, at 47, he finds purpose in teaching about the condition.
You feel isolated, Bongner said at a recent training session, speaking to leaders from agencies that work with HIV-positive clients. You dont want your friends to see you sick. You dont want to go to the doctor and be told youre dying from something else. Your organs are already damaged by HIV, then theres the medication to treat it, then theres the aging. At one point we didnt have an aging HIV-positive population. Now we have 85-year-olds coming through the door.
Sanchez tries to strategize to overcome his limitations. He has a home health aide who helps him with cooking and other basic tasks. He records reminders of things he has to do and sets his phone alarm so he wont forget when to take his medications.
I try to take the bulk of my meds at night so Im better during the day, he said. I have to gauge my energy level.
Sanchez was only 19 when he learned he was HIV positive. The first thing he did was cash out his life insurance policy, thinking it would never mature. It took him seven years and nearly dying to come to terms with it and begin taking medication.
But while he pushes to rehabilitate, he lives from one health crisis to another. Some weeks, he is at the doctors office two to three times. He keeps handy a neat, typewritten list of all his ailments and medications so he can let doctors know what hes taking.
He often reads about men his age who also have HIV but who are more robust and active.
But thats not his life.
He misses out on music festivals because he cant stand for long periods of time. Going to dinner is arduous because of his diet restrictions. Alcohol doesnt mix well with his medications. His aches and pains make being social tough.
He spends a lot of time alone.
They show pictures of men climbing mountains, running marathons and conquering the world, he said of some of the magazines he reads. I feel Im not represented. Our community wants us to be a certain way, and when were not, we are isolated.
Tribune News Service
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 05:42:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Search called off for U.S. Olympic sailor</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/searchers-still-looking-for-missing-olympic-sailor-trevor-moore-off-miami_86242829</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Search suspended for missing Olympic sailor Trevor Moore off Miami
Eric Staats
8:48 PM, Jun 27, 2015
10:48 PM, Jun 27, 2015
top stories | local news
Scott McIntyre
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
NAPLES, Fla. - The U.S. Coast Guard suspended the search Saturday at sunset for a U.S. Olympic sailor with ties to Naples.
Full story available to subscribers only.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:45:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Motorcyclist killed on I-75 ramp to RSW</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/fort-myers-motorcyclist-killed-in-crash-on-i75-ramp-to-southwest-florida-international-airport_58380918</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Share Article
Subscribe to the Naples Daily News
Ready to subscribe to the Naples Daily News? Choose between a Premium or Digital subscription below.
Need Help? Call us at 1-888-878-6842.
Monday-Friday: 6am-6pm / Saturday: 7am-3pm / Sunday: 7am-2pm
Comments
Want to participate in the conversation? Log in or become a subscriber today.  Subscribers can read and comment on any story, anytime.  Non-subscribers will only be able to view comments on select stories.
Trending stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:48:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Southwest Florida hams have a field day</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/southwest-florida-hams-hone-their-emergency-skills-at-annual-naples-field-day_22772790</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Southwest Florida hams hone their emergency skills at annual Naples field day
Hanna Marcus
6:48 PM, Jun 27, 2015
7:35 PM, Jun 27, 2015
top stories | local news
Ken Bills puts on his headset at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
Bruce Funsteon talks on his radio at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
Dave Ducett looks at the 10-meter band radio at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
Bill Reynolds, left, and Mark Harms work on setting up their radio and computer at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
Ken Bills cranks a 10-meter band antenna into the air at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
Ken Bills checks over the antenna before raising it into the air at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
Uli Altvater helps stabilize a 10-meter band antenna as it is raised into the air at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
Frank Halas watches as the 10-meter band antenna is raised into the air at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
Bill Reynolds, left, and Mark Harms work on setting up their radio and computer at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
A radio transceiver at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
Members set up their computer and radio at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
Jerry Smith talks on his radio as Bruce Funsteon looks at his computer at the Amateur Radio Association of Southwest Florida annual field day at the American Red Cross in Naples, Florida, on Saturday, June 27, 2015. The field day is a day to test emergency radio equipment and to practice emergency communications. (Calvin Mattheis/Staff)
Calvin Mattheis
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:32:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Everglades City: First for the Fourth of July</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/little-everglades-city-gets-a-jump-on-fourth-of-july-with-big-dose-of-americana_77827727</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Little Everglades City gets a jump on Fourth of July with big dose of Americana
Jordan Littman
6:32 PM, Jun 27, 2015
6:42 PM, Jun 27, 2015
top stories | local news
Ava Klingbeil, 7, from center left, Kaylee Harris, 6, and Mia Malicoate, 5, wait for results in the Firecracker Pageant on Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Jan House holds her cousin Kingston Robinson, 3, as they wave to passing parade participants Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Makenna Ames, 6, enjoys watermelon Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Parade participants pedal, passing patrons Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Re-enactors from left, Tom Geffert, Eric Smith, Lori Smith and Dolly Geffert watch as a parade passes in front of City Hall on Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Children play in a bounce house Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Martha Daniels adjusts a cupcake during a bake sale Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Kaydence Freeman, 2, clings to her trophy while being held by her father, Travis, in the under-3-year-old category of the Firecracker Pageant Saturday, June 27, 2015 in downtown Everglades City, Fla. Kaydence placed first, a second win for her, the first coming in 2013. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Red Boy, a 5 year-old bichon fris is seen at the feet of his owner, Clare Dana on Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Carol Foss drives a golf cart as patrons look on Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
In a red hat, Noella ODonnell, from left, her daughter, Katie, 4, and mother, Jenny Johns, looks on as paradegoers pass Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Clinging to a rebel battle flag, Augustus Demere, 13 months, is escorted by his mother, Patty, as they kick of the Firecracker Pageant Saturday, June 27, 2015 in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars &amp; Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off July 4th festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Deborah Trujillo creates bubbles adorned with oversized shades Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Dottie Joiner, center, shows her grandson Rocco Campbell, 2, passing parade members as Sophia Campbell, 9, and son-in-law Bob Campbell, look on Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Clinging to a first place trophy for small dogs, Clare Dana, pets her bichon friss Red Boy and Julep, bottom, on Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Diana Curry talks with friends adorned with patriotic apparel Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Patrons pick up candy thrown from floats Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Confetti litters the street after a parade Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Alexis Alaya, 10, left, has her face painted by Jennifer Perry on Saturday, June 27, 2015, in downtown Everglades City, Fla. A few hundred came to celebrate Independence Day with a Stars and Stripes-themed patriotic parade, food, contest, prizes and more. Historically the town is the first in Collier County to kick off Fourth of July festivities. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 00:30:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charleston suspect's life a troubled road</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/charleston-suspects-life-a-troubled-road-to-radicalization</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Charleston suspect's life a troubled road to radicalization
MITCH WEISS &amp; JOHN MONE, Associated Press
5:30 PM, Jun 27, 2015
Previous
Next
This undated file image that appeared on Lastrhodesian.com, a website being investigated by the FBI in connection with Charleston, S.C., shooting suspect Dylann Roof, shows Roof posing for a photo while holding a Confederate flag. Roof is accused of killing nine people inside Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston on June 17. (Lastrhodesian.com via AP, File)
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
FILE - In this June 18, 2015 file photo, Charleston, S.C., shooting suspect Dylann Storm Roof, center, is escorted from the Sheby Police Department in Shelby, N.C. Roof is accused of killing nine people inside Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston on June 17. (AP Photo/Chuck Burton)
Chuck Burton
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
CHAPIN, S.C. - The people who know Dylann Storm Roof  the people who watched his progression from a sweet child to a disturbed man  are struggling with guilt. How could they have missed the signs? Could they have done something to prevent the deaths of nine innocents at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church?
How did it all happen?
Roof himself offers no answers. He sits in North Charleston's Sheriff Al Cannon Detention Center, charged with the murders, his $1 million bail far beyond reach.
But talk to his friends and family, and a portrait emerges of a troubled and confused 21-year-old, often drunk and occasionally threatening violence as he alternated between partying with black friends and spouting white power slogans to white friends. Court documents and nearly two dozen interviews show Roof's early childhood was troubled and confused as well, as he grew up in an unstable, broken home amid allegations of marital abuse and infidelity.
He apparently fell under the thrall of racist websites. But how and why are questions that remain unanswered.
As a 4-year-old, "He was so sweet and bright," recalls Patricia Hastings, who was once his step-grandmother.
Seventeen years later, she is among many who are trying to figure out what happened to Dylann Roof.
___
There is little dispute his childhood was difficult.
Franklin Bennett Roof was a 25-year-old carpenter working for a home construction company, when he met 29-year-old Amelia "Amy" Cowles, a recent divorcee, barely 5-feet tall with blonde hair to her ankles. He was the son of a prominent Columbia attorney; she was a bartender at the Silver Fox. They married in 1988 and had a daughter, Amber, four months later.
They separated in 1990, and divorced a year later. A few years later they briefly reconciled, but split again before Dylann was born on April 3, 1994.
Four years later, Franklin Roof married Paige Hastings.
In an affidavit filed in her 2009 divorce, Paige said she became a surrogate mother for the children: "I raised his kids from a very young age, took them to all of their activities."
Patricia Hastings said her daughter loved Dylann and Amber "unconditionally as her own." She said Amy Roof would leave them in Paige's care with little notice, even though Paige had her own new baby, their half-sister Morgan.
Paige cut Dylann's hair in the bowl cut he still wears; she took Amber to college orientation because "both parents were unavailable," Paige's friend Leslie McArver wrote in an affidavit.
As he grew, Dylann exhibited obsessive compulsive behavior, Hastings said. He would obsess over germs, and insisted on having his hair cut in that same style, Hastings said.
Still, he played video games, interacted with the family, attended church and Bible camp.
But things grew stressful at home. Money was a problem so Paige took a part time job. Franklin Roof was often out of town.
Franklin Roof was verbally abusive, Paige's friend Carol Elliott wrote in an affidavit.
After Paige filed for divorce, Franklin Roof hired a private investigator to shadow her, revealing she was having an affair, according to the court documents.
The divorce was granted in 2009. Hastings recalls that her daughter told her she felt guilty leaving Dylann.
Paige has remarried; her last name is now Mann.
___
Roof began having trouble in school. He failed the ninth grade twice, then dropped out for good in 2010.
People around him worried about his lack of direction. He was spending too much time in his room in front of the computer. They pushed him to get a job, but he was unhappy, his friends said.
Over the past year, Roof became increasingly unhinged.
In February, worried employees at a Columbia shopping mall called the police when Roof, dressed in black, asked them suspicious questions about when stores closed and when they left for the night, according to court records. He was arrested on a misdemeanor charge of possessing the drug Suboxone.
In March, a police officer searched his car and found six empty 40-round magazines for an AR-15 assault rifle, according to a police report. Roof said he was saving up to buy an AR-15, the report said.
In April, he was arrested again on a charge of trespassing at the mall, where he'd been banned.
He had become a recluse. He never responded to an invitation to Amber's wedding  which had been planned for last weekend but was postponed after the massacre. He also appears to have begun a journey into the world of Internet hate sites, according to the Southern Poverty Law Center, which tracks those sites.
"If you don't have much of a social life in the real world, this is a way for you to interact with other individuals and be affirmed and encouraged," said Keegan Hanks, of the Southern Poverty Law Center.
Roof appeared to be "AryanBlood1488," who began posting on the white supremacist site the Daily Stormer in August, Hanks said. Over several months, "AryanBlood1488" described how he typed "black on white crime" into a Google search, found the Council of Conservative Citizens site and descended into radicalism from there.
Kyle Rogers, a member of the Council of Conservative Citizens who lives in Summerville, South Carolina, denied Roof had any direct dealings with the group.
On Feb. 9, according to Internet records, someone using Roof's name, address and phone number registered a new website. On it, were photos of Roof at a Confederate cemetery, brandishing a gun, burning the American flag and spitting on it. The site also contained a manifesto explaining an indoctrination into radical racism.
On his 21st birthday in April, Roof bought himself a present: a .45-caliber Glock semi-automatic handgun with a high-point laser for accuracy.
___
Paige refused to talk to AP, as did Franklin and Amy Roof.
Mann had barely seen her former stepson since her nasty divorce. But last month, when she went to pick up her daughter at her ex-husband's house, he was there.
According to Patricia Hastings, recounting recent conversations with her daughter, Roof was quieter than he used to be; he looked distant, lost. He was no longer the sweet blond kid she helped raise for nearly a decade. As she was getting ready to leave, Roof, not one for affection, hugged her tight.
"It was like he was saying goodbye," Hastings said.
The next time Mann saw him, it was on television as the man accused of the killings.
Roof's friend Joseph Meek said he too is replaying, reinterpreting, his memories of Roof over the last months.
"I just wish he would have talked to me. I wish he would have told me what was bothering him. I would have done something. This will stay with me, with all of us," he said.
___
Associated Press writer Meg Kinnard contributed to this report

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 00:27:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Four men arrested on drug charges at Naples home</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/naples-police-arrest-four-men-on-drug-charges-at-royal-palm-drive-home_79116899</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Naples police arrest four men on drug charges at Royal Palm Drive home
5:27 PM, Jun 27, 2015
6:01 PM, Jun 27, 2015
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
AnesFrljuckic
NAPLES, Fla. - Naples police arrested four men Friday in a Naples home on drug charges.
Full story available to subscribers only.
Share Article
Subscribe to the Naples Daily News
Ready to subscribe to the Naples Daily News? Choose between a Premium or Digital subscription below.
Need Help? Call us at 1-888-878-6842.
Monday-Friday: 6am-6pm / Saturday: 7am-3pm / Sunday: 7am-2pm
Comments
Want to participate in the conversation? Log in or become a subscriber today.  Subscribers can read and comment on any story, anytime.  Non-subscribers will only be able to view comments on select stories.
Trending stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 00:06:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Black bear crashes college party, gets collared</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/watercooler/black-bear-crashes-college-party-gets-collared</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Black bear crashes college party, gets collared
Associated Press
5:06 PM, Jun 27, 2015
An example of a black bear.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
BETHLEHEM, Pa. - A college party got a little wilder than expected when a black bear showed up.
Authorities say the bear crashed the party early Saturday near the campus of Lehigh University, about 50 miles north of Philadelphia.
Emergency officials received a flood of 911 calls after the 300- to 400-pound black bear was seen in south Bethlehem.
Police chief Mark DiLuzio says the bear "lumbered close to the party and scared the living daylights out of people."
Lehigh University said on its website that the bear was captured, tranquilized and removed from the area a couple hours later.
DiLuzio said it was the same bear seen Friday near the university's athletic facilities.
Pennsylvania Game Commission district officer Tyler Krieder says the bear came from New Jersey and probably swam across the Delaware River.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:57:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Communications lag rattles relatives after crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/communications-lag-rattles-relatives-after-alaska-crash</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Communications lag rattles relatives after Alaska crash
BECKY BOHRER, Associated Press
4:57 PM, Jun 27, 2015
The Holland America Line cruise ship Westerdam sits in dock in Ketchikan, Alaska, on Thursday, June 25, 2015. Officials say eight passengers on an excursion off the ship and a pilot were in a plane that was found crashed against the granite rock face of a cliff about 20 miles northeast of Ketchikan, Alaska. All nine people aboard died in the crash, authorities said. (Taylor Balkom/Ketchikan Daily News via AP).
Taylor Balkram
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
JUNEAU, Alaska - Rowland Cheney of Lodi, California, was one of nine victims in a sightseeing plane crash in Alaska.
Alaska State Troopers originally identified the 71-year-old man as Hal Cheney.
The DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop went down Thursday in Misty Fjords National Monument near Ketchikan in southeast Alaska. The shore excursion was sold through Holland America.
Eight passengers from the Holland America Line ship Westerdam and a pilot died.
The other victims are Mary Doucette, 59, of Lodi; Glenda Cambiaso, 31, and Hugo Cambiaso, 65, of North Potomac, Maryland; June Kranenburg, 73, and Leonard Kranenburg, 63, of Medford, Oregon; Margie Apodaca, 63, and Raymond Apodaca, 70, of Sparks, Nevada; and the pilot, Bryan Krill, 64, of Hope, Idaho.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:11:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Authorities ID man in Lehigh Acres homicide</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/authorities-id-man-in-lehigh-acres-homicide</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Authorities ID man in Lehigh Acres homicide
4:11 PM, Jun 27, 2015
Copyright 2014 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
LEHIGH ACRES, Fla. - Lee deputies have identified a man who was found dead at a Lehigh Acres home early Friday morning.
Full story available to subscribers only.
Share Article
Subscribe to the Naples Daily News
Ready to subscribe to the Naples Daily News? Choose between a Premium or Digital subscription below.
Need Help? Call us at 1-888-878-6842.
Monday-Friday: 6am-6pm / Saturday: 7am-3pm / Sunday: 7am-2pm
Comments
Want to participate in the conversation? Log in or become a subscriber today.  Subscribers can read and comment on any story, anytime.  Non-subscribers will only be able to view comments on select stories.
Trending stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:00:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Signed, sealed, delivered</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/naples-group-packs-its-70th-ton-of-supplies-to-ship-to-overseas-troops_65946111</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Naples group packs its 70th ton of supplies to ship to overseas troops
Hanna Marcus
3:00 PM, Jun 27, 2015
4:33 PM, Jun 27, 2015
Previous
Next
NAPLES, Fla. - With a U.S. regulation bugle pressed to his lips, 91-year-old Bob McDonald took a breath and sounded out Reveille.
Full story available to subscribers only.
Subscribe to the Naples Daily News
Ready to subscribe to the Naples Daily News? Choose between a Premium or Digital subscription below.
Need Help? Call us at 1-888-878-6842.
Monday-Friday: 6am-6pm / Saturday: 7am-3pm / Sunday: 7am-2pm
Comments
Want to participate in the conversation? Log in or become a subscriber today.  Subscribers can read and comment on any story, anytime.  Non-subscribers will only be able to view comments on select stories.
Trending stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:21:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two dead in fatal Lee County crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/lehigh-acres-crash-kills-two-cape-coral-residents_79620698</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Lehigh Acres crash kills two Cape Coral residents
2:21 PM, Jun 27, 2015
2:30 PM, Jun 27, 2015
Copyright 2014 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
LEHIGH ACRES, Fla. - Two Cape Coral residents died Friday afternoon in a crash in Lehigh Acres, the Florida Highway Patrol reported.
Full story available to subscribers only.
Share Article
Subscribe to the Naples Daily News
Ready to subscribe to the Naples Daily News? Choose between a Premium or Digital subscription below.
Need Help? Call us at 1-888-878-6842.
Monday-Friday: 6am-6pm / Saturday: 7am-3pm / Sunday: 7am-2pm
Comments
Want to participate in the conversation? Log in or become a subscriber today.  Subscribers can read and comment on any story, anytime.  Non-subscribers will only be able to view comments on select stories.
Trending stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
