<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="scrippsobfeeds">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 05:12:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Scripps National Spelling Bee co-champs crowned</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/scripps-national-spelling-bee-champion-crowned</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Next
Co-champions, back to back.
The Scripps National Spelling Bee finals rapidly boiled down to two experienced spellers on the last year of their eligibility. As in last year, there weren't enough words on the list to separate them.
Vanya Shivashankar, 13, from Olathe, Kansas was trying for the fifth and final chance to win. Her sister Kavya won in 2009. She is in eighth grade at California Trail Middle School.
Gokul Venkatachalam, 14, from St. Louis, Missouri, won on his third try. He finished third last year just behind co-champions AnsunSujue and SriramHathwar. Venkatachalamis in eighth grade at Parkway West Middle School, Chesterfield, Missouri.
Gokul, who got the last word, didn't hesitate. It was "nunatak."
Gavin Stern is a national digital producer for the Scripps National Desk.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:48:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Everglades City seniors take last walk together</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/education/everglades-city-seniors-take-a-last-walk-together_04633290</Link>
        <Description>Savannah Oglesby will line up with the other seniors at Everglades City School as they collect their diplomas, much like they did over a decade ago when they learned to brush their teeth at one of the school's kid-size sinks.</Description>
        <MainBody>Everglades City seniors take a last walk together
Melhor Marie Leonor
Previous
Next
Salutatorian Savannah Oglesby, center right, laughs with classmate valedictorian Houston Brown, right, during graduation rehearsal Thursday at Everglades City School in Everglades City. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Others graduating Friday are Dalton Patt, from left, Nic Jones and Trevyr Daniels.  Corey Perrine/Staff
Corey Perrine
The front of the school after graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone theyll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Savannah Oglesby and Ana Roldan, far left, Houston Brown, in yellow, and Trevyr Daniels, far right, pose for a group photo at age four with the school's Pre-Kindergarten class. They will be part of the Everglades City School graduating class. (Submitted photo)
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Dalton Patt, left, reacts to classmate Ana Roldan, right, walking on stage during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Ana Roldan, from left, Dalton Patt, Dylan Lucas, Nic Jones, Trevyr Daniels, Salutatorian Savannah Oglesby, and Valedictorian Houston Brown act out the turning of their tassels during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
The graduating class is situated during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Ana Roldan, center, does her hair as Dalton Patt speaks at the podium during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Dylan Lucas, center, is coached by Principal Robert Spano, left, and Assistant Principal James Ragusa, during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Reading Coach Michele Wheeler, center, looks on during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Facility Manager Dale Patt playfully acts the part as an indoor plant during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Reading Coach Michele Wheeler, center, helps Valedictorian Houston Brown to the stage during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Ana Roldan, center left, reacts with friends while talking during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Dylan Lucas walks during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
A plan of graduation is seen during rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Reading Coach Michele Wheeler, center right, laughs at a stage malfunction as Facility Manager Dale Patt, right, fixes the issue during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Nic Jones, from left, Trevyr Daniels, Salutatorian Savannah Oglesby and Valedictorian Houston Brown line up during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
Salutatorian Savannah Oglesby, center right, smiles with classmates while being instructed by Principal Robert Spano, left, during graduation rehearsal Thursday, May 28, 2015 at Everglades City School in Everglades City, Fla. The class of 2015 awards seven diplomas Friday. Save one student, the event is another milestone they'll share since Kindergarten, when the group first came together. (Corey Perrine/Staff)
Corey Perrine
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:42:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Search is on for man who robbed Domino's Pizza</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/search-is-on-for-man-who-robbed-east-naples-dominos-pizza</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Search is on for man who robbed East Naples Domino's Pizza
8:42 PM, May 28, 2015
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
EAST NAPLES, Fla. - Collier County sheriff's deputies are looking for a man who robbed an East Naples Domino's Pizza at gunpoint Wednesday night.
Employees at the store at 5494 Rattlesnake Hammock Road called 911 around 11:40 p.m. Wednesday, saying they had been robbed. The store's manager told deputies the suspect ordered him and two other employees to the front of the store to open the register.
Before leaving, the man made the employees go to the back of the restaurant. He left through the front of the door with an undisclosed amount of cash.
The employees described the suspect as wearing a black hoodie, black pants, black gloves and a black bandana across his face. No one was injured during the robbery.

Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:04:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ex-US Speaker charged in relation to hush money</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/politics/ex-us-speaker-charged-in-relation-to-payments-of-hush-money</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Ex-US Speaker charged in relation to payments of hush money
Michael Tarm, Associated Press
8:04 PM, May 28, 2015
FILE - In this June 15, 2007 file photo, House Speaker Dennis Hastert, R-Ill., sits for a portrait in his Capitol Hill office. On Thursday, May 28, 2015, federal prosecutors indicted Hastert, 73, on bank-related charges. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh, File)
Susan Walsh
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
CHICAGO - Former U.S. House Speaker Dennis Hastert agreed to pay $3.5 million in hush money to keep an unidentified person silent about "prior misconduct" by the Illinois Republican who was once third in line to the U.S. presidency, according to a federal grand jury indictment handed down on Thursday in Chicago.
The indictment, which does not describe the misconduct Hastert was allegedly trying to conceal, charges the 73-year-old with one count of evading bank regulations as he withdrew tens of thousands of dollars at a time to make the payments. He is also charged with one count of lying to the FBI about the reason for the unusual bank withdrawals.
Each count of the indictment carries a maximum penalty of 5 years in prison and a $250,000 fine.
The Associated Press left a phone message seeking comment with a person at Hastert's Washington, D.C., office. It was not immediately returned. Hastert did not immediately return a message left on his cellphone seeking comment, or respond to an email.
Hastert withdrew a total of around $1.7 million in cash from various bank accounts from 2010 to 2014, and then provided it to the person identified in the indictment only as Individual A. Hastert allegedly agreed to pay the person $3.5 million, but never apparently paid that full amount.
The indictment notes Hastert was a high school teacher and coach from 1965 to 1981 in suburban Yorkville, about 50 miles west of Chicago. While the indictment says Individual A has been a resident of Yorkville and has known Hastert most of his life, it doesn't describe their relationship.
The indictment says Hastert agreed to the payments after multiple meetings in 2010. It says that "during at least one of the meetings, Individual A and defendant discussed past misconduct by defendant against Individual A that had occurred years earlier" and Hastert agreed to pay Individual A $3.5 million "in order to compensate for and conceal his prior misconduct against Individual A," the indictment says.
The indictment says that between 2010 and 2012 Hastert made fifteen $50,000 withdrawals of cash from bank accounts at Old Second Bank, People's State Bank and Castle Bank and gave cash to Individual A around every six weeks.
Around April 2012, bank officials began questioning Hastert about the large withdrawals, and starting in July of that year, Hastert reduced the amounts he withdrew at a time to less than $10,000 apparently so they would not run afoul of a regulation designed to stop illicit activity such as money laundering , according to the indictment.
Among the focuses of the FBI investigation was whether Hastert, in the words of the indictment, was "the victim of a criminal extortion related to, among other matters, his prior positions in government." The court document does not elaborate.
Investigators questioned Hastert on Dec. 8, 2014 and he lied about why he had been withdrawing so much money at a time. He told investigators he did it because he didn't trust the banking system, the indictment alleges.
"Yeah ... I kept the cash. That's what I am doing," it quotes Hastert as saying.
Hastert was a little known lawmaker from suburban Chicago when chosen to succeed conservative Newt Gingrich as speaker. Hastert was picked after favored Louisiana Congressman Bob Livingston resigned following his admission of several sexual affairs.
As speaker, Hastert pushed President George W. Bush's legislative agenda, helping pass a massive tax cut and expanding Medicare prescription drug benefits.
He retired from Congress in 2007 after eight years as speaker, making him the longest-serving Republican House speaker.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:06:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chase with deputies leads to arrest in drive-by</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/man-arrested-in-drive-by-shooting-after-chase-with-collier-deputies</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Previous
Next
GOLDEN GATE, Fla. - A man suspected in a drive-by shooting outside a billiards bar last week led Collier County deputies on a chase through Golden Gate on Thursday night as they tried to serve him with a warrant.
Deputies identified 31-year-old Roberto Martinez as a suspect while investigating a May 21 shooting outside the Eight Ball Sports Bar at 12275 Collier Blvd. The victim told detectives he heard a gunshot and saw a car driving toward him. Someone in the car then fired a shot toward the victim, who was able to take cover and wasn't injured.
After locating Martinez around 6:10 p.m. Thursday near 54th Terrace Southwest and 23rd Court Southwest, deputies said he refused to pull over. They were able to stop the car using a PIT manuever after a five-minute vehicle pursuit, according to Collier County Sheriff's Office spokeswoman, Michelle Batten.
Martinez was arrested to face charges of fleeing/eluding, drug possession, reckless driving, driving while license suspended and the original charge of aggravated assault. Batten said she was unsure of the exact type of drug Martinez was found in possession of.

Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:21:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why the Bee matters to pronouncer Jacques Bailly</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/why-the-bee-matters-to-pronouncer-jacques-bailly</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Next
Why does the National Spelling Bee matter? Seriously  why does it?
For pronouncer Jacques Bailly, the work that goes into the Spelling Bee taps into his meaning of life. It celebrates the expansion of knowledge and human achievement.
This is a special triumph, its a pinnacle of achievement thats wonderful to see, Bailly said. Its all about the human effort to excel and to show the excellence of knowledge.
Bailly describes himself as a secular humanist with a bit of stoicism. He believes humans have to make their own meaning.
For some people that can be dark, but for me thats liberating, he said.
The accumulation and celebration of knowledge  thats what keeps him coming back since 2003. The Bee itself, to him, is a media event.
This is the big carrot that leads people to try and climb this mountain  but the mountain is what matters, he said. Not the top.
Sometimes he forgets who the winner was, Bailly admits.
The learning and the competition can pay off in so many ways. Studying chemical terms could grease the wheels for a speller to discover a cure for an illness.
Many contestants want to be doctors and scientists, after all.
Were here for a very short time, we know so very little. This is part of going beyond our humble, primate beings, Bailly said. I believe were here to be as good as we can possibly be.
Gavin Stern is a national digital producer for the Scripps National Desk.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:04:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Briefs_everglades-webteaser</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/briefs_evergladeswebteaser_92415020</Link>
        <Description>Listen to the 911 call.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share Article
Subscribe to the Naples Daily News
Ready to subscribe to the Naples Daily News? Choose between a Premium or Digital subscription below.
Need Help? Call us at 1-888-878-6842.
Monday-Friday: 6am-6pm / Saturday: 7am-3pm / Sunday: 7am-2pm
Comments
Want to participate in the conversation? Log in or become a subscriber today.  Subscribers can read and comment on any story, anytime.  Non-subscribers will only be able to view comments on select stories.
Trending stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:04:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Everglades City man charged in shooting</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/everglades-city-man-charged-in-shooting_56275676</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Everglades City man charged in shooting
Daily News staff
7:04 PM, May 28, 2015
2 hours ago
crime
ONeill, Jon
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
An Everglades City man was arrested in a shooting Wednesday night after refusing an offer from an anonymous caller who demanded $27,000 in exchange for not pressing charges in the incident.
Around 8:15 p.m., two men  Clay Daniels Jr., a 30-year-old from Copeland, and Patrick Galloway, a 56-year-old from Everglades City  began fighting outside the back of Everglades City School following a verbal argument. Reports from the Collier County Sheriffs Office say Galloway charged Daniels, who punched Galloway in the chin twice. A witness said Galloway then ran to his truck, grabbed a gun and fired three or four shots at Daniels, who was struck in his right hand but not seriously injured.
While getting into his Dodge pickup to leave, Galloway told a witness to call the law, Ill be at home, according to an incident report. Before driving off, he accidentally discharged his gun through the windshield, leaving a small bullet hole that deputies found later while investigating.
When first contacted by deputies, Daniels said was being treated at Physicians Regional hospital and did not want to press charges. However, later that night, Galloway told deputies he received a phone call from an anonymous male caller who demanded $27,000 in exchange for not pressing charges. Galloway, who admitted to the shooting, said he was not sure if the caller was Daniels.
Daniels denied having knowledge of the phone call when asked by deputies, but ultimately decided that he did indeed want to press charges, according to the report.
Galloway was arrested to face charges of aggravated battery with a deadly weapon and discharging a firearm on school property. As of Thursday night, he remained jailed on bonds totaling $160,000.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:34:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crash cleared on U.S. 41 at Old 41</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/traffic/hit-and-run-crash-blocks-two-southbound-lanes-on-us-41-and-old-41</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Update: The crash on U.S. 41 has been cleared.
Earlier:
A hit-and-run accident on Tamiami Trail is blocking both the southbound left turn lane and the center left laneat Old U.S. 41 according to the Florida Highway Patrol. FHP is reporting that the crash resulted in injuries.
Check back for more updates.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:45:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Friends, family mourn woman found in East Naples</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/man-who-found-body-in-east-naples-the-buzzards-were-eating-her_84573816</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>10:06 AM, May 27, 2015
4 hours ago
The field where a body of a person was found near Bush Blvd. in East Naples on Tuesday, May 26, 2015. (Scott McIntyre/Staff)
Scott McIntyre
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
NAPLES, Fla. - Buzzards showed him where the body was  and a tattoo on her chest confirmed Troy Kings worst fears.
Five days after his daughter Heather went missing, Troy King found her body in the woods behind a hotel off Collier Boulevard in East Naples .
The 21-year-old Bonita Springs resident hadnt been heard from since Thursday, when friends told deputies she suddenly left their hotel without her cell phone. But deputies werent doing enough to search for her, her father said.
It took me 15 minutes to find my daughter, Troy King said. They could have found her if they would have looked.
The Collier County Sheriffs Office said Wednesday that all indications point toward it being Heather King but said they could not confirm the identity of the person who was found because of the condition of the body. Detectives said there were visible tattoos on the body but none that allowed them to positively identify the person.
Troy King said not even the medical examiners office will take his word for it. In the meantime, he went to a funeral home Wednesday afternoon to make preparations.
Heather King was last seen Thursday evening near the Days Inn and Suites at 3387 Tollgate Blvd. Friends said she appeared to be under the influence of an unknown substance when she left on foot around 7:30 p.m.
Shes had her bouts with drugs. I just didnt know if she went off on a bender or whatever, her father said. Thats why I gave it a few days.
But when Tuesday rolled around and Troy King still hadnt heard, he said he went looking  for his own peace of mind.
I feel like half the [Sheriffs Office] took a long weekend, he said. And I dont really think they took it seriously, if at all.
Heathers mother, Pamela Truax, reported her missing Friday night, telling deputies she had dropped her daughter off at the Days Inn around 3 p.m. Thursday to celebrate a friends birthday. Truax said she grew worried after not hearing from her daughter all day.
Truax gave deputies the name of a man she said she had dropped off at the hotel with her daughter, but the name was redacted from a missing person report obtained Wednesday from the Sheriffs Office.
According to the report, deputies who responded to Truaxs call checked the hotel and located two of her friends. The friends, whose names also were redacted from the report, said they did not know where Heather was.
Deputies said they called local hospitals but were unable to find anyone by the name of Heather King. They did not make any sweeps of the area, according to the report.
Sheriffs Office spokeswoman Karie Partington said deputies treat missing persons calls differently, depending on the circumstances. As an example, she said the response to a report of a missing child is usually very different than the response to a report of a missing adult.
An autopsy is still being conducted, but Partington said there is no indication of foul play at this point in the investigation.
Troy King said his daughter lived with her mother in Bonita Springs and had two younger siblings, a 17-year-old sister and a 14-year-old brother, who live with him. She had recently been working as a pet groomer and had always been an animal lover.
Amber Brennan said she has known Heather King since the two were in third grade. Brennan said the two have kept in touch since, fishing, swimming and mudding together. When she went missing, Brennan knew something was wrong.
It just didnt feel right, she said. You dont just disappear like that.
Kings friend Karl Marzella said the last time he spoke with her, she had just gotten the job at a dog groomer and had been staying sober. After she went missing, Marzella, who lives out of state, said he had been staying in contact with her local friends. It was Kings Narcotics Anonymous sponsor who informed him of her death.
Her sponsor, all of us were worried about her, Marzella said.
Hell remember King as the girl who wasnt afraid to be brutally honest, who liked to draw and who always kept things light.
She had a good energy. Even in the sad times, there was always some way we found to smile. Thats the memory Im going to keep, Marzella said. Weve got to focus on the good.  No matter how strange it was at the end, focus on the good.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:21:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bee champion returns for first time in 40 years</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/bee-champion-returns-for-first-time-in-40-years</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>5:21 PM, May 28, 2015
5 hours ago
Michael Kerpan Jr., the 1965 Scripps National Spelling Bee champion. holds an unabridged Mirriam-Webster dictionary at the 2015 Scripps National Spelling Bee.
Gavin Stern
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
In 1965, the Beatles were still releasing albums, the U.S. was in Vietnam and Michael Kerpan Jr., then 12, won the Scripps National Spelling Bee.
A couple things have changed since then. He last attended the Bee in 1971, when his sister Dori competed.
It was a very different era. The Bee has a lot more visibility than it did at that time, Kerpan said. Im shocked. Its four times as many spellers  huge!
Today, Kerpan, 62, is a social security attorney in Boston. He's attending the Bee for the first time in four decades.
Its very fancy with commercials. We didnt have any of that stuff," he said. "It was just all spelling so it moved faster.
There was also no social media. Do newspaper clips count?

Posted by 1965 National Spelling Bee Competitors on Monday, May 11, 2015
When people misspelled words, they disappeared, he said. It was a very different feeling.
For winning the 1965 Spelling Bee, Kerpansschool in Tulsa got a brand new set of Encyclopedias. He was excused from spelling class for a year with an "A."
The cash prize back then was $1,000, Kerpan said. Thats about $7,500 in 2015 dollars  a far cry from todays combined $38,600 in prizes.
I saved it until graduate school and then it was all gone, he said.
Like most Bee competitors, Kerpan had a bright future after the Bee. He judged at local Tulsa Bee competitions, went to college at Harvard and then University of Chicago for law school.
Kerpan is conflicted over the new vocabulary test requirement, introduced in 2013. Though it wasnt required 40 years ago, Kerpan said he knew the definitions to most of his words anyway. It helped him to remember them.
I knew the meaning to most of the words. Most of the people did not, Kerpan said.
But today, he admits the words are much harder.
One-third of them, I wouldnt even be able to guess, Kerpan said.
Gavin Stern is a national digital producer for the Scripps National Desk
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:37:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore gets bloodier as arrests drop</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/baltimore-gets-bloodier-as-arrests-drop-post-freddie-gray</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Baltimore gets bloodier as arrests drop post-Freddie Gray
Juliet Linderman, Associated Press
3:37 PM, May 28, 2015
FILE - In this May 24, 2015, file photo, police pick up a pair of shoes after a double shooting in Baltimore. Residents in West Baltimore say they've been victims of excessive policing in this neighborhood where street crime and drug-dealing have been endemic. Now, one month after riots erupted in the wake of the death of Freddie Gray in police custody, homicides and shootings are up and those same residents feel like they've been abandoned and left to fend for themselves. (Colin Campbell/The Baltimore Sun via AP, File)
Colin Campbell
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
BALTIMORE - A 31-year-old woman and a young boy were shot in the head Thursday, becoming Baltimore's 37th and 38th homicide victims so far this month, the city's deadliest in 15 years.
Meanwhile, arrests have plunged: Police are booking fewer than half the number of people they pulled off the streets last year.
Arrests were already declining before Freddie Gray died on April 19 of injuries he suffered in police custody, but they dropped sharply thereafter, as his death unleashed protests, riots, the criminal indictment of six officers and a full-on civil rights investigation by the U.S. Justice Department that has officers working under close scrutiny.
"I'm afraid to go outside," said Antoinette Perrine, whose brother was shot down three weeks ago on a basketball court near her home in the Harlem Park neighborhood of West Baltimore. Ever since, she has barricaded her door and added metal slabs inside her windows to deflect gunfire.
"It's so bad, people are afraid to let their kids outside," Perrine said. "People wake up with shots through their windows. Police used to sit on every corner, on the top of the block. These days? They're nowhere."
West Baltimore residents worry they've been abandoned by the officers they once accused of harassing them, leaving some neighborhoods like the Wild West without a lawman around.
"Before it was over-policing. Now there's no police," said Donnail "Dreads" Lee, 34, who lives in the Gilmor Homes, the public housing complex where Gray, 25, was chased down. "People feel as though they can do things and get away with it. I see people walking with guns almost every single day, because they know the police aren't pulling them up like they used to."
Police Commissioner Anthony Batts said his officers "are not holding back," despite encountering dangerous hostility in the Western District.
"Our officers tell me that when officers pull up, they have 30 to 50 people surrounding them at any time," Batts said.
Batts provided more details at a City Council meeting Wednesday night, saying officers now fear getting arrested for making mistakes.
"What is happening, there is a lot of levels of confusion in the police organization. There are people who have pain, there are people who are hurt, there are people who are frustrated, there are people who are angry," Batts said. "There are people, and they've said this to me, 'If I get out of my car and make a stop for a reasonable suspicion that leads to probable cause but I make a mistake on it, will I be arrested?' They pull up to a scene and another officer has done something that they don't know, it may be illegal, will they be arrested for it? Those are things they are asking."
Protesters said Gray's death is emblematic of a pattern of police violence and brutality against impoverished African-Americans in Baltimore. In October, Batts and Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake invited the Justice Department to participate in a collaborative review of police policies. The fallout from Gray's death prompted the mayor to ramp that up, and U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch agreed to a more intensive probe into whether the department employs discriminatory policing, excessive force and unconstitutional searches and arrests.
Baltimore was seeing a slight rise in homicides this year even before Gray's death April 19. But the 38 homicides so far in May is a major spike, after 22 in April, 15 in March, 13 in February and 23 in January.
With one weekend still to go, May 2015 is already the deadliest month in 15 years, surpassing the November 1999 total of 36.
Ten of May's homicides happened in the Western District, which has had as many homicides in the first five months of this year as it did all of last year.
Non-fatal shootings are spiking as well  91 so far in May, 58 of them in the Western District.
The mayor said her office is "examining" the relationship between the homicide spike and the dwindling arrest rate.
Even before Gray's death, police were making between 25 and 28 percent fewer arrests each month than they made in the same month last year. But so far in May, arrests are down roughly 56 percent. Police booked just 1,045 people in the first 19 days of May, an average of 55 a day. In the same time period last year, police arrested 2,396 people, an average of 126 a day.
In fact, police did not make any arrests in the triple digits between April 22 and May 19, except on two occasions: On April 27, when protests gave way to rioting, police arrested 246 people. On May 2, the last day of a city-wide curfew, police booked 140 people.
At a news conference Wednesday, Rawlings-Blake said there are "a lot of reasons why we're having a surge in violence."
"Other cities that have experienced police officers accused or indicted of crimes, there's a lot of distrust and a community breakdown," Rawlings-Blake said. "The result is routinely increased violence."
"It's clear that the relationship between the commissioner and the rank-and-file is strained," she added. "He's working very hard to repair that relationship."
Emergency response specialist Michael Greenberger cautions against directly blaming police. The founder and director of the University of Maryland Center for Health and Homeland Security, the spike in homicides is more likely a response to Gray's death and the rioting.
"We went through a period of such intense anger that the murder rate got out of control. I think it's been really hard for the police to keep on top of that," he said.
Lee disagrees. He says rival gang members are taking advantage of the police reticence to settle old scores.
"There was a shooting down the street, and the man was standing in the middle of the street with a gun, just shooting," Lee added. "Usually, you can't walk up and down the street drinking or smoking weed. Now, people are everywhere smoking weed, and police just ride by, look at you, and keep going. There used to be police on every corner. I don't think they'll be back this summer."
Batts acknowledged that "the service we're giving is off-target with the community as a whole" and he promised to pay special attention to the Western District.
Veronica Edmonds, a 26-year-old mother of seven in the Gilmor Homes, said she wishes the police would return, and focus on violent crime rather than minor drug offenses.
"If they focused more on criminals and left the petty stuff alone, the community would have more respect for police officers," she said.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:32:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Psychiatrist testifies in Colo. theater shooting</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/psychiatrist-colorado-shooter-knew-what-he-was-doing</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Psychiatrist: Colorado shooter 'knew what he was doing'
Dan Elliott, Associated Press
3:32 PM, May 28, 2015
Previous
Next
FILE - In this June 4, 2013, file photo Aurora theater shooting suspect James Holmes appears in court in Centennial, Colo. Prosecutors in the Colorado theater shooting trial say they are moving closer toward the heart of their case: whether Holmes was legally insane when he committed one of the worst mass shootings in U.S. history. (Andy Cross/The Denver Post via AP, Pool, File)
Andy Cross
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
This screenshot made from a pdf released by the Colorado Judicial Department on Wed., May 27, 2015, shows a portion of Aurora shooter James Holmes' notebook, after it was presented as evidence in the Holmes murder trial on Tues., May 26, 2015, in Centennial, Colo. The notebook was released into public domain as per court procedure. (Colorado Judicial Department via AP Photos)
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
This screenshot made from a pdf released by the Colorado Judicial Department on Wed., May 27, 2015, shows a portion of Aurora shooter James Holmes' notebook, after it was presented as evidence in the Holmes murder trial on Tues., May 26, 2015, in Centennial, Colo. The notebook entries on these two pages discuss the pros and cons of various methods and venues for committing mass murder and, at right, is a diagram of the theater in Aurora where Holmes carried out the killings. The notebook was released into public domain as per court procedure. (Colorado Judicial Department via AP Photos)
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
This screenshot made from a pdf released by the Colorado Judicial Department on Wed., May 27, 2015, shows a portion of Aurora shooter James Holmes' notebook, after it was presented as evidence in the Holmes murder trial on Tues., May 26, 2015, in Centennial, Colo. The notebook was released into public domain as per court procedure. (Colorado Judicial Department via AP Photos)
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
CENTENNIAL, Colo. - A state-appointed psychiatrist who examined James Holmes long after his attack on a Colorado movie theater said Thursday that whatever he suffered from that night, he knew what he was doing.
Dr. William Reid told jurors he believes Holmes knew the consequences of his actions when he opened fire at a Batman movie premiere, killing 12 people, wounded 58 and injured 12 others in the ensuing chaos.
"Whatever he suffered from, it did not prevent him from forming intent and knowing the consequences of what he was doing," Reid said.
The comment prompted the defense to ask to approach the judge, and lawyers from both sides were called to discuss his testimony privately, prompting a break in the death penalty trial.
District Attorney George Brauchler had told jurors in his opening statements that Reid as well as another state-appointed psychiatrist who examined Holmes concluded he was legally sane during the attack.
Prosecutors are methodically building a case that Holmes knew right from wrong when he planned and carried out the shooting. They want him convicted and executed, not sent to a mental hospital.
But before Reid took the stand Thursday, Judge Carlos Samour reminded prosecutors of the strict parameters both sides had agreed to before trial, limiting what Reid can say about Holmes' sanity and keeping jurors from seeing parts of his videotaped 2014 examination.
The judge said Reid cannot say whether Holmes had a particular mental state at the time of the attack, and can only offer his expert opinion on whether Holmes was "capable of forming" a certain mental state.
Holmes has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity. Under Colorado law, the burden of proof is on Brauchler's team to convince jurors he was sane.
Reid's much-anticipated testimony follows a month of testimony from victims, first responders and investigators about what happened the night of July 20, 2012.
In the coming days, prosecutors plan to ask Reid for his observations as they show jurors a redacted version of the 22 hours of videotaped interviews he conducted with Holmes.
Reid interviewed Holmes in 2014, after prosecutors challenged the conclusions of the first state-ordered review of his sanity, by Dr. Jeffrey Metzner in December 2013.
By then, Holmes had been anti-psychotic medicine for months, in part because 20 doctors who treated Holmes after his arrest agreed he suffers from a serious psychotic illness, defense attorney Dan King said early in the trial.
Earlier this week, prosecutors showed jurors what Holmes wrote in his notebook before the attack, such as an estimate on the police response ("3 mins") and diagrams of the theater complex, down to which auditorium had the fewest exits where victims might escape.
With detailed maps and cramped handwriting, Holmes sketched out a chilling list of choices: mass murder or serial murder; attack a theater or an airport; use guns, bombs or biological warfare.
The graduate student in neuroscience sought to diagnose himself, listing 13 ailments including schizophrenia and "borderline, narcissistic, anxious, avoidant and obsessive compulsive personality disorder."
"So, anyways, that's my mind," Holmes wrote. "It's broken. I tried to fix it."
The defense has said Holmes suffers from schizophrenia and was so warped by psychosis that he did not know right from wrong  Colorado's standard for an insanity verdict.
The notebook is a serious blow to the defense because it "speaks to his appreciation of wrongfulness," said Steven Pitt, a forensic psychiatrist who has worked on sanity cases but isn't involved in the Holmes trial.
"This is a guy who is really struggling and is clearly mentally ill," Pitt said, but mental illness alone won't satisfy an insanity verdict in Colorado.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:32:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Naples man sentenced in ID theft case</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/naples-man-sentenced-in-identity-theft-case_84361269</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Naples man sentenced in identity theft case
Daily News staff
3:32 PM, May 28, 2015
4:13 PM, May 28, 2015
crime
unknown
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
A Naples man was sentenced Thursday to three years in federal prison for his role in an identity theft scheme that nearly netted more than $64,000 in tax refunds.
Rafael Angel Reyes Menjivar, 23, pleaded guilty in February to possessing 15 or more unauthorized access devices and for aggravated identity theft.
On Feb. 5, 2013, during the execution of a search warrant by the Collier County Sheriffs Office, Menjivar was found with 101 unauthorized access devices, namely Social Security Numbers (SSN) of other individuals.
Approximately 16 income tax returns were electronically filed with the IRS using the personal identification information of others.
The total amount of the requested tax refunds was $64,547. Each of the tax refunds was stopped at the service center.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:33:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Report: Cats killed by 'natural predator'</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/report-says-east-naples-cats-killed-by-natural-predator_69321079</Link>
        <Description>Natural predators — not humans — were responsible for killing five cats found in East Naples since the end of April, according to a report from a Texas-based forensics veterinarian.</Description>
        <MainBody>Report says East Naples cats killed by natural predator
Kristine Gill
1:34 PM, May 28, 2015
5 hours ago
Barbara Foelske talks with a Domestic Animal Services officer at her Mockingbird Lane home Friday morning. Her husband found the third dead cat.
KRISTINE GILL/STAFF
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
Natural predators  not humans  were responsible for killing five cats found in East Naples since the end of April, according to a report from a Texas-based forensics veterinarian.
Animal lovers near Estey Avenue have worried that someone was targeting the felines that wander their neighborhood. Seven cats were found dead in recent weeks and donors raised more than $5,000 through the Naples Cat Alliance and Southwest Florida Crime Stoppers looking for information.
"This really hit home for a lot of people," said Megan Sorbara, president of the Naples Cat Alliance.
Now that the report is complete, both the Collier County Sheriff's Office and Domestic Animal Services said they've closed their investigations.
Residents near Estey Avneue remain unsure.
"A lot of us around here aren't really buying that as the whole explanation," said Victoria Sweet, who lives on Mockingbird Lane. "There's too many cats killed in exactly the same way."
Sweet and others are seeking expert opinions from different sources, she said, declining to specify.
Sorbara said once she's reviewed the reports for herself, she plans to contact the 81 donors who raised $5,219 in reward money and give them a few options. They can get their money back, let the shelter have it or put it toward a whistleblower fund which would keep reward money around for other cases like this that might pop up.
Sorbara also remains skeptical, pointing out that only pet cats were targeted and not feral animals.
"The cats could have been killed by someone and then other animals could have come along and gnawed on them," Sorbara said. "It always comes back to this kind of thing, that it's an animal. I dunno if it's easier to just say that and be done with it."
Forensic veterinarian Melinda Merck conducted the necropsies on the five cats through her Austin, Texas consulting service. Veterinary Forensics Consulting, LLC works with local law enforcement agencies as well as the FBI, the U.S. Department of Agriculture, as well as criminal defense attorneys and prosecutors, to determine how animals died.
She's conducted necropsies on cats found in similar situations and most of the time, she said, coyotes are responsible.
"In my experience, 99 percent of these are predator attacks when you're finding (the animals) like that," Merck said.
Coyotes "bite and run," Merck said, so they'll attack prey with a quick chomp that can often sever the body before leaving quickly, taking with them what they have in their mouths.
That's why sometimes only halves of cats are found. And usually those attacks by coyotes don't leave much blood, she said.
"That's very typical with crushing bites. Animals don't bleed like we do," Merck said. "They have smaller capillaries because they're made to survive wounds on their skin because they live outside. So the compression of a bite like that will actually keep it from bleeding."
Another clue for Merck is a cat's frayed claws, which indicate a struggle. Claws can be frayed when a cat runs on outdoor surfaces or defends itself from an attacker, Merck said. Some of the frayed claws in this case were also bloodied.
"Frayed nails alone are not the only finding," Merck said. "That's just one piece."
When a human is responsible for cutting a cat, Merck said there is evidence on the bones that show cut marks. Usually in those cases, parts of the animal are not left behind and weapons are found.
In this case, the only marks found on the cats' bones were U-shaped and V-shaped marks characteristic of another animal's bite.
It cost the Sheriff's Office and animal services $700 to ship and test the cats.
The results conclude investigations for both agencies. Daniel Christenbury, the animal services spokesman, said the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission would be the only other agency that might be interested in pursuing a case like this to determine what kind of animals were attacking the pets. Merck has kept fur samples from the five cats that might have saliva samples that could be tested to determine what attacked the cats. Those tests, she said, cost between $500 and $1,000 per sample.
Merck said the Collier agencies showed they took these cases seriously by submitting the five cats for necropsies.
"It's important because every time it happens you've gotta confirm whether it's humans or animals involved, just like every suspicious death," Merck said. "You should never say oh, it's just coyotes."
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
