<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="scrippsobfeeds">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:16:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Headlines we're working on</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/your-daily-scoop-for-july-7</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your Daily Scoop for July 7
Stories we're working on
9:16 AM, Jul 7, 2015
Previous
Estero residents are raising transportation concerns. Plus County Commission goes on break for the summer.
Estero residents are raising transportation concerns. Plus County Commission goes on break for the summer.
Gill, Kristine
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
NAPLES, Florida - Estero residents are raising transportation concerns. Plus County Commission goes on break for the summer.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:07:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fla. man with 92 dead, sick cats gets 3 years</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/panhandle-man-found-with-92-dead-sick-cats-gets-3-years</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Panhandle man found with 92 dead, sick cats gets 3 years
Associated Press
8:07 AM, Jul 7, 2015
S.Gnatiuk
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
FORT WALTON BEACH, Fla. (AP)  A Florida Panhandle man who had 92 dead and sick cats in his home is being sent to prison for three years.
Jerry McCallam pleaded no contest Monday to felony animal cruelty and misdemeanor animal abandonment charges and admitted to violating his probation. He was then sentenced.
The Northwest Florida Daily News reports that McCallum's probation officer visited McCallum's Crestview home last December and found the animals.
Panhandle Animal Welfare Society officials said some of the cats were already dead and most of the others were so sick they had to be euthanized.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:05:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Coast Guard searching for 2 boaters in Gulf</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/state/coast-guard-searching-for-2-missing-boaters-off-gulf-coast</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Coast Guard searching for 2 missing boaters off Gulf Coast
Associated Press
8:05 AM, Jul 7, 2015
A file photo showing a U.S. Coast Guard cutter. ( U.S. Coast Guard photo by Petty Officer 3rd Class Charles Mark Barney )
Copyright 2014 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
ST. PETERSBURG, Fla. (AP)  The Coast Guard is searching for two boaters missing off Florida's Gulf Coast.
Officials say that Michael Forehand and Lisa Harris were aboard a 39-foot boat over the weekend between Charlotte Harbor and Carrabelle and never returned as expected by Sunday night.
Cell phone pings last show they were about 10 miles west of Indian Rocks Beach on Saturday.
A C-130 Hercules aircraft crew from Air Station Clearwater and the crew of the Coast Guard Cutter Hawk from St. Petersburg are searching for the pair.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:03:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deputies shoot Fla. man after dispute over cats</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/deputies-shoot-florida-man-after-dispute-over-cats-bird</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Deputies shoot Florida man after dispute over cats, bird
Associated Press
8:03 AM, Jul 7, 2015
Show Caption
Previous
Next
PORT RICHEY, Fla. (AP)  A neighborhood argument over cats and a bird led to Florida sheriff's deputies shooting a man after he allegedly threatened a woman with a rifle.
Pasco County sheriff's deputies say 56-year-old Frank Rogers had an ongoing argument about her cats, which he said posed a threat to his bird, "Minnie."
Deputies say Rogers went to the woman's house Monday evening armed with a rifle and forced his way inside. She was able to escape.
Deputies soon arrived and say they ordered Rogers to drop his weapon but he threatened to shoot them. They opened fire, hitting him numerous times. Sheriff's spokesman Eddie Daniels says he was taken to the hospital and is expected to recover.
Daniels says Rogers could face numerous charges.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:52:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teen girl held in shooting of Florida trooper</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/teen-girl-held-without-bail-in-shooting-of-florida-trooper</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Teen girl held without bail in shooting of Florida trooper
Associated Press
6:52 AM, Jul 7, 2015
Show Caption
Previous
Next
VIERA, Fla. (AP)  A teenage girl will remain jailed on charges stemming from the shooting of a Florida Highway Patrol trooper by her boyfriend, who was then killed.
A circuit judge ruled Monday after a three-hour hearing that 16-year-old Morgan McNeil should be held without bail on adult charges of second-degree murder and attempted premeditated murder of a law enforcement officer.
Florida Today reports that Lt. Channing Taylor testified that 15-year-old Zane Terryn pulled a gun on him June 14 and fired a shot from about 6 feet away, hitting him in the shoulder. Taylor returned fire, killing Terryn, as McNeil allegedly tried to drive Terryn away.
Prosecutors say Terryn and McNeil were driving to Ohio to commit suicide when Taylor approached them outside a convenience store because their headlights were off.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:49:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Guns stolen from cars in Jacksonville</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/jacksonville-officials-worried-after-guns-stolen-from-cars</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Jacksonville officials worried after guns stolen from cars
Associated Press
6:49 AM, Jul 7, 2015
Show Caption
Previous
Next
JACKSONVILLE, Fla. (AP)  Jacksonville law officials are worried about a weekend spate of guns stolen during car burglaries.
The Jacksonville Sheriff's Office says an M-4 carbine and a .45 caliber handgun were stolen from an FBI agent's car over the weekend. Six other handguns were stolen from other cars over the weekend. Officers say most of the cars were unlocked.
The Florida Times-Union reports that the guns are being stolen citywide. In April, 69 guns were stolen from cars in the city.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:46:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Florida officer pleads guilty in drug case</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/south-florida-officer-pleads-guilty-in-drug-case</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>South Florida officer pleads guilty in drug case
Associated Press
6:46 AM, Jul 7, 2015
S.Gnatiuk
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
MIAMI (AP)  A South Florida police officer is facing up to 20 years in prison after pleading guilty to federal charges that he worked with a drug trafficker.
Miami Springs Sgt. Andres Quintanilla pleaded guilty Monday to one count of attempting to affect commerce by extortion under color of law. The 33-year-old officer had been arrested by the FBI in May.
The Miami Herald reports that an FBI informant told Quintanilla last September that he was a drug trafficker. Instead of arresting him, Quintanilla offered to help him. Prosecutors say he gave the informant the location of an undercover police drug office and the names of three Miami-Dade County police officers. He then agreed to escort 10 kilograms of cocaine.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:42:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deputies: Man threw dog from second floor</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/deputies-say-man-charged-after-threw-dog-from-second-floor</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Deputies say man charged after threw dog from second floor
Associated Press
6:42 AM, Jul 7, 2015
iStock
Previous
Next
POMPANO BEACH, Fla. (AP)  Authorities say a Pompano Beach man has been charged after he says he threw a dog from the second floor of his apartment building in a dispute with the dog's owner.
The South Florida Sun Sentinel reports that the Broward Sheriff's Office says 29-year-old Robert Noel was charged with causing cruel pain and suffering to an animal following Saturday's incident.
Deputies say they received a call about a man who was seen beating and throwing the dog over the apartment building's second floor railing.
Detectives say Noel told them that the dog belonged to a friend with whom he had been feuding for some time.
Investigators say the dog was found near the apartment building.
Noel's bond was set at $2,500. It wasn't clear if he has an attorney.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:44:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thousands of birds abandon eggs, nests in Fla.</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/environment/thousands-of-birds-abandon-eggs-nests-on-florida-island</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thousands of birds abandon eggs, nests on Florida island
Associated Press
6:36 AM, Jul 7, 2015
3 hours ago
In this Friday, June 19, 2015 photo, ospreys perch on a signpost at Seahorse Key, Fla. off Florida's Gulf Coast. In May, Seahorse Key fell eerily quiet, as thousands of birds suddenly disappeared, and biologists are trying to find the reason why. U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service biologist Vic Doig said what was once the largest bird colony on the state's Gulf Coast is now a "dead zone." (AP Photo/John Raoux)
John Raoux
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
SEAHORSE KEY, Fla. (AP)  The din created by thousands of nesting birds is usually the first thing you notice about Seahorse Key, a 150-acre mangrove-covered dune off Florida's Gulf Coast.
But in May, the key fell eerily quiet all at once.
Thousands of little blue herons, roseate spoonbills, snowy egrets, pelicans and other chattering birds were gone. Nests sat empty in trees; eggs broken and scattered on the muddy ground.
"It's a dead zone now," said Vic Doig, a U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service biologist. "This is where the largest bird colony on the Gulf Coast of Florida used to be."
For decades, Seahorse Key has been a protected way station for myriad bird species. It's part of the Cedar Keys National Wildlife Refuge, which was established in 1929 as a sanctuary for birds devastated by decades of hunting for their colorful plumage. Accessible only by boat, today it's a rare island off Florida not dominated by human activity and development.
When the birds come to nest, so too do biologists and naturalists who study the different colonies. But this year, the birds' exit has the state's avian biologists scrambling for answers.
"It's not uncommon for birds to abandon nests," said Peter Frederick, a University of Florida wildlife biologist who has studied Florida's birds for nearly 30 years. "But, in this case, what's puzzling is that all of the species did it all at once."
Doig said some of the Seahorse birds seem to have moved to a nearby island, but they're just a fraction of the tens of thousands of birds that would normally be nesting on the key right now.
To find answers, service biologists have been acting on the few clues they have.
First, they tested left-behind bird carcasses for disease or contaminants. Those tests came back negative.
Next, they researched possible new predators. Did raccoons swim over from another island? Perhaps some great horned owls flew out at night and started feasting?
Traps caught a few raccoons, which is common, but not enough to have created a wholesale abandonment. There were no telltale signs of owls.
Finally, Doig said, recent years have seen an increase in night flights over the area by surveillance planes and helicopters used to combat drug runners. Although the planes' noise could be disruptive, Doig admits it's a longshot.
The abandonment concerns biologists because it could have a ripple effect: Many bird species here return year after year to the same nesting sites. The disruption provokes anxiety that this important island refuge could somehow be lost.
"Any rookery that's persisted for decades as one of the largest colonies is incredibly important," said Janell Brush, an avian researcher with the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission. "It's quite a large colony. There had to be some intense event that would drive all these birds away."
Biologist also don't know how the disappearance will affect the island's other animals, some of which rely on the birds to survive. Cottonmouth snakes eat bird predators like rodents, and in turn the birds drop lots of fish and other nutrients from the trees to feed the snakes.
In the meantime, tour operators that once spent hours taking naturalists and bird watchers to the island are making other plans.
Mike O'Dell runs tours out of the little marina in nearby Cedar Key. He said on a Tuesday in May he led a group out to view thousands of birds crowding the shores of the key. On Wednesday, there was nothing.
"It's just that drastic," O'Dell said. "There were none. It's like a different world."

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:21:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>2 Americans, 1 Briton gored in Pamplona bull-run</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/world/2-americans-1-briton-gored-in-1st-pamplona-bull-run</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>2 Americans, 1 Briton gored in 1st Pamplona bull-run
Associated Press
6:21 AM, Jul 7, 2015
A reveler falls while others run with a Jandilla's ranch fighting bull during the running of the bulls of the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday, July 7, 2015. Revelers from around the world turned out here to kick off the festival with a messy party in the Pamplona town square, one day before the first of eight days of the running of the bulls. (AP Photo/Daniel Ochoa de Olza)
Daniel Ochoa de Olza
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
PAMPLONA, Spain (AP)  Two Americans and a Briton were gored and eight others injured Tuesday as thousands of daredevils dashed alongside fighting bulls in the first bull-run of Pamplona's San Fermin festival, organizers said
The San Fermin press office said a 38-year-old American identified only by his initials, M.W.O., was gored in the armpit. A 27-year-old Californian identified by the initials D.M.O. was also gored.
A 30-year-old Briton with the initials A.B.O. was gored in the perineum. None of the three was said to be in serious condition.
Three Americans were among the eight others injured, most with bruises sustained in falls and crowd crushes during the nationally televised run that lasted just over two minutes.
In all, 15 people have died from gorings in San Fermin since record-keeping began in 1924.
San Fermin since record-keeping began in 1924.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:15:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>6 bank employees fired for mock IS slaying video</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/world/6-bank-employees-fired-for-staging-mock-is-slaying-video</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>6 bank employees fired for staging mock IS slaying video
Associated Press
6:15 AM, Jul 7, 2015
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
LONDON (AP)  HSBC has fired six employees who staged a mock Islamic State group-style killing during a team-building exercise.
The Sun newspaper reported Tuesday the footage posted online showed five workers wearing overalls and balaclavas laughing as a South Asian colleague wearing an orange jumpsuit knelt at their feet.
One held a coat hanger as a pretend knife while another held the kneeling man by the shoulders. One employee then yells "Allahu Akbar!"  Arabic for "God is great"  a phrase often used before IS hostages are slain.
HSBC says in a statement it had fired those involved in the "abhorrent" video as soon as the Sun brought it to their attention. The company apologized for any offense the video caused.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:00:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Traffic enforcement locations in Collier, Lee</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/traffic/tuesdays-traffic-enforcement-locations-in-collier-lee_070715</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tuesday's traffic enforcement locations in Collier, Lee
5:00 AM, Jul 7, 2015
Copyright Associated Press
NAPLES, Fla. - Here are today's traffic enforcement locations in Collier and Lee counties:
Collier County
The Collier County Sheriff's Office each day lists locations it could target for increased enforcement of traffic violations. In addition to their normal patrols, Collier deputies will target at least one of these locations with stepped up enforcement:
Santa Barbara Boulevard and Recreation Lane  Aggressive driving
Collier Boulevard and Business Circle South  Speeding
Vanderbilt Beach Road and Gulf Pavillion Drive  Red-light running
Lee County
The Lee County Sheriff's Office each day lists locations it could target for increased enforcement of traffic violations. In addition to their normal patrols, Lee deputies will target at least one of these locations with stepped up enforcement:
Six Mile Cypress Parkway, Fort Myers
Plantation Road, Fort Myers
Daniels Parkway, Gateway
Copyright 2014 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:00:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brent Batten: MPO clears the Ayer</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/columnists/brent-batten/brent-batten-mpo-clears-the-ayer-with-directors-dismissal_85321924</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Next
TheAyerhas been let out of Collier County.
LucillaAyer, Colliers embattled Metropolitan Planning Organization executive director, was dismissed suddenly last month when the organizations governing board decided to end her contract.
Ayer, whose job has teetered in and out of jeopardy for two years, is entitled to about $31,000 in severance pay and other benefits.
Her departure comes just as theMPOchairman, Naples City Councilman SamSaad, seeks to distance theMPOfrom county government and establish it as an independent body.
SaadcountedAyeras an ally in that effort, but it was he who made the motion on June 12 to endAyersemployment. It was an extraordinarily difficult proposition for me,Saadsaid of the action. I didnt make my decision until 10 oclock the night before.
TheMPOoperates in obscurity but it is pivotal in the allocation of millions of dollars in state and federal transportation funds that flow into Collier County.
By law, every area of the country that gets federal money is obligated to have anMPOthat sets funding priorities for roads, bridges, airports, seaports and even sidewalks.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:00:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>AP-US-MED--Stroke-Brain Stents side</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/apusmedstrokebrain-stents-side_92100384</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Share Article
Subscribe to the Naples Daily News
Ready to subscribe to the Naples Daily News? Choose between a Premium or Digital subscription below.
Need Help? Call us at 1-888-878-6842.
Monday-Friday: 6am-6pm / Saturday: 7am-3pm / Sunday: 7am-2pm
Comments
Want to participate in the conversation? Log in or become a subscriber today.  Subscribers can read and comment on any story, anytime.  Non-subscribers will only be able to view comments on select stories.
Trending stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:40:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>San Francisco status as 'sanctuary' criticized</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/national/san-francisco-status-as-sanctuary-criticized-after-slaying</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>San Francisco status as 'sanctuary' criticized after slaying
Janie Har and Amy Taxin, Associated Press
9:40 PM, Jul 6, 2015
Previous
Next
A mourner lays down flowers following a vigil for Kathryn Steinle, Monday, July 6, 2015, on Pier 14 in San Francisco. Steinle was gunned down while out for an evening stroll at Pier 14 with her father and a family friend on Wednesday, July 1. (AP Photo/Beck Diefenbach)
Beck Diefenbach
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
FILE - This undated photo provided by the San Francisco Police Department shows Francisco Sanchez. The fatal shooting of a woman at a sightseeing pier has put San Francisco under an uncomforable and nasty spotlight because Sanchez, the Mexican man under arrest, was in the U.S. illegally, had been deported five times and was out on the streets after San Francisco officials refused a request from U.S. immigration authorities to hold him. (San Francisco Police Department via AP, File)
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
SAN FRANCISCO - The killing of a woman at a sightseeing pier has brought criticism down on this liberal city because the Mexican man under arrest was in the U.S. illegally, had been deported five times and was out on the streets after San Francisco officials disregarded a request from immigration authorities to keep him locked up.
San Francisco is one of dozens of cities and counties across the country that do not fully cooperate with federal immigration authorities. The city goes so far as to promote itself as a "sanctuary" for people in the country illegally.
In a jailhouse interview with a TV station, Francisco Sanchez, the 45-year-old repeat drug offender arrested in the shooting Wednesday of Kathryn Steinle, appeared to confirm that he came to the city because of its status as a sanctuary.
Prosecutors on Monday charged Sanchez with murder as San Francisco Sheriff Ross Mirkarimi strongly defended his office's release of Sanchez and pointed the finger back at U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.
He said the federal agency should have issued an arrest warrant for Sanchez.
"ICE knew that he had been deported five times," Mirkarimi said. "You would have thought he met a threshold that he required a court order or a warrant. They did not do that."
The case has prompted a flurry of criticism from ICE officials, politicians and commenters on social media, all of whom portrayed the slaying as a preventable tragedy.
"Most of the blame should fall squarely on the shoulders of the San Francisco sheriff, because his department had custody of him and made the choice to let him go without notifying ICE," said Jessica Vaughan, director of policy studies at the Washington-based Center for Immigration Studies, which wants tougher immigration enforcement.
Rep. Bob Goodlatte, the Virginia Republican who chairs the House Judiciary Committee, blamed sanctuary practices and the Obama administration, saying: "The tragic murder of Kate Steinle once again underscores the need to end these reckless policies."
Mayor Ed Lee issued a statement saying city policy was never intended to protect "repeat, serious and violent felons." He asked for federal and local agencies to review what happened.
California Attorney General Kamala Harris, a former San Francisco district attorney who is running for U.S. Senate, cautioned that when it comes to immigration, "our policy should not be informed by our collective outrage about one man's conduct."
Many other San Francisco politicians stayed quiet as mourners held a late morning vigil at Pier 14 on the downtown waterfront, where the 32-year-old Steinle was gunned down Wednesday, seemingly at random, during an evening stroll with her father and a family friend. She had recently moved to San Francisco.
While many cities have scaled back cooperation with ICE, few have gone as far as San Francisco.
For more than two decades, San Francisco has been considered a sanctuary for people in the U.S. illegally.
The city's sanctuary law prohibits city employees from helping federal authorities with immigration investigations or arrests unless required by law or warrant. That said, the ordinance does not prohibit local law enforcement from informing ICE that they've arrested someone in the country illegally for a felony offense or who has prior felony convictions.
In 2013, Mirkarimi's office started turning over fewer people under arrest to federal immigration authorities for deportation.
Mirkarimi on Monday stood behind the city's sanctuary law as a way to fight crime and promote trust. His office routinely ignores such federal immigration requests unless backed by an active warrant. He said ICE was aware of San Francisco's policy.
Earlier this year, Sanchez was released from federal prison  where he had served a sentence for re-entering the country after deportation  and turned over to the Sheriff's Department on an outstanding drug-related warrant. The San Francisco district attorney's office declined to prosecute what authorities said was a decade-old marijuana possession case, and Sanchez was freed on April 15.
Before he was set free, ICE had filed a so-called detainer with San Francisco authorities, asking to be informed if they intended to let him go, ICE spokeswoman Gillian Christensen said. But she said ICE was never notified.
"We're not asking local law enforcement to do our job," she said in a statement. "All we're asking is that they notify us when a serious foreign national criminal offender is being released to the street so we can arrange to take custody."
In the past 21 months, immigration authorities have issued more than 230,000 detainers, according to ICE. Since January 2014, law enforcement agencies around the country have failed to honor about 17,000 detainers, 61 percent of them in California, ICE said.
Sanchez has been deported five times, most recently in 2009, and has seven felony convictions, four involving drug charges, according to ICE.
From jail, Sanchez told a KGO-TV reporter in a mix of Spanish and English that he found the gun wrapped in a T-shirt while sitting on a bench at the pier.
"So I picked it up and ... it started to fire on its own," Sanchez said, adding that he heard three shots go off.
Asked if he came to San Francisco because of its sanctuary status, he said yes.
"I only want to say that if the court wants to find me guilty, I wouldn't get mad," Sanchez said during the interview, in which he appeared confused and spoke incoherently at times.
The American Civil Liberties Union of Northern California supports sanctuary protections, saying people are more willing to cooperate with police if there's no fear of deportation.
Julia Harumi Mass, a senior staff attorney with the organization, called the details of this case exceptional and put the blame on ICE.
"It is still unclear why the federal government turned over someone who is known to be deportable to the city of San Francisco, knowing that San Francisco is one of the oldest sanctuary cities in the country," she said.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
