<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="scrippsobfeeds">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:04:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Headlines we're working on</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/your-daily-scoop-for-june-26</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your Daily Scoop for June 26
Stories we're working on
8:04 AM, Jun 26, 2015
Previous
Next
Ave Maria will host a training conference this week. Plus Mason Classical Academy's diversity is being questioned.
Ave Maria will host a training conference this week. Plus Mason Classical Academy's diversity is being questioned.
Gill, Kristine
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
NAPLES, Florida - Ave Maria will host a training conference this week. Plus Mason Classical Academy's diversity is being questioned.
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:59:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Last 3 defendants to be sentenced in FAMU hazing</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/final-3-defendants-to-be-sentenced-in-famu-hazing-death</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Final 3 defendants to be sentenced in FAMU hazing death
Associated Press
6:59 AM, Jun 26, 2015
In this Saturday, Nov. 19, 2011, photo, Robert Champion, a drum major in Florida A&amp;M University's Marching 100 band, performs during halftime of a football game in Orlando. The final three former band members charged with manslaughter and felony hazing in Champion's beating death following a football game are on trial for the November 2011 attack. (AP Photo/The Tampa Tribune, Joseph Brown III, File)
Joseph Brown III
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
ORLANDO, Fla. (AP)  The final three defendants convicted of hazing in the death of a FAMU drum major are set to be sentenced.
Benjamin McNamee, Aaron Golson and Darryl Cearnel face up to 20 years in prison Friday after being convicted in April of manslaughter and hazing in the beating death of Robert Champion, who was from Decatur, Georgia.
Attorneys for all three men have asked Judge Renee Roche in court filings to deviate from imposing a maximum penalty. Roche did so earlier this year when she sentenced hazing ringleader Dante Martin to six and half years in prison. Roche did so because she believed it had been demonstrated that Champion was a "willing participant in the hazing ritual.
Prosecutors had asked for a sentence of nine years in Martin's case.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:55:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fines proposed for backing cars into driveways</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/state/fines-proposed-for-those-who-back-cars-into-driveways-in-jacksonville</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Fines proposed for those who back cars into driveways in Jacksonville
Associated Press
6:55 AM, Jun 26, 2015
Show Caption
Previous
Next
JACKSONVILLE, Fla. (AP)  Jacksonville residents could soon face fines for backing their vehicles into their driveways.
The city council is considering a bill aimed at cracking down on people who store vehicles that don't work on their property.
The Florida Times-Union reports proponents of the bill say code enforcement officers have a difficult time cracking down on abandoned vehicles because they need to see license plate information to write a citation. They aren't allowed to go onto private property to get the information if the vehicle is backed into the driveway.
The proposed bill would require the owner to write down tag information with two-inch tall letters and post it in a location that's easy to spot.
The bill also cracks down on outdoor storage of disabled refrigerators, freezers and other appliances.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:51:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cab driver convicted of raping a drunk passenger</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/cab-driver-convicted-of-raping-a-drunk-passenger</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Cab driver convicted of raping a drunk passenger
Associated Press
6:51 AM, Jun 26, 2015
iStock
Previous
Next
MIAMI (AP)  A Miami cab driver has been convicted of raping a drunken woman after picking her up outside a South Beach nightclub.
The Miami Herald reports 52-year-old Marcel Casimir was convicted Thursday in the 2006 rape of the 24-year-old victim and now faces up to 15 years in prison.
Prosecutors say Casimir picked up the woman outside club Priv in in December 2006 and raped her inside her apartment. She reported the attack the next day. Casimir told detectives he did not have sexual contact with the woman, but prosecutors say a DNA sample taken from the woman later matched Casimir.
Casimir, who drove for Central Cab, did not testify at trial. It is unclear when he will be sentenced.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:48:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Miami-Dade cops shot at for 4th time since April</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/miami-dade-police-officers-shot-at-for-4th-time-since-april</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Miami-Dade police officers shot at for 4th time since April
Associated Press
6:48 AM, Jun 26, 2015
Show Caption
Previous
Next
MIAMI (AP)  A suspect trying to flee opened fire on officers inside an unmarked Miami-Dade police car.
Authorities say it's the fourth time Miami-Dade officers have been shot at since April.
The Miami Herald reports the latest shooting occurred Thursday during a stake out. When officers spotted 29-year-old Edward Lamar Greggs driving away, they followed him. But he fired at the vehicle, striking the passenger side door.
An arrest report says the bullet hit a crossbar in the door, likely keeping it from hitting an officer in the passenger seat.
Greggs was arrested and faces multiple charges. It's not known if he has an attorney.
In May, a suspect shot an officer and is accused of attempted murder of a law enforcement officer.
No one was injured in the other shootings.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:46:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Florida teacher's death investigated as homicide</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/death-of-florida-teacher-investigated-as-homicide</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Death of Florida teacher investigated as homicide
Associated Press
6:46 AM, Jun 26, 2015
Show Caption
Previous
Next
TALLAHASEE, Fla. (AP)  Authorities are investigating the death of a long-time Taylor County educator found shot inside her car.
Authorities say 50-year-old Shelly Strickland was found dead Wednesday. Her death is being investigated as a homicide by the Taylor County Sheriff's Office and the Florida Department of Law Enforcement.
TCSO Capt. Ron Rice says investigators are waiting for Strickland's autopsy results Thursday to develop more facts in the case.
Strickland was a long-time educator who served 29 years in the county. Taylor County Schools Superintendent Paul Dyal says she was the principal Taylor County Elementary for a number of years, then looked to finish her career this year in teaching.
Authorities have no suspects or persons of interest.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:42:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>10 cats, 2 dogs rescued from Ocala home fire</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/state/10-cats-2-dogs-rescued-from-ocala-mobile-home-fire</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>10 cats, 2 dogs rescued from Ocala mobile home fire
Associated Press
6:42 AM, Jun 26, 2015
Show Caption
Previous
Next
OCALA, Fla. (AP)  Marion County Fire Rescue crews have rescued 10 cats, two dogs and a turtle from a fire that tore through an Ocala mobile home.
WFTV-TV reports nine cats died in the fire Thursday night. The homeowner, who rescues stray animals, says she thinks the fire was caused by lightning.
Officials say 25 firefighters and 13 units worked to put out the blaze and save the animals. Crews had the fire under control by 7:30 p.m.
Paramedics worked to administer oxygen to the rescued animals, and the homeowner later took the surviving pets to a veterinarian.
The cause of the fire is still under investigation.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:36:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man gets 95 years for shooting, injuring toddler</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/man-gets-95-years-for-shooting-into-home-injuring-toddler</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man gets 95 years for shooting into home, injuring toddler
Associated Press
6:36 AM, Jun 26, 2015
S.Gnatiuk
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
JACKSONVILLE, Fla. (AP)  A man convicted of injuring a toddler after shooting into a northeast Florida home has been sentenced to 95 years in prison.
A Duval County judge sentenced 30-year-old Joseph Patrick Chambers on Thursday. He was convicted in May of four counts of second-degree attempted murder and one count of shooting deadly missiles.
Prosecutors say he fired shots at the house because of a dispute with someone who lived there.
The Florida Times-Union reports that one of the shots struck a 3-year-old girl in the foot while she sat in her living roo
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:31:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Snooty is oldest manatee on record</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/environment/snooty-the-elderly-manatee-recognized-as-record-holder</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Snooty, the elderly manatee, recognized as record holder
Associated Press
6:31 AM, Jun 26, 2015
Los manaties fueron rescatados en la tarde de ayer y trasladados a primeras horas de la maana de hoy al estuario de Indian River Lagoon. EFE/Archivo
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
BRADENTON, Fla. (AP)  Snooty, the beloved manatee, has had plenty of honors in his long life.
Now he has a new one: Guinness World Records says Snooty is the "World's Oldest Manatee in Captivity."
The South Florida Museum announced the news Thursday.
According to the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, the oldest wild Florida manatee was 59 years old. Snooty will turn 67 on July 21.
The Bradenton Herald reports Snooty lives at the South Florida Museum in Bradenton in the Parker Manatee Aquarium, which he shares with young orphaned or injured wild manatees that are being cared for by museum staff as part of the Manatee Rescue and Rehabilitation partnership.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:26:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Over 70 Cuban, Haitian migrants returned home</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/state/over-70-cuban-haitian-migrants-returned-home-by-coast-guard</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Over 70 Cuban, Haitian migrants returned home by Coast Guard
Associated Press
6:26 AM, Jun 26, 2015
Copyright 2014 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Show Caption
Previous
Next
MIAMI (AP)  U.S. Coast Guard officials say homemade vessels recently used by Cuban migrants attempting to reach Florida shores are a "recipe for disaster."
U.S. authorities returned 55 Cuban migrants to Bahia de Cabanas, Cuba, on Thursday. Coast Guard officials say four of the five vessels carrying those migrants were homemade with no navigation or lifesaving equipment on board.
The fifth vessel was a fishing boat that was caught about 12 miles south of Key West with 18 Cuban migrants aboard.
The Coast Guard also repatriated 18 Haitian migrants Thursday, after their vessel was stopped near Palm Beach Gardens.
Coast Guard officials say their efforts to secure the U.S.-Caribbean border help prevent tragedies at sea.
Since Oct. 1, over 2,245 Haitians, 2,800 Cubans and 469 Dominicans have been captured or intercepted at sea.

Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:14:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lee deputies investigating death in Lehigh Acres</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/crime/lee-county-deputies-investigating-death-in-lehigh-acres</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Lee County deputies investigating death in Lehigh Acres
NBC2
6:14 AM, Jun 26, 2015
File
Previous
Next
A crime scene is cordoned off Friday morning involving a death investigation in Lehigh Acres in the area of Bolt Lane and Wilson Road.
A group of grieving people arrived to the scene saying they are family members of the victim. They said deputies called them saying their family member was killed, NBC2 reports .
Lee County Sheriff's Office only confirms this is a death investigation and they received an initial call about it just before 1 a.m.
After a victim was found lifeless in a driveway, police could be seen collecting evidence. Authorities placed markings along the roadway and a driveway.

Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:22:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Seniors now have rental options in retirement</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/health/discovery-village-offers-rental-options-for-retirement-living_58931340</Link>
        <Description>Discovery Village at Naples is fully pre-leased with a waiting list, evidence of the demand for rental-based retirement communities in Southwest Florida.</Description>
        <MainBody>Discovery Village offers rental options for retirement living
Liz Freeman
top stories | development and construction | health | health and fitness
Discovery Village at Naples, a new 120-unit complex with 90 assisted-living apartments and 30 memory-care suites, is slated to open in July. The facility rents one-bedroom assisted living apartments for $3,895 a month and  $4,295 a month for a memory-care suite, (Submitted)
Melody Tollefson
Three meals a day are included in the monthly rental cost at Discovery Village at Naples. The new 120-unit complex has 90 assisted-living apartments and 30 memory-care suites. (Submitted)
Melody Tollefson
Discovery Village at Naples has a full bar and lounge, as well as an ice cream parlor, media center and separate movie theater.  The new 120-unit complex with 90 assisted-living apartments and 30 memory-care suites, is slated to open in July.  (Submitted)
Melody Tollefson
Discovery Village At Naples is a new rental-based senior retirement community near the intersection of Rattlesnake Hammock Road and Collier Boulevard. It has 90 assisted living apartments and 30 memory care suites. The community will open in early July but it is fully pre-leased with a waiting list. (Liz Freeman/Staff)
Melody Tollefson
Discovery Village At Naples is a new rental-based senior retirement community near the intersection of Rattlesnake Hammock Road and Collier Boulevard. It has 90 assisted living apartments and 30 memory care suites. The community will open in early July but it is fully pre-leased with a waiting list. (Liz Freeman/Staff)
Melody Tollefson
Discovery Village At Naples is a new rental-based senior retirement community near the intersection of Rattlesnake Hammock Road and Collier Boulevard. It has 90 assisted living apartments and 30 memory care suites. The community will open in early July but it is fully pre-leased with a waiting list. (Liz Freeman/Staff)
Melody Tollefson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:00:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Traffic enforcement locations in Collier, Lee</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/traffic/fridays-traffic-enforcement-locations-in-collier-lee062615</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Friday's traffic enforcement locations in Collier, Lee
www.naplesnews.com
5:00 AM, Jun 26, 2015
Copyright Associated Press
NAPLES, Fla. - Here are today's traffic enforcement locations in Collier and Lee counties:
Collier County
The Collier County Sheriff's Office each day lists locations it could target for increased enforcement of traffic violations. In addition to their normal patrols, Collier deputies will target at least one of these locations with stepped up enforcement:
- Livingston Road and Orange Blossom Drive  Red-light running
- Collier Boulevard and Immokalee Road  Aggressive driving
- Golden Gate and Wilson boulevards  Aggressive driving
Lee County
The Lee County Sheriff's Office each day lists locations it could target for increased enforcement of traffic violations. In addition to their normal patrols, Lee deputies will target at least one of these locations with stepped up enforcement:
- Bass Road and Park Royal Drive, Fort Myers
- Iona Road, Fort Myers
- Orange River Boulevard, Fort Myers
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:08:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>2 aspiring journalists earn Reynolds scholarship</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/local-news/two-aspiring-journalists-earn-reynolds-scholarship_65974945</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Two aspiring journalists earn Reynolds scholarship
John Osborne
Doris Reynolds Naples Daily News Journalism Scholarship winner Gabrielle Orphali stands for a portrait at the Naples Daily News on Saturday, June 20, 2015.  (Scott McIntyre/Staff)
Scott McIntyre
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Eleanor Rushing is one of two recipients of the Doris Reynolds Naples Daily News Journalism Scholarship. Rushing, an 18-year-old Naples High School graduate, will receive a one-time award of $5,000 to further her studies on the university level. She will attend Rollins College this fall to study journalism. (David Albers/Staff)
David Albers
Doris Reynolds Naples Daily News Journalism Scholarship winner Gabrielle Orphali stands for a portrait at the Naples Daily News on Saturday, June 20, 2015.  (Scott McIntyre/Staff)
Scott McIntyre
Copyright 2015 Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Eleanor Rushing is one of two recipients of the Doris Reynolds Naples Daily News Journalism Scholarship. Rushing, an 18-year-old Naples High School graduate, will receive a one-time award of $5,000 to further her studies on the university level. She will attend Rollins College this fall to study journalism. (David Albers/Staff)
David Albers
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:07:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Briefs_firefighter-webteaser</title>
        <Link>http://www.naplesnews.com/news/briefs_firefighterwebteaser_98509000</Link>
        <Description>Watch a video of firefighter Robert Moore discussing his injury.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share Article
Subscribe to the Naples Daily News
Ready to subscribe to the Naples Daily News? Choose between a Premium or Digital subscription below.
Need Help? Call us at 1-888-878-6842.
Monday-Friday: 6am-6pm / Saturday: 7am-3pm / Sunday: 7am-2pm
Comments
Want to participate in the conversation? Log in or become a subscriber today.  Subscribers can read and comment on any story, anytime.  Non-subscribers will only be able to view comments on select stories.
Trending stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
