<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Sky-News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:19:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Warned To Get 'Serious' At Euro Talks</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514481</Link>
        <Description>France and Germany say there is no time for bluffing or time-wasting as Greece's PM makes his big pitch to eurozone leaders.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Greece Warned To Get 'Serious' At Euro Talks
France and Germany say there is no time for bluffing or time-wasting as Greece's PM makes his big pitch to eurozone leaders.
14:19, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Play video "Greece Extends Bank Closures"
Video: Greece Extends Bank Closures
Share by email
Greece is under intense pressure to show "serious, credible" plans on how it can remain in the euro as its prime minister faces a showdown with eurozone leaders.
The country is perilously close to leaving the currency after some 61% of voters rejected a new bailout deal that demanded further austerity measures.
Newly appointed Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos at the eurozone talks
Prime Minister Alexis Tsiprasis expected to present new proposals to an emergency eurozone summit later today.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel and French President Francois Hollande, who met in Paris on Monday, have said "the door is open" at today's crisis talks - but signalled there is no time for bluffing or protracted negotiations.
Play video "What Next For Greece?"
Video: What Next For Greece?
"It is now up to the government of Alexis Tsipras to make serious, credible proposals so that this willingness to stay in the eurozone can translate into a lasting programme," said Mr Hollande.
Mrs Merkel, under pressure in Germany to cut Athens loose, said the conditions for a new bailout to keep Greece from collapse had not yet been met and demanded "very precise proposals" at the summit in Brussels.
Fears are mounting that banks and cash machines in Greece could run dry if a deal cannot be hammered out in the next few days on its 240bn (170bn) debt.
As the country enters uncharted territory - no state has ever left the currency - its government backtracked on promises that banks would reopen on Tuesday.
1/10
Gallery: Anxious Greeks Play The Waiting Game Ahead Of Crucial Euro Talks
After the euphoria of the referendum result on Sunday, ordinary Greeks are now anxiously waiting on the results of key talks on the euro crisis. Continue through for more images
They will now stay shut until at least Thursday, with a 60 (42) daily limit on ATM withdrawals, that has seen long queues at cash machines, kept in place.
There was some relief on Monday when the European Central Bank (ECB) said it would maintain the Emergency Liquidity Assistance (ELA) Greece needs to keep its banking system afloat.
But the ECB also said it was "adjusting" the conditions - which could make it tougher for some Greek banks to qualify for help.
Mr Tsipras, who praised "brave" Greek voters' rejection of austerity, said he was hopeful of a deal by this evening when he makes his pitch to eurozone leaders.
Play video "Latest: Greece Travel Advice"
Video: Latest: Greece Travel Advice
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker warned that "in Europe there are no simple answers" but added: "We have to find a solution".
Mr Tsipras heads into the talks without his right-hand man, Yanis Varoufakis, who quit as finance minister on Monday.
His departure is said to be a concession to other European ministers apparently angered by his uncompromising stance.
Mr Varoufakis had described demands for further austerity as "fiscal waterboarding".
1/10
Gallery: Greece Referendum: What The European Papers Say
Here's how the papers in Germany and Greece see the country's 'No' vote against more austerity measures. Taxydromos: Sweepingly 'no' from the Greeks
"I shall wear the creditors' loathing with pride," Mr Varoufakis told reporters before later leaving his office with his wife on the back of his motorcycle.
Euclid Tsakalotos, his more mild-mannered replacement, is also painting himself as no pushover, warning Greece "cannot accept a non-viable deal".
A key stumbling block at the talks is likely to be any demands to write-off more debt and Sky's Economics Editor Ed Conway says there is "still a lot of distance between the two sides".
Despite celebrations on the streets after Sundays referendum, three-quarters of Greeks say they want to stay in the euro.
1/23
Gallery: Greece Referendum: Supporters Of The 'No' Campaign Celebrate
'No' campaigners celebrate in Athens following the referendum results
A so-called "Grexit" and a return to the drachma could be catastrophic for the country.
Greeces economy has already shrunk 25% since 2008 and it has been suggested a euro exit could see a further 25% contraction. One in four people in the country is also unemployed and among under-25s the figure is nearly 52%.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:25:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russian Bombers Intercepted Off US Coast</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514728</Link>
        <Description>Fighter jets are scrambled after four long-range Tu-95 "Bear" bombers fly close to Alaska and California on Independence Day.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Russian Bombers Intercepted Off US Coast
Fighter jets are scrambled after four long-range Tu-95 "Bear" bombers fly close to Alaska and California on Independence Day.
12:25, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Four TU-95 "Bear" bombers flew close to the US on Independence Day
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
Four Russian bombers caused the US Air Force to scramble fighter jets after they flew close to the US coast, according to reports.
Two Russian Tu-95 "Bear" bombers were intercepted off Alaska at around 10.30am Eastern Time on Independence Day by two F-22 Raptor jets.
Just half an hour later another pair of Tu-95s were detected off the central coast of California and two F-15 Eagles were scrambled to intercept.
A spokeswoman for the North American Aerospace Defense Command (NORAD) did not confirm if either of the long-range bombers was armed, Fox News reported.
None of the Russian aircraft entered US airspace, which is 12 nautical miles off the coast, but defence officials have not revealed how close they were to US soil.
Michael Kucharek, a spokesman for NORAD, told Fox News: "These are not unprecedented flights, but we are postured to respond whether Alaska or California.
"At no time did the bombers enter North American sovereign airspace."
Russian bombers also flew close to US coastlines on 4 July 2013.
Last year, two more long-range bombers flew within 50 miles of California .
There have been at least 50 reported incidents of Russian aircraft being intercepted by US Air Force jets since 2006, the Washington Times reported.
The incident occurred on the same day that Russian President Vladimir Putin sent a congratulatory message to US President Barack Obama to mark Independence Day.
In 2014, Russian defence officials announced long-range bombers would expand their regular patrols to the Arctic, the Caribbean and the Gulf of Mexico.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:00:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant Found Dead In Channel Tunnel</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514615</Link>
        <Description>The incident comes days after around 150 migrants tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrant Found Dead In Channel Tunnel
The incident comes days after around 150 migrants tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.
11:00, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Both passenger and freight services have been disrupted
A migrant has died trying to reach Britain through the Channel Tunnel on a freight train.
Operator Eurotunnelsaid the incident happened near Calais at around 5amBST (6am local time).
A section of the tunnel was closed for investigation and both freight and passenger services have been disrupted.
"Following the discovery of migrants on a freight shuttle, early this morning, the shuttle was immediately stopped," said a French official.
"During an investigation by border police, a deceased migrant was found in the tunnel," he added.
Play video "Tunnel Travel Chaos After Strike"
Video: Tunnel Travel Chaos After Strike
Authorities have yet to say how the migrant died.
It is the second migrant fatality in as many weeks following the death of an Eritrean while trying to get on a train at Coquelles last month.
A Eurotunnel spokesman said freight services were affected more than passenger trains, which were"running with slight delays".
He added: "We are working very hard to restore full services as soon as possible."
Play video "Migrants Try To Get On To Lorries"
Video: Migrants Try To Get On To Lorries
The incident comes days after around 150 migrants caused delays and cancellations when they tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.
There have been increased calls for a resolution to the migrant crisis in Calais, which has escalated in recent months.
Around 3,000 people displaced from countries including Eritrea, Syria and Afghanistan have set up camp near the port.
Last week more than 3,000 truckers had to queue for several days in high temperatures on the M20 following a wildcat strike by ferry workers in France.
Play video "Inside Asylum-Seeker Camp (Archive)"
Video: Inside Asylum-Seeker Camp (Archive)
Hauliers have also faced problems with migrants desperately trying to clamber on board theirHGVs to the UK.
French authorities have faced claims they are not doing enough to safeguard lorry drivers from intimidation and violence.
The Road Haulage Association (RHA) has suggested deployment of the French military to boost security in Calais amid growing fears that a death could occur.
Port of Dover officials said last week's ferry strike cost the UK economy 1bn.
Play video "Queues At St Pancras And Kent"
Video: Queues At St Pancras And Kent
They have joined calls for "robust contingency plans" to be introduced to ensure the port - a 100bntrade route - can operate unimpeded.
Home Secretary Theresa May and her French counterpart Bernard Cazeneuve last week agreed to increase the joint intervention fund to improve security in and around the Channel Tunnel.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:34:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three Gored During 'Crazy' Pamplona Bull Run</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514757</Link>
        <Description>One regular visitor to the event says the run was "very crazy, very fast" and "very dangerous", and it is lucky no-one was killed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Three Gored During 'Crazy' Pamplona Bull Run
One regular visitor to the event says the run was "very crazy, very fast" and "very dangerous", and it is lucky no-one was killed.
13:34, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Play video "Several Injured In Bull Run"
Video: Several Injured In Bull Run
A British man and two Americans have been gored at the annual Running of the Bulls in the northern Spanish city of Pamplona.
One of the Americans was reportedly injured in the armpit and the Briton in the perineum.
None was said to be in a serious condition.
Eight other people suffered minor injuries - mainly bruising - during the first bull run of Pamplona's San Fermin festival.
It happened as six animals made their way through the streets to the city's bull ring with daredevil members of the public running ahead of them.
1/17
Gallery: Several Runners Gored By Bulls In The San Fermin Festival In Pamplona, Spain
Several bull-runners, including a Briton and two Americans, have been gored during the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain
Peter Remington, from Houston, Texas, who was celebrating his 25th visit to the festival, said: "This one was very crazy, very fast.
"I was down at La Curva. One brown bull had a guy by his pants and was dragging him down the street right by the curve. It was very dangerous."
Fellow American Larry Belcher, who has been taking part in the Running of the Bulls for 40 years, said: "Today was really nasty.
"(One bull) hooked a kid beside down on the curve. I'm not sure whether he took a horn wound or whether he was just rolled around on the cobblestones.
"I'm not sure. I'm just glad it's over and now we can just settle down and seriously try to run."
Every year thousands of tourists from Spain and across the world descend on Pamplona to take part in the festival.
The event was made famous by the American writer Ernest Hemingway in his book The Sun Also Rises.
In all 15 people have been gored to death during the bull run since records began in 1924.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:59:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al Shabaab Gunmen Attack Sleeping Villagers</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514555</Link>
        <Description>Officials say the attackers "just came and hurled explosives" inside houses while people were asleep.</Description>
        <MainBody>Al Shabaab Gunmen Attack Sleeping Villagers
Officials say the attackers "just came and hurled explosives" inside houses while people were asleep.
11:59, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Kenyan troops near the scene of the attack
Share by email
At least 14 people have been killed and 11 wounded in an attack on a residential complex in northeastern Kenya.
Somalia-based al Shabaab militants have said they carried out the raid, at a village near the town of Mandera.
It follows a similar attack last December in which 36 quarry workers were killed.
The entrance to the residential complex
"People were sleeping they just came and hurled explosives in the houses," said Mandera County Commissioner Alex Ole Nkoyo.
"These were al Shabaab from the nature of the attack. They used explosives and guns."
Play video "Survivors Describe Their Ordeal"
Video: Survivors Describe Their Ordeal
Mr Nkoyo said most of the victims worked in a nearby quarry.
Kenya police chief Joseph Boinnetsaid on Twitter: "I can confirm a Shabaab attack in Mandera early this morning."
The Red Cross said it had taken 11 people to hospital and had sent a medical airplane to evacuate the critically-injured to the capital Nairobi.
Play video "More Gunfire Heard At Kenya Mall"
Video: More Gunfire Heard At Kenya Mall
Al Shabaab, which has links to al Qaeda, has been increasingly targeting Kenya over its involvement in the African Union peacekeeping mission in Somalia.
In its deadliest attack to date, in April, four gunmen killed 148 people at a university in the town of Garissa. Most of the victims werestudents.
In 2013, members of the group ran amok at the Westgate shopping mall in Nairobi, killing at least 67 people.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:19:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama: Fight Against IS 'Will Not Be Quick'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514591</Link>
        <Description>The President says it is hard for security agencies to prevent "lone wolf" attacks on US soil, during a speech at the Pentagon.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Obama: Fight Against IS 'Will Not Be Quick'
The President says it is hard for security agencies to prevent "lone wolf" attacks on US soil, during a speech at the Pentagon.
09:19, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Mr Obama said there were no plans to send more US troops to Syria and Iraq
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
Barack Obama has said the US needs to do more to combat the threat of Islamic State and has insisted the military campaign will take time to complete.
The US President said security agencies must focus on preventing attacks at home and prevent IS attempts to recruit followers during a visit to the Pentagon.
He said it was difficult for security agencies to prevent small-scale attacks by "lone wolves" on US soil, despite success at preventing larger scale attacks since the September 11, 2001, attacks on New York and Washington.
But he insisted there were no current plans to send more US troops overseas, and said moderate Syrian rebels needed training and equipping to combat the extremists.
He said: "This will not be quick. This is a long-term campaign. It will take time to root them out, and doing so must be the job of local forces on the ground with training and air support from our coalition.
Play video "Will UK Airstrikes Have Any Effect?"
Video: Will UK Airstrikes Have Any Effect?
"We continue to accelerate the delivery of critical equipment, including anti-tank weapons, to Iraqi security forces.
"And I have made it clear to my team that we will do more to train and equip the moderate opposition in Syria."
On small-scale attacks in the US, he added: "We're going to have to pick up our game to prevent these attacks."
Play video "22 May: Town Under I.S. Control"
Video: 22 May: Town Under I.S. Control
Mr Obama said US attempts to counter extremism and prevent recruitment must not single out Muslim Americans or any faith group.
He said: "We also have to acknowledge that ISIL has been particularly effective at reaching out to and recruiting vulnerable people around the world, including here in the US."
Mr Obama met more than 30 officials and national security advisers during his rare visit to the Pentagon.
Play video "Special Report: IS Recruitment"
Video: Special Report: IS Recruitment
Last August the US led an international airstrike operation on key IS positions within Iraq and Syria. So far there have been around 5,000 strikes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:11:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Worst Footie Team Ever? Micronesia Lose 46-0</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514606</Link>
        <Description>Micronesia's coach admits it was "boys against men" after his team suffered their third hiding in a row at the Pacific Games.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Worst Footie Team Ever? Micronesia Lose 46-0
Micronesia's coach admits it was "boys against men" after his team suffered their third hiding in a row at the Pacific Games.
11:11, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
1/5
Gallery: Footballing Minnows Micronesia Suffer Third Thrashing
Micronesia lined up against Vanuatu after suffering heavy losses against Fiji and Tajiti. Pics: @darlingkevin/Twitter
Share by email
A football team have been beaten 46-0 in one of the most lopsided games ever seen in international football.
Micronesia's drubbing by Vanuatu followed a 38-0 loss to Fiji and a 30-0 score line against Tahiti at the Pacific Games in Papua New Guinea.
It meant the Federated States of Micronesia conceded a total of 114 goals in their three group matches.
Their Australian coach Stan Foster admitted it was "boys against men" and called for help from FIFA, football's world governing body.
"I'm hoping that FIFA will be coming (to Micronesia) next week for inspections and to hopefully affiliate us with Asia," he said.
"If they do, that will lead to us having technical assistance and everything else that brings. That would be a huge boost."
The half-time score was 24-0 but Vanuatu, ranked 200 in the world, showed their opponents no mercy, almost doubling their tally in the second half.
Vanuatu striker Jean Kaltack is now the tournament's top scorer
Vanuatu striker Jean Kaltack helped himself to 16 goals, making him the tournament's top scorer.
"They're boys, not men," Foster said of his team. "And they've been playing against well-seasoned men. I'm hoping the majority of our boys will be here for at least eight years."
Organisers said it was the biggest win in the history of international football, although it is unlikely to go in the record books as Micronesia is not a member of FIFA and it was an under-23 game.
The previous biggest defeat in a senior international was American Samoa's 31-0 loss to Australia in 2001.
Journalist Kevin Darling , reporting from the tournament, told Sky News the team were trying their best.
"The problem is it's not a squad of footballers, it's just a squad of normal blokes," he said.
"The goalkeeper told me he went in goal for the first time ever three weeks ago. And it showed, to be fair.
"Hopefully in 10 years or so they'll have a proper team and this would have all been worth it."
There was some good news for Micronesia as they were told they would be welcomed back when the event is next held in four years.
"That was big relief for me, because I was really worried the organisers would take us out of the competition," said Foster.
"I've been assured that we'll be allowed to come back and that they're aware that this is a development squad."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:55:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China Stocks Sink Despite Intervention Effort</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514734</Link>
        <Description>The Asian stock markets remain volatile, with Shanghai down 1.29% or 48.79 points at close, despite Monday's boost.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sponsored By
China Stocks Sink Despite Intervention Effort
The Asian stock markets remain volatile, with Shanghai down 1.29% or 48.79 points at close, despite Monday's boost.
12:55, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Mainland Chinese markets had enjoyed unprecedented growth
Share by email
Chinese markets fell by as much as 5.05% on Tuesday, despite interventions from the Chinese government aimed at averting a stock market collapse.
Emergency intervention measures introduced by the Chinese government over the weekend seem to be failing to stabilise the markets, in what analysts say is a make-or-break week for the Asian finance sector.
The measures include supporting brokerages and fund managers to allow them to buy more stock using a direct line of liquidity from the Chinese central bank, and halting the release of all initial public offerings, or IPOs, for the near future to encourage traders to buy existing stock rather than new releases.
Shanghai closed down 1.29%, or 48.79 points on Tuesday despite enjoying a boost following the announcement of the measures on Monday, and Chinas second exchange in Shenzhen also slumped by 5.34%.
Hong Kong finished 1.03% down, losing 260.97 points to end at 24975.31, extending losses of 3.18% from Monday.
The mainland Chinese markets have plunged almost 30% in recent weeks after enjoying massive growth in the past 12-18 months.
Previous attempts by China to arrest the slump - including an interest rate cut, relaxed rules on margin trading and proposals to let the state social security funds invest in equities - have so far failed, with analysts saying the new measures are unlikely to make a difference either.
"The more resources authorities commit to propping up the stock market, the more they ratchet up the potential fall-out risks should the market continue to collapse," said Andrew Wood, an analyst at BMI Research.
"This could give rise to a crisis of confidence in the authorities' ability to support both the stock market and the real economy."

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:23:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cosby: I Got Sedatives To Have Sex With Women</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514469</Link>
        <Description>The comedian's lawyers fail to block documents showing he admitted acquiring drugs, despite arguing they were "embarrassing".</Description>
        <MainBody>Cosby: I Got Sedatives To Have Sex With Women
The comedian's lawyers fail to block documents showing he admitted acquiring drugs, despite arguing they were "embarrassing".
10:23, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Play video "Bill Cosby: I Did Drug Woman"
Video: Bill Cosby: I Did Drug Woman
Share by email
Comedian Bill Cosby admitted in 2005 obtaining sedatives with the intent of giving them to women he wanted to have sex with.
The US star made the admission in a civil law suit and documents from that case have only just been made public.
More than 40 women have come forward in the past year to claim that Cosby sexually assaulted them - some also believing they were drugged.
Lawyer Gloria Allred pictured with two alleged victims in January
Cosby admitted under oath he had obtained Quaaludes, known as Mandrax in the UK, after a woman named Andrea Constand sued him for allegedly drugging and assaulting her.
In his deposition, Cosby admitted giving it to at least one woman but claimed he had only given Ms Costand the allergy medicine Benadryl.
Play video "March: Cosby In Odd Video Message"
Video: March: Cosby In Odd Video Message
The case was settled for an undisclosed amount in 2006.
Cosby's lawyers tried to stop the information being released, arguing it would cause him serious embarrassment but the AP news agency won the right to make the documents public.
Celebrity lawyer Gloria Allred, who is representing many of the alleged victims, said it "confirms the allegations of numerous victims who have alleged that he had used drugs to sexually assault them".
1/14
Gallery: A Profile Of Bill Cosby
Bill Cosby was born in Philadelphia in 1937, one of four children
The actor-comedian, best known for hit sitcom The Cosby Show, has never been criminally charged.
Many of the claims date back to the 1970s and are too old for him to face legal proceedings.
But the star has seen his career nosedive since the allegations started to pile up, with TV shows and live events being cancelled.
Play video "Jan: Bill Cosby Heckled"
Video: Jan: Bill Cosby Heckled
Cosbys representatives have dismissed previous claims as "absolutely false" but have yet to respond to the release of the court documents.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:16:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'China's Walter White' Held 'For Selling Drugs'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514695</Link>
        <Description>Police say a university professor set up a chemistry lab and sold an ecstasy substitute online to clients across the world.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
'China's Walter White' Held 'For Selling Drugs'
Police say a university professor set up a chemistry lab and sold an ecstasy substitute online to clients across the world.
11:16, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Actor Bryan Cranston in character as Breaking Bad's Walter White
Share by email
A Chinese professor has been arrested for allegedly selling drugs worth millions of dollars to clients in the US, Britain, Canada and Australia, Chinese state media reported.
The man, identified only as Zhang, was dubbed by the official Xinhua news agency "China's real-life Walter White" in reference to the chemistry teacher-turned-drug kingpin in the TV series Breaking Bad.
According to the allegations, Zhang sold methylone, a psychoactive drug commonly used as a substitute for MDMA, or ecstasy, over the internet.
He first learned about the popularity of such drugs while teaching as a visiting academic in Australia, Xinhua reported.
He then started a chemical company in 2005 and had staff manufacture "hundreds of kilograms" of methylone.
Last month, police raided Zhang's lab in the city of Wuhan and reportedly found 20kg of drugs. Eight people were arrested then.
Zhang, a professor in an unidentified university in Wuhan, is believed to have made millions of dollars, according to police, though no exact figure was provided.
Between March and November 2014, the business allegedly sold at least 193kg of the substance to the overseas customers.
Last May police said they had arrested a former chemistry professor on suspicion of selling a drug recipe to a gang which cooked up synthetic narcotics.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
