<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Sky-News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:30:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Car Bombs Kill 10 At Top Baghdad Hotels</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492476</Link>
        <Description>The blasts, which appear to have been coordinated, went off in the car parks of the hotels a few minutes apart.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Car Bombs Kill 10 At Top Baghdad Hotels
The blasts, which appear to have been coordinated, went off in the car parks of the hotels a few minutes apart.
00:30, UK, Friday 29 May 2015
Smoke rises above one of the hotels where a car bomb exploded
Share by email
At least 10 people have been killed after car bombs exploded at two luxury hotels popular with Westerners in Baghdad, say police.
Reuters reported that a further 30 have been wounded after the blasts, which AP said involved at least one suicide bomber.
Photos on Twitter taken by witnesses show large explosions and palls of smoke rising above the scene.
AP said the two hotels targeted were the Cristal Grand Ishtar, which used to be the Sheraton, and the Babylon Warwick.
The two blasts appear to have been coordinated
Both blasts went off in the car parks.
Several media outlets are thought to be based at the Cristal.
The blasts appear to have been coordinated and went off at around midnight local time (10pm UK time), a few minutes apart.
The first bomb hit the Babylon hotel, where government officials often hold meetings and news conferences, killing six people and wounding 14 others.
The second was outside the Cristal, which is adjacent to the Palestine Hotel, where four people died and 13 were injured.
The bombings come after Iraqi authorities lifted a decade-old night-time curfew in Baghdad earlier this year, as they sought to restore a sense of normality to the capital.
Nobody has claimed responsibility, but a growing number of attacks are being claimed by Islamic State since the group seized large amounts of the country last year.
On 17 May, insurgents seized the city of Ramadi, about 70 miles (100km) west of Baghdad, in the most significant military setback to the government since a US-led coalition launched a campaign of airstrikes against IS last August.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:05:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British Girls In Syria 'No Longer Together'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492358</Link>
        <Description>The teenagers are said to be "safe and in good health" but "unlikely to be returning to the UK in the immediate future".</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
British Girls In Syria 'No Longer Together'
The teenagers are said to be "safe and in good health" but "unlikely to be returning to the UK in the immediate future".
20:05, UK, Thursday 28 May 2015
Kadiza Sultana, Shamima Begum and Adiza Abase
Share by email
Three schoolgirls from London who crossed into Syria in February are no longer together, their families' solicitors have revealed.
Shamima Begum, Amira Abase and Kadiza Sultanaleft their east London homes for Syria, two months after a fellow pupil is thought to have left to join IS there.
And Waterford Solicitors said "some of the girls" had made contact with their families in the UK.
"They have made it known that they are safe and in good health but are no longer in the company of one another," the firm said on Twitter.
The three girls were captured by CCTV at Gatwick, on their way to Syria
"Furthermore, they have intimated that they are unlikely to be returning to the UK in the immediate future.
"The families are grateful to know that their daughters are alive and in good health."
Play video "'Special Mission' For IS Brit Girls"
Video: 'Special Mission' For IS Brit Girls
It comes after a senior female commander from Islamic State told Sky News she has no doubt the trio were groomed by a team of social media experts in Raqqa.
The woman, who calls herself Um Asmah and who defected from IS just days ago, was the first person to contact foreign girls crossing the border.
The 22-year-old said they will "never" go home and are more likely to "die in Iraq or Syria".
"IS is not stupid, they have educated people who know how to deal with (the) psychology of others, how to deal with the human being. All these are in IS," she said.
Play video "Inside The IS Social Media Centre"
Video: Inside The IS Social Media Centre
"They have ways to attract people - especially foreigners. Otherwise young British people wouldn't come and say they will change the flag on Buckingham Palace.
"IS have the ability to manipulate the minds of young people. If they can convince foreigners, it is even easier to convince Arabs and Syrians.
"They have freedom and everything is available - they have no need to come to Syria but they do."
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu May 28 12:33:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First Footage Of Islamic State Grooming HQ</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492005</Link>
        <Description>The internet cafe is where fighters target young foreigners, preying on their vulnerability, to entice them to join Islamic State.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
First Footage Of Islamic State Grooming HQ
The internet cafe is where fighters target young foreigners, preying on their vulnerability, to entice them to join Islamic State.
10:33, UK, Thursday 28 May 2015
Play video "Inside The IS Social Media Centre"
Video: Inside The IS Social Media Centre
Share by email
Sky News has obtained exclusive pictures of the online grooming centre used by terror group Islamic State.
The internet cafe in the Syrian city of Raqqa is the heart of the IS online operation, where fighters try to persuade young and vulnerable foreigners to leave their homes and travel to the war-torn country.
Sky News Chief Correspondent Stuart Ramsaysaid the cameraman had risked his life to get the footage.
It shows fighters and children milling around, chatting and laughing in the cafe, where they work in shifts according to their nationality and the time zones of the people they are targeting.
Ramsayalso spoke with Um Asmah, one of the most senior defectors from IS, who shared information on the sophisticated grooming plans to bring young foreigners to Syria to train and then return home to carry out attacks.
Play video "'Special Mission' For IS Brit Girls"
Video: 'Special Mission' For IS Brit Girls
She said: "IS is not stupid, they have educated people who know how to deal with (the) psychology of others, how to deal with the human being. All these are in IS.
"IS have the ability to manipulate the minds of young people. If they can convince foreigners, it is even easier to convince Arabs and Syrians."
The interview came as a study warned against thinking that women travel to Syria solely to become "jihadibrides".
It described the theory as "simplistic" and "hinder(ing) efforts to prevent other girls from being radicalised".
Other motivations include anger over the perceived persecution of Muslims and the wish to belong to a sisterhood of shared beliefs, according to the Institute for Strategic Dialogue and the International Centre for the Study of Radicalisation at King's College London.
The report's authors, Erin Saltman and Melanie Smith, say that describing the women as "brainwashed, groomed, innocent girls hinders understanding of the threat they pose".
Ms Smith said: "They're not being taken seriously. It's inherently dangerous to label people with the same brush."
Play video "Where Are Islamic State Strongholds"
Video: Where Are Islamic State Strongholds
Around 550 young women, some as young as 13, are estimated to have already travelled to Islamic State-controlled territory.
The authors looked at the social media accounts of more than 100 females on Twitter, Facebook and Tumblr, using photos, online chats and other accounts to place them in Syria or Iraq.
The women came from 15 countries and were largely operating in English.
They often talked about the camaraderie they experienced after moving to IS-controlled territory, regularlyposting images of veiled "sisters" posing together.
This was in contrast to the "false feeling or surface-level relationships" they talked of having held in the West, the report says.
The report says some women go in search of romance and marriage.
Play video "Missing Amira's Dad: 'Come Home'"
Video: Missing Amira's Dad: 'Come Home'
Images shared online of a lion and lioness are used to symbolise a union with a "brave, strong husband".
The idea promoted by the group's social media "messengers" is that "supporting a jihadist husband and taking on the ISIS ideology is an empowering role for females".
But the reality is quite different.
Any woman posting messages critical of life under IS is quickly reprimanded, say the report's authors, with the Twitter hashtag #nobodycaresaboutthewidow having only a very short cyberlife, for example.
But some women living under IS warn those following them that they should be ready to "be tested" by intermittent electricity, water shortages, bitter winters and the challenges of life in a warzone.
Healthcare is particularly difficult, with one western woman describing her experience of having a miscarriage in an IS hospital because she could not communicate with the doctor.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:40:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter: Scandal Brings 'Shame And Humiliation'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492234</Link>
        <Description>The head of world football says a "tiny" number of people are corrupt but admits he "cannot monitor everyone all of the time".</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Blatter: Scandal Brings 'Shame And Humiliation'
The head of world football says a "tiny" number of people are corrupt but admits he "cannot monitor everyone all of the time".
21:40, UK, Thursday 28 May 2015
Play video "FIFA President Condemns Corruption"
Video: FIFA President Condemns Corruption
Share by email
FIFA President Sepp Blatter has opened world football's congress - hours after refusing a request by UEFA to step down.
It is the first time he has been seen in public since the organisation he heads was mired in scandal after it was involved in two separate corruption investigations.
Mr Blatter, who admitted there would be "more bad news" to come, said: "You will agree with me, these are unprecedented and difficult times for FIFA.
"They demand action and change from us all. It has to stop here and now.
"The events of yesterday have cast a long shadow over football and over this week's congress.
Play video "Sponsors Upset Over FIFA Scandal"
Video: Sponsors Upset Over FIFA Scandal
"Actions of individuals, if proven, bring shame and humiliation on football, and demand action and change from us all.
"We cannot allow the reputation of football and FIFA to be dragged through the mud any longer. It has to stop here and now.
"I know many people hold me ultimately responsible for the actions and reputation of the global football community, whether it is a decision for the hosting of a World Cup or a corruption scandal.
"We, or I, cannot monitor everyone all of the time. But it must fall to me to bear the responsibility for the reputation and wellbeing of our organisation, and find a way to fix things."
Play video "Platini: Europe Could Quit FIFA"
Video: Platini: Europe Could Quit FIFA
Mr Blatter was speaking after saying he intends to run for president for a fifth term despite a call by UEFA head Michel Platini for him to quit.
Mr Platini earlier said UEFA could quit FIFA and European teams may not take part in some tournaments including the World Cup if action is not taken to address the alleged corruption.
The European football body decided it would not boycott the congress but is supporting Mr Blatter's opponent Prince Ali bin al Hussein of Jordan in the presidential race.
The vote for president takes place on Friday.
Play video "Gill: I'll Quit FIFA Over Blatter"
Video: Gill: I'll Quit FIFA Over Blatter
Mr Blatter opened the congress after Swiss police confirmed they will be questioning 10 FIFA executives over the decision to award World Cups to Russia and Qatar, and sponsors expressed serious concerns over a corruption scandal engulfing the governing body.
After Mr Blatter's speech, the United Nations said it was reviewing its partnerships with FIFA.
On Wednesday, seven senior FIFA officials were arrested in an early morning raid on their five-star hotel in Zurich as part of an FBI and US Department of Justice investigation into 24-year 96m ($150m) bribery racket.
Two of them, Jeffrey Webb and Eduardo Li, were "provisionally dismissed" by CONCACAF, football's governing body for North America on Thursday evening.
Play video "Russian President, Vladimir Putin"
Video: Russian President, Vladimir Putin
The British member of FIFA's executive committee, former Manchester United CEO David Gill, said earlier he would resign from the body, where he is a vice president, if Mr Blatter is re-elected.
Mr Platini said he had held the private conversation with Mr Blatter because he regarded him as a friend but had urged Mr Blatter to step down because he was giving FIFA a "terrible image".
He said the FIFA president had told him he could not stand down because the congress was about to start.
Mr Platini said: "I was very clear, I told him that I would have liked to have told him this among the two of us.
Play video "'FIFA Has Taken A Battering'"
Video: 'FIFA Has Taken A Battering'
"I'm saying this with sadness and tears in my eyes, but there have been too many scandals, FIFA doesn't deserve to be treated that way."
David Cameron has said he welcomes the investigation in world football's controlling body, tweeting: "I welcome the probe into allegations of FIFA corruption and bribery, and support the FA's call for new leadership and reform."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:40:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA Execs To Be Questioned Over World Cup Vote</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1491936</Link>
        <Description>Swiss police are due to interview 10 officials over the 2018/22 World Cup vote, as FIFA's congress gets under way.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
FIFA Execs To Be Questioned Over World Cup Vote
Swiss police are due to interview 10 officials over the 2018/22 World Cup vote, as FIFA's congress gets under way.
21:40, UK, Thursday 28 May 2015
Play video "'FIFA Has Taken A Battering'"
Video: 'FIFA Has Taken A Battering'
Share by email
Swiss police have said they want to question 10 senior FIFA executives over the decision to award World Cups to Russia and Qatar.
The Executive Committee members - including Russia's Sports Minister VitalyMutko - were involved in the controversial vote for the 2018/2022 tournaments, which is under investigation by Swiss authorities.
The probe is separate from allegations of a96m bribery racket stretching back 24 years, which saw seven senior FIFA officials arrested in an early morning raid on their five-star hotel in Zurich on Wednesday.
Ten senior executives are to be questioned over the 2018/2022 tournaments
The interviews were due to take place as FIFApresident SeppBlatter opened the body's congress, saying that corruption scandals engulfing it bring "shame and humiliation".
The other nine of the ten due to be questioned have been named as Michel D'Hooghe (Belgium), Jacques Anouma (Ivory Coast), Marios Lefkaritis (Cyprus), Angel Villar-Llona (Spain), Senes Erzik (Turkey, Worawi Makudi (Thailand), Issa Hayatou (Cameroon), Hany Abo Rida (Egypt) and Rafael Salguero (Guatemala).
1/10
Gallery: FIFA Officials Facing Swiss Police Questions
Dr Michel D'Hooghe has been on FIFA's Executive Committee since 1988 and is a specialist in sports medicine and rehabilitation
It is not known whether the interviews with Swiss prosecuting authorities have started.
Andre Marty, spokesman for the Swiss attorney general's office, said on Wednesday night that prosecutors had chosen this week to carry out the interviews because they knew the executives would be in the country.
The FIFA congress started on Thursday afternoon and was expected to continue throughout Friday, when Mr Blatter was expected to win a fifth term as president.
Play video "Sponsors Upset Over FIFA Scandal"
Video: Sponsors Upset Over FIFA Scandal
US authorities have said nine different FIFA executives and five sports media and promotions executives face charges over allegations they were part of "rampant and systemic and deep-rooted" corruption running through football.
Seven of those nine men were arrested in Zurich on Wednesday at the request of the US Department of Justice who want them extradited.
Six of those seven have opposed extradition, meaning US authorities now have 40 days to submit formal extradition requests. They face up to 20 years in prison if convicted.
Play video "Debate: Should The FA Leave FIFA?"
Video: Debate: Should The FA Leave FIFA?
Former FIFA executives on the indictment are Jack Warner and Nicolas Leoz, former FIFA executive committee member and South American Football Confederation president.
The US Department of Justice alleges that Mr Warner - who denies wrongdoing - solicited $10m in bribes from the South African government to host the 2010 World Cup.
He surrendered to police in Trinidad on Wednesday after an arrest warrant was issued at the request of US authorities and was granted bail.
Play video "FIFA Arrests 'Far From Surprising'"
Video: FIFA Arrests 'Far From Surprising'
David Cameron has joined calls for Mr Blatter to quit and sponsors have demanded reform at FIFA, but Vladimir Putin gave the under-fire head of world football his backing and the majority of non-European football associations still appear to support him.
FIFA has said the vote for president will go ahead as planned, despite calls from UEFA and French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius for the election to be postponed.
Sources close to Mr Blatter's only rival for the presidency, Prince Ali Bin Al Hussein, have told Sky News they want the election to go ahead as they believe there is a "strong possibility" that he can win.
1/7
Gallery: Who Are FIFA Execs Held In Zurich?
Jeffrey Webb, joint current FIFA vice-president
Speaking in the House of Commons, Culture Secretary John Whittingdale said the latest FIFA allegations suggest "a deeply flawed and corrupt organisation".
He said it was important that commercial sponsors reflect on their links with FIFA and suggested they consider following the example set by Visa, which threatened to pull out of agreements unless there is change at the top of the governing body.
Football Association chairman Greg Dyke said it was vital that Mr Blatter is replaced by "someone who believes in transparency and honesty".
Play video "Blatter 'Not Dancing In His Office'"
Video: Blatter 'Not Dancing In His Office'
Mr Blatter has not been named in the investigation and said he "welcomes" the probe into alleged misconduct.
He told the FIFA congress as it opened: "Those who are corrupt in football are in a small minority, like in society, but like in society, they must be caught and held responsible for their actions. Football cannot be the exception to the rule."
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:40:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA Ethics Chief Welcomes FBI Investigation</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492346</Link>
        <Description>Hans Joachim-Eckert, who is responsible for overseeing inquiries into corruption, tells Sky exclusively the US probe "will help".</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
FIFA Ethics Chief Welcomes FBI Investigation
Hans Joachim-Eckert, who is responsible for overseeing inquiries into corruption, tells Sky exclusively the US probe "will help".
21:40, UK, Thursday 28 May 2015
Hans Joachim-Eckert hopes the FBI will share their findings with him
Share by email
By Paul Kelso, Sports Correspondent, in Zurich
The chairman of FIFA's ethics committee has welcomed the FBI investigation that has plunged football's world governing body into crisis, saying it will help reform the organisation.
Speaking exclusively to Sky News, German judge Hans Joachim-Eckert said he has not spoken directly to the FBI but hopes they will share their findings with him.
"This is a state investigation. It is an investigation into FIFA and I do not have the same power," he said.
"I think it will help and they will give me the results of the FBI investigation, and that will help me."
Judge Eckert has overseen FIFA's internal investigation into corruption allegations arising from the award of the 2018 and 2022 World Cups.
Play video "Sponsors Upset Over FIFA Scandal"
Video: Sponsors Upset Over FIFA Scandal
He is currently making redactions to a full report compiled by American investigator Michael Garcia, who last November resigned in protest at Eckert's summary of his work.
Asked when he will release the report he said: "I will publish the Garcia report when I have finished my work. We are really heavy working."
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 14:49:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sponsors Concerned By FIFA Corruption Scandal</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1491860</Link>
        <Description>Visa, Coca-Cola, Adidas and McDonald's are among the sponsors to express concerns following the arrest of seven FIFA officials.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Sponsors Concerned By FIFA Corruption Scandal
Visa, Coca-Cola, Adidas and McDonald's are among the sponsors to express concerns following the arrest of seven FIFA officials.
12:49, UK, Thursday 28 May 2015
Play video "FIFA Probes Hit Sponsor Confidence"
Video: FIFA Probes Hit Sponsor Confidence
Share by email
Sponsors of the FIFA World Cup have released statements expressing their serious concern at allegations of "rampant, systemic and deep-rooted corruption" at the heart of the organisation.
The companies  which include some of the world's best-known brands  spend tens of millions of dollars every year to be associated with FIFA tournaments, and the arrests of seven senior officials could place the lucrative sponsorship deals in danger.
Swiss police are also preparing to question another 10 senior FIFA executives over their decision to award World Cups to Russia and Qatar.
Mr Dyke has called for FIFA boss Sepp Blatter to resign
McDonald's, The Coca-Cola Company, Adidas, Budweiser and Hyundai have all released comments following Wednesday's dramatic arrests at a five-star Zurich hotel.
Visa issued the strongest statement however, threatening to "reassess its sponsorship" unless the football governing body takes "swift and immediate steps" to address the allegations.
Play video "Debate: Should The FA Leave FIFA?"
Video: Debate: Should The FA Leave FIFA?
It added: "Visa became a sponsor of FIFA because the World Cup is one of the few truly global sporting events with the power to unite people from around the world through a common love of football.
"Our sponsorship has always focused on supporting the teams, enabling a great fan experience, and inspiring communities to come together and celebrate the spirit of competition and personal achievement  and it is important that FIFA makes changes now, so that the focus remains on these going forward."
The Coca-Cola Company said: "This lengthy controversy has tarnished the mission and ideals of the FIFA World Cup and we have repeatedly expressed our concerns about these serious allegations."
Adidas, the German sportswear company, added: "(We are) fully committed to creating a culture that promotes the highest standards of ethics and compliance and we expect the same from our partners."
Budweiser, Hyundai and McDonald's also issued statements to confirm "they were monitoring the situation closely".
According to sports marketing experts, the controversy places sponsors in an awkward position  but they will probably give FIFA "a little bit of time to get their house in order".
Play video "FIFA Arrests 'Far From Surprising'"
Video: FIFA Arrests 'Far From Surprising'
Although the deals are highly profitable for each brand, they could face pressure from shoppers to distance themselves from any corruption.
"The value of the sponsorships is very high or they wouldn't be prepared to pay so much for it," according to Interbrand's chief executive, Jez Frampton.
"Football is one of the few global properties that enable you to connect with people around the world."
Andrew Zimbalist, an economist from Smith College, added: "The large majority of sponsors will hang in there. Most sponsors who were putting money into FIFA knew about FIFA's problems, so this was not new for them."
The controversy comes after seven FIFA officials were arrested in Switzerland on Wednesday over claims they were part of a racket involving bribes adding up to more than $150m (96m).
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:10:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU Reform: Cameron To Meet Merkel For Talks</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492416</Link>
        <Description>The Prime Minister will round off a two-day tour of European capitals by meeting the German Chancellor in Berlin.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
EU Reform: Cameron To Meet Merkel For Talks
The Prime Minister will round off a two-day tour of European capitals by meeting the German Chancellor in Berlin.
02:10, UK, Friday 29 May 2015
Play video "Cameron And Hollande Speak On EU"
Video: Cameron And Hollande Speak On EU
Share by email
David Cameron will hold talks with German Chancellor Angela Merkel today as he continues to seek support from European leaders for reforms to Britain's arrangements with the EU.
The Prime Minister will meet Mrs Merkel for the face-to-face talks in Berlin at the end of his two-day European diplomatic tour.
He is expected to begin the day in Warsaw for talks with his Polish counterpart Ewa Kopacz, before heading to the German capital to see Mrs Merkel.
It comes after Mr Cameron called for "flexible and imaginative" reforms in the European Union after talks with French President Francois Hollande on Thursday.
Play video "Cameron's Grand European Tour"
Video: Cameron's Grand European Tour
Speaking after the talks in Paris, Mr Cameron said: "The status quo is not good enough and I think there are changes that can be made that can benefit not just Britain but the rest of Europe too".
The Prime Minister said solutions could be found to make Europe more competitive and "address the concerns of the British people" ahead of his in-out referendum on EU membership.
Mr Hollande called Mr Cameron's plan for a referendum by the end of 2017 "very risky" - but made clear that France wants Britain to remain in the bloc.
"We think it's in the interest of Europe and in the interest of the United Kingdom to be together but the people must always be respected," he said at a joint news conference.
Mr Cameron added: "We have different priorities but we share a common objective, which is to find solutions to these problems.
"And what matters is that the European Union and its 28 members are flexible and imaginative enough to respond to these issues and to work together to find answers that will make the European Union more successful."
Play video "'A Flawed Union, But UK Better In'"
Video: 'A Flawed Union, But UK Better In'
:: Why Should The UK Stay Hitched To 'Shrinking' EU?
The PM is trying to charm EU leaders into backing his reform drive, something he has promised to complete before giving Britons a vote on staying in the EU.
Details of the EU Referendum Bill have been published, including the wording of the question: "Should the United Kingdom remain a member of the European Union?"
It also gives details of who will be able to vote in the referendum - the same people able to vote in the General Election.
Mr Cameron began his tour with a meeting with Dutch counterpart Mark Rutte in The Hague.
The tour came as Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said "substantial" reforms were needed for the Government successfully to recommend staying in the EU.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:55:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Navy Saves Young Migrants Crammed Into Boat</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492460</Link>
        <Description>Dozens of "horrifyingly young" children packed on to a wooden boat miles from shore are plucked to safety by HMS Bulwark.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Navy Saves Young Migrants Crammed Into Boat
Dozens of "horrifyingly young" children packed on to a wooden boat miles from shore are plucked to safety by HMS Bulwark.
22:55, UK, Thursday 28 May 2015
Play video "Stricken Migrants Saved By Navy"
Video: Stricken Migrants Saved By Navy
Share by email
The Royal Navy's flagship has saved more than 360 migrants - including 50 young children - crammed into a wooden boat trying to cross the Mediterranean.
HMS Bulwark intercepted the stricken boat north of Libya and sent five landing craft to rescue the 369 people crowded on board.
They were then ferried onto the 19,000-tonne warship and given food, water and dry clothes.
It is not known where the migrants are likely to be put ashore.
The mission was one of five rescue operations that took place on Thursday.
1/6
Gallery: Navy Saves Young Children Crammed In Boat
The Royal Navy's flagship has saved more than 300 migrants - including 50 young children - crammed into a wooden boat trying to cross the Mediterranean
The others were carried out by Irish, Italian and German naval units.
HMS Bulwark's Commanding Officer Captain Nick Cooke-Priest said he was sure the migrants would have died without help.
He said some of the children were "horrifyingly young".
1/11
Gallery: HMS Bulwark Picks Up Migrants In Mediterranean
More than 100 refugees were rescued by the Navy from a large rubber boat
Defence Secretary Michael Fallon praised the crew's efforts, but stressed there was more work to be done.
"HMS Bulwark and her crew have once again saved hundreds of lives in the Mediterranean migrant crisis, offering medical assistance, food, water and dry clothes to those in need," he said.
"A wider political solution is required to this crisis, but that does not detract from today's rescue at sea."
Play video "3,600 Migrants Rescued In 48 Hours"
Video: 3,600 Migrants Rescued In 48 Hours
Bulwark was sent to stop migrant drownings in the Mediterranean after more than 800 people died on a boat travelling from Libya last month.
The migration surge has been caused in part by the Libyan civil war, which has allowed people smugglers to work virtually unimpeded.
There have also been rising illegal boat journeys from Egypt and Turkey.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 12:23:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Asks For Help As Migrant Numbers Surge</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492046</Link>
        <Description>Thousands of people, mainly from Syria, are arriving on the coast of Greece, a country already struggling with its own problems.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Greece Asks For Help As Migrant Numbers Surge
Thousands of people, mainly from Syria, are arriving on the coast of Greece, a country already struggling with its own problems.
10:23, UK, Thursday 28 May 2015
1/16
Gallery: Refugees Arrive On Greek Island
An Afghan immigrant family lands at a beach on the Greek island of Kos after crossing a portion of the south-eastern Aegean Sea between Turkey and Greece on a dinghy
Share by email
Greece has asked the European Union for help in dealing with the thousands of migrants who have arrived on its shores in recent months.
According to estimates by the Greek government, some 37,500 immigrants and asylum seekers have reached the country illegally so far this year.
The Greek coast guard says nearly 12,000 were arrested last month, almost a seven-fold increase on the previous month's total of 6,583, with nearly all of them on the islands facing the Turkish coast.
Kos has seen a marked increase in migrant landings - 7,500 people have arrived at the island this year, 6,000 of them in the last month - and local authorities say they are struggling.
Overnight on Wednesday, the coast guard picked up 216 people in the Aegean Sea after they tried to sail to the islands from the Turkish coast.
1/11
Gallery: HMS Bulwark Picks Up Migrants In Mediterranean
More than 100 refugees were rescued by the Navy from a large rubber boat
The people were rescued in eight incidents near the islands of Kos, Lesbos and Chios, but it was not known where they were from.
Migrants arriving at Kos are being given shelter in an abandoned hotel as they wait for overwhelmed Greek authorities to provide them with documents to travel.
One of the migrants, Imaged Baloch, arrived in Kos three days ago, having begun his journey in his native Pakistan.
Play video "Mediterranean Migrants Crisis Talks"
Video: Mediterranean Migrants Crisis Talks
He said he doesn't plan to stay in Greece, adding: "We want to go further, another country like Germany, Switzerland, France, anywhere, but not in Greece. Greece is just a way."
The views of the island's locals are mixed, with one man, a food truck worker named Victor, telling how residents are bringing food and clothing for the migrants but a district officer named Georgos Chalkidios said: "We really beg for bad weather for migrants not to be able to come."
After Italy, Greece is the main destination for refugees, mostly from war-ravaged Syria or Afghanistan, and economic migrants seeking a better life in the European Union.
1/11
Gallery: Latest Images From Iraq And Syria
Syrian Kurdish children arrive at the border between Syria and Turkey after several mortars hit, in the southeastern town of Suruc, Turkey
EU Migration Commissioner Dimitris Avramopoulos, on a visit to Athens earlier this week, said he would back a European Union relocation plan to assist Greece and Italy.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
