<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Sky-News">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:19:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Warned To Get 'Serious' At Euro Talks</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514481</Link>
        <Description>France and Germany say there is no time for bluffing or time-wasting as Greece's PM makes his big pitch to eurozone leaders.</Description>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:25:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia: Gunmen Attack Two Tourist Hotels</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508894</Link>
        <Description>Gunmen have killed at least 27 people in an attack on two tourist hotels in a Tunisian town popular with British holidaymakers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia: Gunmen Attack Two Tourist Hotels
13:25, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
Share by email
Gunmen have killed at least 27 people in an attack on two tourist hotels in a Tunisian town popular with British holidaymakers.
Tourists fled from the beach in Sousse to take refuge in hotel rooms after guns were fired on the beach.
One man said his son saw someone get shot as he raced back to the hotel from the sea.
Photographs seen by Sky News show one man in his 60s or 70s lying in a pool of blood in his swimming shorts.
Tourist John Yeoman has barricaded himself inside his room
One gunman has been killed, according to security sources cited by the Reuters news agency. The country's interior ministry says at least 27 people have been killed.
British tourist Gary Pine said: "We thought fire crackers were going off but you could see quite quickly what was going on.
Play video "'People Are Hysterical'"
Video: 'People Are Hysterical'
"There was a mass exodus off the beach. My son was in the sea at the time and myself and my wife were shouting at him to get out and as he ran up he said Ive just saw someone get shot.
Another holidaymaker, Susan Ricketts, said: "It sounded like a machine gun going off. There are people crying and going hysterical. We just came up to our room."
Tourists are now gathered in hotel reception areas and hiding in rooms as the situation develops.
One said: "People are running around the hotel. No-one has really been told what to do."
Play video "'Ulterior Motive To Tunisia Attack'"
Video: 'Ulterior Motive To Tunisia Attack'
Holidaymaker John Yeoman has barricaded himself inside his hotel room using a bed and chair.
Meanwhile deadly explosions have hit a Shiite mosque in Kuwait's capital after Friday prayers.
More follows...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:05:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beheading And Explosion At French Factory</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508786</Link>
        <Description>Attackers carrying Islamist flags ram a car into gas canisters at the building, setting off an explosion.</Description>
        <MainBody>Beheading And Explosion At French Factory
Attackers carrying Islamist flags ram a car into gas canisters at the building, setting off an explosion.
13:05, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
1/13
Gallery: Police At Scene Of Grenoble Attack
Police stand next to a black plastic sheet after a suspected terror attack in eastern France
Share by email
A man has been decapitated by attackers brandishing Islamist flags at a French factory near Grenoble.
The severed head had Arabic writing scrawled across it and was found on a fence next to twojihadi banners.
Two other people were hurt in explosions at the factory, French President Francois Hollande said.
The blasts in France were triggered when two attackers deliberately crashed a car into gas canisters, according to police.
A 35-year-old man was among several people arrested after the attack.
Explosions were heard at the factory (Google Street View)
Le Parisien reported gunshots and that one Islamist had been killed at the premises in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeastern France.
Le Dauphine newspaper reported that police are hunting for another man associated with the attack.
Play video "Why Pick 'Chemical Valley'?"
Video: Why Pick 'Chemical Valley'?
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve, speaking from the scene, described the attack as "barbarous" and a "terrible terrorist crime".
He said that one of the arrested people had been known to foreign intelligence services may have been radicalised.
The suspect was initially flagged as an extremist in 2006 and then police monitoring dropped off two years later, according to MrCazeneuve.
He did not have a criminal record, the minister added.
MrHollande has cut short all of his engagements at the EU summit in Belgium to return to France for emergency talks.
"The attack was of a terrorist nature since a body was discovered, decapitated and with inscriptions," MrHollande told a news conference in Brussels.
He added that a considerable police force had been deployed in the region and other industrial sites protected to avoid any further incidents.
"The president saw the first images of the attack on the 24-news channels with German Chancellor Angela Merkel beside him, who was visibly shocked," an official added.
The two leaders had just ended a short meeting with Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras.
David Cameron has spoken to MrHollande in Brussels to express his sympathies. Downing Street described the attack as an "appalling incident".
Employees at the factory - Air Products - are said to be "very shocked". 
One witness called Caroline, from a neighbouring factory, said: "I heard a really loud noise. Fire engines arrived with the police.
Play video "President Hollande Condemns Attack"
Video: President Hollande Condemns Attack
"We thought it was a motorway accident."
Air Products is an American chemical company based in Allentown, Pennsylvania.
A statement from the company read: "Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for.
"Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
Henry Samuel, a correspondent for the Daily Telegraph, told Sky News: "The person arrested was allegedly carrying a flag of the Islamic State and he said he was a member of the IS."
The attack came nearly six months after the Islamist attacks in and around Paris that killed 17 people in January.
Those attacks started with a shooting at satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo .
Sky's foreign affairs editor Sam Kiley said: "There has been a concerted effort by Islamic State to reach out to their followers in France and exhortations to conduct this sort of attack.
"We saw with the Charlie Hebdo attack these were also self-starter individuals who had had training from al Qaeda in Yemen.
"One of the three said he was there on behalf of Islamic State, the other two claimed membership of al Qaeda.
"In a sense it doesn't matter. What matters is that people are inspired to carry out terrorist attacks."
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:46:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Emergency Cash To Continue For Greek Banks</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509799</Link>
        <Description>The decision to maintain - but not increase - emergency funding for the banks still leaves Greece facing an uncertain week.</Description>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Greece Warned To Get 'Serious' At Euro Talks
France and Germany say there is no time for bluffing or time-wasting as Greece's PM makes his big pitch to eurozone leaders.
14:19, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Play video "Greece Extends Bank Closures"
Video: Greece Extends Bank Closures
Share by email
Greece is under intense pressure to show "serious, credible" plans on how it can remain in the euro as its prime minister faces a showdown with eurozone leaders.
The country is perilously close to leaving the currency after some 61% of voters rejected a new bailout deal that demanded further austerity measures.
Newly appointed Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos at the eurozone talks
Prime Minister Alexis Tsiprasis expected to present new proposals to an emergency eurozone summit later today.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel and French President Francois Hollande, who met in Paris on Monday, have said "the door is open" at today's crisis talks - but signalled there is no time for bluffing or protracted negotiations.
Play video "What Next For Greece?"
Video: What Next For Greece?
"It is now up to the government of Alexis Tsipras to make serious, credible proposals so that this willingness to stay in the eurozone can translate into a lasting programme," said Mr Hollande.
Mrs Merkel, under pressure in Germany to cut Athens loose, said the conditions for a new bailout to keep Greece from collapse had not yet been met and demanded "very precise proposals" at the summit in Brussels.
Fears are mounting that banks and cash machines in Greece could run dry if a deal cannot be hammered out in the next few days on its 240bn (170bn) debt.
As the country enters uncharted territory - no state has ever left the currency - its government backtracked on promises that banks would reopen on Tuesday.
1/10
Gallery: Anxious Greeks Play The Waiting Game Ahead Of Crucial Euro Talks
After the euphoria of the referendum result on Sunday, ordinary Greeks are now anxiously waiting on the results of key talks on the euro crisis. Continue through for more images
They will now stay shut until at least Thursday, with a 60 (42) daily limit on ATM withdrawals, that has seen long queues at cash machines, kept in place.
There was some relief on Monday when the European Central Bank (ECB) said it would maintain the Emergency Liquidity Assistance (ELA) Greece needs to keep its banking system afloat.
But the ECB also said it was "adjusting" the conditions - which could make it tougher for some Greek banks to qualify for help.
Mr Tsipras, who praised "brave" Greek voters' rejection of austerity, said he was hopeful of a deal by this evening when he makes his pitch to eurozone leaders.
Play video "Latest: Greece Travel Advice"
Video: Latest: Greece Travel Advice
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker warned that "in Europe there are no simple answers" but added: "We have to find a solution".
Mr Tsipras heads into the talks without his right-hand man, Yanis Varoufakis, who quit as finance minister on Monday.
His departure is said to be a concession to other European ministers apparently angered by his uncompromising stance.
Mr Varoufakis had described demands for further austerity as "fiscal waterboarding".
1/10
Gallery: Greece Referendum: What The European Papers Say
Here's how the papers in Germany and Greece see the country's 'No' vote against more austerity measures. Taxydromos: Sweepingly 'no' from the Greeks
"I shall wear the creditors' loathing with pride," Mr Varoufakis told reporters before later leaving his office with his wife on the back of his motorcycle.
Euclid Tsakalotos, his more mild-mannered replacement, is also painting himself as no pushover, warning Greece "cannot accept a non-viable deal".
A key stumbling block at the talks is likely to be any demands to write-off more debt and Sky's Economics Editor Ed Conway says there is "still a lot of distance between the two sides".
Despite celebrations on the streets after Sundays referendum, three-quarters of Greeks say they want to stay in the euro.
1/23
Gallery: Greece Referendum: Supporters Of The 'No' Campaign Celebrate
'No' campaigners celebrate in Athens following the referendum results
A so-called "Grexit" and a return to the drachma could be catastrophic for the country.
Greeces economy has already shrunk 25% since 2008 and it has been suggested a euro exit could see a further 25% contraction. One in four people in the country is also unemployed and among under-25s the figure is nearly 52%.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:25:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russian Bombers Intercepted Off US Coast</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514728</Link>
        <Description>Fighter jets are scrambled after four long-range Tu-95 "Bear" bombers fly close to Alaska and California on Independence Day.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
<<<<<<< HEAD
Russian Bombers Intercepted Off US Coast
Fighter jets are scrambled after four long-range Tu-95 "Bear" bombers fly close to Alaska and California on Independence Day.
12:25, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Four TU-95 "Bear" bombers flew close to the US on Independence Day
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
Four Russian bombers caused the US Air Force to scramble fighter jets after they flew close to the US coast, according to reports.
Two Russian Tu-95 "Bear" bombers were intercepted off Alaska at around 10.30am Eastern Time on Independence Day by two F-22 Raptor jets.
Just half an hour later another pair of Tu-95s were detected off the central coast of California and two F-15 Eagles were scrambled to intercept.
A spokeswoman for the North American Aerospace Defense Command (NORAD) did not confirm if either of the long-range bombers was armed, Fox News reported.
None of the Russian aircraft entered US airspace, which is 12 nautical miles off the coast, but defence officials have not revealed how close they were to US soil.
Michael Kucharek, a spokesman for NORAD, told Fox News: "These are not unprecedented flights, but we are postured to respond whether Alaska or California.
"At no time did the bombers enter North American sovereign airspace."
Russian bombers also flew close to US coastlines on 4 July 2013.
Last year, two more long-range bombers flew within 50 miles of California .
There have been at least 50 reported incidents of Russian aircraft being intercepted by US Air Force jets since 2006, the Washington Times reported.
The incident occurred on the same day that Russian President Vladimir Putin sent a congratulatory message to US President Barack Obama to mark Independence Day.
In 2014, Russian defence officials announced long-range bombers would expand their regular patrols to the Arctic, the Caribbean and the Gulf of Mexico.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:00:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant Found Dead In Channel Tunnel</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514615</Link>
        <Description>The incident comes days after around 150 migrants tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrant Found Dead In Channel Tunnel
The incident comes days after around 150 migrants tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.
11:00, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Both passenger and freight services have been disrupted
A migrant has died trying to reach Britain through the Channel Tunnel on a freight train.
Operator Eurotunnelsaid the incident happened near Calais at around 5amBST (6am local time).
A section of the tunnel was closed for investigation and both freight and passenger services have been disrupted.
"Following the discovery of migrants on a freight shuttle, early this morning, the shuttle was immediately stopped," said a French official.
"During an investigation by border police, a deceased migrant was found in the tunnel," he added.
Play video "Tunnel Travel Chaos After Strike"
Video: Tunnel Travel Chaos After Strike
Authorities have yet to say how the migrant died.
It is the second migrant fatality in as many weeks following the death of an Eritrean while trying to get on a train at Coquelles last month.
A Eurotunnel spokesman said freight services were affected more than passenger trains, which were"running with slight delays".
He added: "We are working very hard to restore full services as soon as possible."
Play video "Migrants Try To Get On To Lorries"
Video: Migrants Try To Get On To Lorries
The incident comes days after around 150 migrants caused delays and cancellations when they tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.
There have been increased calls for a resolution to the migrant crisis in Calais, which has escalated in recent months.
Around 3,000 people displaced from countries including Eritrea, Syria and Afghanistan have set up camp near the port.
Last week more than 3,000 truckers had to queue for several days in high temperatures on the M20 following a wildcat strike by ferry workers in France.
Play video "Inside Asylum-Seeker Camp (Archive)"
Video: Inside Asylum-Seeker Camp (Archive)
Hauliers have also faced problems with migrants desperately trying to clamber on board theirHGVs to the UK.
French authorities have faced claims they are not doing enough to safeguard lorry drivers from intimidation and violence.
The Road Haulage Association (RHA) has suggested deployment of the French military to boost security in Calais amid growing fears that a death could occur.
Port of Dover officials said last week's ferry strike cost the UK economy 1bn.
Play video "Queues At St Pancras And Kent"
Video: Queues At St Pancras And Kent
They have joined calls for "robust contingency plans" to be introduced to ensure the port - a 100bntrade route - can operate unimpeded.
Home Secretary Theresa May and her French counterpart Bernard Cazeneuve last week agreed to increase the joint intervention fund to improve security in and around the Channel Tunnel.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:34:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three Gored During 'Crazy' Pamplona Bull Run</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514757</Link>
        <Description>One regular visitor to the event says the run was "very crazy, very fast" and "very dangerous", and it is lucky no-one was killed.</Description>
=======
Greece Referendum Not A Simple Yes Or No
If Greece does leave the euro, it would face even greater short-term austerity and pain than it has so far, writes Ed Conway.
13:28, UK, Saturday 27 June 2015
Some think a 'no' would effectively mean Greece has voted to leave the euro
Follow Ed
Austerity, deficits, loans and currencies. Greece's euro crisis is about lots of things, but in the end it has always been about something else: national sovereignty and democracy.
When Greece joined the Eurozone (without a referendum, it should be said) it ceded some of its sovereignty.
Since the country now shared a currency with fellow Europeans it would no longer have direct control over its monetary policy.
That was simply part of the deal - and it is part of the explanation for how it ended up in the mess it is in.
It meant a dilution of sovereignty in economic "peacetime".
Play video "Greek PM Says Ultimatums Won't Work"
Video: Greek PM Says Ultimatums Won't Work
As part of the single currency, Greece lost control of its own interest rates, and thus lost influence over the yield on government bonds.
The country could suddenly borrow at unprecedented cheap rates - despite not having the productivity to justify it.
So began the bubble that fuelled the Greek crisis in the first place (a simplified version of history, I admit).
But even during "peacetime" Greece still maintained a certain amount of control over its fiscal policy - taxing and spending.
When the crisis struck and it needed to rely on its fellow Eurozone nations (and the IMF, and ECB) for financial assistance, it effectively ceded most of its fiscal sovereignty too.
In return for the loans, the Greeks had to accede to certain demands.
There is nothing particularly unusual in this.
When the UK borrowed money from the US after the Second World War a whole host of demands came attached to it: that the UK should open up its economic system; that it should sell off a whole load of publicly-owned assets at cheap prices.
There was even talk about selling off the Crown Jewels.
None of this is particularly pleasant, but it is an unfortunate reality.
To make matters worse, in Greece's case, the lenders deciding those conditions discredited themselves repeatedly.
Their forecasts for the impact of austerity on Greece were completely wrong.
Their programme contributed to a depression deeper and longer than anything seen since modern records began.
1/5
Gallery: The Deadlines On The Road Ahead For Athens
After a series of shifting payment deadlines Greece's future within the EU could be decided in the coming days
But, having ceded its sovereignty - both monetary and fiscal - the Greeks could do little about it.
They had to suffer as a poorly-constructed bailout and overly-aggressive austerity was imposed on them.
In January the Greeks voted in Alexis Tsipras as prime minister on a manifesto which promised to cancel austerity.
The problem, of course, was that because of all of the above, in practice the Greeks did not and do not have the sovereign right to do that themselves.
The best Mr Tsipras could do was to try to get a better deal and improve the terms of the bailout, which is what he has been doing in Brussels and Athens for the past six months.
His decision to call a referendum next weekend seems to be a tacit admission he has failed.
There are a number of short and medium term problems, the most pressing of which is what happens to the financial system between now and next weekend.
The slow-motion invisible system-wide bank run afflicting Greece's financial system over the past couple of months threatens to turn into a rapid, visible one.
People are already being photographed queuing up to take money out of their bank accounts.
There is the question of what the Eurozone decides today at its finance ministers' meeting.
Do they grant Greece the five-day bailout extension they are demanding? Do they refuse?
Do they simply talk about plan b - the capital controls and restrictions they would need to impose to incubate Greece ahead of a possible euro exit?
What part does the International Monetary Fund, who will almost certainly not get paid on time on Tuesday, play in the saga?
1/17
Gallery: Pro-EU Protests In Athens
Pro-euro protesters take part in a rally in front of the Parliament in Athens, Greece
But more than these short-term questions is the bigger medium to long term one: if Greeks do as their prime minister is suggesting and vote no to the current bailout deal, what does that imply?
As far as many here in Brussels are concerned, it means Greece will effectively have voted to leave the Eurozone.
But Syriza figures are insisting it simply means another stage in the negotiations.
The answer to that question will determine the way many vote.
In Greece there is both widespread disdain for the bailout and the conditions attached to it, and widespread support for euro membership.
So the way the debate is framed will determine the result.
But the reality is that if Greece did leave the euro, it would face even greater short-term austerity and pain than it has in the past year or so.
It would face more financial turbulence.
It might swap euro bailout conditions with even more shady ones from Russia or China.
It would regain some of its monetary sovereignty, but in exchange for this it would suffer a fair amount of pain.
There are no easy answers here, which is why what looks like a simple yes/no question is far more complex and unpredictable than it seems.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:20:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Was Attack On Factory The Work Of Islamists?</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508871</Link>
        <Description>While the attack would appear to be the work of Islamist militants, little is known about the motives of those responsible.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Was Attack On Factory The Work Of Islamists?
While the attack would appear to be the work of Islamist militants, little is known about the motives of those responsible.
12:20, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
Play video "Why Pick 'Chemical Valley'?"
Video: Why Pick 'Chemical Valley'?
Share by email
French police say the attack on a US gas company in the southeast of the country bears the hallmark of Islamist militants.
A decapitated head was reportedly found on a gate at the entrance to the factory in Saint Quentin-Fallavier, along with two flags bearing Arabic writing.
Sky's Foreign Affairs Editor Sam Kiley said it was too early to be certain about who was responsible.
"Beyond some Arabic writing on a flag we don't really know the genesis of this attack" he said.
"Let's not start running up an Islamist flag and claim it to be a jihadi operation as such until we have further evidence.
Play video "Why Attack This Factory?"
Video: Why Attack This Factory?
"But at the moment there is a suggestion from the French media that this does look like an Islamist attack."
Kiley said there is a possibility that, whoever was responsible, it could have been a robbery that went wrong.
"At this stage there is a lot of confusion. It is not clear the decapitation... was linked to the explosions some time later.
"You have a lot volatile material in this location, so it is conceivable it was a robbery in which people were trying to get hold of potentially dangerous products to use in an attack elsewhere."
1/13
Gallery: Police At Scene Of Grenoble Attack
Police stand next to a black plastic sheet after a suspected terror attack in eastern France
Kiley said there has been a "concerted effort" by Islamic State to reach out to their followers in France and "exhortations to conduct this sort of attack.
"We saw with the Charlie Hebdo attack these were also self-starter individuals who had had training from al Qaeda in Yemen.
"One of the three said he was there on behalf of Islamic State, the other two claimed membership of al Qaeda.
"In a sense it doesn't matter. What matters is that people are inspired to carry out terrorist attacks."
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:10:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British School Children In Belgium Bus Crash</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509749</Link>
        <Description>A coach driver is killed and a British pupil is in intensive care after a bus carrying schoolchildren overturned in Belgium.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
British School Children In Belgium Bus Crash
A coach driver is killed and a British pupil is in intensive care after a bus carrying schoolchildren overturned in Belgium.
15:10, UK, Sunday 28 June 2015
Play video "34 British Children On Crashed Bus"
Video: 34 British Children On Crashed Bus
A coach driver has been killed and his assistant seriously injured after a bus carrying staff and pupils from Brentwood School in Essex crashed in Belgium, a spokesman for the school said.
A child was in intensive care after suffering a head injury in the crash, the school said.
It is believed there were 34 first and second year pupils - aged between 11 and 13 - on the bus, along with six teachers and the two drivers, all on their way to a theme park in the German city of Cologne.
At least one other child was also seriously injured in the crash and 15 of those on board have minor injuries.
The spokesman added that two senior members of staff have travelled to Belgium to help.
1/6
Gallery: UK School Bus Crashes In Belgium
A bus carrying British schoolchildren went off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast
Those who were not injured were taken to a crisis centre where the community of Middelkerke has set up up a support service including clothing, food and psychological assistance.
The bus hit a bridge support and rolled over on the E40 motorway near Middelkerke, in West Flanders at 9.45am local time this morning.
The coach is operated by Northern Ireland-based Richmond Coaches and a spokesman for the company, which is based inLisburn, said what had happened was "a tragedy" and the company was co-operating with the authorities.
Play video "Children On Coach Taken To Hospital"
Video: Children On Coach Taken To Hospital
He said the company's thoughts were with everyone involved.
A spokesman for the Foreign and Commonwealth Office said"We are aware of reports of a bus crash in Belgium involving British nationals.
"We are working with the Belgian authorities to establish details of the incident".
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:45:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Latest In A Series Of Attacks In France</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508811</Link>
        <Description>From the Charlie Hebdo massacre to opportunistic assaults on soldiers - a recent history of Islamist terror attacks in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Latest In A Series Of Attacks In France
From the Charlie Hebdo massacre to opportunistic assaults on soldiers - a recent history of Islamist terror attacks in France.
10:45, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
French police during the terror attacks in Paris in January
Share by email
There has been a string of suspected or confirmed Islamist terrorist attacks in France in the past three years alone, including the notorious Charlie Hebdo massacre in January.
19 April 2015:A woman was murdered by a gunman in Paris whose plot to attack a church was foiled shortly after. Aurelie Chatelain was found lying in a burning car in the southern suburb after apparently being shot
7-9 January 2015: An attack on the offices of satirical magazine Charlie Hebdowas followed by four more attacks in and around Paris, ending in two sieges. Seventeen people died. Fundamentalist brothers Said and Cherif Kouachi, plus accomplice Amedy Coulibaly, were killed in shoot-outs with police.
21 December 2014: In Dijon a man shouting "AllahuAkbar" ran over 11 pedestrians with his vehicle. The attacker shouted to passers by that he was acting on behalf of the "children of Palestine". No-one died but two people were left with serious injuries.
20 December 2014: A police officer is killed and three others are injured by a knife-wielding man yelling "Allahu Akbar".
23 May 2013: Days after British soldier Lee Rigby was killed in Woolwich, a French soldier is attacked and stabbed in the Paris suburb of La Defense in what was described as a terrorist attack. He survived.
11 March 2012: Three gun attacks target French soldiers and Jewish civilians in the cities of Montaubanand Toulouse. Seven people are killed and five others injured. The perpetrator - who said he was motivated by France's involvement in the Afghanistan conflict - is shot dead.
More follows...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:24:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Marikana Massacre: Police 'Followed Orders'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508596</Link>
        <Description>South African police criticise the tactics used to break up the Marikana mining strike, saying they were told to "shoot to kill".</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Marikana Massacre: Police 'Followed Orders'
South African police criticise the tactics used to break up the Marikana mining strike, saying they were told to "shoot to kill".
07:24, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
Play video "Marikana Cops Told 'Shoot To Kill'"
Video: Marikana Cops Told 'Shoot To Kill'
Share by email
Two policemen have told Sky News that officers were following orders from senior commanders when they opened fire on striking South African mining workers in 2012.
Speaking on condition of anonymity, the officers criticised the police tactics used to break up the demonstration at the Lonmin PLC platinum mine near Marikana.
One of the officers said police were told to "shoot to kill" by their superiors if they felt they were in danger.
He said police were instructed that "if your life is under threat, or your colleague's life is under threat, therefore you shoot to kill".
He added: "That is my interpretation."
Play video "Mine Massacre 'Horrendous Tragedy'"
Video: Mine Massacre 'Horrendous Tragedy'
Asked by Sky's Alex Crawford to confirm that senior police commanders told officers to "shoot to kill", he added: "Yeah, I think (so)."
He added: "We did what was instructed to us. We just followed orders."
Another policeman said: "We did what was expected from us. We followed the instructions.
"I guess we did not want those people to be killed in the first place."
Thirty-four people died during the massacre on 16 August, 2012.
Families of the victims have accused police of using excessive force.
Play video "2012: Striking Miners Speak To Sky"
Video: 2012: Striking Miners Speak To Sky
South Africa's President Jacob Zuma said the government-appointed panel's report recommended prosecutors determine whether any officers are criminally liable for the deaths.
"The commission recommends a full investigation under the direction of the director of public prosecutions... with a view to ascertaining criminal liability on the part of all members of the South African Police Service who were involved in the incidents," he said.
Mr Zuma described the killings as a "horrendous tragedy that has no place in democracy", adding that the world did not expect such an episode in a "free and democratic South Africa".
In the days leading up to the attack, 10 others were murdered near the platinum mine, including non-striking miners, security guards and two police officers who were hacked to death.
Mr Zuma said the inquiry has recommended that all killings prior to 16 August should also be investigated.
"We should, as a nation, learn from this painful episode," he said.
"We should use it to build a more united, peaceful and cohesive society."
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 06:18:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds Injured In Taiwan Water Park Blast</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509591</Link>
        <Description>Inflatable dinghies are used to carry away casualties or as makeshift beds to treat those injured in the explosion and fire.</Description>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Three Gored During 'Crazy' Pamplona Bull Run
One regular visitor to the event says the run was "very crazy, very fast" and "very dangerous", and it is lucky no-one was killed.
13:34, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Play video "Several Injured In Bull Run"
Video: Several Injured In Bull Run
A British man and two Americans have been gored at the annual Running of the Bulls in the northern Spanish city of Pamplona.
One of the Americans was reportedly injured in the armpit and the Briton in the perineum.
None was said to be in a serious condition.
Eight other people suffered minor injuries - mainly bruising - during the first bull run of Pamplona's San Fermin festival.
It happened as six animals made their way through the streets to the city's bull ring with daredevil members of the public running ahead of them.
1/17
Gallery: Several Runners Gored By Bulls In The San Fermin Festival In Pamplona, Spain
Several bull-runners, including a Briton and two Americans, have been gored during the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain
Peter Remington, from Houston, Texas, who was celebrating his 25th visit to the festival, said: "This one was very crazy, very fast.
"I was down at La Curva. One brown bull had a guy by his pants and was dragging him down the street right by the curve. It was very dangerous."
Fellow American Larry Belcher, who has been taking part in the Running of the Bulls for 40 years, said: "Today was really nasty.
"(One bull) hooked a kid beside down on the curve. I'm not sure whether he took a horn wound or whether he was just rolled around on the cobblestones.
"I'm not sure. I'm just glad it's over and now we can just settle down and seriously try to run."
Every year thousands of tourists from Spain and across the world descend on Pamplona to take part in the festival.
The event was made famous by the American writer Ernest Hemingway in his book The Sun Also Rises.
In all 15 people have been gored to death during the bull run since records began in 1924.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:59:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al Shabaab Gunmen Attack Sleeping Villagers</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514555</Link>
        <Description>Officials say the attackers "just came and hurled explosives" inside houses while people were asleep.</Description>
        <MainBody>Al Shabaab Gunmen Attack Sleeping Villagers
Officials say the attackers "just came and hurled explosives" inside houses while people were asleep.
11:59, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Kenyan troops near the scene of the attack
Share by email
<<<<<<< HEAD
At least 14 people have been killed and 11 wounded in an attack on a residential complex in northeastern Kenya.
Somalia-based al Shabaab militants have said they carried out the raid, at a village near the town of Mandera.
It follows a similar attack last December in which 36 quarry workers were killed.
The entrance to the residential complex
"People were sleeping they just came and hurled explosives in the houses," said Mandera County Commissioner Alex Ole Nkoyo.
"These were al Shabaab from the nature of the attack. They used explosives and guns."
Play video "Survivors Describe Their Ordeal"
Video: Survivors Describe Their Ordeal
Mr Nkoyo said most of the victims worked in a nearby quarry.
Kenya police chief Joseph Boinnetsaid on Twitter: "I can confirm a Shabaab attack in Mandera early this morning."
The Red Cross said it had taken 11 people to hospital and had sent a medical airplane to evacuate the critically-injured to the capital Nairobi.
Play video "More Gunfire Heard At Kenya Mall"
Video: More Gunfire Heard At Kenya Mall
Al Shabaab, which has links to al Qaeda, has been increasingly targeting Kenya over its involvement in the African Union peacekeeping mission in Somalia.
In its deadliest attack to date, in April, four gunmen killed 148 people at a university in the town of Garissa. Most of the victims werestudents.
In 2013, members of the group ran amok at the Westgate shopping mall in Nairobi, killing at least 67 people.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:19:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama: Fight Against IS 'Will Not Be Quick'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514591</Link>
        <Description>The President says it is hard for security agencies to prevent "lone wolf" attacks on US soil, during a speech at the Pentagon.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Obama: Fight Against IS 'Will Not Be Quick'
The President says it is hard for security agencies to prevent "lone wolf" attacks on US soil, during a speech at the Pentagon.
09:19, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Mr Obama said there were no plans to send more US troops to Syria and Iraq
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
Barack Obama has said the US needs to do more to combat the threat of Islamic State and has insisted the military campaign will take time to complete.
The US President said security agencies must focus on preventing attacks at home and prevent IS attempts to recruit followers during a visit to the Pentagon.
He said it was difficult for security agencies to prevent small-scale attacks by "lone wolves" on US soil, despite success at preventing larger scale attacks since the September 11, 2001, attacks on New York and Washington.
But he insisted there were no current plans to send more US troops overseas, and said moderate Syrian rebels needed training and equipping to combat the extremists.
He said: "This will not be quick. This is a long-term campaign. It will take time to root them out, and doing so must be the job of local forces on the ground with training and air support from our coalition.
Play video "Will UK Airstrikes Have Any Effect?"
Video: Will UK Airstrikes Have Any Effect?
"We continue to accelerate the delivery of critical equipment, including anti-tank weapons, to Iraqi security forces.
"And I have made it clear to my team that we will do more to train and equip the moderate opposition in Syria."
On small-scale attacks in the US, he added: "We're going to have to pick up our game to prevent these attacks."
Play video "22 May: Town Under I.S. Control"
Video: 22 May: Town Under I.S. Control
Mr Obama said US attempts to counter extremism and prevent recruitment must not single out Muslim Americans or any faith group.
He said: "We also have to acknowledge that ISIL has been particularly effective at reaching out to and recruiting vulnerable people around the world, including here in the US."
Mr Obama met more than 30 officials and national security advisers during his rare visit to the Pentagon.
Play video "Special Report: IS Recruitment"
Video: Special Report: IS Recruitment
Last August the US led an international airstrike operation on key IS positions within Iraq and Syria. So far there have been around 5,000 strikes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:11:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Worst Footie Team Ever? Micronesia Lose 46-0</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514606</Link>
        <Description>Micronesia's coach admits it was "boys against men" after his team suffered their third hiding in a row at the Pacific Games.</Description>
=======
Identifying all British victims of the Tunisia terror attack will take time because few of the holidaymakers gunned down on the beach were carrying IDs, Theresa May has warned.
The Home Secretary, who chaired a meeting of the Government's emergency Cobra committee, also said there was no evidence that the gunman had specifically targeted British tourists in Friday's attack, which left 38 people dead.
Meanwhile, Prime Minister David Cameron has asked for the flags over No 10 to be flown at half-mast in memory of the victims of the attack.
"The process of identifying individuals who have been affected and the deceased is a complex one," she told reporters, rejecting suggestions that the Foreign Office had been slow in helping families looking for information on the missing.
"It is imperative that we get it absolutely right for the families, and that can sometimes take time."
1/7
Gallery: Victims Of Tunisia Gun Attack
Carly Lovett, 24, recently became engaged and was from Gainsborough, Lincolnshire. She worked as a beauty blogger and was a former student at the University of Lincoln
Ms May said the victims would not have had passports or other forms of identification with them on the beach in Sousse and some victims were being moved between hospitals in the country.
She said the UK had dispatched a medical liaison team and a small group of advisers to look at security arrangements in the area, which attracts thousands of western tourists every year.
The British ambassador to Tunisia was due to meet with senior government officials later in the day.
Earlier on Sunday, the Foreign Office warned that further terrorist attacks in Tunisia are possible following the beach resort massacre.
"Further terrorist attacks in Tunisia, including in tourist resorts, are possible, including by individuals who are unknown to the authorities and whose actions are inspired by terrorist groups via social media," the updated advice on the Foreign Office website reads.
"You should be especially vigilant at this time and follow the advice of Tunisian security authorities and your tour operator."
1/4
Gallery: Tunisia Peace Rally After Attack
Hundreds of people gathered for a peace rally near the site of the attack in Sousse, a Tunisian beach resort popular with foreigners
The victims of gunman Seifeddine Rezgui include 15 Britons , though officials have warned that the toll is expected to rise.
Ms May noted the Tunisia shooting marked the most significant loss of British life since the attacks on 7 July 2005 in London, in which 52 people were killed.
Speaking earlier on the BBC's Andrew Marr Show, she warned that the risk to Britain had become "more diverse" in recent years - including not just the risk of groups plotting over time to strike in the country but also that of spontaneous attacks by a "lone wolf".
She said that some 40 plots had been foiled in the UK in the past decade, including "a number of plots" in recent months.
Mrs May said the Government will be introducing a counter-extremism strategy to tackle radicalisation.
In Tunisia, security officials added an extra 1,000 police to tourist sites and beaches.
Play video "'We Were In Lock Down'"
Video: 'We Were In Lock Down'
"We don't want to make tourist establishments into barracks, that's not our goal. But we must act to guarantee the security of the tourist sector," saidInterior Minister Mohamed Najem Gharsalli.
But thousands of shocked tourists were leaving the nation after the attack.
Up to 2,500 more people could return to the UK from Tunisia today, as part of holiday firms' efforts to get those on holiday at the beach resort home as soon as possible .
On Saturday, Thomson and First Choice said it had already expatriated 1,000 of its customers, but added that there were still 5,400 remaining.
Tui Group, which runs the companies, was unable to confirm how many of the 38 people killed or injured in the shooting were its customers, but said there had been a "number of fatalities".
An additional 11 Thomson flights as well as one third-party flight with Nouvelle Air are currently due to leave today.
Play video "Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism"
Video: Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism
The Association of British Travel Agents, known as Abta, estimates there are approximately 20,000 customers currently on holiday with Abta members in Tunisia.
But it said there will also be a number of holidaymakers who have travelled independently.
Holidaymakers elsewhere in the country were advised to contact their tour operators and follow any instructions issued by local authorities.
While many have left, a scattering of foreign tourists are still reportedly at the resort.
Welsh couple Angela Chambers and Peter Phillips told the Associated Press they declined their tour operator's offer to take them to the airport last night.
"I think we feel safer here than last night going to the airport," said Ms Chambers.
1/6
Gallery: Sky Obtains Exclusive Images Of Tunisian Attacker Seifeddine Yacoubi
Sky News has obtained exclusive images of the Tunisian terrorist walking down a beach after carrying out an attack that killed 39 people, 15 of them British
Mr Phillips added that "we want to see our holiday out".
In Sousselast night, people gathered for a protest against terrorism.
Crowds gathered after dark with some holding candles while others carried flags including those of the United Kingdom and Tunisia.
Some people held posters aloft proclaiming "Peace" and "Sousse will never die".
:: Watch Death On The Beach, a special Sky News report on Tunisia at 4.30pm, 6.30pm, 7.30pm and 9.30pm today on skynews.com, mobile, tablet, Sky go, or on TV: Sky 501, Virgin 602, Freesat 202, Freeview 132.
There will also be a special Sky News Tonight programme Terror In Tunisia at 7pm.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:29:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU Talks Over Greece Debt End Without Deal</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1507909</Link>
        <Description>German Chancellor Angela Merkel tells EU leaders there must be a debt deal with Greece before financial markets open next Monday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sponsored By
EU Talks Over Greece Debt End Without Deal
German Chancellor Angela Merkel tells EU leaders there must be a debt deal with Greece before financial markets open next Monday.
17:29, UK, Thursday 25 June 2015
Play video "Five Questions Answered On Greece"
Video: Five Questions Answered On Greece
Share by email
A meeting of eurozone finance ministers trying to agree a deal on Greece's debt crisis has broken up in Brussels without agreement.
The Greek government badly needs 7.2bn from creditors to keep its economy going and to help with a 1.6bn payment it has to make to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) by next Tuesday.
Otherwise, Athens may default on its debts which could lead to the country leaving the single currency.
German Chancellor Angela Merkelhas said there must be a debt deal with Greece before financial markets open on Monday.
She also told a meeting of European leaders before an EU summit in Brussels that Germany "will not be blackmailed" by Greece.
Play video "Brexit vs Grexit Analysis"
Video: Brexit vs Grexit Analysis
The talks will resume on Saturday, but Germany's finance minister earlier on Thursday expressed pessimism that a deal could be struck.
Wolfgang Schaeublesaid the two sides were "even further apart" as discussions took place between the Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsiprasand the IMF and European Central Bank (ECB).
The creditors presented Athens with new proposals over the economic reforms it wants made in an attempt to find a breakthrough over its bailout.
But Greece was still not on board, raising fresh doubts about whether it was possible to clinch a deal before the end of June.
Play video "What Proposals Could We See?"
Video: What Proposals Could We See?
However, Mr Tsiprassaid he was confident of reaching a compromise despite a deadlock in the talks.
According to Greek officials at the talks, creditors were seeking a different mix of austerity measures than those proposed by Athens, making the cuts more immediate.
They included broad pension cuts, higher revenue from sales tax, and a faster elimination of tax exemptions - demands that are likely to fuel dissent within the government if accepted.
1/18
Gallery: Monday: Pro-EU Protests In Athens
Pro-euro protesters take part in a rally in front of the Parliament in Athens, Greece
Hopes of a settlement had faded on Wednesday evening after the IMF cast doubts on Greece's new debt plan .
The proposals put forward by Athens aim to raise 8bn, mostly through new taxes on the wealthy and businesses, early retirement restrictions, VAT increases and a cut in defence spending.
But the IMF was cautious about the mix of reforms Greece proposed, saying they rely too heavily on tax increases that can hurt the economy.
Play video "Tragedy And Turmoil In Greece"
Video: Tragedy And Turmoil In Greece
It wants more spending cuts because of the possible effect of tax rises on businesses.
Stock markets across Europe were down after the IMF's negative reaction to the proposals.
Assuming a deal is thrashed out with the EU and IMF, Mr Tspiras still needs to convince his anti-austerity Syriza party to approve concessions needed to unblock the desperately needed bailout funds.
He only has a slim majority within the Greek parliament and opposition within his own party to proposed concessions means ratification in Greece is by no means assured.
1/4
Gallery: The Deadlines On The Road Ahead For Athens
After a series of shifting payment deadlines Greece's future within the EU could be decided in the coming days
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:44:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Shock For Tunisians Who Tried To Stop Killer</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509630</Link>
        <Description>As the blood of massacre victims is washed from the streets, locals are stunned that one of their own carried out the atrocity.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Shock For Tunisians Who Tried To Stop Killer
As the blood of massacre victims is washed from the streets, locals are stunned that one of their own carried out the atrocity.
13:44, UK, Sunday 28 June 2015
Play video "Tunisia Terror Attacks May Continue"
Video: Tunisia Terror Attacks May Continue
By Stuart Ramsay, Chief Correspondent, In Sousse
It is a macabre scene, but it is the reality of what happened here.
The blood of the victims of the Tunisian terror attack is sluiced away from the still soiled paths and roadways of the hotel complex.
Their hotel is all but closed now. The predominantly British guests, the survivors, are on their way home in hastily arranged charter flights.
The Tunisian population, who depend on the tourist business, are left contemplating what happened here.
Shopkeeper Mohammed Kamis' stock was riddled with bullets
Their simple question is why would one of their own do this? It will ruin them.
Mohammed Kamis witnessed the gunman's final moments. He was killed a hundred yards from his shop, that he passed, still firing.
Play video "Tourists Return Home"
Video: Tourists Return Home
As he showed me the deflated blow up boats and rubber rings that were broken in a hail of bullets he said he had no answers to the events of Friday.
"What can we do. He isn't one of us is he?" he said.
"We saw him walking and then turning and firing at people chasing him. Workmen on the roof above threw cement and bricks at him trying to kill him. Then he turned the corner and the police saw him and he was killed," he added.
There were many other lucky escapes.
Kevin McCabe from Ireland, now resident here, took me round the shops and hotels where his friends are now looking at another summer of almost no trade.
1/6
Gallery: Sky Obtains Exclusive Images Of Tunisian Attacker Seifeddine Yacoubi
Sky News has obtained exclusive images of the Tunisian terrorist walking down a beach after carrying out an attack that killed 39 people, 15 of them British
He walks the same stretch of beach where the attack happened, every day. His son had emailed him that something was going on, so he decided to hurry home.
"I saw the guy. If I had stayed where I was I would be his first victim," he said as we walked the beach where the shooter attempted to escape.
"What is really important to remember is that local people took this guy on.
"They chased him and he fired and I saw them falling. I don't know if they were hit but they went down.
"They were unarmed but they chased him and others did everything they could to save the foreigners. It is amazing," he said.
Play video "Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism"
Video: Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism
The various hotel owners on the beach are demanding more security with armed police on patrol and at the hotels. But they want more.
"There needs to be a change in attitude both here and abroad," said Mohammed Becheur, the owner of the hotel where most casualties were recorded.
"The international community and Tunisia needs to control these Islamists or we will have lost."
Tunisia has suffered badly since the Arab Spring revolution of 2011.
Things have got better - but the terror attacks have continued and it is widely acknowledged that there is nothing to suspect they will stop any time soon.
1/7
Gallery: Victims Of Tunisia Gun Attack
Carly Lovett, 24, recently became engaged and was from Gainsborough, Lincolnshire. She worked as a beauty blogger and was a former student at the University of Lincoln
:: Watch Death On The Beach, a special Sky News report on Tunisia at 4.30pm, 6.30pm, 7.30pm and 9.30pm today on skynews.com, mobile, tablet, Sky go, or on TV: Sky 501, Virgin 602, Freesat 202, Freeview 132.
There will also be a special Sky News Tonight programme Terror In Tunisia at 7pm.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:03:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why Crucial Greek Debt Talks Keep Collapsing</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508515</Link>
        <Description>Sky's Economics Editor Ed Conway examines the three main reasons why the negotiations to reach a deal remain deadlocked.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sponsored By
Why Crucial Greek Debt Talks Keep Collapsing
Sky's Economics Editor Ed Conway examines the three main reasons why the negotiations to reach a deal remain deadlocked.
22:03, UK, Thursday 25 June 2015
Play video "Five Questions Answered On Greece"
Video: Five Questions Answered On Greece
If you've been following the Greek crisis for the past week or so you're probably wondering why on Earth it is that all of these crunch meetings have been collapsing.
You can boil it down to three reasons.
First, it's because there's so much at stake:
Syriza came into power promising to fight austerity; if it signs up to all the lender conditions it will be seen to have failed.
IMF head Christine Lagarde and Greek finance minister Yanis Varoufakis
The lenders, meanwhile, worry that any concessions to Greece will simply encourage other troubled eurozone countries to borrow and spend even more in the future, casting the long-term stability of European Monetary Union into doubt.
Second, it's because none of the participants are particularly familiar with the protocol here:
Play video "What Would A Greek Default Mean?"
Video: What Would A Greek Default Mean?
The lenders are used to dictating the terms, but this time around theyve agreed to a Brussels-level negotiation with the Greeks. For their part, the Greeks are totally unfamiliar with the language of Brussels, since theyre a new government with little institutional memory of what it takes to be a "Sherpa" (a lead negotiator).
The upshot is that each of the three eurogroup meetings weve had in the past week has begun without an agreed draft text: instead there have been multiple drafts floating around, meaning the ministers dont have anything to use as the basis for discussion.
Third, it's because of the manifold misunderstandings that still float around about the Greek economy:
Take pensions, one of the main issues at stake here. The Greeks are under extreme pressure to reform their pension system in exchange for extending their bailout (there has to be a quid pro quo, after all). The Germans are furious that some Greeks can retire so early. They moan about the comparative generosity of the set-up.
And indeed, looked at through some prisms, they have a point. The average age at which Greek workers receive a pension is lower than most other EU countries - 57.8 years old. Then again, this is about the same as Italy (58), is far higher than Slovenia (56.6) and is already poised to go up sharply, with the retirement age set to be increased to 67 in the coming decades. (The speed with which this happens is one of the contentious points in the negotiations.)
Play video "Brexit vs Grexit Analysis"
Video: Brexit vs Grexit Analysis
The Greek pension system is costly - around 13% of GDP, compared with an average of 7.8% across the developed OECD nations - though it's worth attaching a couple of riders to this concern.
First, the Greek population is older, on average, than in the rest of the EU - which in turn makes pension costs higher. Second, the generosity of the Greek pension system is in part a consequence of the stinginess of the rest of Greeces welfare state. For instance, Greek spending on incapacity benefits is lower than almost anywhere else in the OECD.
Spending on family benefits (stuff equivalent to Britains child tax credits) is likewise lower than the average.
The upshot of all of this is that over decades Greece's pensions system has become a kind of surrogate form of benefits for many Greek families. Many people retire early, lured by the pension, but also use that pension not just for themselves but to, say, support their unemployed son.
And these issues are not lost on Greece's lenders. The IMF, for instance, wants to cut the amount Greece pays out on pensions (most of its proposals thus far have revolved around increasing pension contributions, not cutting spending). But it also wants Greece to increase the sufficiency of its welfare system.
1/4
Gallery: The Deadlines On The Road Ahead For Athens
After a series of shifting payment deadlines Greece's future within the EU could be decided in the coming days
Or take another issue: taxes. It's often assumed that Greeks pay too little tax. Actually, when you look at the governments total revenues and compare them with other countries, Greece is actually already quite highly taxed. Yes, in part this is an artefact of the low GDP against which taxes are measured, but even before the crisis Greece wasnt the lowest-taxed country out there. The fact that there is widespread avoidance often overshadows the fact that tax revenues in Greece are already pretty high.
Then there's defence. Why is it that Greece's military is better funded than any other country in Europe? This helps explain why the IMF are so keen that defence gets cut as part of any agreement. And yet there is a reason for high defence spending: Greece sits at a strategic point at the edge of the EU.
Moreover, the Greek military are particularly politically powerful. They wouldn't take cuts lying down. The fact that Greece has had its own (recent) history of military coups only underlines this issue.
Such nuanced arguments are often lost, both in the coverage of the negotiations and, sometimes, in the negotiation rooms themselves. But they matter enormously in the long-run. And they explain why this is one of those knotty subjects where straightforward answers on either side dont always help all that much.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:44:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia Gunman Seifeddine Yacoubi Breakdancing</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509651</Link>
        <Description>Sky News obtains footage showing Seifeddine Rezgui wearing a hoodie and performing for a camera before he was radicalised.</Description>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Worst Footie Team Ever? Micronesia Lose 46-0
Micronesia's coach admits it was "boys against men" after his team suffered their third hiding in a row at the Pacific Games.
11:11, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
1/5
Gallery: Footballing Minnows Micronesia Suffer Third Thrashing
Micronesia lined up against Vanuatu after suffering heavy losses against Fiji and Tajiti. Pics: @darlingkevin/Twitter
Share by email
<<<<<<< HEAD
A football team have been beaten 46-0 in one of the most lopsided games ever seen in international football.
Micronesia's drubbing by Vanuatu followed a 38-0 loss to Fiji and a 30-0 score line against Tahiti at the Pacific Games in Papua New Guinea.
It meant the Federated States of Micronesia conceded a total of 114 goals in their three group matches.
Their Australian coach Stan Foster admitted it was "boys against men" and called for help from FIFA, football's world governing body.
"I'm hoping that FIFA will be coming (to Micronesia) next week for inspections and to hopefully affiliate us with Asia," he said.
"If they do, that will lead to us having technical assistance and everything else that brings. That would be a huge boost."
The half-time score was 24-0 but Vanuatu, ranked 200 in the world, showed their opponents no mercy, almost doubling their tally in the second half.
Vanuatu striker Jean Kaltack is now the tournament's top scorer
Vanuatu striker Jean Kaltack helped himself to 16 goals, making him the tournament's top scorer.
"They're boys, not men," Foster said of his team. "And they've been playing against well-seasoned men. I'm hoping the majority of our boys will be here for at least eight years."
Organisers said it was the biggest win in the history of international football, although it is unlikely to go in the record books as Micronesia is not a member of FIFA and it was an under-23 game.
The previous biggest defeat in a senior international was American Samoa's 31-0 loss to Australia in 2001.
Journalist Kevin Darling , reporting from the tournament, told Sky News the team were trying their best.
"The problem is it's not a squad of footballers, it's just a squad of normal blokes," he said.
"The goalkeeper told me he went in goal for the first time ever three weeks ago. And it showed, to be fair.
"Hopefully in 10 years or so they'll have a proper team and this would have all been worth it."
There was some good news for Micronesia as they were told they would be welcomed back when the event is next held in four years.
"That was big relief for me, because I was really worried the organisers would take us out of the competition," said Foster.
"I've been assured that we'll be allowed to come back and that they're aware that this is a development squad."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:55:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China Stocks Sink Despite Intervention Effort</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514734</Link>
        <Description>The Asian stock markets remain volatile, with Shanghai down 1.29% or 48.79 points at close, despite Monday's boost.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sponsored By
China Stocks Sink Despite Intervention Effort
The Asian stock markets remain volatile, with Shanghai down 1.29% or 48.79 points at close, despite Monday's boost.
12:55, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Mainland Chinese markets had enjoyed unprecedented growth
Share by email
Chinese markets fell by as much as 5.05% on Tuesday, despite interventions from the Chinese government aimed at averting a stock market collapse.
Emergency intervention measures introduced by the Chinese government over the weekend seem to be failing to stabilise the markets, in what analysts say is a make-or-break week for the Asian finance sector.
The measures include supporting brokerages and fund managers to allow them to buy more stock using a direct line of liquidity from the Chinese central bank, and halting the release of all initial public offerings, or IPOs, for the near future to encourage traders to buy existing stock rather than new releases.
Shanghai closed down 1.29%, or 48.79 points on Tuesday despite enjoying a boost following the announcement of the measures on Monday, and Chinas second exchange in Shenzhen also slumped by 5.34%.
Hong Kong finished 1.03% down, losing 260.97 points to end at 24975.31, extending losses of 3.18% from Monday.
The mainland Chinese markets have plunged almost 30% in recent weeks after enjoying massive growth in the past 12-18 months.
Previous attempts by China to arrest the slump - including an interest rate cut, relaxed rules on margin trading and proposals to let the state social security funds invest in equities - have so far failed, with analysts saying the new measures are unlikely to make a difference either.
"The more resources authorities commit to propping up the stock market, the more they ratchet up the potential fall-out risks should the market continue to collapse," said Andrew Wood, an analyst at BMI Research.
"This could give rise to a crisis of confidence in the authorities' ability to support both the stock market and the real economy."

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:23:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cosby: I Got Sedatives To Have Sex With Women</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514469</Link>
        <Description>The comedian's lawyers fail to block documents showing he admitted acquiring drugs, despite arguing they were "embarrassing".</Description>
        <MainBody>Cosby: I Got Sedatives To Have Sex With Women
The comedian's lawyers fail to block documents showing he admitted acquiring drugs, despite arguing they were "embarrassing".
10:23, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Play video "Bill Cosby: I Did Drug Woman"
Video: Bill Cosby: I Did Drug Woman
Share by email
Comedian Bill Cosby admitted in 2005 obtaining sedatives with the intent of giving them to women he wanted to have sex with.
The US star made the admission in a civil law suit and documents from that case have only just been made public.
More than 40 women have come forward in the past year to claim that Cosby sexually assaulted them - some also believing they were drugged.
Lawyer Gloria Allred pictured with two alleged victims in January
Cosby admitted under oath he had obtained Quaaludes, known as Mandrax in the UK, after a woman named Andrea Constand sued him for allegedly drugging and assaulting her.
In his deposition, Cosby admitted giving it to at least one woman but claimed he had only given Ms Costand the allergy medicine Benadryl.
Play video "March: Cosby In Odd Video Message"
Video: March: Cosby In Odd Video Message
The case was settled for an undisclosed amount in 2006.
Cosby's lawyers tried to stop the information being released, arguing it would cause him serious embarrassment but the AP news agency won the right to make the documents public.
Celebrity lawyer Gloria Allred, who is representing many of the alleged victims, said it "confirms the allegations of numerous victims who have alleged that he had used drugs to sexually assault them".
1/14
Gallery: A Profile Of Bill Cosby
Bill Cosby was born in Philadelphia in 1937, one of four children
The actor-comedian, best known for hit sitcom The Cosby Show, has never been criminally charged.
Many of the claims date back to the 1970s and are too old for him to face legal proceedings.
But the star has seen his career nosedive since the allegations started to pile up, with TV shows and live events being cancelled.
Play video "Jan: Bill Cosby Heckled"
Video: Jan: Bill Cosby Heckled
Cosbys representatives have dismissed previous claims as "absolutely false" but have yet to respond to the release of the court documents.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:16:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'China's Walter White' Held 'For Selling Drugs'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1514695</Link>
        <Description>Police say a university professor set up a chemistry lab and sold an ecstasy substitute online to clients across the world.</Description>
=======
Sky News has obtained video showing Seifeddine Rezgui as a breakdancing youth around five years before he murdered almost 40 people in a popular beach resort.
In the footage, thought to have been filmed in 2010, Rezgui wears skinny jeans, a hoodie and baseball cap and performs spins and handstands to a techno soundtrack.
The video was posted on a Facebook page set up by a group of friends interested in rap music and breakdancing and has attracted a string of comments since the Sousse massacre.
One reads: "Before he was an artist - then he became a demon."
The group was created in 2010 and while early posts focus on members' dancing exploits, entries took on a more political nature as the Arab Spring - which began in Tunisia in 2010 - gripped the region.
1/6
Gallery: Sky Obtains Exclusive Images Of Tunisian Attacker Seifeddine Yacoubi
Sky News has obtained exclusive images of the Tunisian terrorist walking down a beach after carrying out an attack that killed 39 people, 15 of them British
How and when the 23-year-old turned from an easy-going teenager into a disciple of the Islamic State death cult will be a central focus for investigators in Tunisia.
Friends told Sky News that even two days before the attack, Rezgui showed no signs of radicalisation, visiting a cafe and going for a walk.
Those accounts were backed up by the killer's uncle Ali al Rezgui, who told the Telegraph the family had seen nothing to worry them - although Seifeddine Rezgui had apparently been traumatised by the death of his brother in a lightning strike in 2010.
Play video "Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism"
Video: Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism
Mr Rezgui told the paper:"He used to use hair gel and wear the nicest of clothes, and he used to do break dancing.
"He even used to go to competitions and things like that in Tunis, he was well known for that here. He didn't even have a beard, and I've never seen him with anyone with a beard.
"We have extremists like that in Gaafour, but never have I seen him with them. Now he's shooting people with a Kalashnikov, it's just so confusing."
Play video "Special Report: IS Recruitment"
Video: Special Report: IS Recruitment
:: Watch Death On The Beach, a special Sky News report on Tunisia at 4.30pm, 6.30pm, 7.30pm and 9.30pm today on skynews.com, mobile, tablet, Sky go, or on TV: Sky 501, Virgin 602, Freesat 202, Freeview 132.
There will also be a special Sky News Tonight programme Terror In Tunisia at 7pm.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:24:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fifteen Libya Emails Missing From Clinton Cache</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508754</Link>
        <Description>The emails, relating to security in the country before a 2012 attack, are given to the State Department by Sidney Blumenthal.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Fifteen Libya Emails Missing From Clinton Cache
The emails, relating to security in the country before a 2012 attack, are given to the State Department by Sidney Blumenthal.
09:24, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
Hillary Clinton has said she handed over all her "work-related" emails
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
The US State Department has said it cannot find 15 emails from Hillary Clinton's private server that were released by a House of Representatives panel investigating the 2012 attack in Benghazi.
The emails, which all pre-date the 11 September attack on the US diplomatic compound, contain intelligence reports passed to Mrs Clinton by her long-time adviser Sidney Blumenthal, officials have said.
Several previously undisclosed emails were handed over to the State Department by Mr Blumenthal, which revealed it did not have a complete record from Mrs Clinton's time in office as Secretary of State.
US ambassador Chris Stevens and three other Americans were killed in 2012
The 15 emails were either missing from the records she provided, or included only in partial form.
They include a media account about the killing of one of Moammar Gaddafi's sons, reports on internal politics among Libyan rebels and news of the assassination of a former Gaddafi minister in Vienna.
Play video "Hillary Clinton 'Sensitive' Emails"
Video: Hillary Clinton 'Sensitive' Emails
The last one was sent 28 August, 2012 - two weeks before the Benghazi attack.
Nick Merrill, a spokesman for Mrs Clinton, said the Democratic presidential candidate had given the department "all emails in her possession from Mr Blumenthal".
He said he could not explain where the origin of the additional correspondence Mr Blumenthal had provided in response to a subpoena.
Mrs Clinton - the front-runner for the Democratic nomination for the 2016 presidential election - has faced strong criticism that she flouted record-keeping and transparency rules by using a private email account for her work.
The private address was connected to a server in her home.
Mrs Clinton has insisted she used the private account for convenience and has broken no rules. The account was revealed in March, more than two years after she stepped down as the top US diplomat.
Trey Gowdy, the Republican congressman who heads the select committee investigating the Benghazi attack, said the incomplete email record "raises serious questions".
He said: "This has implications far beyond Libya, Benghazi and our committee's work.
"This conclusively shows her email arrangement with herself, which was then vetted by her own lawyers, has resulted in an incomplete public record."
In March, Mrs Clinton said that she had given the State Department all the emails she sent and received that "could possibly be work-related".
She said the 30,490 emails she handed over in December included all those that referred to Libya or Benghazi, along side work-related correspondence from "long-time friends".
She said that after those emails were copies, all her correspondence - including another 30,000 that were deemed personal - were deleted from the server.
It comes after an Islamic-State militant thought to have been involved in the attack in Benghazi was reportedly killed in a drone strike in Iraq last week.
Four Americans, including US ambassador Chris Stevens, were killed during the attack on the US outpost in Benghazi on 11 September 2012.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:44:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia: Exclusive Pictures Of Gunman On Beach</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509487</Link>
        <Description>Sky News obtains exclusive pictures of Seifeddine Rezgui strolling calmly along the shore with his Kalashnikov.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia: Exclusive Pictures Of Gunman On Beach
Sky News obtains exclusive pictures of Seifeddine Rezgui strolling calmly along the shore with his Kalashnikov.
13:44, UK, Sunday 28 June 2015
Play video "First Images Of Tunisia Gunman"
Video: First Images Of Tunisia Gunman
Share by email
Chilling pictures have emerged of the Tunisia gunman on the beach where he killed at least 38 tourists.
The images show Seifeddine Rezgui strolling down the shore with his weapon as people watch in horror from behind.
The pictures have emerged as witnesses described how he was "very, very calm" when he opened fire on holidaymakers after emerging from the sea.
Tourists also told how Tunisian builders threw bags of cement and bricks at Rezgui from the top of buildings as he fired his weapon in nearby streets.
Others described how Tunisians pleaded with the killer "why are you killing these people?" - but he just sneered and walked on.
1/6
Gallery: Sky Obtains Exclusive Images Of Tunisian Attacker Seifeddine Yacoubi
Sky News has obtained exclusive images of the Tunisian terrorist walking down a beach after carrying out an attack that killed 39 people, 15 of them British
The accounts, and pictures, were revealed by Sky's Chief Correspondent Stuart Ramsay, reporting from the beach in Sousse.
"The shooter had his weapon concealed inside a sun umbrella - he basically came here, went into the water and washed," Ramsay said.
"Then he came out, he got his gun out.
"He was very, very calm - he then attacked one woman shooting her dead immediately.
"He then shot other individuals we are told and began spraying into the beach area which had a lot of people."
Play video "The Gunman's Route Of Destruction"
Video: The Gunman's Route Of Destruction
Ramsay continued: "He then went inside the hotel again - again there was firing.
"Some said they heard explosions, some say he was throwing grenades and more people who werecaught at that gate were killed.
"Afterwards, after he'd been in, he came out and he walked now along the beach, which was full of people who had come to see what had happened and disappeared up a side road.
"He walked past a number of Tunisians who said to him 'why are you killing these people, why are you killing these people?'.
"He basically sneered at them and said 'well I'm not killing you' and basically walked on past them.
Play video "People Run From Gunfire"
Video: People Run From Gunfire
"He was still firing when he walked into the street.
"We are told that builders who were working on the tops of buildings were throwing bricks and bags of cement on to him to see if they could actually hit him.
"By the time he turned the next corner, the police were there and from high positions they shot him dead."
Ramsay said it is believed the shooting lasted between 30 and 35 minutes.
"Some of the questions people are asking are how long did it take the police to get here, were they too slow, should there have been more police here already."
Play video "'It Was A Bloodbath'"
Video: 'It Was A Bloodbath'
:: Watch Death On The Beach, a special Sky News report on Tunisia at 4.30pm, 6.30pm, 7.30pm and 9.30pm today on skynews.com, mobile, tablet, Sky go, or on TV: Sky 501, Virgin 602, Freesat 202, Freeview 132.
There will also be a special Sky News Tonight programme Terror In Tunisia at 7pm.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:25:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Family Flees $1.3m Home Over 'Watcher' Threats</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508851</Link>
        <Description>Creepy letters about "young blood" and asking "have they found what is in the walls?" scare the family from their New Jersey home.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Family Flees $1.3m Home Over 'Watcher' Threats
Creepy letters about "young blood" and asking "have they found what is in the walls?" scare the family from their New Jersey home.
11:25, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
The family received threatening letters shortly after buying the $1.3m home
Share by email
A New Jersey couple has sued the people who sold them a $1.3m house after they claim a series of threatening letters from a stalker called "The Watcher" forced them to leave the property.
According to the lawsuit, the family began receiving creepy messages from "The Watcher" three days after they had bought their new home in Westfield.
It claims the previous owners of the house had also received letters from the stalker but failed to disclose it during the sale in the summer of 2014.
The letters read: "Why are you here? I will find out. My grandfather watched the house in the 1920s and my father watched in the 1960s. It is now my time.
The couple never moved into the property because of the letters
"Do you need to fill the house with the young blood I requested? Once I know their names I will call to them and draw them to me. I asked the [prior owners] to bring me young blood.
"Have they found what is in the walls yet? In time they will. I am pleased to know your names and the names now of the young blood you have brought to me."
The letters also asked "will the young bloods play in the basement?" and asked to know "who has the rooms facing the street?"
The family found the letters so disturbing, they never moved into the property, NJ.com reported.
The lawsuit, filed at Superior Court in Elizabeth, reads: "Upon information and belief, defendants suppressed all information regarding 'The Watcher' even though they were either on constructive or actual notice of the harm that could befall the plaintiffs and their minor children.
"Both [former owners] knew or should have known that 'peace of mind' and 'security' were and are of paramount importance to the plaintiffs, specifically and in general as is true to the high end market to whom defendants were marketing the home for sale."
Westfield Township Mayor Andrew Skibitsky told a public council hearing that an "exhaustive investigation" had been carried out into the threatening letters.
No suspect has been identified and no charges have been filed in the case.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 13:06:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Watch: Terrified People Flee Tunisia Attack</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509287</Link>
        <Description>New footage catches the confusion and panic during the attack on a Tunisian resort, showing people fleeing as gunshots ring out.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Watch: Terrified People Flee Tunisia Attack
New footage catches the confusion and panic during the attack on a Tunisian resort, showing people fleeing as gunshots ring out.
11:06, UK, Saturday 27 June 2015
Play video "Gunshots Ring Out"
Video: Gunshots Ring Out
Share by email
Footage has emerged showing terrified people running away amid the terror attack in Tunisia.
The mobile phone video, filmed from the balcony of the Hotel Imperial Marhaba, captures the confusion and panic amid the attack.
People can be seen fleeing as gunshots ring out in the background.
"They're here, they're here," a voice is heard saying in the video, shot by holidaymaker Matthew Kenyon.
In the attack on Friday, a gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel with a rifle he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 38 people and injuring scores of others.
Play video "People Run As Gunshots Are Heard"
Video: People Run As Gunshots Are Heard
Terrified tourists ran for cover after the gunfire erupted, many barricading in their hotel rooms for hours.
The Islamic State has claimed responsibility for the attack.
A British Embassy crisis team has been sent here to help tourists caught up in the terror, many of whom are desperate to catch flights home.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:32:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deal On Migrants Struck Amid Calais Chaos</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508570</Link>
        <Description>EU leaders strike a deal to relocate 40,000 migrants - as Sky News joins a lorry driver travelling from Calais to Dover.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Deal On Migrants Struck Amid Calais Chaos
EU leaders strike a deal to relocate 40,000 migrants - as Sky News joins a lorry driver travelling from Calais to Dover.
07:32, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
Migrants rest after disembarking in the Sicilian harbour of Augusta, Italy
Share by email
A deal has been struck to relocate tens of thousands of migrants who have arrived in Italy and Greece to other EU states.
The deal, made by EU leaders in Brussels, will see member states share the burden of 40,000 migrants who have crossed theMediterranean.
However, there will be no mandatory quotas for countries, and Britain's opt-out on EU home affairs issues means it is not obliged to take part.
New figures from UNHCR- the UN refugee agency - reveal that 63,000 migrants have arrived in Greece by sea this year and 62,000 in Italy.
After late-night talks at the European Council summit, president Donald Tusk said: "Leaders agreed that 40,000 persons in need will be relocated from Greece and Italy to other states over the next two years.
Play video "Calais Under Pressure"
Video: Calais Under Pressure
"Interior ministers will finalise the scheme by the end of July."
The deal came amid chaos at Calais as hundreds of migrants boarded queuing lorries this week during French ferry worker strike action.
David Cameron described the situation as "totally unacceptable" and called for the French and British authorities to work together.
One of the lorry drivers who regularly makes the crossing to Dover says it has been a nightmare in recent weeks.
1/8
Gallery: Truckers' Checklist
"Wednesday was the worst it's been. The migrants were everywhere, trying to get into lorries, and it was chaos," Dave Currie told Sky News.
"It felt like being in Beirut or somewhere."
MrCurriesaid it can be intimidating at times when desperate migrants try to get into the lorries.
But he said sometimes it is quiet and there is little interaction as police are out in large numbers.
Play video "Endless Attempts To Cross Border"
Video: Endless Attempts To Cross Border
Sky News reporter Joe Tidy has been invited to sit alongside MrCurrie during his trip and fit cameras to his lorry.
You can follow the journey on social media throughout Friday.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:03:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What We Know About The Tunisia Attack Gunman</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509439</Link>
        <Description>Seifeddine Rezgui, an aviation student in his early 20s, had never travelled abroad and may have been radicalised on home soil.</Description>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
'China's Walter White' Held 'For Selling Drugs'
Police say a university professor set up a chemistry lab and sold an ecstasy substitute online to clients across the world.
11:16, UK, Tuesday 07 July 2015
Actor Bryan Cranston in character as Breaking Bad's Walter White
Share by email
<<<<<<< HEAD
A Chinese professor has been arrested for allegedly selling drugs worth millions of dollars to clients in the US, Britain, Canada and Australia, Chinese state media reported.
The man, identified only as Zhang, was dubbed by the official Xinhua news agency "China's real-life Walter White" in reference to the chemistry teacher-turned-drug kingpin in the TV series Breaking Bad.
According to the allegations, Zhang sold methylone, a psychoactive drug commonly used as a substitute for MDMA, or ecstasy, over the internet.
He first learned about the popularity of such drugs while teaching as a visiting academic in Australia, Xinhua reported.
He then started a chemical company in 2005 and had staff manufacture "hundreds of kilograms" of methylone.
Last month, police raided Zhang's lab in the city of Wuhan and reportedly found 20kg of drugs. Eight people were arrested then.
Zhang, a professor in an unidentified university in Wuhan, is believed to have made millions of dollars, according to police, though no exact figure was provided.
Between March and November 2014, the business allegedly sold at least 193kg of the substance to the overseas customers.
Last May police said they had arrested a former chemistry professor on suspicion of selling a drug recipe to a gang which cooked up synthetic narcotics.
=======
The gunman in the Tunisian attack was not on a terror watch list, but may have been radicalised by extremist preachers about six months ago, according to security officials.
Seifeddine Rezgui was an aviation student from Gaafour  a town approximately 100 miles from Sousse, where 38 people were killed when he withdrew a Kalashnikov from a beach umbrella and began shooting at foreigners, most of them British.
He had been dressed like any other tourist, wearing dark shorts, a T-shirt and a necklace  and it is estimated his rampage lasted for seven minutes before he was shot dead by police outside the hotel.
Rezgui, who was in his early 20s, had never travelled abroad in his lifetime, prompting fears that he was radicalised at home, potentially at a local mosque.
His family said they had seen no signs that he had been drawn to the extremism of Islamic State - although he apparently been traumatised by his brother's death in a lightning strike in 2010.
1/6
Gallery: Sky Obtains Exclusive Images Of Tunisian Attacker Seifeddine Yacoubi
Sky News has obtained exclusive images of the Tunisian terrorist walking down a beach after carrying out an attack that killed 39 people, 15 of them British
Video has emerged showing him wearing a hoodie andbreakdancing five years ago, although more recent Facebook postings suggest he may have taken an interest in jihad.
Islamic State has claimed responsibility for the attack  and in Twitter messages, referred to Rezgui using the jihadist pseudonym Abu Yahya al Qayruhni.
It is believed Rezgui was extremely familiar with the layout of the Imperial Marhaba resort.
Play video "Returned Tunisians Imprisoned"
Video: Returned Tunisians Imprisoned
One English tourist who was leaving Tunisia said: "It was horror what we saw, he was killing in an incredible way. It was clear he knew the hotel, he was everywhere.
"There was no sign he was an extremist, he just looked like a normal young man."
A waiter who was at the scene when the attack unfolded added: "I was on the beach when he started shooting. We got everyone back towards the hotel, but he followed us."
Play video "The Gunman's Route Of Destruction"
Video: The Gunman's Route Of Destruction
Tunisian Prime Minister Habib Essid described Rezgui as a "good student" who was always attending classes  and other accounts have emerged of a young man who liked partying.
More than 3,000 Tunisians are believed to be fighting for IS and other extremist groups in Iraq, Libya and Syria  with some militants warning they would return to their homeland to launch a terrorist attack.
:: Watch Death On The Beach, a special Sky News report on Tunisia at 4.30pm, 6.30pm, 7.30pm and 9.30pm today on skynews.com, mobile, tablet, Sky go, or on TV: Sky 501, Virgin 602, Freesat 202, Freeview 132.
Play video "Special Report: IS Recruitment"
Video: Special Report: IS Recruitment
There will also be a special Sky News Tonight programme Terror In Tunisia at 7pm.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Promoted Stories
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
