<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Sky-News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:46:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Emergency Cash To Continue For Greek Banks</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509799</Link>
        <Description>The decision to maintain - but not increase - emergency funding for the banks still leaves Greece facing an uncertain week.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Emergency Cash To Continue For Greek Banks
The decision to maintain - but not increase - emergency funding for the banks still leaves Greece facing an uncertain week.
14:46, UK, Sunday 28 June 2015
Play video "'A Very Important Week For Greece'"
Video: 'A Very Important Week For Greece'
Share by email
The European Central Bank has announced it will continue its emergency cash lifeline to Greece's banks at the amount agreed on Friday - but there will be no increase.
The ECB said it would watch financial markets and "the potential implications for the monetary policy stance" closely amid fears of turmoil and contagion when markets re-open tomorrow.
It added: "The Governing Council decided to maintain the ceiling to the provision of emergency liquidity assistance (ELA) to Greek banks at the level decided on Friday.
"The Governing Council stands ready to reconsider its decision,"
Greek finance ministerYanis Varoufakis said Greece would work with the ECBon responding to the cash crisis facing its banks before they open tomorrow.
1/5
Gallery: Cash Machine Queues As Time Begins To Run Out For Greece
A woman walks past graffiti calling for Greece to exit the EU
When questioned, however, he seemed to suggest Greece might not pay the 1.6bn it owes to the International Monetary Fund on Tuesday, saying the European Central Bank should pay the money to the IMF out of the profits it made on Greek bonds in 2014.
The ECB's announcement came after Bank of Greece chief Yannis Stournaras said his bank "will take all measures necessary to ensure financial stability for Greek citizens in these difficult circumstances".
The news will do little to calm the fears of thousands of Greeks who queued to clear out their accounts, despite pleas from finance minister NadiaValavani to remain calm and not try to withdraw their savings.
European creditors had already refused to extend Greece's international bailout beyond Tuesday and, with a bank run gathering pace, the country still faces a financial crunch.
Play video "179 out of 300 MPs Back Referendum"
Video: 179 out of 300 MPs Back Referendum
Sky News Europe correspondent Robert Nisbet said the decision meant "a very uncertain week" ahead for Greece, adding: "people may not be able to get enough cash out of their bank accounts, it may affect businesses trading but all of this is done to protect the integrity of the banking system until that referendum happens on Sunday."
He said it was likely that "capital controls" would be brought in tomorrow, which would see banks closed until the referendum.
In a speech before the vote, Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras has already said he is confident that "the Greek people will say an emphatic no to the ultimatum" by the country's creditors.
The expression "emphatic no" is a reference to when Greek authorities declared "no" to an ultimatum by the Italian army demanding to occupy Greek territory in 1940. One of the two Greek national holidays, 28 October, is named "the day of no".
Play video "Greek Bailout To End Tuesday Night"
Video: Greek Bailout To End Tuesday Night
On Saturday, eurozone finance ministers refused to extend Greece's bailout programme beyond Tuesday - meaning Athens is at risk of defaulting on its 1.5bn IMF payment.
MrVaroufakis had requested an extension of several weeks until the referendum had taken place, but Mr Dijisselbloem said it would not be possible to provide a temporary extension until the result of the ballot is known.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:28:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Referendum Not A Simple Yes Or No</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509399</Link>
        <Description>If Greece does leave the euro, it would face even greater short-term austerity and pain than it has so far, writes Ed Conway.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Greece Referendum Not A Simple Yes Or No
If Greece does leave the euro, it would face even greater short-term austerity and pain than it has so far, writes Ed Conway.
13:28, UK, Saturday 27 June 2015
Some think a 'no' would effectively mean Greece has voted to leave the euro
Follow Ed
Austerity, deficits, loans and currencies. Greece's euro crisis is about lots of things, but in the end it has always been about something else: national sovereignty and democracy.
When Greece joined the Eurozone (without a referendum, it should be said) it ceded some of its sovereignty.
Since the country now shared a currency with fellow Europeans it would no longer have direct control over its monetary policy.
That was simply part of the deal - and it is part of the explanation for how it ended up in the mess it is in.
It meant a dilution of sovereignty in economic "peacetime".
Play video "Greek PM Says Ultimatums Won't Work"
Video: Greek PM Says Ultimatums Won't Work
As part of the single currency, Greece lost control of its own interest rates, and thus lost influence over the yield on government bonds.
The country could suddenly borrow at unprecedented cheap rates - despite not having the productivity to justify it.
So began the bubble that fuelled the Greek crisis in the first place (a simplified version of history, I admit).
But even during "peacetime" Greece still maintained a certain amount of control over its fiscal policy - taxing and spending.
When the crisis struck and it needed to rely on its fellow Eurozone nations (and the IMF, and ECB) for financial assistance, it effectively ceded most of its fiscal sovereignty too.
In return for the loans, the Greeks had to accede to certain demands.
There is nothing particularly unusual in this.
When the UK borrowed money from the US after the Second World War a whole host of demands came attached to it: that the UK should open up its economic system; that it should sell off a whole load of publicly-owned assets at cheap prices.
There was even talk about selling off the Crown Jewels.
None of this is particularly pleasant, but it is an unfortunate reality.
To make matters worse, in Greece's case, the lenders deciding those conditions discredited themselves repeatedly.
Their forecasts for the impact of austerity on Greece were completely wrong.
Their programme contributed to a depression deeper and longer than anything seen since modern records began.
1/5
Gallery: The Deadlines On The Road Ahead For Athens
After a series of shifting payment deadlines Greece's future within the EU could be decided in the coming days
But, having ceded its sovereignty - both monetary and fiscal - the Greeks could do little about it.
They had to suffer as a poorly-constructed bailout and overly-aggressive austerity was imposed on them.
In January the Greeks voted in Alexis Tsipras as prime minister on a manifesto which promised to cancel austerity.
The problem, of course, was that because of all of the above, in practice the Greeks did not and do not have the sovereign right to do that themselves.
The best Mr Tsipras could do was to try to get a better deal and improve the terms of the bailout, which is what he has been doing in Brussels and Athens for the past six months.
His decision to call a referendum next weekend seems to be a tacit admission he has failed.
There are a number of short and medium term problems, the most pressing of which is what happens to the financial system between now and next weekend.
The slow-motion invisible system-wide bank run afflicting Greece's financial system over the past couple of months threatens to turn into a rapid, visible one.
People are already being photographed queuing up to take money out of their bank accounts.
There is the question of what the Eurozone decides today at its finance ministers' meeting.
Do they grant Greece the five-day bailout extension they are demanding? Do they refuse?
Do they simply talk about plan b - the capital controls and restrictions they would need to impose to incubate Greece ahead of a possible euro exit?
What part does the International Monetary Fund, who will almost certainly not get paid on time on Tuesday, play in the saga?
1/17
Gallery: Pro-EU Protests In Athens
Pro-euro protesters take part in a rally in front of the Parliament in Athens, Greece
But more than these short-term questions is the bigger medium to long term one: if Greeks do as their prime minister is suggesting and vote no to the current bailout deal, what does that imply?
As far as many here in Brussels are concerned, it means Greece will effectively have voted to leave the Eurozone.
But Syriza figures are insisting it simply means another stage in the negotiations.
The answer to that question will determine the way many vote.
In Greece there is both widespread disdain for the bailout and the conditions attached to it, and widespread support for euro membership.
So the way the debate is framed will determine the result.
But the reality is that if Greece did leave the euro, it would face even greater short-term austerity and pain than it has in the past year or so.
It would face more financial turbulence.
It might swap euro bailout conditions with even more shady ones from Russia or China.
It would regain some of its monetary sovereignty, but in exchange for this it would suffer a fair amount of pain.
There are no easy answers here, which is why what looks like a simple yes/no question is far more complex and unpredictable than it seems.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:10:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British School Children In Belgium Bus Crash</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509749</Link>
        <Description>A coach driver is killed and a British pupil is in intensive care after a bus carrying schoolchildren overturned in Belgium.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
British School Children In Belgium Bus Crash
A coach driver is killed and a British pupil is in intensive care after a bus carrying schoolchildren overturned in Belgium.
15:10, UK, Sunday 28 June 2015
Play video "34 British Children On Crashed Bus"
Video: 34 British Children On Crashed Bus
A coach driver has been killed and his assistant seriously injured after a bus carrying staff and pupils from Brentwood School in Essex crashed in Belgium, a spokesman for the school said.
A child was in intensive care after suffering a head injury in the crash, the school said.
It is believed there were 34 first and second year pupils - aged between 11 and 13 - on the bus, along with six teachers and the two drivers, all on their way to a theme park in the German city of Cologne.
At least one other child was also seriously injured in the crash and 15 of those on board have minor injuries.
The spokesman added that two senior members of staff have travelled to Belgium to help.
1/6
Gallery: UK School Bus Crashes In Belgium
A bus carrying British schoolchildren went off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast
Those who were not injured were taken to a crisis centre where the community of Middelkerke has set up up a support service including clothing, food and psychological assistance.
The bus hit a bridge support and rolled over on the E40 motorway near Middelkerke, in West Flanders at 9.45am local time this morning.
The coach is operated by Northern Ireland-based Richmond Coaches and a spokesman for the company, which is based inLisburn, said what had happened was "a tragedy" and the company was co-operating with the authorities.
Play video "Children On Coach Taken To Hospital"
Video: Children On Coach Taken To Hospital
He said the company's thoughts were with everyone involved.
A spokesman for the Foreign and Commonwealth Office said"We are aware of reports of a bus crash in Belgium involving British nationals.
"We are working with the Belgian authorities to establish details of the incident".
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 06:18:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds Injured In Taiwan Water Park Blast</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509591</Link>
        <Description>Inflatable dinghies are used to carry away casualties or as makeshift beds to treat those injured in the explosion and fire.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Hundreds Injured In Taiwan Water Park Blast
Inflatable dinghies are used to carry away casualties or as makeshift beds to treat those injured in the explosion and fire.
04:18, UK, Sunday 28 June 2015
Play video "Explosion At Taiwan Water Park"
Video: Explosion At Taiwan Water Park
Share by email
More than 500 people have been injured after an explosion and fire during a concert at a Taiwan water park.
The blast and ensuing blaze happened when a coloured powder being sprayed near a music stage ignited and turned into a fireball that swept through the 1,000-strong crowd.
Footage from the scene showed the stage on fire and crowds running away, some of them only dressed in swimwear.
A powder spray ignited and sent a fireball through the crowd
Of those hurt, more than 80 are said to have been seriously injured.
There are reports some victims had suffered burns to more than 40% of their bodies.
Inflatable rubber dinghies were used to carry casualties away from the scene or used as makeshift beds to treat those injured.
A spokesman for the New Taipei City fire department said: "Our initial understanding is this explosion and fire... was caused by the powder spray. It could have been due to the heat of the lights on the stage."
Of those hurt, more than 80 are said to have been seriously injured
Officials said the blaze at the Formosa Water Park, just outside the island's capital Taipei, was brought swiftly under control.
One eyewitness told local news channel CTI: "It started on the left side of the stage.
"At the beginning I thought it was part of the special effects of the party but then I realised there was something wrong and people started screaming and running."
An injured man is given aid at the scene
New Taipei Mayor Eric Chu said: "We feel sad and regretful about the accident."
Extra medical staff had also been called in to help treat the victims.
"I've ordered the park to shut down immediately and be placed under a rigorous investigation," he added.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:58:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Identifying All British Victims 'Will Take Time'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509639</Link>
        <Description>Theresa May warns the identification process is complex, as flags over No 10 will be flown at half-mast in memory of the victims.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Identifying All British Victims 'Will Take Time'
Theresa May warns the identification process is complex, as flags over No 10 will be flown at half-mast in memory of the victims.
14:58, UK, Sunday 28 June 2015
Play video "May: Identifying Victims 'Complex'"
Video: May: Identifying Victims 'Complex'
Share by email
Identifying all British victims of the Tunisia terror attack will take time because few of the holidaymakers gunned down on the beach were carrying IDs, Theresa May has warned.
The Home Secretary, who chaired a meeting of the Government's emergency Cobra committee, also said there was no evidence that the gunman had specifically targeted British tourists in Friday's attack, which left 38 people dead.
Meanwhile, Prime Minister David Cameron has asked for the flags over No 10 to be flown at half-mast in memory of the victims of the attack.
"The process of identifying individuals who have been affected and the deceased is a complex one," she told reporters, rejecting suggestions that the Foreign Office had been slow in helping families looking for information on the missing.
"It is imperative that we get it absolutely right for the families, and that can sometimes take time."
1/7
Gallery: Victims Of Tunisia Gun Attack
Carly Lovett, 24, recently became engaged and was from Gainsborough, Lincolnshire. She worked as a beauty blogger and was a former student at the University of Lincoln
Ms May said the victims would not have had passports or other forms of identification with them on the beach in Sousse and some victims were being moved between hospitals in the country.
She said the UK had dispatched a medical liaison team and a small group of advisers to look at security arrangements in the area, which attracts thousands of western tourists every year.
The British ambassador to Tunisia was due to meet with senior government officials later in the day.
Earlier on Sunday, the Foreign Office warned that further terrorist attacks in Tunisia are possible following the beach resort massacre.
"Further terrorist attacks in Tunisia, including in tourist resorts, are possible, including by individuals who are unknown to the authorities and whose actions are inspired by terrorist groups via social media," the updated advice on the Foreign Office website reads.
"You should be especially vigilant at this time and follow the advice of Tunisian security authorities and your tour operator."
1/4
Gallery: Tunisia Peace Rally After Attack
Hundreds of people gathered for a peace rally near the site of the attack in Sousse, a Tunisian beach resort popular with foreigners
The victims of gunman Seifeddine Rezgui include 15 Britons , though officials have warned that the toll is expected to rise.
Ms May noted the Tunisia shooting marked the most significant loss of British life since the attacks on 7 July 2005 in London, in which 52 people were killed.
Speaking earlier on the BBC's Andrew Marr Show, she warned that the risk to Britain had become "more diverse" in recent years - including not just the risk of groups plotting over time to strike in the country but also that of spontaneous attacks by a "lone wolf".
She said that some 40 plots had been foiled in the UK in the past decade, including "a number of plots" in recent months.
Mrs May said the Government will be introducing a counter-extremism strategy to tackle radicalisation.
In Tunisia, security officials added an extra 1,000 police to tourist sites and beaches.
Play video "'We Were In Lock Down'"
Video: 'We Were In Lock Down'
"We don't want to make tourist establishments into barracks, that's not our goal. But we must act to guarantee the security of the tourist sector," saidInterior Minister Mohamed Najem Gharsalli.
But thousands of shocked tourists were leaving the nation after the attack.
Up to 2,500 more people could return to the UK from Tunisia today, as part of holiday firms' efforts to get those on holiday at the beach resort home as soon as possible .
On Saturday, Thomson and First Choice said it had already expatriated 1,000 of its customers, but added that there were still 5,400 remaining.
Tui Group, which runs the companies, was unable to confirm how many of the 38 people killed or injured in the shooting were its customers, but said there had been a "number of fatalities".
An additional 11 Thomson flights as well as one third-party flight with Nouvelle Air are currently due to leave today.
Play video "Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism"
Video: Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism
The Association of British Travel Agents, known as Abta, estimates there are approximately 20,000 customers currently on holiday with Abta members in Tunisia.
But it said there will also be a number of holidaymakers who have travelled independently.
Holidaymakers elsewhere in the country were advised to contact their tour operators and follow any instructions issued by local authorities.
While many have left, a scattering of foreign tourists are still reportedly at the resort.
Welsh couple Angela Chambers and Peter Phillips told the Associated Press they declined their tour operator's offer to take them to the airport last night.
"I think we feel safer here than last night going to the airport," said Ms Chambers.
1/6
Gallery: Sky Obtains Exclusive Images Of Tunisian Attacker Seifeddine Yacoubi
Sky News has obtained exclusive images of the Tunisian terrorist walking down a beach after carrying out an attack that killed 39 people, 15 of them British
Mr Phillips added that "we want to see our holiday out".
In Sousselast night, people gathered for a protest against terrorism.
Crowds gathered after dark with some holding candles while others carried flags including those of the United Kingdom and Tunisia.
Some people held posters aloft proclaiming "Peace" and "Sousse will never die".
:: Watch Death On The Beach, a special Sky News report on Tunisia at 4.30pm, 6.30pm, 7.30pm and 9.30pm today on skynews.com, mobile, tablet, Sky go, or on TV: Sky 501, Virgin 602, Freesat 202, Freeview 132.
There will also be a special Sky News Tonight programme Terror In Tunisia at 7pm.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:44:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Shock For Tunisians Who Tried To Stop Killer</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509630</Link>
        <Description>As the blood of massacre victims is washed from the streets, locals are stunned that one of their own carried out the atrocity.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Shock For Tunisians Who Tried To Stop Killer
As the blood of massacre victims is washed from the streets, locals are stunned that one of their own carried out the atrocity.
13:44, UK, Sunday 28 June 2015
Play video "Tunisia Terror Attacks May Continue"
Video: Tunisia Terror Attacks May Continue
By Stuart Ramsay, Chief Correspondent, In Sousse
It is a macabre scene, but it is the reality of what happened here.
The blood of the victims of the Tunisian terror attack is sluiced away from the still soiled paths and roadways of the hotel complex.
Their hotel is all but closed now. The predominantly British guests, the survivors, are on their way home in hastily arranged charter flights.
The Tunisian population, who depend on the tourist business, are left contemplating what happened here.
Shopkeeper Mohammed Kamis' stock was riddled with bullets
Their simple question is why would one of their own do this? It will ruin them.
Mohammed Kamis witnessed the gunman's final moments. He was killed a hundred yards from his shop, that he passed, still firing.
Play video "Tourists Return Home"
Video: Tourists Return Home
As he showed me the deflated blow up boats and rubber rings that were broken in a hail of bullets he said he had no answers to the events of Friday.
"What can we do. He isn't one of us is he?" he said.
"We saw him walking and then turning and firing at people chasing him. Workmen on the roof above threw cement and bricks at him trying to kill him. Then he turned the corner and the police saw him and he was killed," he added.
There were many other lucky escapes.
Kevin McCabe from Ireland, now resident here, took me round the shops and hotels where his friends are now looking at another summer of almost no trade.
1/6
Gallery: Sky Obtains Exclusive Images Of Tunisian Attacker Seifeddine Yacoubi
Sky News has obtained exclusive images of the Tunisian terrorist walking down a beach after carrying out an attack that killed 39 people, 15 of them British
He walks the same stretch of beach where the attack happened, every day. His son had emailed him that something was going on, so he decided to hurry home.
"I saw the guy. If I had stayed where I was I would be his first victim," he said as we walked the beach where the shooter attempted to escape.
"What is really important to remember is that local people took this guy on.
"They chased him and he fired and I saw them falling. I don't know if they were hit but they went down.
"They were unarmed but they chased him and others did everything they could to save the foreigners. It is amazing," he said.
Play video "Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism"
Video: Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism
The various hotel owners on the beach are demanding more security with armed police on patrol and at the hotels. But they want more.
"There needs to be a change in attitude both here and abroad," said Mohammed Becheur, the owner of the hotel where most casualties were recorded.
"The international community and Tunisia needs to control these Islamists or we will have lost."
Tunisia has suffered badly since the Arab Spring revolution of 2011.
Things have got better - but the terror attacks have continued and it is widely acknowledged that there is nothing to suspect they will stop any time soon.
1/7
Gallery: Victims Of Tunisia Gun Attack
Carly Lovett, 24, recently became engaged and was from Gainsborough, Lincolnshire. She worked as a beauty blogger and was a former student at the University of Lincoln
:: Watch Death On The Beach, a special Sky News report on Tunisia at 4.30pm, 6.30pm, 7.30pm and 9.30pm today on skynews.com, mobile, tablet, Sky go, or on TV: Sky 501, Virgin 602, Freesat 202, Freeview 132.
There will also be a special Sky News Tonight programme Terror In Tunisia at 7pm.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:44:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia Gunman Seifeddine Yacoubi Breakdancing</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509651</Link>
        <Description>Sky News obtains footage showing Seifeddine Rezgui wearing a hoodie and performing for a camera before he was radicalised.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Tunisia Gunman Seifeddine Yacoubi Breakdancing
Sky News obtains footage showing Seifeddine Rezgui wearing a hoodie and performing for a camera before he was radicalised.
13:44, UK, Sunday 28 June 2015
Play video "Tunisian Gunman As Breakdancer"
Video: Tunisian Gunman As Breakdancer
Share by email
Sky News has obtained video showing Seifeddine Rezgui as a breakdancing youth around five years before he murdered almost 40 people in a popular beach resort.
In the footage, thought to have been filmed in 2010, Rezgui wears skinny jeans, a hoodie and baseball cap and performs spins and handstands to a techno soundtrack.
The video was posted on a Facebook page set up by a group of friends interested in rap music and breakdancing and has attracted a string of comments since the Sousse massacre.
One reads: "Before he was an artist - then he became a demon."
The group was created in 2010 and while early posts focus on members' dancing exploits, entries took on a more political nature as the Arab Spring - which began in Tunisia in 2010 - gripped the region.
1/6
Gallery: Sky Obtains Exclusive Images Of Tunisian Attacker Seifeddine Yacoubi
Sky News has obtained exclusive images of the Tunisian terrorist walking down a beach after carrying out an attack that killed 39 people, 15 of them British
How and when the 23-year-old turned from an easy-going teenager into a disciple of the Islamic State death cult will be a central focus for investigators in Tunisia.
Friends told Sky News that even two days before the attack, Rezgui showed no signs of radicalisation, visiting a cafe and going for a walk.
Those accounts were backed up by the killer's uncle Ali al Rezgui, who told the Telegraph the family had seen nothing to worry them - although Seifeddine Rezgui had apparently been traumatised by the death of his brother in a lightning strike in 2010.
Play video "Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism"
Video: Tunisia's Homegrown Terrorism
Mr Rezgui told the paper:"He used to use hair gel and wear the nicest of clothes, and he used to do break dancing.
"He even used to go to competitions and things like that in Tunis, he was well known for that here. He didn't even have a beard, and I've never seen him with anyone with a beard.
"We have extremists like that in Gaafour, but never have I seen him with them. Now he's shooting people with a Kalashnikov, it's just so confusing."
Play video "Special Report: IS Recruitment"
Video: Special Report: IS Recruitment
:: Watch Death On The Beach, a special Sky News report on Tunisia at 4.30pm, 6.30pm, 7.30pm and 9.30pm today on skynews.com, mobile, tablet, Sky go, or on TV: Sky 501, Virgin 602, Freesat 202, Freeview 132.
There will also be a special Sky News Tonight programme Terror In Tunisia at 7pm.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:44:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia: Exclusive Pictures Of Gunman On Beach</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509487</Link>
        <Description>Sky News obtains exclusive pictures of Seifeddine Rezgui strolling calmly along the shore with his Kalashnikov.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia: Exclusive Pictures Of Gunman On Beach
Sky News obtains exclusive pictures of Seifeddine Rezgui strolling calmly along the shore with his Kalashnikov.
13:44, UK, Sunday 28 June 2015
Play video "First Images Of Tunisia Gunman"
Video: First Images Of Tunisia Gunman
Share by email
Chilling pictures have emerged of the Tunisia gunman on the beach where he killed at least 38 tourists.
The images show Seifeddine Rezgui strolling down the shore with his weapon as people watch in horror from behind.
The pictures have emerged as witnesses described how he was "very, very calm" when he opened fire on holidaymakers after emerging from the sea.
Tourists also told how Tunisian builders threw bags of cement and bricks at Rezgui from the top of buildings as he fired his weapon in nearby streets.
Others described how Tunisians pleaded with the killer "why are you killing these people?" - but he just sneered and walked on.
1/6
Gallery: Sky Obtains Exclusive Images Of Tunisian Attacker Seifeddine Yacoubi
Sky News has obtained exclusive images of the Tunisian terrorist walking down a beach after carrying out an attack that killed 39 people, 15 of them British
The accounts, and pictures, were revealed by Sky's Chief Correspondent Stuart Ramsay, reporting from the beach in Sousse.
"The shooter had his weapon concealed inside a sun umbrella - he basically came here, went into the water and washed," Ramsay said.
"Then he came out, he got his gun out.
"He was very, very calm - he then attacked one woman shooting her dead immediately.
"He then shot other individuals we are told and began spraying into the beach area which had a lot of people."
Play video "The Gunman's Route Of Destruction"
Video: The Gunman's Route Of Destruction
Ramsay continued: "He then went inside the hotel again - again there was firing.
"Some said they heard explosions, some say he was throwing grenades and more people who werecaught at that gate were killed.
"Afterwards, after he'd been in, he came out and he walked now along the beach, which was full of people who had come to see what had happened and disappeared up a side road.
"He walked past a number of Tunisians who said to him 'why are you killing these people, why are you killing these people?'.
"He basically sneered at them and said 'well I'm not killing you' and basically walked on past them.
Play video "People Run From Gunfire"
Video: People Run From Gunfire
"He was still firing when he walked into the street.
"We are told that builders who were working on the tops of buildings were throwing bricks and bags of cement on to him to see if they could actually hit him.
"By the time he turned the next corner, the police were there and from high positions they shot him dead."
Ramsay said it is believed the shooting lasted between 30 and 35 minutes.
"Some of the questions people are asking are how long did it take the police to get here, were they too slow, should there have been more police here already."
Play video "'It Was A Bloodbath'"
Video: 'It Was A Bloodbath'
:: Watch Death On The Beach, a special Sky News report on Tunisia at 4.30pm, 6.30pm, 7.30pm and 9.30pm today on skynews.com, mobile, tablet, Sky go, or on TV: Sky 501, Virgin 602, Freesat 202, Freeview 132.
There will also be a special Sky News Tonight programme Terror In Tunisia at 7pm.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 13:06:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Watch: Terrified People Flee Tunisia Attack</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509287</Link>
        <Description>New footage catches the confusion and panic during the attack on a Tunisian resort, showing people fleeing as gunshots ring out.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Watch: Terrified People Flee Tunisia Attack
New footage catches the confusion and panic during the attack on a Tunisian resort, showing people fleeing as gunshots ring out.
11:06, UK, Saturday 27 June 2015
Play video "Gunshots Ring Out"
Video: Gunshots Ring Out
Share by email
Footage has emerged showing terrified people running away amid the terror attack in Tunisia.
The mobile phone video, filmed from the balcony of the Hotel Imperial Marhaba, captures the confusion and panic amid the attack.
People can be seen fleeing as gunshots ring out in the background.
"They're here, they're here," a voice is heard saying in the video, shot by holidaymaker Matthew Kenyon.
In the attack on Friday, a gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel with a rifle he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 38 people and injuring scores of others.
Play video "People Run As Gunshots Are Heard"
Video: People Run As Gunshots Are Heard
Terrified tourists ran for cover after the gunfire erupted, many barricading in their hotel rooms for hours.
The Islamic State has claimed responsibility for the attack.
A British Embassy crisis team has been sent here to help tourists caught up in the terror, many of whom are desperate to catch flights home.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:03:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What We Know About The Tunisia Attack Gunman</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1509439</Link>
        <Description>Seifeddine Rezgui, an aviation student in his early 20s, had never travelled abroad and may have been radicalised on home soil.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
What We Know About The Tunisia Attack Gunman
Seifeddine Rezgui, an aviation student in his early 20s, had never travelled abroad and may have been radicalised on home soil.
12:03, UK, Sunday 28 June 2015
Seifeddine Rezgui was an aviation student
Share by email
The gunman in the Tunisian attack was not on a terror watch list, but may have been radicalised by extremist preachers about six months ago, according to security officials.
Seifeddine Rezgui was an aviation student from Gaafour  a town approximately 100 miles from Sousse, where 38 people were killed when he withdrew a Kalashnikov from a beach umbrella and began shooting at foreigners, most of them British.
He had been dressed like any other tourist, wearing dark shorts, a T-shirt and a necklace  and it is estimated his rampage lasted for seven minutes before he was shot dead by police outside the hotel.
Rezgui, who was in his early 20s, had never travelled abroad in his lifetime, prompting fears that he was radicalised at home, potentially at a local mosque.
His family said they had seen no signs that he had been drawn to the extremism of Islamic State - although he apparently been traumatised by his brother's death in a lightning strike in 2010.
1/6
Gallery: Sky Obtains Exclusive Images Of Tunisian Attacker Seifeddine Yacoubi
Sky News has obtained exclusive images of the Tunisian terrorist walking down a beach after carrying out an attack that killed 39 people, 15 of them British
Video has emerged showing him wearing a hoodie andbreakdancing five years ago, although more recent Facebook postings suggest he may have taken an interest in jihad.
Islamic State has claimed responsibility for the attack  and in Twitter messages, referred to Rezgui using the jihadist pseudonym Abu Yahya al Qayruhni.
It is believed Rezgui was extremely familiar with the layout of the Imperial Marhaba resort.
Play video "Returned Tunisians Imprisoned"
Video: Returned Tunisians Imprisoned
One English tourist who was leaving Tunisia said: "It was horror what we saw, he was killing in an incredible way. It was clear he knew the hotel, he was everywhere.
"There was no sign he was an extremist, he just looked like a normal young man."
A waiter who was at the scene when the attack unfolded added: "I was on the beach when he started shooting. We got everyone back towards the hotel, but he followed us."
Play video "The Gunman's Route Of Destruction"
Video: The Gunman's Route Of Destruction
Tunisian Prime Minister Habib Essid described Rezgui as a "good student" who was always attending classes  and other accounts have emerged of a young man who liked partying.
More than 3,000 Tunisians are believed to be fighting for IS and other extremist groups in Iraq, Libya and Syria  with some militants warning they would return to their homeland to launch a terrorist attack.
:: Watch Death On The Beach, a special Sky News report on Tunisia at 4.30pm, 6.30pm, 7.30pm and 9.30pm today on skynews.com, mobile, tablet, Sky go, or on TV: Sky 501, Virgin 602, Freesat 202, Freeview 132.
Play video "Special Report: IS Recruitment"
Video: Special Report: IS Recruitment
There will also be a special Sky News Tonight programme Terror In Tunisia at 7pm.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
