<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Sky-News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:25:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia: Gunmen Attack Two Tourist Hotels</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508894</Link>
        <Description>Gunmen have killed at least 27 people in an attack on two tourist hotels in a Tunisian town popular with British holidaymakers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia: Gunmen Attack Two Tourist Hotels
13:25, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
Share by email
Gunmen have killed at least 27 people in an attack on two tourist hotels in a Tunisian town popular with British holidaymakers.
Tourists fled from the beach in Sousse to take refuge in hotel rooms after guns were fired on the beach.
One man said his son saw someone get shot as he raced back to the hotel from the sea.
Photographs seen by Sky News show one man in his 60s or 70s lying in a pool of blood in his swimming shorts.
Tourist John Yeoman has barricaded himself inside his room
One gunman has been killed, according to security sources cited by the Reuters news agency. The country's interior ministry says at least 27 people have been killed.
British tourist Gary Pine said: "We thought fire crackers were going off but you could see quite quickly what was going on.
Play video "'People Are Hysterical'"
Video: 'People Are Hysterical'
"There was a mass exodus off the beach. My son was in the sea at the time and myself and my wife were shouting at him to get out and as he ran up he said Ive just saw someone get shot.
Another holidaymaker, Susan Ricketts, said: "It sounded like a machine gun going off. There are people crying and going hysterical. We just came up to our room."
Tourists are now gathered in hotel reception areas and hiding in rooms as the situation develops.
One said: "People are running around the hotel. No-one has really been told what to do."
Play video "'Ulterior Motive To Tunisia Attack'"
Video: 'Ulterior Motive To Tunisia Attack'
Holidaymaker John Yeoman has barricaded himself inside his hotel room using a bed and chair.
Meanwhile deadly explosions have hit a Shiite mosque in Kuwait's capital after Friday prayers.
More follows...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:05:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beheading And Explosion At French Factory</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508786</Link>
        <Description>Attackers carrying Islamist flags ram a car into gas canisters at the building, setting off an explosion.</Description>
        <MainBody>Beheading And Explosion At French Factory
Attackers carrying Islamist flags ram a car into gas canisters at the building, setting off an explosion.
13:05, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
1/13
Gallery: Police At Scene Of Grenoble Attack
Police stand next to a black plastic sheet after a suspected terror attack in eastern France
Share by email
A man has been decapitated by attackers brandishing Islamist flags at a French factory near Grenoble.
The severed head had Arabic writing scrawled across it and was found on a fence next to twojihadi banners.
Two other people were hurt in explosions at the factory, French President Francois Hollande said.
The blasts in France were triggered when two attackers deliberately crashed a car into gas canisters, according to police.
A 35-year-old man was among several people arrested after the attack.
Explosions were heard at the factory (Google Street View)
Le Parisien reported gunshots and that one Islamist had been killed at the premises in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeastern France.
Le Dauphine newspaper reported that police are hunting for another man associated with the attack.
Play video "Why Pick 'Chemical Valley'?"
Video: Why Pick 'Chemical Valley'?
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve, speaking from the scene, described the attack as "barbarous" and a "terrible terrorist crime".
He said that one of the arrested people had been known to foreign intelligence services may have been radicalised.
The suspect was initially flagged as an extremist in 2006 and then police monitoring dropped off two years later, according to MrCazeneuve.
He did not have a criminal record, the minister added.
MrHollande has cut short all of his engagements at the EU summit in Belgium to return to France for emergency talks.
"The attack was of a terrorist nature since a body was discovered, decapitated and with inscriptions," MrHollande told a news conference in Brussels.
He added that a considerable police force had been deployed in the region and other industrial sites protected to avoid any further incidents.
"The president saw the first images of the attack on the 24-news channels with German Chancellor Angela Merkel beside him, who was visibly shocked," an official added.
The two leaders had just ended a short meeting with Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras.
David Cameron has spoken to MrHollande in Brussels to express his sympathies. Downing Street described the attack as an "appalling incident".
Employees at the factory - Air Products - are said to be "very shocked". 
One witness called Caroline, from a neighbouring factory, said: "I heard a really loud noise. Fire engines arrived with the police.
Play video "President Hollande Condemns Attack"
Video: President Hollande Condemns Attack
"We thought it was a motorway accident."
Air Products is an American chemical company based in Allentown, Pennsylvania.
A statement from the company read: "Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for.
"Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
Henry Samuel, a correspondent for the Daily Telegraph, told Sky News: "The person arrested was allegedly carrying a flag of the Islamic State and he said he was a member of the IS."
The attack came nearly six months after the Islamist attacks in and around Paris that killed 17 people in January.
Those attacks started with a shooting at satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo .
Sky's foreign affairs editor Sam Kiley said: "There has been a concerted effort by Islamic State to reach out to their followers in France and exhortations to conduct this sort of attack.
"We saw with the Charlie Hebdo attack these were also self-starter individuals who had had training from al Qaeda in Yemen.
"One of the three said he was there on behalf of Islamic State, the other two claimed membership of al Qaeda.
"In a sense it doesn't matter. What matters is that people are inspired to carry out terrorist attacks."
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:20:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Was Attack On Factory The Work Of Islamists?</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508871</Link>
        <Description>While the attack would appear to be the work of Islamist militants, little is known about the motives of those responsible.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Was Attack On Factory The Work Of Islamists?
While the attack would appear to be the work of Islamist militants, little is known about the motives of those responsible.
12:20, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
Play video "Why Pick 'Chemical Valley'?"
Video: Why Pick 'Chemical Valley'?
Share by email
French police say the attack on a US gas company in the southeast of the country bears the hallmark of Islamist militants.
A decapitated head was reportedly found on a gate at the entrance to the factory in Saint Quentin-Fallavier, along with two flags bearing Arabic writing.
Sky's Foreign Affairs Editor Sam Kiley said it was too early to be certain about who was responsible.
"Beyond some Arabic writing on a flag we don't really know the genesis of this attack" he said.
"Let's not start running up an Islamist flag and claim it to be a jihadi operation as such until we have further evidence.
Play video "Why Attack This Factory?"
Video: Why Attack This Factory?
"But at the moment there is a suggestion from the French media that this does look like an Islamist attack."
Kiley said there is a possibility that, whoever was responsible, it could have been a robbery that went wrong.
"At this stage there is a lot of confusion. It is not clear the decapitation... was linked to the explosions some time later.
"You have a lot volatile material in this location, so it is conceivable it was a robbery in which people were trying to get hold of potentially dangerous products to use in an attack elsewhere."
1/13
Gallery: Police At Scene Of Grenoble Attack
Police stand next to a black plastic sheet after a suspected terror attack in eastern France
Kiley said there has been a "concerted effort" by Islamic State to reach out to their followers in France and "exhortations to conduct this sort of attack.
"We saw with the Charlie Hebdo attack these were also self-starter individuals who had had training from al Qaeda in Yemen.
"One of the three said he was there on behalf of Islamic State, the other two claimed membership of al Qaeda.
"In a sense it doesn't matter. What matters is that people are inspired to carry out terrorist attacks."
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:45:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Latest In A Series Of Attacks In France</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508811</Link>
        <Description>From the Charlie Hebdo massacre to opportunistic assaults on soldiers - a recent history of Islamist terror attacks in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Latest In A Series Of Attacks In France
From the Charlie Hebdo massacre to opportunistic assaults on soldiers - a recent history of Islamist terror attacks in France.
10:45, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
French police during the terror attacks in Paris in January
Share by email
There has been a string of suspected or confirmed Islamist terrorist attacks in France in the past three years alone, including the notorious Charlie Hebdo massacre in January.
19 April 2015:A woman was murdered by a gunman in Paris whose plot to attack a church was foiled shortly after. Aurelie Chatelain was found lying in a burning car in the southern suburb after apparently being shot
7-9 January 2015: An attack on the offices of satirical magazine Charlie Hebdowas followed by four more attacks in and around Paris, ending in two sieges. Seventeen people died. Fundamentalist brothers Said and Cherif Kouachi, plus accomplice Amedy Coulibaly, were killed in shoot-outs with police.
21 December 2014: In Dijon a man shouting "AllahuAkbar" ran over 11 pedestrians with his vehicle. The attacker shouted to passers by that he was acting on behalf of the "children of Palestine". No-one died but two people were left with serious injuries.
20 December 2014: A police officer is killed and three others are injured by a knife-wielding man yelling "Allahu Akbar".
23 May 2013: Days after British soldier Lee Rigby was killed in Woolwich, a French soldier is attacked and stabbed in the Paris suburb of La Defense in what was described as a terrorist attack. He survived.
11 March 2012: Three gun attacks target French soldiers and Jewish civilians in the cities of Montaubanand Toulouse. Seven people are killed and five others injured. The perpetrator - who said he was motivated by France's involvement in the Afghanistan conflict - is shot dead.
More follows...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:24:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Marikana Massacre: Police 'Followed Orders'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508596</Link>
        <Description>South African police criticise the tactics used to break up the Marikana mining strike, saying they were told to "shoot to kill".</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Marikana Massacre: Police 'Followed Orders'
South African police criticise the tactics used to break up the Marikana mining strike, saying they were told to "shoot to kill".
07:24, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
Play video "Marikana Cops Told 'Shoot To Kill'"
Video: Marikana Cops Told 'Shoot To Kill'
Share by email
Two policemen have told Sky News that officers were following orders from senior commanders when they opened fire on striking South African mining workers in 2012.
Speaking on condition of anonymity, the officers criticised the police tactics used to break up the demonstration at the Lonmin PLC platinum mine near Marikana.
One of the officers said police were told to "shoot to kill" by their superiors if they felt they were in danger.
He said police were instructed that "if your life is under threat, or your colleague's life is under threat, therefore you shoot to kill".
He added: "That is my interpretation."
Play video "Mine Massacre 'Horrendous Tragedy'"
Video: Mine Massacre 'Horrendous Tragedy'
Asked by Sky's Alex Crawford to confirm that senior police commanders told officers to "shoot to kill", he added: "Yeah, I think (so)."
He added: "We did what was instructed to us. We just followed orders."
Another policeman said: "We did what was expected from us. We followed the instructions.
"I guess we did not want those people to be killed in the first place."
Thirty-four people died during the massacre on 16 August, 2012.
Families of the victims have accused police of using excessive force.
Play video "2012: Striking Miners Speak To Sky"
Video: 2012: Striking Miners Speak To Sky
South Africa's President Jacob Zuma said the government-appointed panel's report recommended prosecutors determine whether any officers are criminally liable for the deaths.
"The commission recommends a full investigation under the direction of the director of public prosecutions... with a view to ascertaining criminal liability on the part of all members of the South African Police Service who were involved in the incidents," he said.
Mr Zuma described the killings as a "horrendous tragedy that has no place in democracy", adding that the world did not expect such an episode in a "free and democratic South Africa".
In the days leading up to the attack, 10 others were murdered near the platinum mine, including non-striking miners, security guards and two police officers who were hacked to death.
Mr Zuma said the inquiry has recommended that all killings prior to 16 August should also be investigated.
"We should, as a nation, learn from this painful episode," he said.
"We should use it to build a more united, peaceful and cohesive society."
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:29:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU Talks Over Greece Debt End Without Deal</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1507909</Link>
        <Description>German Chancellor Angela Merkel tells EU leaders there must be a debt deal with Greece before financial markets open next Monday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sponsored By
EU Talks Over Greece Debt End Without Deal
German Chancellor Angela Merkel tells EU leaders there must be a debt deal with Greece before financial markets open next Monday.
17:29, UK, Thursday 25 June 2015
Play video "Five Questions Answered On Greece"
Video: Five Questions Answered On Greece
Share by email
A meeting of eurozone finance ministers trying to agree a deal on Greece's debt crisis has broken up in Brussels without agreement.
The Greek government badly needs 7.2bn from creditors to keep its economy going and to help with a 1.6bn payment it has to make to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) by next Tuesday.
Otherwise, Athens may default on its debts which could lead to the country leaving the single currency.
German Chancellor Angela Merkelhas said there must be a debt deal with Greece before financial markets open on Monday.
She also told a meeting of European leaders before an EU summit in Brussels that Germany "will not be blackmailed" by Greece.
Play video "Brexit vs Grexit Analysis"
Video: Brexit vs Grexit Analysis
The talks will resume on Saturday, but Germany's finance minister earlier on Thursday expressed pessimism that a deal could be struck.
Wolfgang Schaeublesaid the two sides were "even further apart" as discussions took place between the Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsiprasand the IMF and European Central Bank (ECB).
The creditors presented Athens with new proposals over the economic reforms it wants made in an attempt to find a breakthrough over its bailout.
But Greece was still not on board, raising fresh doubts about whether it was possible to clinch a deal before the end of June.
Play video "What Proposals Could We See?"
Video: What Proposals Could We See?
However, Mr Tsiprassaid he was confident of reaching a compromise despite a deadlock in the talks.
According to Greek officials at the talks, creditors were seeking a different mix of austerity measures than those proposed by Athens, making the cuts more immediate.
They included broad pension cuts, higher revenue from sales tax, and a faster elimination of tax exemptions - demands that are likely to fuel dissent within the government if accepted.
1/18
Gallery: Monday: Pro-EU Protests In Athens
Pro-euro protesters take part in a rally in front of the Parliament in Athens, Greece
Hopes of a settlement had faded on Wednesday evening after the IMF cast doubts on Greece's new debt plan .
The proposals put forward by Athens aim to raise 8bn, mostly through new taxes on the wealthy and businesses, early retirement restrictions, VAT increases and a cut in defence spending.
But the IMF was cautious about the mix of reforms Greece proposed, saying they rely too heavily on tax increases that can hurt the economy.
Play video "Tragedy And Turmoil In Greece"
Video: Tragedy And Turmoil In Greece
It wants more spending cuts because of the possible effect of tax rises on businesses.
Stock markets across Europe were down after the IMF's negative reaction to the proposals.
Assuming a deal is thrashed out with the EU and IMF, Mr Tspiras still needs to convince his anti-austerity Syriza party to approve concessions needed to unblock the desperately needed bailout funds.
He only has a slim majority within the Greek parliament and opposition within his own party to proposed concessions means ratification in Greece is by no means assured.
1/4
Gallery: The Deadlines On The Road Ahead For Athens
After a series of shifting payment deadlines Greece's future within the EU could be decided in the coming days
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:03:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why Crucial Greek Debt Talks Keep Collapsing</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508515</Link>
        <Description>Sky's Economics Editor Ed Conway examines the three main reasons why the negotiations to reach a deal remain deadlocked.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sponsored By
Why Crucial Greek Debt Talks Keep Collapsing
Sky's Economics Editor Ed Conway examines the three main reasons why the negotiations to reach a deal remain deadlocked.
22:03, UK, Thursday 25 June 2015
Play video "Five Questions Answered On Greece"
Video: Five Questions Answered On Greece
If you've been following the Greek crisis for the past week or so you're probably wondering why on Earth it is that all of these crunch meetings have been collapsing.
You can boil it down to three reasons.
First, it's because there's so much at stake:
Syriza came into power promising to fight austerity; if it signs up to all the lender conditions it will be seen to have failed.
IMF head Christine Lagarde and Greek finance minister Yanis Varoufakis
The lenders, meanwhile, worry that any concessions to Greece will simply encourage other troubled eurozone countries to borrow and spend even more in the future, casting the long-term stability of European Monetary Union into doubt.
Second, it's because none of the participants are particularly familiar with the protocol here:
Play video "What Would A Greek Default Mean?"
Video: What Would A Greek Default Mean?
The lenders are used to dictating the terms, but this time around theyve agreed to a Brussels-level negotiation with the Greeks. For their part, the Greeks are totally unfamiliar with the language of Brussels, since theyre a new government with little institutional memory of what it takes to be a "Sherpa" (a lead negotiator).
The upshot is that each of the three eurogroup meetings weve had in the past week has begun without an agreed draft text: instead there have been multiple drafts floating around, meaning the ministers dont have anything to use as the basis for discussion.
Third, it's because of the manifold misunderstandings that still float around about the Greek economy:
Take pensions, one of the main issues at stake here. The Greeks are under extreme pressure to reform their pension system in exchange for extending their bailout (there has to be a quid pro quo, after all). The Germans are furious that some Greeks can retire so early. They moan about the comparative generosity of the set-up.
And indeed, looked at through some prisms, they have a point. The average age at which Greek workers receive a pension is lower than most other EU countries - 57.8 years old. Then again, this is about the same as Italy (58), is far higher than Slovenia (56.6) and is already poised to go up sharply, with the retirement age set to be increased to 67 in the coming decades. (The speed with which this happens is one of the contentious points in the negotiations.)
Play video "Brexit vs Grexit Analysis"
Video: Brexit vs Grexit Analysis
The Greek pension system is costly - around 13% of GDP, compared with an average of 7.8% across the developed OECD nations - though it's worth attaching a couple of riders to this concern.
First, the Greek population is older, on average, than in the rest of the EU - which in turn makes pension costs higher. Second, the generosity of the Greek pension system is in part a consequence of the stinginess of the rest of Greeces welfare state. For instance, Greek spending on incapacity benefits is lower than almost anywhere else in the OECD.
Spending on family benefits (stuff equivalent to Britains child tax credits) is likewise lower than the average.
The upshot of all of this is that over decades Greece's pensions system has become a kind of surrogate form of benefits for many Greek families. Many people retire early, lured by the pension, but also use that pension not just for themselves but to, say, support their unemployed son.
And these issues are not lost on Greece's lenders. The IMF, for instance, wants to cut the amount Greece pays out on pensions (most of its proposals thus far have revolved around increasing pension contributions, not cutting spending). But it also wants Greece to increase the sufficiency of its welfare system.
1/4
Gallery: The Deadlines On The Road Ahead For Athens
After a series of shifting payment deadlines Greece's future within the EU could be decided in the coming days
Or take another issue: taxes. It's often assumed that Greeks pay too little tax. Actually, when you look at the governments total revenues and compare them with other countries, Greece is actually already quite highly taxed. Yes, in part this is an artefact of the low GDP against which taxes are measured, but even before the crisis Greece wasnt the lowest-taxed country out there. The fact that there is widespread avoidance often overshadows the fact that tax revenues in Greece are already pretty high.
Then there's defence. Why is it that Greece's military is better funded than any other country in Europe? This helps explain why the IMF are so keen that defence gets cut as part of any agreement. And yet there is a reason for high defence spending: Greece sits at a strategic point at the edge of the EU.
Moreover, the Greek military are particularly politically powerful. They wouldn't take cuts lying down. The fact that Greece has had its own (recent) history of military coups only underlines this issue.
Such nuanced arguments are often lost, both in the coverage of the negotiations and, sometimes, in the negotiation rooms themselves. But they matter enormously in the long-run. And they explain why this is one of those knotty subjects where straightforward answers on either side dont always help all that much.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:24:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fifteen Libya Emails Missing From Clinton Cache</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508754</Link>
        <Description>The emails, relating to security in the country before a 2012 attack, are given to the State Department by Sidney Blumenthal.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Fifteen Libya Emails Missing From Clinton Cache
The emails, relating to security in the country before a 2012 attack, are given to the State Department by Sidney Blumenthal.
09:24, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
Hillary Clinton has said she handed over all her "work-related" emails
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
The US State Department has said it cannot find 15 emails from Hillary Clinton's private server that were released by a House of Representatives panel investigating the 2012 attack in Benghazi.
The emails, which all pre-date the 11 September attack on the US diplomatic compound, contain intelligence reports passed to Mrs Clinton by her long-time adviser Sidney Blumenthal, officials have said.
Several previously undisclosed emails were handed over to the State Department by Mr Blumenthal, which revealed it did not have a complete record from Mrs Clinton's time in office as Secretary of State.
US ambassador Chris Stevens and three other Americans were killed in 2012
The 15 emails were either missing from the records she provided, or included only in partial form.
They include a media account about the killing of one of Moammar Gaddafi's sons, reports on internal politics among Libyan rebels and news of the assassination of a former Gaddafi minister in Vienna.
Play video "Hillary Clinton 'Sensitive' Emails"
Video: Hillary Clinton 'Sensitive' Emails
The last one was sent 28 August, 2012 - two weeks before the Benghazi attack.
Nick Merrill, a spokesman for Mrs Clinton, said the Democratic presidential candidate had given the department "all emails in her possession from Mr Blumenthal".
He said he could not explain where the origin of the additional correspondence Mr Blumenthal had provided in response to a subpoena.
Mrs Clinton - the front-runner for the Democratic nomination for the 2016 presidential election - has faced strong criticism that she flouted record-keeping and transparency rules by using a private email account for her work.
The private address was connected to a server in her home.
Mrs Clinton has insisted she used the private account for convenience and has broken no rules. The account was revealed in March, more than two years after she stepped down as the top US diplomat.
Trey Gowdy, the Republican congressman who heads the select committee investigating the Benghazi attack, said the incomplete email record "raises serious questions".
He said: "This has implications far beyond Libya, Benghazi and our committee's work.
"This conclusively shows her email arrangement with herself, which was then vetted by her own lawyers, has resulted in an incomplete public record."
In March, Mrs Clinton said that she had given the State Department all the emails she sent and received that "could possibly be work-related".
She said the 30,490 emails she handed over in December included all those that referred to Libya or Benghazi, along side work-related correspondence from "long-time friends".
She said that after those emails were copies, all her correspondence - including another 30,000 that were deemed personal - were deleted from the server.
It comes after an Islamic-State militant thought to have been involved in the attack in Benghazi was reportedly killed in a drone strike in Iraq last week.
Four Americans, including US ambassador Chris Stevens, were killed during the attack on the US outpost in Benghazi on 11 September 2012.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:25:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Family Flees $1.3m Home Over 'Watcher' Threats</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508851</Link>
        <Description>Creepy letters about "young blood" and asking "have they found what is in the walls?" scare the family from their New Jersey home.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Family Flees $1.3m Home Over 'Watcher' Threats
Creepy letters about "young blood" and asking "have they found what is in the walls?" scare the family from their New Jersey home.
11:25, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
The family received threatening letters shortly after buying the $1.3m home
Share by email
A New Jersey couple has sued the people who sold them a $1.3m house after they claim a series of threatening letters from a stalker called "The Watcher" forced them to leave the property.
According to the lawsuit, the family began receiving creepy messages from "The Watcher" three days after they had bought their new home in Westfield.
It claims the previous owners of the house had also received letters from the stalker but failed to disclose it during the sale in the summer of 2014.
The letters read: "Why are you here? I will find out. My grandfather watched the house in the 1920s and my father watched in the 1960s. It is now my time.
The couple never moved into the property because of the letters
"Do you need to fill the house with the young blood I requested? Once I know their names I will call to them and draw them to me. I asked the [prior owners] to bring me young blood.
"Have they found what is in the walls yet? In time they will. I am pleased to know your names and the names now of the young blood you have brought to me."
The letters also asked "will the young bloods play in the basement?" and asked to know "who has the rooms facing the street?"
The family found the letters so disturbing, they never moved into the property, NJ.com reported.
The lawsuit, filed at Superior Court in Elizabeth, reads: "Upon information and belief, defendants suppressed all information regarding 'The Watcher' even though they were either on constructive or actual notice of the harm that could befall the plaintiffs and their minor children.
"Both [former owners] knew or should have known that 'peace of mind' and 'security' were and are of paramount importance to the plaintiffs, specifically and in general as is true to the high end market to whom defendants were marketing the home for sale."
Westfield Township Mayor Andrew Skibitsky told a public council hearing that an "exhaustive investigation" had been carried out into the threatening letters.
No suspect has been identified and no charges have been filed in the case.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:32:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deal On Migrants Struck Amid Calais Chaos</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1508570</Link>
        <Description>EU leaders strike a deal to relocate 40,000 migrants - as Sky News joins a lorry driver travelling from Calais to Dover.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Deal On Migrants Struck Amid Calais Chaos
EU leaders strike a deal to relocate 40,000 migrants - as Sky News joins a lorry driver travelling from Calais to Dover.
07:32, UK, Friday 26 June 2015
Migrants rest after disembarking in the Sicilian harbour of Augusta, Italy
Share by email
A deal has been struck to relocate tens of thousands of migrants who have arrived in Italy and Greece to other EU states.
The deal, made by EU leaders in Brussels, will see member states share the burden of 40,000 migrants who have crossed theMediterranean.
However, there will be no mandatory quotas for countries, and Britain's opt-out on EU home affairs issues means it is not obliged to take part.
New figures from UNHCR- the UN refugee agency - reveal that 63,000 migrants have arrived in Greece by sea this year and 62,000 in Italy.
After late-night talks at the European Council summit, president Donald Tusk said: "Leaders agreed that 40,000 persons in need will be relocated from Greece and Italy to other states over the next two years.
Play video "Calais Under Pressure"
Video: Calais Under Pressure
"Interior ministers will finalise the scheme by the end of July."
The deal came amid chaos at Calais as hundreds of migrants boarded queuing lorries this week during French ferry worker strike action.
David Cameron described the situation as "totally unacceptable" and called for the French and British authorities to work together.
One of the lorry drivers who regularly makes the crossing to Dover says it has been a nightmare in recent weeks.
1/8
Gallery: Truckers' Checklist
"Wednesday was the worst it's been. The migrants were everywhere, trying to get into lorries, and it was chaos," Dave Currie told Sky News.
"It felt like being in Beirut or somewhere."
MrCurriesaid it can be intimidating at times when desperate migrants try to get into the lorries.
But he said sometimes it is quiet and there is little interaction as police are out in large numbers.
Play video "Endless Attempts To Cross Border"
Video: Endless Attempts To Cross Border
Sky News reporter Joe Tidy has been invited to sit alongside MrCurrie during his trip and fit cameras to his lorry.
You can follow the journey on social media throughout Friday.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
