<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Sky-News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:39:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Freudian Slip? PM's 'Career Defining' Mix-Up</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1475851</Link>
        <Description>The Prime Minister quickly corrects himself but Labour adviser David Axelrod pounces, calling it a Freudian slip.</Description>
        <MainBody>Freudian Slip? PM's 'Career Defining' Mix-Up
The Prime Minister quickly corrects himself but Labour adviser David Axelrod pounces, calling it a Freudian slip.
12:39, UK, Friday 01 May 2015
Play video "PM Says Election 'Career-Defining'"
Video: PM Says Election 'Career-Defining'
Share by email
David Cameron has described the General Election as "career-defining" in a slip-up during a question and answer session on the campaign trail.
The Prime Minister immediately corrected himself while speaking at Asda's headquarters in Leeds, saying it was a "country-defining" election.
But Labour's press team quickly tweeted: "Revealing Cameron slip up at Q&amp;A - says the election is 'career defining' ... It's all about Dave."
Labour adviser and former Obama campaign chief David Axelrod described it as a "Freudian slip".
He tweeted: "The PM's Freudian slip showing? In speaking to crowd, Cameron describes next week's vote as 'career defining', before subbing word 'country'."
Play video "Sky News #GeneralAffection Song"
Video: Sky News #GeneralAffection Song
Shadow cabinet office minister Jon Ashworthsaid: "The problem with David Cameron is he always gets his priorities wrong. He puts his career before country, just as he puts a privileged few before working people."
UKIP's economic spokesman Patrick O'Flynn piled in, writing on Twitter: "Guess that's the ultimate comment of a career politician from David Cameron."
Mr Cameron's appearance at Asda followed a BBC Question Time special in the city on Thursday night in which the main party leaders were quizzed by a studio audience .
He used the opportunity to say that Ed Miliband's insistence that he will not lead a Labour government dependent on a deal with the SNP "changes nothing".
"Is he really saying 'If Labour don't get a majority, but Labour and the Scottish National Party is a majority, I won't be prime minister'?
Play video "Final TV Clash For Party Leaders"
Video: Final TV Clash For Party Leaders
"Of course he is not saying that. So the threat today is the same as the threat yesterday - Ed Miliband propped up by the SNP, not governing on behalf of the whole of the country. That's the problem, and Labour shadow ministers have been out this morning confirming that my view is correct."
Meanwhile Labour leader Ed Milibandwas in Cardiff on Friday morning, while Lib Dem leader Nick Cleggwas in Manchester supporting local candidates.
Mr Clegg said Mr Miliband'srefusal to do deals in the event of a hung parliament was "ludicrous".
Speaking at a golf club in the marginal Manchester Withington seat, he said: "Ed Miliband will have to eat his words. It's just a democratic fact. It's such a silly thing to say."
Mr Clegg also insisted he will not lead his party into government without clear commitments from a larger party for fair funding of the NHS.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:40:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Miliband: I'd Rather Lose Than Do SNP Deal</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1475500</Link>
        <Description>David Cameron is judged the "winner" in a snap poll as the three main party leaders get a rough ride from a studio audience.</Description>
        <MainBody>Poll Tracker
Miliband: I'd Rather Lose Than Do SNP Deal
David Cameron is judged the "winner" in a snap poll as the three main party leaders get a rough ride from a studio audience.
07:40, UK, Friday 01 May 2015
Play video "Final TV Clash For Party Leaders"
Video: Final TV Clash For Party Leaders
Share by email
Ed Miliband has said if being prime minister meant a deal with the SNP then there would be no Labour government.
It is the furthest the Labour leader has gone on ruling out any agreement with the Scottish National Party, leaving little wriggle room for post 7 May negotiations.
As the General Election campaign enters its endgame both Mr Miliband and David Cameron attempted to persuade voters to help them win a majority victory in a weeks time.
In a bruising 90-minute BBC Question Time both leaders insisted they would not need to compromise and could deliver their manifestos in full without needing support from other parties.
An ICM/Guardian poll on the TV battle, with 30-minute sessions for each of the three main parties, suggested Mr Cameron was the victor.
Play video "Miliband Defends Labour Spending"
Video: Miliband Defends Labour Spending
It indicated 44% thought Mr Cameron performed best, 38% Mr Miliband, while only 19% put Nick Clegg ahead.
Mr Miliband said: "Let me be plain - we are not going to do a deal with the SNP."
He added: "I'm not going to sacrifice the future of our country, the unity of our country, I'm not going to give in to SNP demands around Trident, around the deficit or anything like that.
"I'm not going to have Labour government if it means deals or coalitions with the SNP."
Play video "Cameron Forced To Clarify"
Video: Cameron Forced To Clarify
Speaking to Sky News on Friday SNP leader Nicola Sturgeon said: "If that is his position, he is hammering the final nail in the coffin of Scottish Labour."
Mr Cameron said if the Conservatives had to team up with another party to stay in power he could be trusted to "do the right thing for the country" as he did in 2010.
However, he said this time he was confident he could win the 23 seats he said he would need to win a majority.
But he added: "I believe I did the right thing in forming a coalition and having a decisive government to deal with the mess that we are left but this time I think we can go one better."
The audience, widely considered to be the winners of the programme, made clear they were not convinced either would be able to govern without the support of another party and polls have consistently suggested neither party will win a majority.
Play video "Nick Clegg Tackles Tuition Fees"
Video: Nick Clegg Tackles Tuition Fees
Nick Clegg agreed one of them would be prime minister but said it was for the public to decide which party would put them there - his, the SNP or UKIP.
He said the Liberal Democrats would seek to form a coalition with the party which got the "biggest mandate" from voters first but would consider speaking to the second-place party.
He said: "The party that gets the biggest mandate from you, in other words the party with the most votes and the most seats, even if they haven't got a slam-dunk result, has in a democracy the right to make the first move, to reach out to other parties to assemble a government if they so choose.
"It may not then work out, other parties may not reciprocate and then other arrangements might need to be arrived at."
However, polls have indicated his party may not win enough seats to push either the Conservatives or Labour to a majority government.
Play video "UKIP's Farage On Immigration Levels"
Video: UKIP's Farage On Immigration Levels
Mr Clegg said he would not quit as Lib Dem leader if the party failed to get into coalition with whoever ended up in number 10.
:: Leader Profiles Box Set
Much was made of Mr Milibandslipping off the edge of the stage as he made his exit, but Labour was quick to suggest he had slipped on Mr Cameron's sweat.
All three of the main party leaders were questioned on their trustworthiness during their 30-minute slots in front of the studio audience.
Play video "Sturgeon Responds To Miliband"
Video: Sturgeon Responds To Miliband
Mr Cameron was asked why the Tories were not trusted with the NHS, Mr Miliband was asked how Labour could be trusted not to overspend and borrow too much and Mr Clegg was asked how he could be trusted after his about-turn on student tuition fees.
Taking the first slot, the Prime Minister attempted to convince voters on welfare cuts, immigration and the NHS.
He insisted the NHS was his "life's work". And he rejected the Liberal Democrat claims the Tories were planning to cut child tax credits and child benefits if they returned to power.
But he did vow to press ahead with 12bn of welfare cuts telling the audience: "We have to reform welfare, making sure that work always pays, keeping taxes down, that is the programme. If you want unlimited welfare increases, that is Ed Miliband's programme."
Mr Miliband was given a rough ride over Labour's record in power, starting with the note left by the Chief Secretary to the Treasury Liam Byrne in 2010 which said there was no money left.
Play video "PM Told: 'You're Wrong' On NHS"
Video: PM Told: 'You're Wrong' On NHS
He was accused of lying when he said that the party had not overspent in power.
Mr Miliband said: "We have a global financial crisis, causing the deficit to rise. President Obama is not dealing with a high deficit because we have got schools and hospitals. He was dealing with that because of the global financial crisis."
The audience is made up of 25% Conservative supporters, 25% Labour, 25% Liberal Democrat, 15% other parties and 10% who are undecided.
UKIP leader NigelFarage was not included in the debate, which he told Sky News he was unhappy about.
He added that he wanted Thursday to establish his party as the third biggest in British politics, and said UKIP would target Labour votes harder in future.
Play video "Miliband's Stumble After Grilling"
Video: Miliband's Stumble After Grilling
"Next Thursday, what I want to see is more than a handful of MPs elected.
"I want to see UKIP with a really good percentage score showing us as the third party in British politics and the popular vote.
"And what will be really interesting for the longer term is how many seats do we come second in, particularly in the midlands and the north of england, because the longer term future for UKIP is that it's the Labour vote that will come to us in bigger numbers as the years go on."
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:51:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>McCann Trolls: Police Won't Take Action</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1475870</Link>
        <Description>Police say some of the online messages sent to the family were "extremely distasteful", but none would lead to prosecutions.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
McCann Trolls: Police Won't Take Action
Police say some of the online messages sent to the family were "extremely distasteful", but none would lead to prosecutions.
12:51, UK, Friday 01 May 2015
Gerry McCann said last year that trolls should be prosecuted
Share by email
No further action will be taken against dozens of people accused of targeting online abuse at the family of Madeleine McCann, Sky sources have revealed.
Anti-abuse campaigners had compiled a dossier of names after becoming alarmed at the threatening nature of some tweets, posts and messages on online forums directed at Kate and Gerry McCann.
Hundreds of messages have been posted by trolls who believe, despite no evidence, that the McCanns had some involvement in the disappearance of their daughter in Portugal in 2007.
In a letter to the campaigners, Leicestershire Police Assistant Chief Constable Roger Bannister said: "While finding that much of the material was extremely distasteful and unpleasant in nature, it was determined that none of the messages/postings constituted a prosecutable offence."
Madeleine went missing in Portugal in 2007
Sky News Crime Correspondent Martin Brunt said: "Leicestershire Police had spent about eight months investigating the dossier, which effectively was a catalogue of abuse tweeted and posted online elsewhere by antagonists of Kate and Gerry McCann.
"There were dozens of such individuals identified in the dossier. They had threatened violence and even death against the couple."
The online posts included words like petrol and matches, handcuffs, shooting, torture and lynching, Brunt said.
One woman named in the dossier, Brenda Leyland, committed suicide after being confronted on Sky News.
Brunt said those who compiled the dossier have reacted with "absolute dismay" at the decision not to prosecute.
"They say it is tantamount to giving the trolls, as they call them, carte blanche to carry on abusing the McCanns," he said.
Stella Creasy (L) and Caroline Criado-Perez both faced online abuse
"Although we haven't heard directly from the McCanns, I'm sure they too will be astonished because when Sky News revealed this dossier in September last year, Gerry McCann said such trolls should be prosecuted."
Successful prosecutions have been brought against online trolls in the UK.
In September, Peter Nunn, who sent abusive Twitter messages to Labour MP Stella Creasy, was jailed for 18 weeks.
The abuse started after Ms Creasy supported a successful campaign to put the image of Jane Austen on the 10 note.
Two other people who sent abusive tweets to Ms Creasy, as well as to fellow banknote campaigner Caroline Criado-Perez, were also given jail sentences last year.
Isabella Sorley was jailed for 12 weeks and John Nimmo for eight. They were ordered to pay 400 compensation to both victims.
In June, Jake Newsome, who wrote an offensive Facebook post about Ann Maguire, a teacher stabbed to death in her classroom, was jailed for six weeks.
In his bestselling book, Goncalo Amaral claimed the McCanns hid their daughter's body and faked an abduction after she died in an accident.
A civil court in Lisbon ordered Mr Amaral to pay 606,000 (433,000) to the McCanns.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:37:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds Mourn Abandoned Baby With No Name</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1475953</Link>
        <Description>A community whose hearts were touched by the tragedy of an infant found dead on a railway path is finally able to lay him to rest.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Hundreds Mourn Abandoned Baby With No Name
A community whose hearts were touched by the tragedy of an infant found dead on a railway path is finally able to lay him to rest.
13:37, UK, Friday 01 May 2015
Several of those who attended carried flowers
Share by email
Hundreds of people have attended the funeral of a baby boy whose identity has remained a mystery since his lifeless body was found abandoned.
The infant was discovered wrapped in a blanket on a path along a disused railway in the Seafield area of Edinburgh in July 2013.
Police have been unable to find out his identity or that of his parents.
A piper leads those carrying the coffin of the 'wee one' with no name
As a result, the boy - thought to be only a few weeks old at the time of his death - was buried without a name.
He was laid to rest in the sunshine at the city's Seafield Cemetery, close to where he was discovered.
More than 200 mourners gathered to say goodbye to a child they did not know.
These bikers were among the people paying their respects
Several of them were tearful as his tiny white coffin was lowered into the ground, as a lone piper played bagpipes.
Leading the service, Reverend Erica Wishart, of Tranent Parish Church, said: "This is the kind of tragedy that surely touches everyone who hears about it. All of us who gather here today are grieving.
"We represent everyone in this community and beyond who feels deep sadness that this tiny baby is never going to have the chance to grow up and live his life."
Hundreds gathered to listen to the words of the presiding vicar
She added: "We are here to say goodbye to this wee one, with the dignity and respect he deserves."
A message left at his grave said: "Rest in God's arms, goodnight little baby."
A child looks at flowers left at the graveside
The funeral was arranged by Police Scotland with the help of volunteers.
Afterwards, officers handed out leaflets saying their investigation will continue and they are "still looking for the the vital piece of information which would help identify the child and his mother".
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:35:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman Arrested After Daughter Killed In Crash</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1475798</Link>
        <Description>A woman was arrested on suspicion of causing death by dangerous driving after her young daughter was killed in a crash.</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman Arrested After Daughter Killed In Crash
11:35, UK, Friday 01 May 2015
Traffic officer attending road accident. Pic: WM Police
Share by email
A woman was arrested on suspicion of causing death by dangerous driving after her young daughter was killed in a crash.
The car in which the woman was driving left the road and hit a tree in Gibbins Road, in the Selly Oak area of Birmingham.
It happened at around 4pm on Thursday. The mother was also questioned over an allegation of child neglect.
The woman's two-year-old daughter, who was in the back seat, suffered critical injuries.
Passers-by and paramedics tried to revive the girl but she was pronounced dead after arriving at hospital.
Four other people in the car, including the girl's mother, suffered minor injuries.
A post-mortem examination was due to take place to determine the cause of death.
Police are appealing for anyone who saw the collision and who has not yet spoken to officers to call the Collision Investigation Unit on 101.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Doctor In Court Over Teacher's Caesarean Death</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1475908</Link>
        <Description>The case also sees an NHS trust charged for the first time with corporate manslaughter in a landmark prosecution.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Doctor In Court Over Teacher's Caesarean Death
The case also sees an NHS trust charged for the first time with corporate manslaughter in a landmark prosecution.
12:47, UK, Friday 01 May 2015
Frances Cappuccini died after undergoing the emergency procedure in 2012
Share by email
A doctor has appeared in court charged with the manslaughter of a woman who died after giving birth by emergency Caesarean section.
ErrolCornish, 67, attendedSevenoaks Magistrates' Court along with Glenn Douglas, chief executive of Maidstone and Tunbridge Wells NHS Trust, whichis accused of corporate manslaughter over the death ofFrances Cappuccini.
It is the first time an NHS trust has been charged with the offence since it was introduced in 2008.
Mrs Cappuccini, 30, died at Tunbridge Wells Hospital in Pembury, Kent, after giving birth to her son by the emergency procedure on 9 October, 2012.
She was described as a "much-loved and dedicated" teacher at Offham School in Kent, where she tookreception and early year classes.
Kent police announced last month the decision to prosecute South African-born consultant anaesthetist Cornish, along with Dr Nadeem Azeez, 52, for the gross negligence manslaughter of Mrs Cappuccini.
The force said an arrest warrant has been issued for Azeez, formerly of Chestnut Avenue, Tunbridge Wells, who has returned to Pakistan.
Douglas, 56, appearing for the trust, and Cornish, of Holmbury Park, Bromley, southeast London, spoke only to confirm their name and date of birth during the initial magistrates' hearing.
The case was committed to Maidstone Crown Court, with a preliminary hearing listed for 22 May.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:46:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rescue Dog Camera Shows Nepal Devastation</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1475653</Link>
        <Description>A canine's camera captures the aftermath of Nepal's worst earthquake in 80 years, which has killed more than 6,200 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Rescue Dog Camera Shows Nepal Devastation
A canine's camera captures the aftermath of Nepal's worst earthquake in 80 years, which has killed more than 6,200 people.
09:46, UK, Friday 01 May 2015
Play video "Nepal Earthquake: Dog Cam Footage"
Video: Nepal Earthquake: Dog Cam Footage
Share by email
A video filmed from the perspective of a rescue dog shows the mammoth challenges faced on the ground in disaster-hit Nepal.
The Israel Defense Forces released footage of their canine in the rubble as efforts to find survivors continue nearly a week on.
The video captures some of the devastation left by the 7.8-magnitude quake, the worst to strike the country in 80 years.
With the number of people confirmed dead at 6,200, and nearly 14,000 people injured, Nepal is urging the international community to help.
The government says it needs to raise at least $2bn (1.2bn) for rebuilding homes, hospitals and government offices.
Play video "Moment Quake Hit In Bhaktapur"
Video: Moment Quake Hit In Bhaktapur
The Red Cross is "extremely concerned" about the welfare of the hundreds of thousands of people affected in far-flung areas of the poor Himalayan nation.
Its teams assessing the situation warned of "total devastation" in some towns and villages close to the quake's epicentre.
"One of our teams that returned from Chautara in Sindupalchowk district reported that 90% of the homes are destroyed," said Jagan Chapagain, Asia Pacific director of the Red Cross.
"The hospital has collapsed, and people are digging through the rubble with their hands in the hope that they might find family members who are still alive.
"We can expect the situation to be the same if not worse in many other places where aid has not yet been delivered."
1/25
Gallery: Nepal Quake Rescue Efforts Continue
Krishna Kumari Khadka is pulled from wreckage by French, Israeli and Norwegian rescuers
Further aid is arriving from Britain, with three Royal Air Force CH47 Chinook helicopters travelling from RAF Brize Norton to Nepal over the next few days.
They will bolster the aid efforts currently under way from a C-17 aircraft which arrived on Thursday carrying a team of Gurkha engineers and 18 tonnes of supplies.
The UK will also contribute 2.5m to the UN's Humanitarian Air Service to increase helicopter capacity and allow aid supplies to reach isolated areas.
Britain initially pledged 15m to the aid relief effort, while more than 19m was raised in public donations by the Disasters Emergency Committee a day after it was launched.
Twelve European Union citizens died in the disaster, it has been confirmed.
Play video "Everest: What's Left At Base Camp"
Video: Everest: What's Left At Base Camp
The EU ambassador to Nepal, Rensje Teerink, also said 1,000 EU citizens remained unaccounted for. Most of those had been trekking in the remote Langtang mountain range.
One British dual national killed has been named as Hemchandra Rai, a 42-year-old married father-of-three who lived in Hong Kong.
Although the hopes of finding survivors are fading, there have been moments of hope - on Thursday, a woman was pulled alive from the rubble five days after the devastating earthquake struck .
French, Israeli and Norwegian rescuers took 10 hours to get the woman - named as Krishna Kumari Khadka - to safety.
Play video "Rescued Boy: 'The Ceiling Fell In'"
Video: Rescued Boy: 'The Ceiling Fell In'
Hours earlier, a 15-year-old boy was freed from a collapsed hotel in Kathmandu.
Prime Minister Sushil Koirala has warned the death toll could reach 10,000.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:44:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Second Major Quake Strikes Papua New Guinea</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1475815</Link>
        <Description>The quake happened 128km (79 miles) southwest of Rabaul, a town that lies in the shadow of Mount Tavurvur, an active volcano.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Second Major Quake Strikes Papua New Guinea
The quake happened 128km (79 miles) southwest of Rabaul, a town that lies in the shadow of Mount Tavurvur, an active volcano.
10:44, UK, Friday 01 May 2015
Rabaul lies in the shadow of Mount Tavurvur, an active volcano
A 6.7-magnitude earthquake has hit Papua New Guinea, followed by an even more intense aftershock measuring 7.1.
TheUS Geological Survey recorded the quakes a day after a 6.9 tremor shook the nation .
After the latest scare, people were warned of the possibility of a "hazardous tsunami", but that alert has now been lifted.
Dr Roger Musson, of the British Geological Survey, told Sky News: "This is another thrust earthquake, which is the same sort of fault movement as occurred in the earthquake in Nepal .
"In this case, it is an ocean plate - the Solomon Sea is being pushed underneath New Britain (Island) - and it is a very active seismic zone  it's produced much larger earthquakes than this one we've had.
"A magnitude of 7.1 is probably not big enough to have a large impact. There have been earthquakes as large as magnitude 8 in this area before.
"The last big one that we had in this area, of magnitude 8, caused a tsunami that killed about 40 people but this one, I think, is too small and too deep."
There are no immediate reports of casualties or damage to property.
Rabaul, the town nearest where the earthquake hit, is on East New Britain Island.
It lies in the shadow of active volcano Mount Tavurvur. The town was destroyed 21 years ago when the volcano erupted.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:01:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fiancee Charged With Murder Of Missing Kayaker</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1475812</Link>
        <Description>Police arrest a woman who said her fiance's kayak had capsized in choppy waters on the Hudson River and she had tried to save him.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Fiancee Charged With Murder Of Missing Kayaker
Police arrest a woman who said her fiance's kayak had capsized in choppy waters on the Hudson River and she had tried to save him.
10:01, UK, Friday 01 May 2015
Angelika Graswald, 35, faces a second-degree murder charge
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
A woman whose fiance has been missing since a kayaking trip on the Hudson River 11 days ago has been charged with his murder.
Angelika Graswald, 35, has been arrested on a second-degree murder charge in connection with the death of Vincent Viafore, 46.
She toldinvestigators that she and Mr Viafore were kayaking on 19 April when his boat capsized in choppy, cold waters.
Graswald called 911 and said she could not find her fiance in the water.
The couple last year
She reported falling out of her kayak as she tried to help him, and said she was picked up by a boater. She was treated for hypothermia.
Graswald also gave a TV interview in which she tearfully said she watched Mr Viafore fall in the water.
"He said, 'I don't think I'm gonna make it,' and I said, 'What are you talking about? Of course you are,'" she told News 12, a Westchester TV station.
State troopers have spent days searching the river near Cornwall-On-Hudson, a town 80 km (50m) north of New York City.
They have found both kayaks but so far have not been able to recover the body. However, police believe he is dead.
Officials said Graswald was wearing a life jacket but they believe Mr Viafore was not.
Investigators cited inconsistencies in her account as they announced the murder charge on Thursday afternoon.However, they did not elaborate on how she allegedly killed him or why.
The search for Mr Viafore continues, by boat and helicopter, and police have asked boaters, fishermen and hikers to be on the lookout.
It is unclear whetherGraswald has entered a plea. She is due to appear in court on 5 May.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:56:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charles Jokes About Harry's 'Budgie Smugglers'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1475757</Link>
        <Description>The Prince of Wales reveals his suspicions about what his son is getting up to during his stint in Australia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Charles Jokes About Harry's 'Budgie Smugglers'
The Prince of Wales reveals his suspicions about what his son is getting up to during his stint in Australia.
09:56, UK, Friday 01 May 2015
Play video "Charles In 'Budgie Smugglers' Quip"
Video: Charles In 'Budgie Smugglers' Quip
Share by email
The Prince of Wales has been joking with an audience of Australians in London about what his "old Harry" is up to in their homeland.
Speaking at the opening of the Indigenous Australia Exhibition at the British Museum, Prince Charles pointed out that Prince Harry had now been in Australia for nearly four weeks serving with the armed forces.
The two princes at last month's Gallipoli ceremony
At the end of his stretch in Australia, Harry will leave the British Army next month. Meanwhile, his father said, he was sure his boy was making the most of his time in Australia.
Prince Charles said: "I suspect my old Harry is pretty well acclimatised by now and will probably be eating lamingtons[a type of small cake], Vegemite sandwiches, Iced VoVos [a brand of biscuit] and VioletCrumble bars - and may even be threatening to buy a pair of 'budgie smugglers'.
Play video "April 29 - Charles Works Out"
Video: April 29 - Charles Works Out
"Whatever the case Ladies and Gentlemen, I am sure he'll be happy down under because of the Aussies' fondness for 'rangas'."
Rangas - or wrangers - is a slang, light-hearted term for redheads.
Charles also pointed out: "Harry, has in recent weeks gone walkabout with the Australian Army alongside Aboriginal soldiers who patrol, if you can believe it, nearly 700,000 square miles of land in the Northern Territory and in the Kimberley region of Western Australia."
Meanwhile, Harry has reportedly been impressing locals in the Western Australian city of Perth.
The Prince went to a fast-food restaurant on Friday and ordered one of its staples, the QVB burger.
While ordering, he asked what QVB stood for.
Hannah Wadsworth, who works at the Flipside restaurant, said the Royal laughed when he was told it stands for "Queen Victoria Burger".
"He was really nice. Quiet but friendly," Ms Wadsworth told the Australian Broadcasting Corporation.
Earlier in the day, Harry surprised staff at a bakery at Bindoon, west of Perth, which is near an army base.
Bindoon Bakehaus and Cafe owner Leanne Phillipson described him as "very pleasant, lovely, very relaxed, chilled and down to earth."
Sue Blay, who was working at the bakery, said she was "shocked" when the Prince turned up with about "10 or 15" others.
"He spotted one of the girls' English accents and my Irish accents and asked 'what are you doing here in the middle of nowhere?'," she told Fairfax Media.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
