<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Sky-News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:37:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Queen's Speech: Tax Break For Low Wage Earners</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1491262</Link>
        <Description>The Conservatives say the Queen's Speech is for working families, but Labour fears it will be "very different from the rhetoric".</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Queen's Speech: Tax Break For Low Wage Earners
The Conservatives say the Queen's Speech is for working families, but Labour fears it will be "very different from the rhetoric".
01:37, UK, Wednesday 27 May 2015
Play video "Tax Break For Low Income Earners"
Video: Tax Break For Low Income Earners
Share by email
By Sophy Ridge, Political Correspondent
People working 30 hours a week on minimum wage will no longer have to pay income tax under the first Conservative programme for government since 1992.
The Queen's Speech today will set out the Tory administration's legislative plans for the next five years.
The traditional address is spoken by the Queen, but written by Prime Minister David Cameron's team.
The Queen will announce an EUReferendum Bill that will give a vote on Britain's membership by 2017 , and an immigration bill to curb illegal immigration.
Speaking ahead of the speech, Mr Cameron said: "This is the Queen's Speech for working people from a One Nation Government that will bring our country together.
Play video "Tory Manifesto In 60 Seconds"
Video: Tory Manifesto In 60 Seconds
"We have a mandate from the British people, a clear manifesto and the instruction to deliver. And we will not waste a single moment in getting on with the task.
"As part of our long-term plan to back working people and make work pay, the Government is determined to reward work by letting people keep even more of the money they earn."
In a traditional address to Parliament, the Queen will confirm legislation will be brought forward to ensure that future increases in the income tax personal allowance will reflect changes to the minimum wage.
This will mean that anyone working 30 hours a week on the minimum wage will pay no income tax.
Other plans to be laid out by the Queen include doubling the amount of free childcare, creating three million apprenticeships and introducing 8bn more funding for the NHS.
Devolution will be another key focus, with extra powers to English regions and the Scotland bill promising more devolution north of the border.
And a five-year "tax lock" will mean there will be no income tax, VAT or national insurance rises in this Parliament.
The acting Labour leader Harriet Harman says she fears the reality of the Tories' plans "will be very different from the rhetoric".
Play video "2014: Page Boy Faints In Speech"
Video: 2014: Page Boy Faints In Speech
"The Queen's Speech will talk of a 'One Nation approach' - yet Cameron sets the nations of the country against each other," she said.
"The Queen's Speech will talk of helping 'working people' - yet Cameron threatens basic rights at work.
"The real question for this Queen's Speech will be whether it improves our country, our communities and people."
The pageantry begins with the Queen's procession from Buckingham Palace to Westminster, escorted by the Household Cavalry.
She arrives at Sovereign's Entrance before leading the Royal Procession to the chamber of the House of Lords.
A senior official known as Black Rod is sent to summon the Commons, where the doors to the chamber are shut in his face - symbolising the Commons' independence from the monarchy.
Black Rod strikes the door three times before it is opened, and MPs then follow him to the Lords Chamber to listen to the speech.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:41:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What You Need To Know About The Queen's Speech</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1491005</Link>
        <Description>The Queen delivers her speech at the State Opening of Parliament today. Here's what you need to know.</Description>
        <MainBody>What You Need To Know About The Queen's Speech
01:41, UK, Wednesday 27 May 2015
The EU and human rights will be at the centre of the Queen's Speech
The Queen delivers her speech at the State Opening of Parliament today. Here's what you need to know.
What is the Queen's Speech?
It sets out what the Government will do in the coming parliamentary year and is delivered at the State Opening of Parliament.
Does the Queen write it?
No, ministers do. The Queen just reads it out on behalf of her Government - from a throne in the House of Lords.
Play video "2014: Page Boy Faints In Speech"
Video: 2014: Page Boy Faints In Speech
How long does it last?
Around 10 minutes. It's long enough for a page boy to faint - as one did last year.
And the pomp and ceremony?
There's plenty of that. The Queen wears the Imperial State Crown and Robe of State.
For the first time last year the monarch travelled from Buckingham Palace to Westminster in the Diamond Jubilee State Coach, made of oak from HMS Victory, slivers of Isaac Newton's apple tree, bits of Sir Edmund Hillary's Everest ladders and a bolt from a Spitfire.
How old is the tradition?
There is some evidence of speeches dating back to the 16th century but the event has existed in its current form since 1852.
How many times has the Queen read the speech?
This will be the Monarch's 64th. She was excused in 1959 and 1963 when she was pregnant. The Lord Chancellor read the speech instead.
:: What happens?
Black Rod, a House of Lords official, summons MPs from the Commons to come and hear the speech in the Lords.
It is tradition that the doors of the Commons are shut in his face - a custom that dates back to the Civil War and symbolises the independence of the Government and the monarchy.
Black Rod knocks three times at the door and then issues the summons to the Speaker. MPs then proceed to the Lords chamber to hear the speech.
No monarch has set foot in the Commons since Charles I in 1642.
:: And what will be in the Queen's Speech this year?
::EU- a referendum on Britain's membership of the EU due by the end of 2017
:: British Bill of Rights - Human Rights Act to be scrapped and likely withdrawal from European Convention on Human Rights
::"Snoopers' Charter" - intelligence agencies to be able to see the emails you have been sending, calls you have made and internet sites you have browsed
:: Tax lock bill - guarantee the government will not increase VAT, National Insurance and Income Tax
:: Tax-free minimum wage - personal allowance to rise in line with the minimum wage so lowest paid, on 30 hours a week, never pay income tax
:: Childcare - double free childcare provision for three and four year olds to 30 hours a week
:: Right to buy - 1.3m housing association tenants able to buy their properties
:: Northern Powerhouse - devolution bill to give more powers to cities like Manchester
:: More powers for Scotland - as promised ahead of last years referendum
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:32:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU Referendum: 'Yes' To Stay Or 'No' To Leave</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1491272</Link>
        <Description>Voters are expected to be asked to choose "yes" to remain in Europe or "no" to leave in a referendum on EU membership.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
EU Referendum: 'Yes' To Stay Or 'No' To Leave
Voters are expected to be asked to choose "yes" to remain in Europe or "no" to leave in a referendum on EU membership.
01:32, UK, Wednesday 27 May 2015
Play video "'Yes' To Remain Or 'No' To Leave"
Video: 'Yes' To Remain Or 'No' To Leave
Share by email
By Faisal Islam, Political Editor
The wording put to voters in the referendum on European Union membership will ask Britons to vote "yes" to remain in the union or "no" to leave, Sky sources say.
The precise question proposed by the Government will be published in the EU Referendum Bill within 24 hours.
The question is expected to be similar to the Electoral Commission's suggested modification to then-backbencher James Wharton's private member's bill.
That question stated: "Should the United Kingdom remain in the European Union?"
The Commission was concerned that too few potential voters were aware that Britain was already a member of the EU.
The question will be the subject of considerable debate and possible amendment in Parliament.
Play video "Tax Break For Low Income Earners"
Video: Tax Break For Low Income Earners
Other bills on immigration, apprenticeships, Scotland, city devolution, and housing will be announced by the Queen.
But the EU referendum towers above everything else.
European officials are starting to make life difficult for Prime Minister David Cameron's strategy on European reform.
The window is closing on the "full-on" EUtreaty change wanted and expected by the PM and his backbenchers.
Germany had been the big hope for the UK's renegotiation.
Berlin had wanted to get the Eurozone fiscal compact written into the EUtreaty at some point, to give watertight restrictions on borrowing within the single currency zone.
This realignment would have provided the only real opportunity for Britain to change its legal relationship within the European Union.
France is opposed to treaty change however, and what has emerged in the past few months is that as many as 18 of the EU's 28 member states are also not in favour.
Domestic politics is the main reason: the ratification of a treaty change would be a tough ask against a backdrop of the rise of populist far-right and far-left parties.
The Le Monde newspaper's leak of the Franco-German position paper, confirmed by its recipient - Jean-Claude Juncker's spokesman - is confirmation that Germany is not going to give a treaty change opportunity for Mr Cameron to take.
The Franco-German paper refers to "four areas of action, which should be developed in the framework of the current treaties in the coming years".
Responding to the story, Mr Cameron's spokesman said there has been "no change whatsoever (on treaty change)... widely known that Eurozone countries have been discussing for some time a range of issues".
Senior Conservative backbenchers again stressed the importance of achieving formal treaty change.
Mr Cameron's more immediate challenge following the Franco-German position paper will be to get his reform proposals on the agenda for June's European Leaders Summit in Brussels.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:22:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police Vow To 'Provide Justice' Over Abuse</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1490903</Link>
        <Description>Staffordshire Police are investigating claims made by Esther Baker, who told Sky News she was raped while officers stood guard.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Police Vow To 'Provide Justice' Over Abuse
Staffordshire Police are investigating claims made by Esther Baker, who told Sky News she was raped while officers stood guard.
18:22, UK, Tuesday 26 May 2015
Play video "'Cops Stood Guard As I Was Raped'"
Video: 'Cops Stood Guard As I Was Raped'
Share by email
By Tom Parmenter, Sky News Correspondent
Police say they are "in the early stages" of investigating claims that a woman was sexually abused while she was a young girl, as uniformed police officers stood guard.
Waiving her right to anonymity, Esther Baker, 32, spoke exclusively to Sky News about her tormented childhood that saw her sexually abused by men at various locations.
She claimed police officers would stand guard for the perpetrators and on some occasions even joined in the abuse in woodland on Cannock Chase in Staffordshire.
She said: "I got the feeling very much that they were protecting somebody, that they were with one of the men.
"One of them (police officers) I knew from church. There were a few occasions where they would be in uniform and I kind of knew, I learnt that when they were in uniform that it was going to be a rough night.
Play video "'Cops Stood Guard As I Was Raped'"
Video: 'Cops Stood Guard As I Was Raped'
Responding to the claims, Staffordshire Police Assistant Chief Constable Jon Drake said officers were in the early stages of investigating the case and interviewing Ms Baker.
He added: "We are determined to thoroughly gather any evidence which will allow us to bring those who may have been involved to justice, while taking a sensitive approach to supporting the victim throughout.
"We will continue to interview her over the coming days, recognising the horrific nature of what we are investigating.
"To be clear, anyone, regardless of role, who has been involved in criminal offences will be investigated to provide justice for the victim."
He encouraged anyone with information about the allegations - or any other victims of sexual abuse - to contact police on 101 or anonymously through Crimestoppers on 0800 555111.
While Ms Baker has chosen to waive her legal right to anonymity, Mr Drake said police would protect the anonymity of anyone who came forward as a victim of child or sexual abuse.
From the age of six, Ms Baker was taken to be abused by different men on Cannock Chase, at various properties around Staffordshire and beyond.
Other children were often there and sometimes they were given alcohol: "We were all pretty much the same, same ages, we never spoke."
She says the sexual abuse was often filmed and involved men of varying ages from different parts of the country.
She said: "I was brought up in a religious household and one thing that kept me so sure that what they were doing was right was that there were references to people, Lords and a judge.
"I picked up on those names, because I thought one of them must have been God because one of them was 'Our Lord'.
Play video "Child Abuse Inquiry Will Be Robust"
Video: Child Abuse Inquiry Will Be Robust
"I just thought that they were on God's authority."
Decades on, Ms Baker has decided to speak to Sky News in the hope of finding other victims or the police officers who were involved.
She said: "I need them to fill in the gaps that I just don't know, I need people that were adults then but they couldn't stop it for whatever reason, it is time for them to stop it now."
The other children who were allegedly abused on Cannock Chase may also hold vital information.
Ms Baker added: "Every one of us that comes forward will hold a different piece of the puzzle. I can't fill it in on my own."
She said: "I always swore I would never go near the police again - never ... but I have hid it for 20 years, that has not worked, that hasn't taken the fear away - I have got nothing to lose anymore."
Gabrielle Shaw of the National Association for People Abused in Childhood, said Ms Bakers story was absolutely harrowing.
She added: "It's not easy for anyone to come forward and tell their storybut with every survivor who comes forward like Esther Baker, it helps other survivors come forward as well, chips away at the wall of silence."
Ms Shaw said she had seen a "real seachange" in the way police worked with victims of sexual abuse, adding: "They're not swept under the carpet".
A Home Office spokesperson said: "The Home Secretary set up the independent inquiry, under the chairmanship of Justice Goddard, to examine the extent to which abuse has taken place in state and non-state institutions in England and Wales.
"She is confident the inquiry will establish why it was possible for such abuse to take place and challenge individuals and institutions without fear or favour."
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:54:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Texas Flood 'Tsunami': Death Toll Keeps Rising</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1490958</Link>
        <Description>Among the missing are members of two families who were in a holiday home that was swept away by a swollen river.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Texas Flood 'Tsunami': Death Toll Keeps Rising
Among the missing are members of two families who were in a holiday home that was swept away by a swollen river.
21:54, UK, Tuesday 26 May 2015
Play video "Devastating Floods Claim More Lives"
Video: Devastating Floods Claim More Lives
Share by email
By Sky News US Team
Thirteen people are missing in Texas after flash floods that have already claimed at least 16 lives in that state and Oklahoma.
The Hays County commissioner in central Texas said earlier they were looking for 30 people along the swollen Blanco River, but most have since been accounted for.
The floodwaters kept rising on Tuesday as storms dumped yet more rain on the already deluged Houston area.
Among the missing are members of two families who were in a holiday home that was swept away over the weekend.
Vehicles left stranded on a flooded Interstate in Houston, Texas
The property in Wimberley, Texas, was lifted off its foundations and slammed into a bridge on the BlancoRiver, which is at three times its normal level.
Laura McComb, who is missing with her two children, reportedly called her sister as the home was uprooted.
1/14
Gallery: Dozens Missing As Lone Star State Deluged
Flood-damaged vehicles and debris in San Marcos, Texas, which has been inundated by raging waters
"We are in a house that is now floating down the river," she said, according to KXAN-TV. "Call Mom and Dad. I love you. And pray."
Three fatalities were confirmed in Houston on Tuesday morning.
Swathes of America's fourth largest city have been inundated and more than 1,000 vehicles submerged on swamped roads.
Fans at Monday night's Houston Rockets baseball game stayed in the Toyota Center arena until the early hours because of the extreme weather.
Residents have been urged to stay off roads with many of the routes into the city flooded and blocked by stalled vehicles.
Some 100,000 householders were without electricity across Texas because of the storms.
More than 1,000 homes have been damaged or destroyed and thousands of residents displaced.
President Barack Obama said on Tuesday he had assured Texas Governor Greg Abbott that he could count on help from the federal government.
1/7
Gallery: Twister Kills 13 People In Mexico Border Town
A twister has killed at least 13 people in northern Mexico
Governor Abbott, who has declared a disaster in 37 counties, said: "This is the biggest flood this area of Texas has ever seen.
"It is absolutely massive - the relentless tsunami-type power of this wave of water."
Among the dead are an 18-year-old swept away by floodwaters in Devine, Texas, as she drove home from her school prom on Saturday.
A 14-year-old boy's body was found in a storm drain on Monday morning along with his dog in DeSoto, Texas.
A firefighter was also swept into a storm drain in Claremore, Oklahoma,while attempting a rescue on Sunday.
The system is among a line of storms that have drenched areas from the Gulf of Mexico to the Great Lakes.
There was a devastating tornado in a northern Mexican border city on Monday, leaving at least 13 dead and others missing.
It swept through Ciudad Acuna, flipping over cars, tearing down homes and ripping a child from its mother's arms .
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:15:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NI Govt 'In Real Trouble' Over Budget Row</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1491223</Link>
        <Description>The crisis was caused by the failure to pass welfare reforms and means the government could be in danger of collapse.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
NI Govt 'In Real Trouble' Over Budget Row
The crisis was caused by the failure to pass welfare reforms and means the government could be in danger of collapse.
01:15, UK, Wednesday 27 May 2015
Play video "NI Govt In Danger Of Collapsing"
Video: NI Govt In Danger Of Collapsing
Share by email
Northern Ireland's devolved government is facing suspension or possible collapse amid a row over welfare reforms that has left the faltering administration facing an estimated 600m funding gap.
The crisis has been sparked by the failure of the assembly to pass a welfare reform bill agreed in Westminster in 2013.
The nationalist parties at Stormont introduced a petition of concern, effectively a veto, which requires any bill to have sufficient support from both unionist and nationalist parties to go through.
Sky's Ireland Correspondent David Blevinssaid the fall of the legislation means the devolved government is in "very real trouble".
He explained: "In short, the devolved government never implemented the welfare cuts agreed in Westminster in 2013.
Play video "Dec: Northern Ireland Deal Agreed"
Video: Dec: Northern Ireland Deal Agreed
"The parties finally reached agreement on a way forward last Christmas, the Stormont House agreement.
"But Sinn Fein had a change of heart in March of this year and withdrew its support for the bill.
"The problem is that Sinn Fein finds itself in a difficult position. It cannot be anti-austerity in the Republic of Ireland but push through an austerity budget in Northern Ireland."
Blevins added: "David Cameron will now have to decide whether he triggers a suspension for the first time in eight years or allows the devolved government to fall and move to an election."
Unless leaders can agree a lasting deal on welfare in the coming days, a senior civil servant could be forced to step in to take over departmental spends later in the summer.
This would likely increase the chances of one of the main parties in the Executive - the DUP and Sinn Fein - walking away.
In the absence of any deal, the Democratic Unionists have suggested another option - the UK Government stepping in to implement the welfare reforms over the head of the devolved administration.
However, Downing Street has shown no appetite for this, and such a move would likely be a resigning matter for Sinn Fein.
DUP social development minister Mervyn Storey claimed the SDLP and Sinn Fein had backtracked on the Stormont House agreement.
He said: "They want, like Pontius Pilate, to wring their hands, to almost cleanse their consciences that somehow they had not signed the dotted line."
But Sinn Fein Deputy First Minister Martin McGuinness said "Tory cuts" were to blame for the deadlock.
He said: "The current crisis has come about solely through the actions of the British Government, it could only be resolved by the actions of the British Government."
The fall of the bill has also endangered other elements of the Stormont House accord struck between the five members of the coalition and the British and Irish governments, such as the devolution of corporation tax powers and new structures to tackle the legacy of the Troubles.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:01:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wednesday's National Newspaper Front Pages</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1491251</Link>
        <Description>Sky News takes a look at the stories making a splash in Wednesday's national newspapers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wednesday's National Newspaper Front Pages
Sky News takes a look at the stories making a splash in Wednesday's national newspapers.
23:01, UK, Tuesday 26 May 2015
Play video "Wednesday's Newspaper Front Pages"
Video: Wednesday's Newspaper Front Pages
THE PAPERS' TOP STORIES
:: Financial Times
David Cameron will use the Queen's Speech to set out plans to fast-track an EU referendum bill through the House of Commons.
:: The Daily Telegraph
The Prime Minister will also pledge to "not waste a single moment" in cutting taxes for 30 million people.
1/14
Gallery: Wednesday's National Newspaper Front Pages
David Cameron will use the Queen's Speech to set out plans to fast-track an EU referendum bill through the House of Commons, the Financial Times reports
:: The Times, The Sun, Daily Mail
However, Mr Cameron has stepped back from an early confrontation with his own MPs over a controversial move to scrap European human rights laws - delaying the move for at least a year.
:: The Guardian
Nick Clegg will warn MPs that Britain's civil liberties hang in the balance because of measures in the Queen's Speech.
:: The Independent, i
Scientists have the first proof that an entirely new way of combating cancer, using genetically modified viruses to attack tumour cells, can benefit patients.
:: Metro
A company boss who cost small-time investors hundreds of millions of pounds has been fined a record 75m by the City watchdog.
:: Daily Express
Fury has erupted after a secret French and German plot to impose a "crippling" new tax rate on Britain was exposed.
:: Daily Mirror
The family of cancer victim Jeffrey Spector have been overwhelmed by support for his decision to die in Swiss suicide clinic Dignitas.
:: Daily Star
Amanda Holden went into meltdown when Stephen Mulhern mocked her Botox habit.
:: Watch the Press Preview on Sky News every evening at 10.30pm and 11.30pm. Wednesday night's reviewers will be The Sun's political editor, Tom Newton-Dunn, and the New Statesman's Caroline Crampton.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:55:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Radio Boss Defends Killing Rabbit Live On Air</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1490826</Link>
        <Description>The station chief says the controversy highlights the fact "animal welfare is an issue for some animals but not for others".</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Radio Boss Defends Killing Rabbit Live On Air
The station chief says the controversy highlights the fact "animal welfare is an issue for some animals but not for others".
18:55, UK, Tuesday 26 May 2015
Play video "Radio Chief Defends Rabbit Killing"
Video: Radio Chief Defends Rabbit Killing
Share by email
A Danish radio station boss has defended the killing of a baby rabbit during a live show, telling Sky News there is a "discrepancy" in how we care for different animals.
The Radio24syvpresenter Asger Juhl was hosting a debate on animal welfare when he hit nine-week-old Allan three times with a bicycle pump, before wringing its neck.
The station has been criticised over the item, but Mr Juhl, 34, said it was to demonstrate the hypocrisy of animal rights campaigners who eat meat from supermarkets.
Allan 'had a comfortable existence' before his death (Pic: Radio24syv)
And the station's chief executive,Jorgen Ramskov, told Sky News: "We wanted to raise a discussion about why animal welfare is an issue for some animals but not for other animals.
"In Denmark, at least, we have a very industrialised agricultural industry and a lot of these animals in this sector are not basically viewed as animals, they're machines delivering meat to our tables and we don't really care about their animal welfare.
"We have some animals that we have decided that we care about their animal welfare and that discrepancy we wanted to address.
Mr Juhl with Allan before hitting him three times with a bicycle pump
"The rabbit is something you can eat, but also an animal we care a lot about. Why don't we care for a piglet, why don't we care for a small cow, or lamb?"
He also insisted the radio had taken advice from experts on how to kill rabbit "instantly and in a way that the animal doesn't suffer".
"According to the person from the zoo, that's how you kill a rabbit," he said.
"I am sure there are other ways to kill rabbits."
Allan being cooked in a stew
He also said Mr Juhl was raised on a farm, and had previous experience of killing rabbits.
Linse Kessler, who had been part of an earlier discussion in the studio, talked her way back inside in a bid to save Allan butcould not prevent the bunny's death.
On the radio's Facebook page, a video was posted of meat being cooked in a stew, with a comment from the station saying that Mr Juhl and co-hostKristoffer Eriksen would be eating the rabbit following its death.
There was also a sound recording of Allan's final moments.
The broadcast prompted an angry response from listeners, with some calling for a boycott of the station.
Mr Juhl enjoys a glass of wine while eating Allan
The radio station's spokesman said they had "anticipated strong reactions".
"We knew that we would be accused of provocation," he said.
"And yes, we indeed wanted to provoke the public and to stir a debate about the hypocrisy when it comes to perceptions of cruelty towards animals.
"Consumers generally do not kill animals themselves, but we buy and eat animals, that have lead sad lives. We just dont see it, and dont consider the animals cute as the rabbit.
"These animals have often endured horrific suffering on their way to our dinner tables. These animals are killed according to the same controlled conditions as our studio rabbit, and without it invoking any strong reactions or calls for boycott.
"We at least believe that the studio rabbit have had a comfortable existence.
"We wanted to expose the vast hypocrisy surrounding our relationship with animals. So far we have succeeded. We wanted and want to have a debate about animal welfare - for all animals."
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:45:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Books Fighting Back In Battle With E-Readers</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1491249</Link>
        <Description>Authors tell Sky News "the novelty of the e-book has worn off", amid hopes the big fall in paperback sales has come to an end.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Books Fighting Back In Battle With E-Readers
Authors tell Sky News "the novelty of the e-book has worn off", amid hopes the big fall in paperback sales has come to an end.
01:45, UK, Wednesday 27 May 2015
Booklovers flock to the annual Hay Literary Festival
Share by email
By Lucy Cotter, Entertainment Correspondent
After years of being under threat from the growing popularity of e-readers, sales figures show the printed book now appears to be holding its own.
The latest statistics from the Publishing Association show that although physical book sales are slightly down, the two mediums are co-existing - with digital revenues accounting for 35% of a sector worth 4.3bn.
At The Hay Literary Festival in Wales, thousands of book lovers flock to read, discuss and dissect their favourite works.
John Boyne, the author of best-selling novel The Boy In The Striped Pyjamas, believes the digital danger has passed.
"I think the novelty of e-book has worn off, people have their Kindles, I have a Kindle and I use it when I'm travelling," he said.
Play video "2014: Books In The Digital Age"
Video: 2014: Books In The Digital Age
"It's easier than putting books in a bag but people who like books tend to like books as a physical object, so I think the moment when e-books could have superseded books is gone."
The biggest success in the sector has been in children's literature, which has enjoyed an increase in sales of 11% overall.
Comedian and author David Baddiel is at the festival to promote his first children's book, The Parent Agency, which has been a massive hit already.
"Children really like having the tangible object of the book. It feels to me like kids think of a book especially if it's got brilliant illustrations like Jim Field has done on my book, like I used to feel when I bought a record," he said.
"It's not just about thinking 'Oh I want to read this important book so I'm going to download it on my kindle'. I want to have the thing; it's like a badge of identity."
It is by no means an easy time for the physical book and the challenge has been finding new ways to keep people engaged.
Alexander McCall Smith, who has just won the Bollinger Everyman Woodhouse prize for Fatty O'Leary's Dinner Party, says the novel is here to stay.
"I'm rather optimistic about the state of the novel," he said.
"I think the book club has done an immense amount for reading - the fact that people are discovering the joy of reading a book with six or seven other people in their book club and discussing it. I'm sure that had a major effect on keeping the novel alive."
Peter Florence started the Hay Festival 28 years ago and believes the future for publishing is exciting.
"Somebody will be telling stories (and) what format they use is up in the air, it's up for grabs, it's an amazing opportunity," he said.
"But this (the book) could last for another 200 years, it's a beautiful piece of work."
The Hay Literary Festival is on until 31 May.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:52:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Footballer To Give Young Fan Shirt After Storm</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1491137</Link>
        <Description>Ted Dockray will be given the hat-trick hero's spare shirt, after a woman sparked anger by taking the match-worn garment from him.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Footballer To Give Young Fan Shirt After Storm
Ted Dockray will be given the hat-trick hero's spare shirt, after a woman sparked anger by taking the match-worn garment from him.
18:52, UK, Tuesday 26 May 2015
The woman takes the shirt from the eight-year-old (Pic: Sky Sports)
Share by email
Preston will present a schoolboy with a signed Jermaine Beckford shirt after television footage showed a woman wrenching the striker's match-worn garment off him at the Sky Bet League One play-off final.
Beckford, who scored a hat-trick in a 4-0 win for Preston, handed eight-year-old Ted Dockray his shirt before cameras showed a woman apparently wrestling the top from his grasp.
The footage then went viral, sparking anger among many other fans and social media users.
But Preston North End have now said they will give the boy Beckford's spare shirt from the game and also treat him to a free stadium tour of Deepdale.
A club statement read: "The club are fully aware of an incident in Sunday's Play-Off Final win over Swindon Town involving Jermaine Beckford's match shirt.
"The club have been in consultation with the Football League and the parents of the child who is alleged to have had the shirt taken from him as seen on television cameras covering the match.
"Please note, no one involved in this situation is connected with Preston North End in any way, shape or form.
"The people seated in the area of the incident attended the Play-Off Final as part of the League One Football League Kids' Cup Final which was played earlier in the day.
"We are delighted to say that Jermaine is more than happy to sign and present the child involved with his spare match shirt from the game.
"The club will also provide a stadium tour for the youngster.
"If the shirt that Jermaine wore is returned to us, we will of course present this to the child in question instead.
"The club will not be commenting further on the matter at this time and would like the focus returned to Sunday's fantastic achievement and building towards what will be an exciting season in the Championship."
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
