<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="SMH">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Mon Aug 17 17:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant find 'hot spots' warming faster</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/environment/climate-change/university-of-nsw-climate-researchers-steven-sherwood-and-nidhi-nishant-find-hot-spots-warming-faster-20150618-ghhlxd.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant find 'hot spots' warming faster
Date
Climate researcher Steven Sherwood has found data issues are to blame for not detecting hot spots.
Photo: James Brickwood
This article is part ofClimate for Change,aFairfax Media series on global warming. Full coverage can be found here .Follow our coverage on Facebook .
It's the hole in the science that global warming sceptics have long exploited  the apparent lack of "hot spots" high in the atmosphere over the tropics that should be there if climate models were accurate.
We found the global warming signal is stronger than we thought it would be.
Climate researcher Steven Sherwood
After years of debate, University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant have resolved data issues that not only reveal those "hot spots" to be there  but they are in fact warming some 10 per cent faster than modelling has predicted.
"[We found] the global warming signal is stronger than we thought it would be," Professor Sherwood said.
Advertisement
For Professor Sherwood, it's just another example  along with the "global warming hiatus" that has been deemed this month by US scientists to be a data error  of how so-called climate sceptics can divert or distort debate.
"The models predict that if, and only if, man is the cause of warming, the tropical upper air, six miles above the ground, should warm up to thrice as fast as the surface, but this tropical uppertroposphere "hotspot" has not been observed in 50 years of measurement," Christopher Monckton, a prominent Britishsceptic, wrote in 2010.
That the upper troposphere hadn't warmed compared with the surface would be a major surprise for science, Professor Sherwood said.
Surfacetemperatures have been rising at about 0.15 degrees per decade. As air rises over the tropics, a lot of water vapour condenses, releasing latent heat, that warms up the air.
"It would have been truly astonishing if the temperatures in the upper troposphere hadn't been going up faster than at the surface," Professor Sherwood said.
"If it didn't appear, it would have nothing to do with whether humans are causing climate change, but it would mean there is something about the way air mixes in the atmosphere that we didn't know," he said. "And the ramifications for climate change could go either way."
Professor Sherwood's paper found data issues were to blame for not detecting the hot spot that really was there.
One source of the bad data was the result of weather balloons becoming more accurate by making the monitors less susceptible to warming by the sun.
"Over time, it has happened less, so it has made the temperatures appear not to rise when they really did rise," he said.
Professor Sherwood said he hadn't bothered to follow how sceptics had responded to his paper, saying that scientist had merely identified a problem and worked to resolve it.
He is more critical, though, of the role played by the sceptics in proclaiming an apparent slowdown in surface temperature warming over the past decade or so.
Even this so-called hiatus is now being viewedby the US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as largely the result of instrument misreadings.
"A lot of scientific effort went into the hiatus although none of us believed it was very significant just because the sceptics were making so much hay out of it," he said "It's an example of where the sceptics are succeeding to some extent in distracting scientists away from perhaps more important work that they could be doing."
Sceptics' interest in "hot spots" they believed weren't there and the fact they couldn'taccount for the additional heat being trapped by the Earth from its increased greenhouse gases, pointedto a contrast in approaches, he said.
"They're not aiming for a self-consistent and reasonably comprehensive description of the world. What they are aiming at is to discredit something," he said.
Resolving issues such as the hot spot removedone more data dispute for sceptics to pick over, he said, adding,"the inconsistencies don't go on forever".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:35:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>10 climate actions to curb global warming, lift GDP</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/environment/climate-change/10-climate-actions-to-curb-global-warming-lift-gdp-20150707-gi7aej.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>10 climate actions to curb global warming, lift GDP
Date
Print
Fighting climate change doesn't have to cost the earth.
More efficient energy use and investments in greener cities are among 10 measures that can help the world to slow global warming while also spurring economic growth, an international report said on Tuesday.
Action across the 10 areas could achieve between 59 and 96 per cent of the cuts in greenhouse gas emissions needed by 2030 to keep global warming below a U.N. maximum of 2 degrees Celsius (3.6 Fahrenheit) above pre-industrial levels, it said.
"We've identified some of the most promising opportunities," Felipe Calderon, a former Mexican president who chairs the Global Commission on the Economy and Climate, told Reuters of the 10 goals.
"The most profitable ... is energy efficiency," he said of the report, drawn up by former heads of government, business leaders, economists and other experts.
Advertisement
It urged the Group of 20 major economies to set high global energy efficiency standards in sectors such as lighting, vehicles and buildings, estimating that curbs on energy waste could boost world economic output by up to $US18 trillion by 2035.
Investments by cities in cleaner public transport, building insulation and better management of waste could cut greenhouse gas emissions and air pollution and bring savings worth $US16.6 trillion ($22 trillion) by 2050, the report said.
Last year, the Commission said action to combat climate change, mainly shifting from fossil fuels to renewable energies such as solar and wind power, could lift economic growth rather than depress it as many governments fear.
Weighing the costs
Apart from energy efficiency and cities, Tuesday's report recommended greater focus on forestry, $US1 trillion a year in clean energy investment, carbon pricing, infrastructure, low-carbon innovation, business and investor action, limits on aviation and shipping emissions and curbs on hydrofluorocarbons, which are potent greenhouse gases.
The report did not estimate dollar benefits for each sector, some of which overlap. Benefits hinge on assumptions about the cost of damage from greenhouse gases, which are now emitted without penalty in many nations.
Last year's report estimated, for instance, that air pollution, largely from burning coal or oil, was equivalent to a 4.4 per cent brake on annual world gross domestic product. Such pollution causes 3.7 million premature deaths a year, it said.
Tuesday's report urged governments to step up action before a U.N. summit in Paris in December that will try to agree a global deal to limit emissions, blamed by almost all experts for causing more heat waves, downpours and rising seas.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:07:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain pays tribute to 7/7 victims 10 years after London bombings</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/britain-pays-tribute-to-77-victims-10-years-after-london-bombings-20150707-gi7a46.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Britain pays tribute to 7/7 victims 10 years after London bombings
Date
'We will never be cowed by terrorism': a wreath laid by British Prime Minister David Cameron on the memorial in Hyde Park.
Photo: Pool
Prime Minister David Cameron led sombre tributes on Tuesday as Britain commemorated the 10th anniversary of attacks that killed 56 people in London, the first suicide bombings by Islamist militants in western Europe.
Relatives of the victims, survivors, and senior politicians gathered to remember those killed in the July 7 2005 bombings with emotions still raw after a massacre in Tunisia last month, Britain's worst loss of life in a militant assault since London.
"Today the country comes together to remember the victims of one of the deadliest terrorist atrocities on mainland Britain," Mr Cameron said in a statement.
British Prime Minister David Cameron and London Mayor Boris Johnson lay wreaths during a ceremony at the memorial to the victims of the July 7, 2005 London bombings in Hyde Park.
Photo: Getty
"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly - the murder of 30 innocent Britons whilst holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact. But we will never be cowed by terrorism."
Advertisement
In the early hours of July 7 a decade ago, four young British Muslims travelled down to London where they detonated homemade bombs hidden in rucksacks on three underground trains and a bus during the morning rush-hour.
Inspired by al Qaeda, they killed themselves and 52 other people and wounded around 700 others. Citizens from Poland, Israel, Australia, France, Italy, Afghanistan, Nigeria, New Zealand and a Vietnamese-American were among the victims.
Mr Cameron and London mayor Boris Johnson stood silently, heads bowed, before laying a wreath at the 7/7 memorial in Hyde Park. They later joined other senior figures, victims' families, survivors and members of the emergency services caught up in the bombings for a service of remembrance at St Paul's Cathedral.
It included a national minute of silence, which camejust four days after Britain paid a similar tribute to those killed when an Islamist gunman opened fire at the Tunisian resort of Sousse.
A further service was due to be held later at the memorial site for survivors and relatives which Prince William, Queen Elizabeth's grandson, will attend.
Esther Hyman, 46, whose sister Miriam was killed on the Number 30 bus when it was blown up at Tavistock Square, told Reuters many young people seemed unaware of the bombings.
"The events of 7/7 do seem to have slipped out of public consciousness," said Ms Hyman, who with her mother last week launched an educational programme to help teach school pupils about the attacks and to steer them away from violent extremism.
"It's worth remembering an event like 7/7 and learning lessons from it so that it didn't happen in vain."
Britain is currently on its second highest alert level of "severe", meaning a militant attack is considered highly likely, mainly due to the danger the authorities say is posed by Islamic State (IS) fighters and Britons who have joined them.
Andrew Parker, head of Britain's domestic spy agency MI5, said only a "tiny fraction of the population" posed a threat.
"But the continuing fact that some people, born in the UK, with all the opportunities and freedoms that modern Britain offers, can nonetheless make those sorts of warped choices presents a serious societal and security challenge," Mr Parker said in a rare public statement.
The government plans new measures to counter extremism and Mark Rowley, Britain's most senior counter-terrorism police officer, said the country was better prepared than 10 years ago, although the threat itself had morphed.
He said IS was creating an "enormous" list of potential targets, focused on propaganda value.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:11:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Aust mull toss and XI for Ashes opener</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-sport/aust-mull-toss-and-xi-for-ashes-opener-20150707-3yx25.html</Link>
        <Description>Australian captain Michael Clarke says he'll consider bowling first in the first Test of the Ashes, unless the green seamer in Cardiff is pared back.</Description>
        <MainBody>Aust mull toss and XI for Ashes opener
World Cricket Breaking News Sport Sport
Date
The chat last week was England could play two tweakers in the Ashes opener, which starts on Wednesday in Cardiff.
Having inspected the pitch, Michael Clarke isn't sure Australia will play one.
Spin-friendly Sophia Gardens was considered a surprise choice for the first Test when the fixtures were announced last year.
The venue has certainly stunned the Australian camp, which had previously been spruiking Nathan Lyon's potential to unsettle England's many left-handed batsmen.
Advertisement
"It's got a lot of grass on it. It's surprising how much grass is on it," Clarke said of the strip that will decide who takes the early advantage in the five-Test series.
"The selectors - I think they'll contemplate playing four fast bowlers if the wicket stays like that.
"As much as I always love having a spinner in the team, you've got to pick the best XI for the conditions."
Clarke added he would have no hesitation in sending the opposition in on day one of an Ashes, a tactic that famously backfired in 2002 for Nasser Hussain at the Gabba.
"If the wicket's how it is today and you win the toss, you'd definitely bowl first. I think both teams would do that," he said.
The reality is the pitch is likely to look a lot different on Wednesday at 8pm (AEST), when Australia start their campaign to win a Test series in England for the first time since 2001.
However, rain and overcast conditions might limit what the curator can achieve before day one.
"It'll come down to what England are after - if they want grass cut off, I'm sure they'll cut it off," Clarke said.
"If they're worried about spin bowling, they'll leave more grass on it.
"I don't really care, to be honest.
"If we can adapt and play our best cricket, I'm confident of success."
For all the recent conjecture about Australia's XI for the first Test, it looks to be fairly settled.
Selectors are expected to bank on Shane Watson's experience and control with the ball ahead of younger allrounder Mitch Marsh's power batting and bowling ability.
Chris Rogers is set to return from concussion and open alongside David Warner, replacing Shaun Marsh in the team.
Lyon is likely to play, although Peter Siddle is adding to the case for a four-prong pace attack.
"Sidds was unplayable in the nets ... and he was probably the pick of the bowlers in the last tour game," Clarke said.
England captain Alastair Cook didn't comment on his side's spin selection showdown between Moeen Ali and Adil Rashid, but agreed Cardiff could potentially be a paceman's paradise.
"The grass on English wickets can keep the pace and bounce in it more than you see abroad," Cook said.
Both Clarke and Cook downplayed the importance of past series and weren't ready to look further ahead than this week.
"Beating teams in their own backyard is always the toughest part of our game and I'm sure this series will be no different," Clarke said of Australia's 14-year wait for Ashes success in England.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:05:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cook challenges Johnson to fire again</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-sport/cook-challenges-johnson-to-fire-again-20150707-3yx1y.html</Link>
        <Description>Alastair Cook says Mitchell Johnson had the Ashes 'series of a lifetime' but the challenge will be to repeat his form in English conditions.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cook challenges Johnson to fire again
World Breaking News Sport Sport Cricket
Date
England captain Alastair Cook put forward three reasons his Ashes side would be a different beast to the one tamed so easily in 2013-14.
One, it's on the other side of the world.
Two, England's XI has changed significantly since then.
Three, Mitchell Johnson's 37 wickets in that series represented a freakish once-in-a-lifetime performance.
Advertisement
The Australian camp will care little and can do nothing about the first two, but Johnson will be out to prove Cook wrong on Wednesday when the Ashes series begins in Cardiff.
When asked about the prospect of Johnson reprising his role as the intimidator, Cook noted the left-armer's challenge was to back it up.
And the opener hinted that might not be possible, likening it to the staggering 766 Test runs the English skipper scored in England's successful tour of Australia in 2010-11.
"Mitchell had the series of a lifetime, pretty similar to what happened in 2010-11 with my form," Cook said.
"You get on a bit of a roll and you can't do no wrong.
"Credit when it's due, he bowled very well and bowled quickly.
"Whether he can repeat that, that's the challenge and we've got to make sure we cope with it better if he does."
Cook also echoed the thoughts of Stuart Broad, who suggested last week that local conditions should leave England better equipped to face Johnson.
"Obviously, the pace and bounce in these wickets aren't as much (as Australia)," he said.
Without naming names, Cook noted there were a few English veterans in the most-recent Ashes that were "kind of hanging on".
Whereas now, most players are at the early stage of their cricket careers - or, in the case of Adil Rashid, yet to play a Test.
"They've got the chance to create their own history," he said.
"That side at the end of 2013-14 was right at the end of its life cycle, I suppose."
Cook added "a lot has happened" since the 2013-14 Ashes.
"It wasn't the last game we played," he said.
"It's a different set-up and ... we know how hard it is when you travel abroad to play."
Cook described Trevor Bayliss as a no-nonsense operator, adding the division of labour between coach and captain had largely stayed the same.
"The captain does get a big say," he said.
"It hasn't changed too much."
The series starts at 8pm (AEST).
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:53:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi forces fighting to regain IS-held city of Fallujah</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/iraqi-forces-fighting-to-regain-isheld-city-of-fallujah-20150707-gi6qh8.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Iraqi forces fighting to regain IS-held city of Fallujah
Date
Shiite paramilitaries launch a rocket north of Fallujah in Iraq.
Photo: Reuters
Cairo: Iraqi armed forces and allied militia were fighting to reach the gates of Fallujah on Monday, in the first major attempt to recapture a city in the largely Sunni province of Anbar since most of it fell to Islamic State militants last year.
The government of Iraqi Prime Minister Haider al-Abadi is trying to reverse gains by IS after it seized the state capital, Ramadi, in May.
Despite Baghdad's promises that its armed forces would recapture Ramadi swiftly, Shiite militia that are far more numerous and powerful than the government forces they operate alongside have said that an attack on Fallujah, a long-established seat of militancy, was the priority.
A photo provided by a website of the Islamic State group, shows a wounded man being treated by doctors in Raqqa, after US-led coalition air strikes.
Photo: Supplied
Fallujah lies between Ramadi and Baghdad, and the new offensive is aimed at protecting the capital and cutting IS supply lines.
Advertisement
The push came as IS fighters stormed a Syrian town held by Kurdish-led forces near Raqqa city on Monday, part of a wider offensive by the militants two days after their de facto capital was hit by some of the heaviest US-led air strikes in the conflict.
The Kurdish YPG militia said it was fighting to expel IS fighters who had attacked the town of Ain Issa, which was only captured from them two weeks ago with aerial support from the US.
Iraqi security forces search for survivors after a bombing authorities said was accidental in the eastern neighbourhood of New Baghdad.
Photo: AP
US Defence Secretary Ash Carter said strikes around Raqqa over the weekend were aimed at disrupting the ability of IS forces to respond to advances on the ground by Syrian Kurdish forces.
On a visit to the Pentagon, US President Barack Obama again ruled out more US troops in the region and warned that military force alone will not "degrade" and "destroy" IS. "Ideologies are not defeated with guns," he said. "They're defeated by better ideas, more attractive and more compelling vision."
Republican senator John McCain, a persistent critic of the administration's strategy in Syria and Iraq, said Mr Obama's comments "reveal the disturbing degree of self-delusion that characterises the administration's campaign".
An Iraqi man grieves after losing several members of his family in the New Baghdad bombing.
Photo: AP
Pro-Iraqi government forces were said to be within a few kilometres of the entrance to Fallujah, approaching from the north and their main base in Habbaniyah, on the road to Ramadi.
Ground forces are being supported by a US-led coalition which has been carrying out air strikes for nearly a year against IS in its self-declared caliphate across parts of Iraq and Syria.
Fallujah, a Sunni-majority city which staged some of the fiercest resistance to US-led troops in 2003 and was the scene of fierce battles again in 2004, will prove a stern test for the uneasy coalition of forces edging towards it.
A man carries an injured child away from the scener of the New Baghdad bombing.
Photo: Reuters
The Iraqi government has already been accused of failing to prevent civilian casualties in the run-up to the offensive. One of Fallujah's most senior health officials, Ahmad Shami, said last week that the government's air strikes had seemed "random".
On Sunday, an air strike reportedly hit a football pitch where IS players had joined local residents in a match, killing at least 50 people.
Yesterday, an Iraqi warplane accidentally bombed a civilian neighbourhood in eastern Baghdad, killing at least eight people and wounding 17, officials said, blaming a "technical problem".
US Defence Secretary Ash Carter and his French counterpart Jean-Yves Le Drian at the Pentagon.
Photo: AP
As anti-IS forces pushed forwards, the jihadists set off a wave of bombs, one of them rigged to a bulldozer, in the town of Haditha, west of Ramadi, killing seven Iraqi soldiers, apparently as a distraction tactic. Haditha and its nearby dam lie in one of the few parts of Anbar that remained under government control after Ramadi's capitulation.
Analysts say local support for the Fallujah offensive will be crucial to any lasting peace. Ahmed Ali, a senior fellow at the Washington-based Education for Peace in Iraq Centre, said there were signs this lesson has been heeded. "The slow and patient approach these forces are pursuing in Anbar is a sign that they want to build local support," he said.
However, Fallujah has long been a centre of Sunni resistance to Baghdad, and the battle by the Americans to take it in 2004 was one of the bloodiest episodes of the post-invasion occupation of Iraq.
Telegraph, London, Reuters, TNS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:43:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama shows a looser side on Twitter</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-world/obama-shows-a-looser-side-on-twitter-20150707-3yx06.html</Link>
        <Description>US President Barack Obama is taking to Twitter to muse about sports, pop culture, even Supreme Court rulings - at all hours of the day.</Description>
        <MainBody>Obama shows a looser side on Twitter
World Breaking News World
Print
Forget the prime-time interviews or the formal, choreographed news conferences.
US President Barack Obama is taking to Twitter to muse about sports, pop culture, even Supreme Court rulings - at all hours of the day.
The White House has used Twitter to promote the president's views for years, but mostly in a highly scripted manner, with tweets composed by press aides and released at strategic times.
Only occasionally would Obama post to Twitter himself, identifying a bona fide presidential tweet by appending his initials.
Advertisement
Now Obama is composing his own tweets almost daily, weighing in on issues of the day from any location, without the filter of his press office.
He's been tweeting with increased frequency since inaugurating his personal twitter account, (at)POTUS, earlier this summer.
"Hello, Twitter! It's Barack. Really!" Obama wrote in May.
"Six years in, they're finally giving me my own account."
So how, exactly, does a president tweet?
Obama, who has been known to use an iPad and a Blackberry, can send tweets from a variety of secure devices, according to the White House.
Obama gives his team a heads up before he tweets, and his staff says he sometimes agrees to tweet about topics his aides suggests.
In the six weeks since Obama kicked off the account, he's already amassed more than three million followers.
He follows only 66 Twitter users - mostly sports teams, federal agencies and top government officials.
He briefly set a record for the attracting a million followers faster than any other Twitter user.
But Obama's record was quickly broken by Caitlyn Jenner.
Josh Earnest, the White House press secretary, says Obama was enthusiastic about having the chance to use venues like Twitter to communicate with people.
"He's really taken to the idea," Earnest said.
A LOOK AT SOME OF OBAMA'S RECENT TWEETS:
GAY MARRIAGE
Obama's first reaction to the Supreme Court's historic ruling legalising gay marriage nationwide came not in a press release or a Rose Garden appearance, but through his Twitter account.
"Today is a big step in our march toward equality," Obama tweeted on June 26.
"Gay and lesbian couples now have the right to marry, just like anyone else."
HOLY GUACAMOLE
When an enthusiastic debate broke out on Twitter this month about including peas in guacamole, Obama took to Twitter to say he had no appetite for the added ingredient.
He responded to the pea-laden recipe in The New York Times during a "Twitter town hall" - a medium the White House has been trying out in which the president takes questions from Americans directly on Twitter.
"Respect the NYT, but not buying peas in guac," the president wrote, offering his personal recipe: "Onions, garlic, hot peppers. Classic."
BRING IN THE BAND
After Obama tweeted that he'd spent his morning listening to the new album from The Black Keys, the rock band tweeted back asking if they could use Air Force One for their upcoming gigs.
A few hours later - at 8pm on a weeknight - Obama tweeted his response to the band: "It's not mine; just a loaner. Maybe you can come play at the White House sometime instead?"
No word on whether the group will be rocking out at 1600 Pennsylvania Ave.
NO. 1 FAN
Obama congratulated the American team and midfielder Carli Lloyd for their victory on Sunday night in the Women's World Cup.
"What a win for Team USA!" Obama wrote, adding: "Your country is so proud of all of you. Come visit the White House with the World Cup soon."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:43:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>El Nino tracks path of most intense event as bureau expects further strengthening</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/environment/weather/el-nino-tracks-path-of-most-intense-event-as-bureau-expects-further-strengthening-20150707-gi6yfx.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>El Nino tracks path of most intense event as bureau expects further strengthening
Date
The El Nino remains on course to be particularly strong this year.
Photo: Timothy Connell
Cyclone Raquel gives El Nino a kick along
The El Nino climate pattern building in the Pacific is on track to be one of the strongest on record, with recent cyclones likely to intensify the event, the Bureau of Meteorology said.
Sea-surface temperatures in the central equatorial Pacific in June recorded the second largest anomalies on record for the month, behind only theJune 1997 reading during the super 1997-98 El Nino event, t he bureau said in its latest update .
Weekly sea-surface temperatures (see below) were also more than 1 degree above average for each of the regions monitored, their warmest sustained values since the 1997-98 event.
Advertisement
A string of tropical cyclones, including the rare July southern hemisphere storm, Cyclone Raquel, mean the El Nino will likely strengthen in coming weeks as "a strong reversal of trade winds" near the equator takes place.
"This is likely to increase temperatures below the surface of the tropical Pacific Ocean, which may in turn raise sea-surface temperatures further in the coming months," the bureau said.
Unlike the last few El Ninos, the eastern Pacific is particularly warm, much like the "canonical" events of 1982-83 and 1997-98, Lynette Bettio, a senior climatologist with the bureau said. Model projections also have the event lasting well into next autumn.
The Southern Oscillation Index, which measures the pressure difference between Darwin and Tahiti, had also dropped sharply in recent weeks, one gaugewatched closely by farmers worried about the rainfall outlook, she said.
El Ninos are characterised by central and eastern parts of the Pacific warming relative to those in the west. One result is that the normally easterly trade winds slow or reverse, with rainfall patterns tending to shift eastwards away from eastern Australia and south-east Asia.
Cool patch coming
While global temperatures tend to be boosted by El Ninos, the pattern does not mean all regions are warmer than usual for the event's duration.
Australia, for instance, is about to enter a relatively cool patch mostly as a series of powerful cold fronts from the south penetrate unusually far to the north.
The first of them should move across south-eastern Australia on Friday and Saturday, and "is going to be the coldest front of the year", Tristan Meyers, a meteorologist at Weatherzone , said. (See below for Sunday's synoptic chart.)
Temperatures will be noticeably cooler in Melbourne, with the maximum dropping from 15 degrees on Thursday to 11-13 from Saturday to Tuesday. In Sydney, relatively mild maximums of 19 degrees on Friday and Saturday will retreat to 15 degrees by Sunday.
"We're going to see some frost up in south-east Queensland," Mr Meyers said.
Towns such as Stanthorpe will likely have a top of just 8 degrees on Sunday and Monday, with overnight lows of minus-2 to zero, according to the bureau.
While the front as a while won't be bringing a lot of rain, the ski resorts should receive another 10 centimetres or so of snow to boost their thin natural cover, Mr Meyer said, adding that more fronts won't be far behind.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:17:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Singers appeal for money to save crisis-hit Italian opera houses</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/singers-appeal-for-money-to-save-crisishit-italian-opera-houses-20150707-gi6qa8.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Singers appeal for money to save crisis-hit Italian opera houses
Date
A man stands under a banner protesting cuts to Italy's national budget for culture outside Milan's La Scala opera house in 2010.
Photo: Reuters
Rome: A group of singers has set up an online fundraising campaign to save Italy's dilapidated opera houses, hundreds of which have been left to rot.
Many of the country's more than 800 theatres lie unused and neglected, victims of the economic crisis.
But in the town of Bevagna, Perugia, citizens have donated thousands of dollars to reopen the Francesco Torti theatre, which was built as a palazzo in the 12th century and converted into an opera house 600 years later.
In recent years, the only performers to appear underneath its frescoed ceilings depicting the dancing muses have been local schoolchildren.
Advertisement
But three operas will be staged thanks to an initiative by Susanna Ohtonen, a Finnish soprano who has lived and worked in Italy for 25 years, called Adopt a Theatre. It asked opera lovers for donations via its website.
"Nobody has any more money to keep these theatres up," said Ohtonen, who is working on the project with the music association Opera Extravaganza, a group made up of European opera professionals. "Or sometimes they are in good condition, but they are not being used as they should. There's no money any more to put on operas.
"What we're doing is bringing these theatres back to life. Not just the music, but the whole city, as opera and music is part of Italy's cultural heritage."
Some theatres have been sold off to private buyers, such as the 19th-century Teatro Comunale in Florence, which was sold last year for 23 million ($33.8 million). Other opera houses, such as the Teatro Petruzzelli in Bari, Italy's fourth-largest theatre, have been forced to cut entire seasons from their schedules.
Last year, the Federculture Association, which represents Italy's cultural associations, warned of "disturbing" cuts to funding after a report found that spending on Italy's cultural heritage dropped from 165 million in 2008 to 75 million in 2013. It is thought the country's opera houses have accumulated debts of 300 million.
The crowd-funding campaign in Bevagna, launched in May, raised 8000 to stage the three operas at the Torti theatre, which will also be broadcast live online.
Ms Ohtonen is keen to export the initiative to other small towns. "We had a lot of donations from local people who wanted to see their theatre come alive again," she said.
Luigi de Filippi, an Italian violinist and conductor working on the fundraising campaign, said a shortage of money had contributed to a lack of new ideas in Italian opera. "Various governments have not invested properly in culture," he said.
Telegraph, London
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:45:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kenyan leaders warn Obama on gay rights</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/kenyan-leaders-warn-obama-on-gay-rights-20150707-gi6q53.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Kenyan leaders warn Obama on gay rights
Date
Kenyan legislator Irungu Kang'ata Kiharu leads a march as they chant anti-gay slogans in Kenya's capital Nairobi.
Photo: Reuters
Johannesburg: US President Barack Obama has been warned by senior Kenyan politicians not to raise the issue of homosexuality when he visits his ancestral homeland later this month.
The country's deputy president and its parliamentary speaker told Mr Obama to avoid the subject, saying homosexuality was "un-Christian" and "dirty".
Mr Obama is, however, likely to disregard the advice, weeks after the US Supreme Court allowed same-sex marriage across the United States.
The White House illuminated in rainbow colours after the Supreme Court's ruling legalised gay marriage across the nation in June.
Photo: Reuters
On a previous visit to South Africa, Tanzania and Senegal, Mr Obama refused to shy away from the topic, despite many African countries being opposed to gay rights.
Advertisement
The visit to Kenya, where Mr Obama's father was born, is his first as president. He is expected to arrive on July 23 to attend a global entrepreneurial summit before flying on to Ethiopia, where he will address African leaders at the African Union's base in Addis Ababa.
Some Kenyans have discussed on Twitter what they want to come from Mr Obama's visit. Gay rights featured heavily. At the same time, 100 people marched through Nairobi under the banner "Protect the Family".
About 100 people attended the "Protect the Family" march ahead of Barack Obama's visit to the country where his father was born.
Photo: Reuters
During a church service on Sunday, Kenyan Deputy President William Ruto promised to defend the country against any "dirty" ideas. "Homosexuality is against the plan of God," he said.
Telegraph, London
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:15:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek debt crisis: Europe splitting at seams ahead of crucial meeting</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/greek-debt-crisis-europe-splitting-at-seams-ahead-of-crucial-meeting-20150707-gi71mw.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Greek debt crisis: Europe splitting at seams ahead of crucial meeting
Date
Euclid Tsakalotos, Greece's new finance minister has a new proposal to put to lenders.
Photo: Bloomberg
Athens
Europe is splitting at the seams over the Greek crisis, with growing evidence of a rift over Tuesday night's crucial meeting in Brussels on a new bailout deal.
The near-bankrupt country needs a financial lifeline within days, amid reports that its banks will stay shut until at least Thursday  and are likely to run out of cash altogether by the end of the week.
One Greek minister said there was only 48 hours before his country could be forced to leave the euro.
Advertisement
Greece's prime minister and its new finance minister Euclid Tsakalotos flew to Brussels with a new proposal to put to lenders, and the heads of the Eurozone countries.
According to local reports, the new proposal is based on the most recent deal offered by the European Commission  including tax rises.
On Sunday Greece voted to reject Europe's previous austerity-themed rescue package for the near-bankrupt country.
Mr Tsipras intends to use that mandate to argue for a more gradual implementation of some measures, to soften the blow on the Greek people, Kathimerini reported.
French president Francois Hollande met German Chancellor Angela Merkel in Paris on Monday evening, and said the "door was open" for new negotiations over Greece's debts.
"It is now up to the government of Alexis Tsipras to make serious, credible proposals so that this willingness to stay in the Eurozone can translate into a lasting programme," Mr Hollande said.
"Time is running out and there is urgency for Greece and the Eurozone."
Ms Merkel said they were waiting for "very precise proposals" from the Greek prime minister, and "a programme that will allow Greece to return to prosperity."
Spain's finance minister, Luis de Guindos, said he was "absolutely not contemplating" that Greece could leave the euro, and he was open to negotiating a third rescue package which was "absolutely necessary".
But there were also plenty of voices in northern Europe saying a more generous deal for Greece was not on the table.
Netherlands' prime minister Mark Rutte, said Greece would have to accept deep reforms if it wants to remain in the Eurozone.Mr Rutte said Greece should not get any rescue deal without committing to reform.
"If things stay the way they are, then we're at an impasse," he said.
German MP Klaus-Peter Willsch, from Merkel's own CDU party, wrote in the London Telegraph that "the only thing which can help Greece is a (perhaps temporary) exit from the Eurozone".
"Greece's exit should come first, before assistance is provided by its European partners," he said.
"Greece would endure a few years of hardship but then people would be able to see light at the end of the tunnel."
Monday began with the surprise resignation of finance minister Yanis Varoufakis, the confrontational economics professor who proved a necessary sacrifice in bringing Europe and Greece's creditors back to the negotiating table.
He literally jumped on his motorbike and drove out of Athens, leaving his colleagues locked in talks with other Greek political parties about tactics ahead of Tuesday's emergency Euro summit in Brussels.
Mr Varoufakis has been replaced by Oxford-educated economist Euclid Tsakalotos, who said he was "nervous and anxious" about the challenge he faced in finding a viable solution for Greece.
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras met with his political allies and opponents for almost five hours on Monday, emerging with a joint statement signed by almost the entire political spectrum backing his efforts to seek a new deal from the country's creditors.
Large parts of Greece's economy have been paralysed by the capital controls imposed at the start of last week to prevent the collapse of the banks.
Businesses must make special applications to buy goods  such as food, petrol and medicine  from abroad. Many small businesses now demand payment in cash, which is hard in a country where the banks are closed.
Many ATMs are empty and the rest only dispense 60 euros a day per person  in theory, though since they are running short of 20 euro notes, most will now only dispense 50 euros.
Some bank branches opened on Tuesday morning, to pay pensioners without an ATM card.
Public and private businesses said import restrictions were starting to hit  for example newspaper publishers said they only had enough paper left to print until Sunday.
The government is also running out of money to pay public service wages and pensions, and supply hospitals and other public bodies. To reduce financial hardship for citizens it decided to go easy on revenue-raising: in Athens the public transport is free until further notice, and tax collection has "almost dried up" according to one report.
The Kathimerini newspaper reported that banks were estimating they will only remain liquid until Thursday.
Late on Monday the European Central Bank announced it would not provide extra liquidity to Greek banks. Instead, it passed a resolution making it harder for Greek banks to access emergency funds, making their collapse more likely, more quickly.
Greece's economy minister Giorgos Stathakis told the BBC that without extra help from the ECB, the banks could survive until Friday under current withdrawal and transfer restrictions.
He said the country was 48 hours away from deciding whether to leave the Eurozone, if there was no financial lifeline.
Financial markets and analysts  many of whom wrongly predicted a 'Yes' vote in the referendum  were pessimistic on the chances of Greece making a deal and preventing an exit from the Eurozone.
Ratings agency Fitch warned that "time is short and the risk of policy missteps, or that the two sides simply cannot agree a deal, is high".
Greece has already missed a billion-euro interest payment to the IMF, and faces a new deadline of July 20 when it is supposed to repay 3.5 billion euros to the European Central Bank.
But the IMF chose to send a ray of hope, with managing director Christine Lagarde saying it would "stand ready to assist Greece if requested to do so".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:19:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Historic flyby of Pluto on track despite probe glitch, NASA says</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/historic-flyby-of-pluto-on-track-despite-probe-glitch-nasa-says-20150707-gi6ppn.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Historic flyby of Pluto on track despite probe glitch, NASA says
Date
This combination of images from July 1 to July 3 provided by NASA shows Pluto at different distances from the New Horizons spacecraft.
Photo: NASA
Cape Canaveral, Florida: NASA said on Monday it expects the New Horizons spacecraft to be back in service on Tuesday after a computer glitch on the weekend threatened its upcoming historic flyby of Pluto.
Nearing the end of a 9-year journey to the solar system's unexplored outer reaches, New Horizons shut down radio communications with Earth for a nail-biting 81 minutes on Saturday.
The cause of the problem was a timing flaw in the final batch of software uploaded to the spacecraft, NASA said. The mission will provide the first up-close observations of Pluto when it passes within 12,550 kilometres of the icy planet on July 14.
"Now - with Pluto in our sights - we're on the verge of returning to normal operations," NASA's planetary science director Jim Green said.
Advertisement
Diagnosis and recovery efforts have been complicated by the nine-hour round-trip lag time to communicate with the spacecraft, which is nearly 4.8 billion kilometres from Earth.
New Horizons spent most of its long journey to Pluto in hibernation. It was revived in January to begin collecting navigation and science data.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:12:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thai paralysed after collision with Aussie</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-world/thai-paralysed-after-collision-with-aussie-20150707-3ywp7.html</Link>
        <Description>A member of the Australian embassy in Thailand has allegedly offered $400 to the family of a man paralysed in a collision with his superbike.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thai paralysed after collision with Aussie
World Breaking News World
Print
A member of the defence section at the Australian embassy in Thailand who allegedly crashed his motorbike into a Thai man and left him permanently paralysed has offered just $400 in compensation, according to the injured man's family.
In the June 14 accident, an Australian warrant officer riding an unregistered superbike collided with 62-year-old Suchart Rotkaew, according to an official police report into the incident.
The police report, seen by AAP, said the collision occurred in central Bangkok when the superbike struck Mr Suchart's bicycle.
Both parties were injured and unable to make statements. They were taken to hospital, the police report says.
Advertisement
The warrant officer cited the Australian embassy in Bangkok as his address.
Mr Suchart's son, Veerachon Rotkaew, told AAP his father would never be able to work again.
"The doctor said he had a brain haemorrhage," and had surgery to the left side of his brain.
"(His left) body, hands, feet, he can't move at all. He can only move on his right side of the body," Mr Veerachon said.
Mr Suchart worked as a security guard and owned a small garage.
Mr Veerachon said there had been little contact with the warrant officer since the accident.
"Fees for helping, the travelling expenses, they gave us 10,000 baht ($A400) for that," he said.
The family will have to rely on Thai social security to care for Mr Suchart. They had hoped funds would be available from insurance payments, but the Thai police report says the Australian's bike was unregistered, leaving in doubt any insurance claims.
A longstanding restriction on Australian military personnel in Thailand riding motorcycles was recently lifted despite Thailand's high record of motorbike accidents.
A Defence Department spokesperson said in an email Australian Defence Force members working at overseas posts must adhere to the local road rules.
"Defence generally does not place limitations on personnel operating any type of motor vehicle overseas, provided they meet host-nation licensing and other regulatory requirements for the vehicle they are operating," the spokesperson said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
