<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="SMH">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Mon Aug 17 17:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant find 'hot spots' warming faster</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/environment/climate-change/university-of-nsw-climate-researchers-steven-sherwood-and-nidhi-nishant-find-hot-spots-warming-faster-20150618-ghhlxd.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant find 'hot spots' warming faster
Date
Climate researcher Steven Sherwood has found data issues are to blame for not detecting hot spots.
Photo: James Brickwood
This article is part ofClimate for Change,aFairfax Media series on global warming. Full coverage can be found here .Follow our coverage on Facebook .
It's the hole in the science that global warming sceptics have long exploited  the apparent lack of "hot spots" high in the atmosphere over the tropics that should be there if climate models were accurate.
We found the global warming signal is stronger than we thought it would be.
Climate researcher Steven Sherwood
After years of debate, University of NSW climate researchers Steven Sherwood and Nidhi Nishant have resolved data issues that not only reveal those "hot spots" to be there  but they are in fact warming some 10 per cent faster than modelling has predicted.
"[We found] the global warming signal is stronger than we thought it would be," Professor Sherwood said.
Advertisement
For Professor Sherwood, it's just another example  along with the "global warming hiatus" that has been deemed this month by US scientists to be a data error  of how so-called climate sceptics can divert or distort debate.
"The models predict that if, and only if, man is the cause of warming, the tropical upper air, six miles above the ground, should warm up to thrice as fast as the surface, but this tropical uppertroposphere "hotspot" has not been observed in 50 years of measurement," Christopher Monckton, a prominent Britishsceptic, wrote in 2010.
That the upper troposphere hadn't warmed compared with the surface would be a major surprise for science, Professor Sherwood said.
Surfacetemperatures have been rising at about 0.15 degrees per decade. As air rises over the tropics, a lot of water vapour condenses, releasing latent heat, that warms up the air.
"It would have been truly astonishing if the temperatures in the upper troposphere hadn't been going up faster than at the surface," Professor Sherwood said.
"If it didn't appear, it would have nothing to do with whether humans are causing climate change, but it would mean there is something about the way air mixes in the atmosphere that we didn't know," he said. "And the ramifications for climate change could go either way."
Professor Sherwood's paper found data issues were to blame for not detecting the hot spot that really was there.
One source of the bad data was the result of weather balloons becoming more accurate by making the monitors less susceptible to warming by the sun.
"Over time, it has happened less, so it has made the temperatures appear not to rise when they really did rise," he said.
Professor Sherwood said he hadn't bothered to follow how sceptics had responded to his paper, saying that scientist had merely identified a problem and worked to resolve it.
He is more critical, though, of the role played by the sceptics in proclaiming an apparent slowdown in surface temperature warming over the past decade or so.
Even this so-called hiatus is now being viewedby the US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as largely the result of instrument misreadings.
"A lot of scientific effort went into the hiatus although none of us believed it was very significant just because the sceptics were making so much hay out of it," he said "It's an example of where the sceptics are succeeding to some extent in distracting scientists away from perhaps more important work that they could be doing."
Sceptics' interest in "hot spots" they believed weren't there and the fact they couldn'taccount for the additional heat being trapped by the Earth from its increased greenhouse gases, pointedto a contrast in approaches, he said.
"They're not aiming for a self-consistent and reasonably comprehensive description of the world. What they are aiming at is to discredit something," he said.
Resolving issues such as the hot spot removedone more data dispute for sceptics to pick over, he said, adding,"the inconsistencies don't go on forever".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:22:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Decapitation suspect 'confessed' to French attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/decapitation-suspect-confessed-to-french-attack-20150628-gi01yy.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Decapitation suspect 'confessed' to French attack
Date
French President Francois Hollande said the "terrorist" attack was designed to blow up the whole building.
Photo: LOIC VENANCE
Paris: The man suspected of decapitating his boss in an attack on a gas factory in France has confessed to the grisly crime, sources say.
Yassin Salhi, 35, "has also given details about the circumstances" surrounding the killing, according to identities close to the investigation, who said he would be transferred to Paris for further questioning later on Sunday by anti-terrorist police.
Mr Salhi's confession came after it emerged the married father of three sent a gruesome selfie photo including the severed head to a WhatsApp number in Canada.
Herve Cornara's severed head was found lashed to the gates of the factory near two flags.
Photo: AFP
Investigators have warned, however, that it could be a relay number and the intended recipient could be anywhere in the world.
Advertisement
After several hours of silence, MrSalhi has begun to open up to investigators about the assault, which came six months after 17 people were killed in Islamist attacks in Paris that began with the Charlie Hebdo massacre.
On Friday morning, Mr Salhi rammed his van into the US-owned Air Products factory near France's second city of Lyon in what President Francois Hollande said was a "terrorist" attack designed to blow up the whole building.
He was overpowered by a firefighter as he was trying to prise open a bottle of acetone in an apparent suicidal bid to destroy the factory.
Police then made the grisly discovery of the severed head of Mr Salhi's boss, 54-year-old Herve Cornara, lashed to the gates of the factory near two flags on which were written the Muslim profession of faith.
Prime Minister Manuel Valls repeated that the world was engaged in a "war against terrorism".
"We cannot lose this war because it's fundamentally a war of civilisation," Mr Valls told the iTELE rolling news channel."It's our society, our civilisation that we are defending."
France was facing "a major terrorist threat" that needed to be fought "over the long term", warned the Prime Minister.
It was not a question of whether there would be another attack, but "when" and "where", stressed Mr Valls.
Friday's attack came on a day of bloodshed on three continents in which38 people were mown down on a Tunisian beach and 26 killed in a suicide attack in Kuwait.
The Islamic State extremist group has claimed responsibility for those two attacks, but no group has said it carried out the French operation.
Sources close to the investigation said Mr Salhi was radicalised more than a decade ago after contact with Muslim convert Frederic Jean Salvi,known as "Ali",who is suspected of preparing attacks in Indonesia with al-Qaeda militants.
An autopsy on Mr Salhi's victim has proved inconclusive, with experts unable to determine whether he was killed before being beheaded or decapitated alive.
The French investigation is focusing on Syria, where hundreds of people from France have gone to wage jihad, officials say.
Anti-terrorist authorities have identified 473 people who have left France to fight in Iraq or Syria.
Mr Valls said 1800 people in France were "linked" in some way to the jihadist cause.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said on Friday that MrSalhi had been investigated for links to radical Salafists in Lyon, but was not known to have taken partin terrorist activities and did not have a criminal record.
AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:32:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Armed police swarm streets of Tunisia; Britain warns of further attacks</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/armed-police-swarm-streets-of-tunisia-britain-warns-of-further-attacks-20150628-gi017t.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Armed police swarm streets of Tunisia; Britain warns of further attacks
Date
Soldiers stand guard near the Imperial Marhaba Hotel where 39 people were killed on Friday.
Photo: Getty Images
Hundreds of armed police patrolled the streets of Tunisia's beach resorts on Sunday and the government said it will deploy hundreds more inside hotels after the Islamist militant attack in Sousse that killed 39 foreigners, mostly Britons.
Thousands of tourists have left Tunisia since Friday's attack, which has shocked the North African country that relies heavily on tourism for jobs and foreign currency revenues.
Britain's Foreign Office warned late on Saturday that Islamist militants may launch further attacks on tourist resorts after a gunman opened fire on the Imperial Marhaba resort, in the worst assault of its kind in modern Tunisian history.
At least 15 Britons were among the dead and wounded along with German, Irish and Belgian nationals in Sousse, a popular resort town. It was the most significant attack on Britons since the attack on the London transport system in 2005.
Advertisement
"We are going to deploy 1000 armed police to protect hotels and tourists," Tunisian Interior Minister Najem Gharsalli told reporters late on Saturday night.
Since its 2011 uprising to oust autocrat Zine El-Abidine Ben Ali, Tunisia has been praised for its peaceful transition to democracy with a new constitution and free elections seen as a model for the region.
But its young democracy has also been tested by the rise of hardline Islamist movements, some of which have turned to violence. The army has been fighting a campaign against pockets of Islamist militants near the Algerian border.
Islamic State has claimed the Sousse attack. But officials say the gunman, named as Saif Rezgui, was not any watchlist of known potential militants. One source said he appeared to have been radicalised over the last six months by recruiters.
It was the second major attack in Tunisia this year, following an Islamist militant assault on the Bardo Museum in Tunis in March when gunmen killed a group of foreign visitors as they arrived by bus.
The tourism minister has described the Sousse attack as a catastrophe for the industry, which accounts for about 7per cent of the country's gross domestic product.
More than 3000 tourists had already left the country a day after the attack.
"Tunisia is a beautiful country, and we will come back, but right now we need to leave, we need to forget what happened," said Lucy, a young British tourist leaving from a local airport near Sousse. "It's clear it is not safe here at the moment."
Islamist jihadists have attacked North African tourist sites before, seeing them as legitimate targets because of their open Western lifestyles and tolerance of alcohol. Tunisia is one of the most secular countries in the Arab world.
Prime Minister Habib Essid said his government plans within a week to close down 80 mosques that remain outside state control, for inciting violence, and crack down on financing for certain associations, in order to counter jihadi rectruiters.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:52:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Smith at first drop helps England: Broad</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-sport/smith-at-first-drop-helps-england-broad-20150628-3yhu7.html</Link>
        <Description>Paceman Stuart Broad says Steve Smith's promotion to first drop will help England's bid to reclaim the Ashes.</Description>
        <MainBody>Smith at first drop helps England: Broad
World Sport Cricket Breaking News Sport
Date
It wasn't quite as forthright as Graeme Swann's declaration, but the message was largely the same.
England are licking their lips at the prospect of testing out Steve Smith's technique at first drop.
So says Stuart Broad, the 29-year-old who delivered an inspired spell of swing bowling to seal the hosts' Ashes win in 2013.
Broad insisted Smith's recent promotion to No.3 was a major boost to England's bid to reclaim the urn, adding further spice to the series opener that starts in Cardiff on July 8.
Advertisement
"It's an advantage for us with him coming in at No.3 with the Dukes ball in England," Broad said.
"If he comes in at five like Joe Root does for us, there's not many weaknesses there.
"But with the ball moving around in England, we know how hard it is to bat in that top three.
"I'm certainly not doubting the quality of him as a player ... but you have to have a very tight technique to bat in the top three against the Dukes ball in England."
Broad also pointed to Smith's output two years ago as cause for confidence against the 26-year-old, who occupies top spot on the International Cricket Council's Test batting rankings.
"He's not had amazing success in England. When he played in the 2013 series he got a hundred at the Oval on a flat wicket," he said.
Smith, speaking after posting a ton on day two of Australia's opening tour game against Kent, suggested he was a completely different player compared to 2013.
"I know my game a lot better now than I did then. I was fresh back in the side then, I have certainly got a lot more confidence in my game now," he said.
Broad was confident his side could stop Smith's incredible run of form, which has featured five tons in his past six Tests.
"I've got a few ideas to run past a few players that seem to think it might be a good option. I won't share them with you yet," he said.
Smith wasn't fazed.
"It is obviously going to be a challenge playing against the new ball, particularly in these conditions," he said.
"But I have enjoyed batting at No.3 so far and hopefully I can continue having some success there."
Former England offspinner Swann opined earlier this week that Smith "must have surprised himself, as well as everyone else, with his output".
"I still don't think he's got a great technique," Swann said.
"I don't think he'll score runs at three if it's swinging."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:45:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait says mosque suicide bomber was Saudi: state media</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/kuwait-says-mosque-suicide-bomber-was-saudi-state-media-20150628-ghzyzu.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Kuwait says mosque suicide bomber was Saudi: state media
Date
Please Log in to update your video settings
Video will begin in 5 seconds.
Please Log in to update your video settings
Kuwaitis bury dead from mosque bombing
RAW VISION: Security officials make arrests as mourners bury victims of a mosque bombing that killed 27 in Kuwait.
PT1M21S 620 349
Video settings
Kuwait has identified the suicide bomber who carried out the country's worst attack as a Saudi citizen, Kuwait state media reported on Sunday.
The interior ministry named the bomber as Fahd Suliman Abdul-Muhsen al-Qabaa and said he flew into Kuwait's airport at dawn on Friday, only hours before he detonated explosives at a Shiite Muslim mosque killing at least 27 people.
The owner of the car that was used by the bomber to drive to the Imam Sadiq Mosque in Kuwait City, where he detonated his device among the worshippers inside the mosque, has also been arrested.
Thousands of Sunnis and Shiites from across the country take part in a mass funeral procession on Saturday for 27 people killed in a suicide bombing at the Shiite Imam Sadiq Mosque.
Photo: AP
Another of the suspects is a 25-year-old from Kuwait's "bidoon" community, which is largely made up of descendants of desert nomads considered stateless by the government, police added. People from that community have long claimed the government is depriving them of citizenship and rights.
Advertisement
The bombing, claimed by an affiliate of the Islamic State group, also wounded more than 200 male worshippers who were taking part in midday Friday prayers, and was the first terrorist attack in Kuwait in more than two decades.
Thousands of Sunnis and Shiites from across the country took part in a mass funeral procession and prayer at Kuwait's Grand Mosque for the dead. Many carried the Kuwaiti flag; others a simple black flag to signify mourning. Some in the crowd chanted: "Sunnis and Shiites are brothers!"
Relatives of the victims of Friday bombing console each other at the Al Jafariya cemetery in Suleibikhat, Kuwait.
Photo: Reuters
Sunni groups in Kuwait and leaders from across the Middle East have strongly condemned the attack, which Gulf officials said was aimed at provoking a backlash from Shiites and sparking sectarian war. More than a third of Kuwait's 1.2 million citizens are believed to be Shiite. The majority of Kuwaitis are Sunni Muslims.
Kuwait's deputy prime minister Sheikh Mohammed Al-Hamad Al-Sabah described the bombing as "grotesque".
AP, Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:31:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deformed mutt named World's Ugliest Dog</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/deformed-mutt-named-worlds-ugliest-dog-20150628-ghzwii.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Deformed mutt named World's Ugliest Dog
Date
Quasi Modo, an eight-year-old mixed breed from Florida, walks across the stage during the World's Ugliest Dog Contest.
Photo: George Nikitin
A 10-year-old mutt named Quasi Modo, whose spinal birth defects have left him a bit hunchbacked, is the winner of the annual World's Ugliest Dog contest.
The pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix and his owner took the $US1,500 ($A1,938.99) prize on Friday night, besting 25 other dogs competing in the contest that applauds imperfection, organisers said.
Quasi Modo was abandoned at an animal shelter before being adopted by a veterinarian in Loxahatchee, Florida, according to his biography posted on the contest's website.
Click for more photos
World's Ugliest Dog Competition 2015
Some of the planet's weirdest looking creatures were on display at the 27th annual World's Ugliest Dog competition in Petaluma, California over the weekend.Photo: George Nikitin
"My appearance can be a little unsettling to some (I have had grown men jump on top of their cars to get away from me because they thought I was a hyena or Tasmanian devil) but once they get to know me I win them over with my bubbly personality," his biography said.
Advertisement
Two Chinese crested and Chihuahua mixes named Sweepee Rambo and Frodo took the second- and third-place prizes, respectively.
An eight-year-old Chihuahua named Precious received the "spirit award," honouring a dog and owner who have overcome obstacles and/or are providing service to the community.
Precious, who is blind in one eye, is trained to monitor smells related to low blood sugar levels and alert her owner, a disabled veteran, of the problem, her biography said.
The contest, held at the Sonoma-Marin Fairgrounds in Petaluma, California, is in its 27th year.
The dogs are scored by a three-judge panel in several categories, including special or unusual attributes, personality and natural ugliness.
AAP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 09:15:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Family man Hewitt savours Wimbledon finale</title>
        <Link>http://news.smh.com.au/breaking-news-sport/family-man-hewitt-savours-wimbledon-finale-20150628-3yhgv.html</Link>
        <Description>Family man and former world No.1 Lleyton Hewitt is savouring every moment of his Wimbledon swansong with wife Bec and three children Mia, Cruz and Ava.</Description>
        <MainBody>Family man Hewitt savours Wimbledon finale
Tennis Sport Breaking News Sport World
Date
Print
Whatever happens over the coming fortnight, Lleyton Hewitt knows he's already living the dream entering his 17th and final Wimbledon.
Few athletes get to bow out on their own terms - and even less get to perform on tennis's most hallowed lawns in front of their children.
But Hewitt will on Monday when he takes on Finland's Jarkko Nieminen almost certainly for a second-round centre-court shot at world No.1 and defending champion Novak Djokovic.
While the South Australian accepts he's unlikely to hoist the trophy with his two daughters watching from the stands, as Roger Federer did three years ago, Hewitt says it's more than enough having Mia, almost 10, six-year-old son Cruz and youngest daughter Ava, four, even on hand.
Advertisement
"I didn't think I'd be playing at 30, let alone 34 and having three kids," Hewitt said as he reflected on a remarkable journey that began with a Wimbledon doubles debut alongside a teenaged Federer way back in 1999.
"All of them, especially the two eldest - but Ava now - will be able to remember being here and me enjoying it with them. It's been great."
The former world No.1 says Mia "totally understands what's going on".
"That it's my last year and that I'm only playing a few big tournaments," he said.
"She's pretty switched on. It's great, it's fantastic."
It's impossible, though, for Hewitt not to savour the moment most with tennis-loving Cruz, whose been You-tubed hitting with Federer and following in his father's footsteps wherever he ventures at the All England Club.
"Walking around with him, having him part of it, I'm soaking it up more," Hewitt said.
"I've tried to enjoy that more than anything.
"He's been in the locker-room with me. They gave him a locker down there. He's got his own bag. I had to buy him a special Wimbledon bag.
"He's been getting everyone's autograph in his autograph book this week.
"It's just been little things like that."
An honorary life member by virtue of his championship success in 2002, Hewitt will undoubtedly be back with his son one day.
But he's not quite ready to say goodbye just yet.
"Obviously Novak's waiting in the second round. Assuming he was to get through, I'd love nothing more than to go out and have a crack at him," Hewitt said.
"But I'm certainly not looking past Nieminen.
"He's a tough competitor, really tough competitor. He always gives 100 per cent.
"It's going to be a tough match and, even though I've had the edge on him in head-to-head matches, we've had some battles in the past and I'm sure Monday will be no different."
Hewitt is unsure if he'll be nervous, but he suspects not overly so.
He's too focused for that.
"So far it hasn't felt that different yet. I'm that much of a competitor and everyone knows that I'm going to do absolutely anything I can to get over the line," he said.
"Once you've got your game face on - if I start thinking like that, I'm going to have issues. I won't play at my best."
LLEYTON HEWITT CAREER SNAPSHOT
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 09:04:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Protester removes Confederate flag from flagpole in South Carolina</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/protester-removes-confederate-flag-from-flagpole-in-south-carolina-20150628-ghzuus.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Protester removes Confederate flag from flagpole in South Carolina
Date
Pro-confederate flag demonstrators argue with anti-confederate flag protesters outside the South Carolina State House.
Photo: AFP
COLUMBIA: A protester has scaled a flagpole on the grounds of the South Carolina legislature at dawn and removed the Confederate flag.
The black woman climber was arrested on Saturday as soon as she came down the nine metre pole, and a new flag was restored to the original position with an hour.
Pictures on social media showed a woman, named as Bree Newsome, 30, being escorted by an officer, her hands behind her back. #FreeBree was trending on Twitter within hours.
Also arrested was a 30-year-old white man named as James Ian Tyson. Both are from neighbouring North Carolina and have been charged with defacing a monument.
Advertisement
Within hours of the incident, an online crowdfunding site had raised more than $US80,000 ($103,413) to pay for Newsome's bail and to help other activists "taking direct action in the movement for Black lives".
There has been a growing clamour for the flag - branded "a reminder of systemic oppression and racial subjugation" by President Barack Obama on Friday - to be removed from the grounds of the state house in Columbia.
Once flown by the rebel army of the slave-owning South, the confederate flag is seen by some as a symbol of regional heritage. But many more view it as an ugly reminder of racism's cruel legacy.
Impassioned debate about the flag was sparked by the mass shooting of nine black worshippers last week in Charleston, also in South Carolina.
The white alleged supremacist gunman, Dylann Roof, 21, later appeared in disturbing photos online with the flag.
Newsome, an activist whose full name is Brittany Ann Byuarim Newsome, said in a statement: "We removed the flag today because we can't wait any longer.
"We can't continue like this another day. It's time for a new chapter where we are sincere about dismantling white supremacy and building toward true racial justice and equality," added the statement, carried in the local The Post and Courier newspaper.
Her protest came ahead of a small demonstration by pro-Confederate flag supporters who chanted and waved the banner at the state house.
AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 09:42:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Over 500 injured in powder fire at dance party in Taiwan amusement Park</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/over-500-injured-in-powder-fire-at-dance-party-in-taiwan-amusement-park-20150628-ghztsl.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Over 500 injured in powder fire at dance party in Taiwan amusement Park
Date
Please Log in to update your video settings
Video will begin in 5 seconds.
Please Log in to update your video settings
Hundreds injured in Taiwan fire
Fire breaks out at Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200, many seriously burned.
PT0M40S 620 349
Video settings
Colored powder caught fire in a park in Taiwan's New Taipei city on Saturday, injuring at least 500 among thousands of young people at a themed party.
Burn victims lay on inflatable pool rings at the Formosa Fun Coast recreational park as they waited for stretchers, footage on cable network TVBS showed. Some 510 people were hospitalised, of whom 183 were in intensive care, the Ministry of Health &amp; Welfare said in a statement on Sunday.
Fire broke out about 8.30 pm local time as powder on the stage exploded, the ministry said in the statement. Amateur video captured by an attendee and broadcast on CTi TV showed coloured powder being sprayed from a stage catching fire and spreading into areas where revelers were standing.
People run as the fire engulfs the dance floor.
New Taipei City Mayor Eric Chu said at a news conference carried by cable TV networks that a thorough investigation into what caused the accident would be carried out. The police are investigating five people including the event's organiser and technicians, Central News Agency reported.
Advertisement
More than 10,000 young people had congregated at the venue for a color-themed party, according to TVBS.
Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 08:15:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Photos of CIA 'black sites' come to light</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/photos-of-cia-black-sites-come-to-light-20150628-ghzmzm.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Photos of CIA 'black sites' come to light
Date
Print
Smoke rises and debris falls from the World Trade Center south tower on September 11.
Washington: Military prosecutors earlier this year learned about a massive cache of CIA photographs of its former overseas "black sites" while reviewing material collected for the Senate investigation of the agency's interrogation program, according to USofficials.
The existence of the approximately 14,000 photographs will probably cause yet another delay in the military commissions at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, as attorneys for the defendants demand all of the images be turned over to them and the government wades through the material to decide what it thinks is relevant to the proceedings.
Defence attorneys said they have not yet been informed about the photographs and said it is unacceptable that they should come to light only now, more than three years after the arraignment of Khalid Sheik Mohammed and four other defendants accused of planing the September11 attacks.
Abu Zubaydah, a member of al-Qaeda, was captured in a daring raid in Pakistan.
The death penalty cases against the five men first began in 2008 under the Bush administration and were abandoned by the Obama administration for a planned trial in federal court in New York. That effort collapsed, and the prosecution was returned to the military in 2011.
Advertisement
Also on trial at Guantanamo is Abd al-Rahim al-Nashiri, a Saudi of Yemeni descent who also was held by the CIA. He could receive the death penalty for his alleged role in the 2000 bombing of the USS Cole in Yemen.
The electronic images depict external and internal shots of facilities where the CIA held al-Qaeda suspects after 9/11, but they do not show detainee interrogations, including the torture of some suspects who were subjected to waterboarding and other brutal techniques.
They do include images of naked detainees during transport, according to the officials, who spoke on the condition of anonymity because the material remains classified.
The pictures also show CIA personnel and members of foreign intelligence services, as well as psychologists Bruce Jessen and James Mitchell, among the architects of the interrogation program.
The report's declassified executive summary makes reference only to a picture of a wooden waterboard in Afghanistan and detainees being transported to black sites.
It's unclear whether the military prosecutors have been able to review all the photographs and why they hadn't unearthed them years earlier.
"It raises the question whether the agency is being cooperative with the prosecutors," said James Harrington, the civilian attorney for 9/11 defendant Ramzi Binalshibh. "It's beyond preposterous."
Among the images are those of cells and bathrooms at the detention sites, including a facility in Afghanistan known as "Salt Pit", where the waterboard was photographed.
A USofficial described the photographs of the Salt Pit as looking like a dungeon. The official added that many of the pictures appear to have been taken for budgetary reasons to document how money was being spent.
The bulk of the photographs depict black sites in Thailand, Afghanistan and Poland. There are fewer shots of prisons in Romania and Lithuania, which were among the last to be used before they were closed in 2006.
A USofficial said there are also photographs of confinement boxes where detainees such as Abu Zubaydah, who is now at Guantanamo, were forced into for hours.
Also among the photographs are images of Zubaydah shortly after he was captured in 2002; he was wounded in the leg during a shootout with Pakistani security forces. The pictures show his injury.
Later shots show him wearing an eye patch. A former CIA official said Zubaydah had a pre-existing eye injury that was infected when the agency captured him. The eye was later removed.
"Why is it we are still learning about this stuff?" said Joe Margulies, Zubaydah's attorney. "Who knows what is still out there? What else is there? That's what is appalling."
Washington Post
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 08:13:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Women go ape over ripped Japanese gorilla</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/environment/animals/women-go-ape-over-ripped-japanese-gorilla-20150628-ghzrot.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Women go ape over ripped Japanese gorilla
Date
Giant male gorilla Shabani, weighing around 180kg, at the Higashiyama Zoo.
Photo: HIGASHIYAMA ZOO
A giant gorilla with brooding good looks and rippling muscles is causing a stir at a Japanese zoo, with women flocking to check out the hunky pin-up.
Shabani, an 18-year-old silverback who tips the scales at around 180 kilograms, has become the star attraction at Higashiyama Zoo and Botanical Gardens in Nagoya, striking smouldering poses the movie model in Zoolander would be proud of.
"He often rests his chin on his hands and looks intently at you," zoo spokesman Takayuki Ishikawa said on Friday.
The 18-year-old silverback with brooding good looks and rippling muscles is causing a stir at the Japanese zoo.
Photo: Supplied
"He is more buff than most gorillas and he's at his peak physically. We've seen a rise in the number of female visitors - women say he's very good-looking."
Advertisement
Shabani, who has been at the zoo since 2007, shot to fame after being made the campaign model for the zoo's spring festival earlier this year, Ishikawa said, adding that the ape's paternal skills are also a big hit with women.
"He's a father and he always protects and looks over his children," he said. "Zoo-goers think his kindness is attractive too."
Ben Stiller in Zoolander.
Photo: Supplied
Women have taken to social media to swoon about Shabani's rugged looks, describing him as "ikemen" - or a hunk - and likening him to a male model.
A recent flurry of tweets has made Shabani a national celebrity, with Japan's broadcasters NHK and NTV featuring the gorilla on popular shows.
"He will look you in the eye and sometimes if you're taking photos it will look like he's posing for you like a model," said Ishikawa.
"But he's the head of a group of five gorillas so it's likely he's just watching out for them and keeping an eye on you."
AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 07:47:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>When ordinary men turn into militant terrorists</title>
        <Link>http://www.smh.com.au/world/when-ordinary-men-turn-into-militant-terrorists-20150628-ghzsh3.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>When ordinary men turn into militant terrorists
Date
Please Log in to update your video settings
Video will begin in 5 seconds.
Please Log in to update your video settings
Terror in Tunisia
Dozens of tourists have died in a surprise gun attack in the Tunisian resort town of Sousse.
PT1M5S 620 349
Gunman joked with tourists before killing spree
The photograph is like countless others released by Islamic State's propaganda wing: a young man sits flanked by a pair of Kalashnikovs, grinning excitedly at the prospect of proving himself in combat.
Yet when Seifeddine Rezgui's turn for martyrdom came, it was not in the tough battlegrounds of Syria or Iraq, but in a killing field that could scarcely be easier - a group of unsuspecting tourists sunbathing on a Tunisian beach, some of whom may not even have seen his face.
Tunisian gunman Seifeddine Rezgui
Photo: AP
According to Tunisia's prime minister, Habib Essid, Rezgui was a 23-year-old engineering student who originally hailed from Gaafour, a drab and unremarkable town some 80 kilometres south-west of Tunis. He had never travelled abroad, Mr Essid said, and was not known by the police to hold extremist views.
Advertisement
"We were all shocked when we heard the news and saw his picture, and his mother was devastated," saidhis uncle, Ali Al-Rezgui."Yes, he went to mosque and prayed, but just like the other young men, he would then go to a cafe and play football with his friends.
Another suspected militant Islamist who was probably acting alone has beenaccused of decapitating his boss and attempting to blow up a gas plant in southeastern France.Yassim Salhi, a 35-year-old of North African parentage, is being held in the city of Lyon after ramming his delivery van into a warehouse storing gas containers on Friday. He was apprehended minutes later while opening canisters containing flammable chemicals. Salhi, whose wife and sister are also being detained along with a fourth person, is known to have associated with Islamists over more than a decade and had previously been flagged as a potential risk.
A boy leaves flowers at a memorial on the Tunisian beach where the attack took place.
Photo: Jeff J Mitchell
Investigators searching his home in Saint-Priest, near Lyon, seized a laptop, a tablet computer and a fake pistol but found no trace of explosives or radical propaganda."We don't know whether we're dealing with a fundamentalist who just lost it or a real terrorist," asource said.
Salhi tooka macabre "selfie" with the severed head before his arrest, a source close to the investigation said on Saturday, and thenreportedly sent the photo to a Canadian mobile phone number via WhatsApp.
Rezgui, too, was adept at internet technology: hisFacebook pageincludes fan postings about rap music, Real Madrid and Tunisia's chances in the Africa Cup of Nations, along with numerous postings in support of Islamic State, as well as several of its propaganda videos.
People lock arms after viewing the deadly scene at the beach.
Photo: Getty Images
Notably, most of Rezgui's radical postings appear to have started only early last year, prior to which he seemed to be more interested in rap music and sharing jokes. His final entry is dated New Year 2015 and reads: "May God take me out of this unjust world and perish its people and make them suffer. They just remember you when they die."
Why Rezgui stopped all his Facebook activity after that date will now be a matter for the authorities, which on Friday seized a laptop during a raid on his family home in Gaafour, where his parents were also arrested.But a clue may lie in Rezgui's Islamic State nom de guerre, Abu Yahya al Qayrawani. The last name is a reference to the Tunisian city of Kairouan, where Rezgui last year enrolled for a master's degree at the local university.
The ancient city, which sits on the edge of the Sahara desert, was one of the earliest centres of Sunni Muslim Islamic scholarship and has long been considered one of holiest sites in the Muslim world.
More recently, though, it has also been a centre for Islamic radicalism, and until two years ago was the main gathering place in Tunisia for Ansar al-Sharia, the radical Islamic group that first sprang up in neighbouring Libya after the 2011 Arab Spring.
Following Ansar al-Sharia's attack on a US embassy compound in Libya in 2012, in which ambassador Chris Stevens was killed, it was declared a terrorist group by Washington. At the time, the Tunisian government chose not to follow suit, wary of being seen to act in the same authoritarian fashion as the country's deposed dictator, Zine El Abidine Ben Ali. But in 2013, it too outlawed the group, after a riot erupted when police stopped its followers holding their annual rally in Kairouan.
Since then, many of its hardcore members are believed to fled abroad to fight with Islamic State in Syria and Iraq. Such is the exodus that Tunisia is now believed to have contributed some 3000 jihadist fighters to the conflict, more than any other country.
"If jihad is a crime," SeifeddineRezgui wrote in hislast Facebook posting,"the world shall know that I'm a criminal."
Telegraph, London, Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
