<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Telegraph">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:39:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why has France become a target for recent terror attacks?</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf01/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C1170A11640CWhy0Ehas0EFrance0Ebecome0Ea0Etarget0Efor0Erecent0Eterror0Eattacks0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Following the decapitation of a man in Grenoble, The Telegraph's Henry Samuel explains why France has become a target for terror attacks in recent months</Description>
        <MainBody>France
Why has France become a target for recent terror attacks?
Following the decapitation of a man in Grenoble, The Telegraph's Henry Samuel    explains why France has become a target for terror attacks in recent months
By Telegraph Video, contains video from APTN
1:39PM BST 26 Jun 2015
A man has been decapitated during a suspected Islamist terror attack in France .
A message in Arabic was reportedly found on the victim's head, which had been pinned to a fence.
Two attackers arrived at a gas factory near Grenoble in a car, bearing banners written in Arabic, and set off explosions.
Grenoble attack: Man found beheaded and Islamist flag raised above factory in France - latest
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier. Credit: AFP/Getty
France 's anti-terror prosecutor said the attack was carried out by "a terrorist group" and it is understood one man has been arrested.
The decapitation comes a few months after the Islamist attacks in and around Paris in which 17 people were killed.
The Telegraph's France correspondent Henry Samuel explains why France has become a target for terror attacks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Grenoble attack: Man found beheaded and Islamist flag raised above factory in France - latest</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dcf/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C1170A0A5130CGrenoble0Eattack0EMan0Efound0Ebeheaded0Eand0EIslamist0Eflag0Eraised0Eabove0EFrench0Efactory0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>There were explosions reportedly heard near the industrial gas factory near Grenoble, south-eastern France where one person is believed to be dead and several hurt</Description>
        <MainBody>This page will automatically update every 30 secondsOn Off
 A decapitated body was found near a gas factory in south-eastern France, near Grenoble
 There was Arabic writing on the head
 A man suspected has been arrested and identified
 An attacker is believed to have killed one person and injured several others
 The attacker set off several explosions, a legal source says
Latest
13.45
French anti-terror raid police are currently raiding the home of Yacine Sali, the suspect arrested this morning at the factory, Henry Samuel in Paris writes.
A second suspect said to be "close" to him has been arrested, the interior ministry says.
Anti-terror police currently raiding home of arrested France factory attack suspect Yacine Salhi #Isre
 Henry Samuel (@H_E_Samuel) June 26, 2015
"France has been struck again by terror," the country's prime minister, Manuel Valls, said as he was cutting short a trip to South America to return to Paris.
"The terrorists' threats and blind horrors spare no nation. My thoughts go to the victims of Isre and the victims in Tunisia," he said from Colombia.
13.30
Sgolne Royale, a French socialist politician, has been speaking to reporters, James Rothwell writes.
She said: "This was an abominable attack... my thoughts go first of all to the families of the victims and the employees of this factory, who have no doubt been profoundly traumatised.
"The French government and authorities have reacted by increasing security at other sensitive sites. I would like to also say, as a member of the government, that unity among the French at this tragic moment is absolutely essential."
French Gendarmes block the access road to the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier (Reuters)
13.17
France's prime minister said an attack on a factory Friday was "Islamist terrorism," announcing he was cutting short a visit to South America to deal with the crisis.
"Islamist terrorism has hit France again," Manuel Valls told a press conference in Colombia's capital Bogota, adding that he would take part by telephone in an emergency meeting called by M r Hollande, then rush back to France.
The suspect arrested is reportedly married with three kids.
"Brave" fireman "neutralised" suspect who placed him "out of harm's way" says int min Bernard Cazeneuve as "second man arrested". #Isere
 Henry Samuel (@H_E_Samuel) June 26, 2015
13.12
The Telegraph's James Rothwell has been looking at French media reaction:
Jean-Jack Queyranne, president of the Rhne-Alpes region, told Le Figaro: "I feel a sense of horror in the face of the barbarism that has just taken place in Isre in the heart of our region.
First of all I would like to express my solidarity with the victims, their families and those close to them.
"We must be careful to ensure that fear does not become widespread. As in January [during the Charlie Hebdo massacre] the nation must unite as a whole to face up to this danger. For it is the nation that must combat terror."
French police and firefighters gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier (AFP/Getty Images)
12.59
Germany stands united with France against "terror's blind hate" and in defence of "free society", Frank-Walter Steinmeier, the foreign minister, said
Mr Steinmeier said he was appalled by the "shocking news of a heinous murder and an assault with several injured", calling it an "act of terror and fanaticism which we condemn in the strongest terms".
Barack Obama has been briefed on the attack at a US gas company in France, a senior administration official said, providing no further details.
12.30
Mr Cazeneuve says the suspected accomplices in the attack are being held by police. The man arrested has been known to security services since 2006 but surveillance stopped in 2008. He has no criminal record.
The interior minister said he had been filed as possibly being radicalised.
The French attack suspect had 'link' to Salafist movement, AFP reports.
Suspect named as Yacine Sali, 30. "Others who may have been involved arrested", says int min Cazeneuve #Isre
 Henry Samuel (@H_E_Samuel) June 26, 2015
12.20
BREAKING: Bernard Cazeneuve has named the suspect arrested as Yacine Sali.
12.09
Mr Hollande learnt of the terrorist attack just as the European Council was reconvening before 10am, Matthew Holehouse in Brussels writes. Here are some more comments in full from Mr Hollande.
The interior minister and public prosecutor "immediately" went to the site. The plant is under further protection and "all measures" are being taken, he said.
Bernard Cazeneuve will speak later to provide limited "useful" information.
Our thoughts go to the victim. It is a matter of solidarity. The European Council has expressed solidarity.
"There is a lot of emotion but it cannot be the only answer. Other answers are protection, deterrence. And the necessity to spread our values and never give in to fear, and to shoulder our responsibilities in all circumstances.
"It is not about spreading suspicion, but doing our job, protecting our people while finding out the truth and the individuals responsible for such actions."
Mr Hollande is to hold a meeting at the Elysee at 3.30pm.
12.01
More detail from Mr Hollande's press conference just now from Matthew Holehouse in Brussels.
Mr Hollande confirmed one person has died and two injured. He said a suspect has been arrested and identified.
He explained some of what happened during the attack and said a car driven by one person, maybe two, to the factory and their target was a gas bottle factory.
"This attack was in a vehicle driven by one person, perhaps accompanied by another."
Their intention was to provoke an explosion, he said.
A body was found decapitated, and two injured as well as a message found. "It is a terrorist attack - there is no doubt about it," Mr Hollande said
He will return to Paris to oversee the operation and said "huge" numbers of troops have been deployed to protect other facilities
He said: "We will never give in to fear."
11.54
Donald Tusk, the European Council president, has offered his condolences.
I offer my sincere condolences and solidarity to @fhollande and the people of France following the attack in #Isre .
 Donald Tusk (@eucopresident) June 26, 2015
11.49
President Francois Hollande is speaking and says troops have been deployed in the region to prevent another attack.
Earlier he said the attacker had been identified but said there was an "ongoing investigation". He said there were one or two assailants.
"Our thoughts go to the victims. The European Council expressed his solidarity - we remember what happened in our country and other countries."
He also said: "The attack was of a terrorist nature given that a corpse with Islamist inscriptions were found."
11.48
Two men are believed to have driven into the main gate before 10am. The second suspect is an unconfirmed entity.
The car then drove around in circles and a person inside threw gas cylinders around the main yard, Mail Online reported.
Local prosecuting sources said a man jumped out of the car and then "decapitated a man".
Emergency personnel work at the scene of a suspected Islamist attack, outside the Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier (EPA)
11.38
Alain Jupp, the mayor of Bordeaux, has condemned the attacks saying that France "must make every effort to protect its citizens".
"The terrorist threat is at a maximum," he says.
La menace terroriste est maximum. L'attentat en Isre nous le rappelle hlas! L'Etat doit tout mettre en uvre pour protger ses citoyens.
 Alain Jupp (@alainjuppe) June 26, 2015
Mr Hollande is returning home early from the EU summit on Friday, officials said.
"He will return early this afternoon and is in constant contact with Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve and the security services," the official said, adding that he would make a statement to the press in Brussels before 1100 GMT.
"The president saw the first images of the attack on the 24-news channels with Angela Merkel, German chancellor, beside him, who was visibly shocked," an official added.
The two leaders had just ended a short meeting with Alexis Tsipras, the Greek prime minister.
(Pic: Le Dauphine )
11.32
The man arrested is refusing to talk, according to BFM TV reporters. The channel reports that the individual has no papers that can identify him thus police have not yet been able to either.
A security official said the torso was found near the site of the explosion but that the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
Two flags, one white and one black and both with Arabic inscriptions, were found at the scene, Associated Press reported.
11.30
David Cameron, the Prime Minister, has spoken to Mr Hollande to convey his sympathies, writes Steven Swinford, Deputy Political Editor.
The Prime Minister has spoken to Francois Hollande, the French President, at the EU summit in Brussels about the terror attack. A British official said:
He expressed his sympathies for what looks like an appalling incident there. It clearly looks like an extremely concerning situation and our thoughts are with all those that are affected by it."
The interior minister has now arrived at the factory as this pictures shows from Le Dauphine .
11.17
Francois Hollande is expected to return to France. Sky News are reporting that police are still looking for a man near the factory earlier today.
11.15
Some background from Josie Ensor about Air Products.
It is interesting to note that the president of the company targeted in the attack, Air Products, is a Shia Iranian named Seifi Ghasemi.
Iran supports Bashar al-Assad's regime in Syria, which is battling against Sunni Islamic State militants.
The scene in Grenoble via Le Dauphine .
11.10
A video from the scene via ledauphine.com.
France's anti-terror prosecutors have opened an inquiry for "murder and attempted murder in a group in relation to a terrorist organisation", writes Henry Samuel in Paris.
Itele cites police sources as describing as "false" reports that the man arrested is known to French intelligence services.
The 40-odd employees in the factory have been evacuated.
Witnesses at the scene said there was more than one attacker involved but this is unconfirmed.
11.05
What we know so far from AFP:
A suspected Islamist attacker pinned a decapitated head covered with Arabic writing to the gates of a gas factory in eastern France on Friday before being arrested, police say
The suspect entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices, the source said at around 10am local time
Police said it was unclear whether the attacker was acting alone, or had accomplices
A man thought to be the person who carried out the attack has been arrested - it is reported he is known to the security services
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minister said is on his way to the scene, his office say
11.02
The man arrested reportedly said he was a member of Islamic State.
10.56
France's president and prime minister are both currently abroad, but it looks like Franois Hollande, the president, may be returning prematurely from Brussels to handle the crisis, Henry Samuel writes.
10.55
This is the factory where the attack took place earlier today.
Banners with Arabic writing were found near the body, one official has told Associated Press.
10.52
French authorities have officially opened a terrorist investigation into today's attack.
10.48
Air Products, the American company targeted in the attack has 21,000 employees, according to its website, and sold industrial gases including nitrogen, oxygen, hydrogen, The Telegraph's Josie Ensor writes.
10.45
Francois Hollande, the president, is in Brussels for the EU summit but the meetings have begun without the leader.
We do not know yet if he will be returning to France.
Manuel Valls, the prime minister, has said that there will be tightened security measures on 'sensitive' sites after the attack.
Mr Valls also called for "heightened vigilance" at all sensitive sites in the Rhne-Alpes area.
"the head of the victim was found hanging on the fence of the Company enclosure" Oh damn... http://t.co/qfl2xan3MO #frankrijk #attack
 Rick Schipper (@Enoxiz) June 26, 2015
10.43
Sky News has said the arrested man is believed to be 30 years old and known to France's anti-terrorist police (DGSI).
There was Arabic writing on severed head pinned to French factory gates, a legal source tells AFP.
10.39
Here is what we know so far:
Two men brandishing what appears to be an Islamic State flag launched an attack on a chemical factoy in Isre, southeastern France, on Friday morning, Henry Samuel writes.
The Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier produces industrial gas and is considered a sensitive site, said a Erwann Binet, Socialist MP for the Isre dpartement. The factory is on the outskirts of Lyon.
The two assailants rammed a vehicle carrying bottles of gas into the Air Products factory in Saint Quentin, in the south-eastern Isre area.
One was brandishing what appears to be an Islamic State flag.
A strong explosion ensued. According to the interior ministry, two employees were injured in the blast. Another man was found decapitated near the factory. According to iTele, the rolling news channel, he was not a factory employee.
One man, thought to be one of the assailants, has been arrested, said the interior ministry.
France's elite GIGN anti-terror police have been sent to the site.
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minsiter, said he is on his way to the area "immediately".
We are all in a state of shock as we didnt expect any attack in our territory, said Mr Binet.
A police source cited by RTL radio said "other attacks cannot be ruled out".
10.33
Le Dauphin Liber reports that a man has been arrested but it is unknown if he is the suspected attacker. AFP cites a source saying that it is the attacker.
According to Sky News, there could be two attackers.
Meanwhile, the Local France reports that the decapitated man was not an employee at the factory.
The attack is believed to have taken place at 10am local time, 9am BST.
10.30
More from AFP's source:
"According to the initial findings of the enquiry, one or several individuals on board a vehicle, drove into the factory. An explosion then took place," said one of the sources.
"The decapitated body of a person was found nearby the factory but we do not yet know whether the body was transported to the place or not," added this source, adding that a "flag with Arabic writing on it was found on the scene."
According to a local French newspaper a man's head was chopped off and then hung on fence of the factory in St Quentin Fallavier. This remains unconfirmed.
BREAKING: Man arrested after "Islamist attack" in central France - http://t.co/pHSJoV49Ca pic.twitter.com/1yPISpnsFY
 The Local France (@TheLocalFrance) June 26, 2015
10.26
There are reports that the factory belongs to Air Products. French media report that the suspected attacker rammed his car into the factory.
10.23
The explosions are believed to have been set off in the factory using gas canisters.
10.20
Hello and welcome to the Telegraph's live coverage of the attack on a French factory where a decapitated body was found nearby.
An attacker carrying an Islamist flag killed one person and injured several others today at a gas factory in eastern France, according to a legal source, AFP reported.
The suspected attacker entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices, the source said.
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minister, said he would go "immediately" to the scene, his office said.
The attack comes six months after the Charlie Hebdo attack and the three-day siege in Paris during which 17 people were killed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:24:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italian grandfather finally completes middle school education - at the age of 91</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf02/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Citaly0C1170A0A7360CItalian0Egrandfather0Efinally0Ecompletes0Emiddle0Eschool0Eeducation0Eat0Ethe0Eage0Eof0E910Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A large family and a hard working life meant he never had time to complete his education</Description>
        <MainBody>Follow
In a case of better late than never, a grandfather in Italy has finished middle school with flying colours at the age of 91.
Nicola Torello, who as a 19-year-old served in the Italian army in Greece during the Second World War, made up for lost time by returning to school in his home town of Chieti in the mountainous Abruzzo region of central Italy.
A large family and a life of hard work as a tailor meant that he never finished his basic education as a child.
Mr Torello, who turns 92 in October, received top marks in his maths exam and even managed to learn some English for an oral test.
He also wrote an essay about his wartime experiences, when he served with an Italian army brigade in Greece.
He said he returned to school in part to help him get over the death of his wife, Licia.
His four children and six grand children turned up at the school to see him awarded his school certificate.
Even the mayor of Chieti came to offer his congratulations.
Buoyed by the success, Mr Torello now wants to learn how to use a computer.
He said he had remained fit and active by swimming twice a week and by continuing to drive a white Fiat 600 around town.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:20:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia attack: deadly shooting in front of tourist beach hotel in Sousse - latest</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf05/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1170A10A430CTunisia0Eattack0Edeadly0Eshooting0Ein0Efront0Eof0Etourist0Ebeach0Ehotel0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 27 dead after gunman opened fire in terrorist attack on popular beach resort in Sousse, Tunisia</Description>
        <MainBody>This page will automatically update every 30 secondsOn Off
 Gunmen killed in shoot-out
 Tourists gunned down on popular beach
 Pictures circulating on social media of bodies on the beach
 Attacks comes as 12 killed in Isil bomb on Kuwait mosque
Latest
13.46
One of the hotels targeted in the attack was the Imperial Marahaba. It's promoted by Thomson Holidays, among others, and has 366 rooms over five floors. It's an all-inclusive resort, described as a "grand beachside hotel".
13.42
Susan Rickett, who was staying at the Palm Marina Hotel near Sousse, said: 'My sister was talking to someone who had seen some people shooting and had shot someone on a sun bed but we don't know if that's true.
'It sounded like a machine gun going off... and there was a kind of explosion a little bit later.
'They're saying its going on in the hotel next to us. Police were chasing some men, that's all I know.'
13.40
The Interior Ministry has just revised the number of dead up to 27. Spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said security forces intervened immediately and killed one of the attackers, while the other fled the scene.
13.22
Another British tourist close to the scene of a deadly attack on a Tunisian beach resort has described his experiences.
Gary Pine said he was on the beach and heard what "we thought was firecrackers going off" 100 yards away, followed by an explosion from the next hotel complex along.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach," he said. He said his son said he had seen someone get shot on the beach.
He said guests at his hotel were first told to lock themselves in their rooms, and later to gather in the lobby.
Tunisia is popular with British tourists. The Foreign Office says 424,707 British nationals visited Tunisia in 2014.
13.22
Tunisia's Interior Ministry says two gunmen opened fire on a beach in the coastal resort of Sousse Friday, killing at least seven people.
Pictures posted on Instagram appeared to shot a couple dead on the beach with a couple dead with gunshot wounds to the head.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
It is one of the North African country's most popular beach resorts, drawing tourists from Europe and neighbouring countries. Tunisia has been high alert since Islamist gunmen attacked the Bardo museum in Tunis in March, killing a group of foreign visitors.
13.24
The body of one gunman lay at the scene with a Kalashnikov assault rifle after he was shot in an exchange of gunfire with police, the source said.
British tourist David Schofield told Sky News that he was by the pool when he heard "quite a large explosion" and guests started to run back towards the hotel. "We heard people saying there were guns on the beach. People were shooting on the beach," he said.
"People are running around the hotel. No-one has really been told what to do."
13.17
At least 27 people have been killed in an attack on a beach hotel in the Tunisian city of Sousse, and at least one gunman has been killed in a shoot-out.
The attack, which took place around 12pm local time, was said to have taken place outside the five-star hotel the Imperial Marhaba hotel.
"The operation was carried out in two hotels. There are seven dead, maybe more," ministry spokesman Mohamed Ali Aroui told Mosaique radio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:18:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Barack Obama came to raise his voice on race</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf06/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C116999470CHow0EBarack0EObama0Ecame0Eto0Eraise0Ehis0Evoice0Eon0Erace0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>As Barack Obama speaks in Charleston in the wake of one of the most vile racially motivated attacks in America's history, we look back at his previous remarks on race</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
How Barack Obama came to raise his voice on race
As Barack Obama speaks in Charleston in the wake of one of the most vile    racially motivated attacks in America's history, we look back at his    previous remarks on race
By Peter Foster, and David Lawler in Washington
1:18PM BST 26 Jun 2015
On Friday, President Obama will mourn with the city of Charleston, South Carolina, where nine people were killed last week at a historic black church. He'll deliver a eulogy at the funeral for Rev. Clementa Pinckney, a state lawmaker and pastor of Emanuel African Methodist Church.
Mr Obama made history when he became Americas first black president, but for much of his presidency he has walked a fine line on the contentious issue of race.
Mr Obama was careful to note he would be a president for all Americans and not simply a black president focusing on racial issues.
It was a position he first outlined in his 1995 memoir, Dreams from my Father, in which he wrote: My identity might begin with the fact of my race, but it didn't, couldn't end there. At least that's what I would choose to believe.
Mr Obama was criticised throughout his first term by some more traditional voices in the black community for failing to do more to root out Americas still-endemic racial discrimination.
However following his re-election in 2012 several high-profile incidents, starting with the shooting of the unarmed black teenager Trayvon Martin, have led Mr Obama to engage much more explicitly on the need to tackle Americas racial divide.
Here we chart the evolution of Mr Obamas public statements on the race issue since 2008.
March, 2008: A more perfect Union
In early 2008, during his first presidential campaign, Mr Obama came under fire for his links to the Rev Jeremiah Wright, a fiery black Chicago pastor who had exclaimed God damn America! in a sermon.
With his campaign suddenly reeling, Mr Obama delivered what became known as his more perfect union speech  a speech that is still widely ranked as one of his absolute best.
His message  embodied in his own candidacy and life story - was fundamentally hopeful.
I believe deeply that we cannot solve the challenges of our time unless we solve them together - unless we perfect our union by understanding that we may have different stories, but we hold common hopes; that we may not look the same and we may not have come from the same place, but we all want to move in the same direction - towards a better future for of children and our grandchildren.
July, 2013: Trayvon Martin  could have been my son
After Florida neighbourhood watch captain George Zimmerman was cleared of the murder of the unarmed black teenager Trayvon Martin in July 2013, Mr Obama respected the verdict, but spoke passionately about the black experience in what was widely seen as a departure from his typical language on race issues.
You know, when Trayvon Martin was first shot I said that this could have been my son. Another way of saying that is Trayvon Martin could have been me 35 years ago.... There are very few African American men in this country who haven't had the experience of being followed when they were shopping in a department store. That includes me. There are very few African American men who haven't had the experience of walking across the street and hearing the locks click on the doors of cars. That happens to me -- at least before I was a senator."
August, 2014: Ferguson shooting - "This is an issue for America"
The shooting of Michael Brown, an unarmed black teenager in Ferguson, Missouri prompted outbreaks of violence in cities across America, uniting protestors under the banner of black lives matter.
As the streets of Ferguson burned over the decision by a Grand Jury not to prosecute the officer involved, Mr Obama went on television to appeal for calm, but his lofty remarks were at stark odds with the passions unfolding on the streets.
We need to recognize that this is not just an issue for Ferguson, this is an issue for America. We have made enormous progress in race relations over the course of the past several decades. I've witnessed that in my own life. And to deny that progress I think is to deny Americas capacity for change."
June, 2015: Charleston- 'societies don't change overnight'
After nine people were left dead in a racially motivated attack on a black church in South Carolina, Mr Obama again found hope amid the horror.
The fact that this took place in a black church obviously also raises questions about a dark part of our history. This is not the first time that black churches have been attacked, and we know the hatred across races and faiths pose a particular threat to our democracy and our ideals.The good news is I am confident that the outpouring of unity and strength and fellowship and love across Charleston today, from all races, from all faiths, from all places of worship, indicates the degree to which those old vestiges of hatred can be overcome.
But in an interview more noted for the language he used, Mr Obama acknowledged the depth of the challenge.
It's not just a matter of it not being polite to say n----- in public That's not the measure of whether racism still exists or not. It's not just a matter of overt discrimination. Societies don't, overnight, completely erase everything that happened 200 to 300 years prior."
Barack Obama never pretended he could bring an end to racial prejudice in America. But he has confronted it with growing force in his second term, without abandoning his vision of the more perfect union to come.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:35:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japanese women go ape over 'handsome' gorilla named Shabani</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798a476/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cjapan0C1170A0A4270CJapanese0Ewomen0Ego0Eape0Eover0Ehandsome0Egorilla0Enamed0EShabani0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Japan
Japanese women go ape over 'handsome' gorilla named Shabani
Giant male gorilla Shabani, weighing around 180kg, at the Higashiyama Zoo in Nagoya in Aichi prefecture, central JapanPhoto: AFP/Getty
By Flynn Murphy, Sydney
Comments
An Australian-raised gorilla is winning hearts in Japan where his good-looks have made him a hit with female zoo-goers.
Shabani, a western lowland gorilla born in the Netherlands and raised in a Sydney zoo, is popular for his handsome looks and dramatic poses, with local admirers dubbing him an ikemen, or good-looking man.
Shabani is popular for his handsome looks (AFP/Getty)
The gorilla lives in Higashiyama Zoo and Botanical Gardens in Nagoya, Japan, where he moved in 2007 after spending his formative years at Taronga Zoo on the shores of Sydney Harbour.
And while the 18-year-old has local women enthralled, Shabani may have been a late bloomer.
I have seen quite an early photo of him and he's not the handsome man that he is today, Madeleine Smitham, a media relations officer at Taronga Zoo, told the Telegraph.
Shabani lives in Higashiyama Zoo and Botanical Gardens in Nagoya (AFP/Getty)
He certainly didnt have quite the same following here that he has in Japan.
On Twitter many Japanese women have tweeted praise and pictures of Shabani, Mail Online reported , including one women who wrote: "I went to Higashiyama Zoo. This hot Shabani ikemen was certainly handsome."
Another female visitor shared an image of the zoo with her friends and the caption: "The meeting of going to see the handsome gorilla Shabani... it was a fun holiday."
Shabani arrived at Taronga Zoo as a baby with another silverback, Kibabu, who is now living out his retirement at a zoo on the NSW south coast, explained another staffer, Paul Fahy.
Obviously western lowland gorillas are a critically endangered species, so Tarongas part of a coordinated breeding programme. The decision was made for Shabani to go to Japan as part of the breeding program, which is all about ensuring genetic diversity, Fahy said.
Shabani weighs around 180kg (AFP/Getty)
This is not the first time Shabani has gone viral. There was a video a couple of years ago of him tightrope walking at the zoo in Japan, Fahy said.
Back in Sydney, Shabani may have some competition. Weve now got a young aspiring silverback here now, who we like to think is quite dashing in his own way, Fahy said.
Thats Kibali, a French-born western lowland gorilla.
And in perhaps heartening news for the men of Japan, there is currently no plan to send Kibali overseas.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:17:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China warns Glastonbury organisers after Dalai Lama's invite</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798a477/sc/11/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Ctibet0C1170A0A90A50CChina0Ewarns0EGlastonbury0Eorganisers0Eafter0EDalai0ELamas0Einvite0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Tibet's spiritual leader has been invited to speak at the festival, much to the ire of China</Description>
        <MainBody>China warns Glastonbury organisers after Dalai Lama's invite
Tibet's spiritual leader has been invited to speak at the festival, much to    the ire of China
China is far from impressed with festival organisers for inviting the Dalai Lama to Glastonbury 2015Photo: Paul Faith/PA
The office of the Dalai Lama said on Thursday that the Dalai Lama would speak at the Glastonbury Festival during his trip to Britain. He is not due to meet any officials.
His Holiness the Dalai Lama is to visit Glastonbury Festival on Sunday http://t.co/Nm8irCL5jx pic.twitter.com/8y8kehepzu
 Glastonbury Festival (@GlastoFest) June 25, 2015
The Dalai Lama is also going to Britain again in September, just ahead of Chinese President Xi Jinping's trip to the country in October. Xi's state visit is the first to Britain in a decade by a Chinese head of state.
Beijing denounces the Dalai Lama as a dangerous separatist who wants an independent Tibet. He denies espousing violence and says he only wants genuine autonomy for his Himalayan homeland.
Foreign Ministry spokesman Lu Kang told a daily news briefing that he was not aware of the details of what the Dalai Lama was doing at the Glastonbury Festival.
Lu said, however, that China's position on the "international scuttling about of the 14th Dalai Lama to serve his political aims" is consistent.
"China resolutely opposes any country, organisation, body or individual giving any kind of platform to the 14th Dalai Lama to engage in anti-China splittist activities," Lu said.
"It's a decision for the festival-goers and the Dalai Lama," A British government source said, when asked about China's caution that inviting him to visit one of Europe's largest music festivals was tantamount to giving him a platform to engage in anti-China activities.
China routinely denounces any country that hosts the Dalai Lama. In 2012, British Prime Minister David Cameron had to put his trip to China on hold after Beijing took offence at him holding a meeting with the Dalai Lama.
China has ruled Tibet with an iron fist since troops "peacefully liberated" the region in 1950. The Dalai Lama fled into exile in India in 1959 after an abortive uprising against Chinese rule.
Representatives of the Nobel Peace laureate held rounds of talks with China until 2010, but formal dialogue has stalled amid leadership changes in Beijing and a crackdown in Tibet.
Organiser Emily Eavis welcomed the announcement (Rex)
 Glastonbury 2015: festival weather
The announcement has been welcomed by Emily Eavis, daughter of Mike, who founded the festival on his farm in Somerset.
"We're honoured to welcome the Dalai Lama to Glastonbury 2015, she said. He will be talking in the Green Fields and exploring the farm this Sunday as part of his trip to the UK.
What a special moment for the Festival!"
The Dalai Lama has visited Britain regularly since walking over the Himalayas into exile from Tibet as the 1959 uprising against Chinese rule was crushed.
However, meeting international leaders - including David Cameron, the prime minister - has become increasingly difficult, as China threatens retaliation against countries that give him a political presence on the world stage.
The Dalai Lama with David Cameron and Nick Clegg
Relations between Britain and Beijing are only just now recovering from a brief meeting at St Pauls Cathedral between the Dalai Lama, Mr Cameron and then deputy prime minister Nick Clegg in 2012.
Instead, he has concentrated on taking his message direct to supporters, including at events like Glastonbury. The Eavis family may now be considering what form Chinese retaliation against Somerset could take.
 Happy Glasto campers prepare for music and mud, in pictures
The Dalai Lama, whose birthday is on July 6, will probably be the oldest act to put in an appearance at Glastonbury - but not by much.
Patti Smith is 68, and Paul Weller 57, while Mick Jagger was almost 70 when he played at Glastonbury in 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:16:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>For sale: Tom Cruise's $59m ski lodge</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753a8/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctravel0Csnowandski0Cpicture0Egalleries0C116983380CFor0Esale0ETom0ECruises0E59m0Eski0Elodge0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Take a look around the Hollywood hero's glamorous ski pad, on the market for a cool $59m</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE...
Hollywood action man Tom Cruise is selling his seven-bedroom, nine-bathroom    luxury ski lodge in Telluride, Colorado. Advertised by a local estate agent    and boasting its own helipad and private airport, as well as money-cant-buy    views of the area's National Forest, let's see what a mere $59,000,000 will    get you.
--
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:25:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Celebrity Sightings: Kimye, Maria Sharapova and Reese Witherspoon</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd3/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Ccelebritynews0C1170A0A60A90CCelebrity0ESightings0EKimye0EMaria0ESharapova0Eand0EReese0EWitherspoon0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Starring: Kimye, Maria Sharapova and Reese Witherspoon</Description>
        <MainBody>Kim Kardashian and hubby Kanye West treated themselves to a fancy meal at Hakassan in London's swanky Mayfair ahead of him headlining the world-famous Glastonbury Festival in rural SomersetPicture: Rex Features

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:25:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pictures of the day: 26 June 2015</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753ad/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Cpicturesoftheday0C1170A0A40A70CPictures0Eof0Ethe0Eday0E260EJune0E20A150Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Today: A handsome gorilla, a flapping flamingo and a Glastonbury hotel</Description>
        <MainBody>A walrus wallows in shallow water off the coast of Svalbard in the ArcticPicture: Franco Banfi/Solent News

Comments are closed on this picture gallery.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:25:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suicide bomber blows up vehicle in Kobane</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd5/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctelegraphtv0C1170A0A7350CSuicide0Ebomber0Eblows0Eup0Evehicle0Ein0EKobane0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Video footage shows bomb exploding on Thursday in Kobane, Syria</Description>
        <MainBody>Suicide bomber blows up vehicle in Kobane
Video footage shows bomb exploding on Thursday in Kobane, Syria
By Sophie Jamieson, video source: APTN
11:25AM BST 26 Jun 2015
CCTV footage captured the moment a suicide bomber blew up a vehicle in Kobane, Syria .
Video from a surveillance camera shows a pick up truck driving down a road before exploding.
The attack came on Thursday as Islamic State forces re-entered Kobane at the Turkish border on Thursday and clashed with Kurdish YPG forces in the town.
At least 146 civilians are believed to have been killed in the latest violence in Kobane and a nearby village, making it the second-biggest massacre by the hardline group in the country, a conflict monitor said on Friday.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:20:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France terror attack in Grenoble - watch live</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd6/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C1170A0A6370CFrance0Eterror0Eattack0Ein0EGrenoble0Ewatch0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Watch live police response after explosions were reportedly heard at a gas factory near Grenoble, eastern France, where one person is believed to be dead and several hurt</Description>
        <MainBody>France
France terror attack in Grenoble - watch live
Watch live police response after explosions were reportedly heard at a gas    factory near Grenoble, eastern France, where one person is believed to be    dead and several hurt
By Telegraph Video, video source APTN
11:20AM BST 26 Jun 2015
An attacker carrying an Islamist flag has killed one person and injured several others today at a gas factory in eastern France , according to a French official.
The suspected attacker is understood to have entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices.
Grenoble attack: Man found beheaded and Islamist flag raised above French factory - latest
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minister, said he would go "immediately" to the scene, his office said.
The attack comes six months after the Charlie Hebdo attack and the three-day siege in Paris during which 17 people were killed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:18:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>School students caught selling salt to make lunch taste better</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd7/sc/26/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cfoodanddrink0Cfoodanddrinknews0C1170A0A6620CSchool0Estudents0Ecaught0Eselling0Esalt0Eto0Emake0Elunch0Etaste0Ebetter0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Secondary school pupils in America have been caught selling salt to their classmates to make their school dinners taste nicer</Description>
        <MainBody>Food and Drink News
School students caught selling salt to make lunch taste better
Secondary school pupils in America have been caught selling salt to their    classmates to make their school dinners taste nicer
Under new guidelines, high school students have taken to selling salt to make their lunches taste nicerPhoto: ALAMY
By Saffron Alexander
Comments
Since 2010, the lunches offered to American school students have changed drastically, thanks largely to Michelle Obama's "Let's Move!" childhood obesity initiative and the Healthy, Hunger-Free Kids Act.
Nutritional guidelines now state that students must be offered both fruits and vegetables every day of the week, only fat-free or low-fat milks can be available, and that calories must be limited based on children's ages.
The rules have not gone down well with either school cafeteria workers or students.
 #thanksMichelleObama: disgruntled students tweet photos of their school lunches
Students prefer unhealthy lunches (GETTY)
Now, students at schools in Indiana have been caught bringing salt, pepper and sugar with them to make their lunches taste better. Some have even been caught selling the seasonings to their classmates.
John Payne, president of the Blackford County School Board of Trustees, called for schools to be allowed more flexibility with the nutrition standards set by Congress. "This 'contraband' economy is just one example of many that reinforce the call for flexibility," he said.
"More students bring their lunch, and a few parents even 'check out' their child from campus, taking them to a local fast-food restaurant or home for lunch."
 US school dinner lady fired for handing out free lunches to poor kids
Critics of the rules have also said students are going to class hungry, because they don't like the food they are served and simply throw away the fruits and vegetables.
Todd Rokita told The Indy Star: "From firsthand experience, I can verify that despite the increased federal involvement in the school meals program, many students are still going to class hungry.
"I've stuck my head in a lot of garbage cans lately in school cafeterias and I've seen a lot of that."
Michelle Obama eating one of her healthy lunches with school children (AP)
Despite the criticism, Donna Martin, director of the school nutrition program in Burke County, believes the new rules are affecting her students positively.
 Want to lose weight? Become more right-wing
She told The Indy Star they are "gobbling up their whole-grain biscuits, and fresh Georgia peaches and blueberries.
"We have the opportunity to change a generation. We have an opportunity to raise kids that, when they go into McDonald's, they want a whole wheat hamburger bun."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:02:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Biggest US Spanish-language broadcaster to drop Miss USA pageant over Trump comments</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd8/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1170A0A3920CBiggest0EUS0ESpanish0Elanguage0Ebroadcaster0Eto0Edrop0EMiss0EUSA0Epageant0Eover0ETrump0Ecomments0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The network made the decision after the Republican candidate and businessman suggested Mexican immigrants "bring drugs, crime, [and] they're rapists"</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Biggest US Spanish-language broadcaster to drop Miss USA pageant over Trump comments
The network made the decision after the Republican candidate and businessman    suggested Mexican immigrants "bring drugs, crime, [and] they're rapists"
Donald Trump, co-owner of the Miss Universe Organization, poses with Miss Connecticut Erin Brady in Las Vegas in 2013 Photo: Reuters
By AP
Comments
A Univision network is dropping the Miss USA pageant in a spiralling controversy over comments Donald Trump made recently about Mexican immigrants.
Univision said on Thursday it would pull the plug on its Spanish-language coverage of the pageant July 12 by its UniMas network and the company said it will cut all business ties with the Republican presidential candidate.
It also severed its business relationship with the Miss Universe Organisation, which produces the Miss USA pageant , due to what it called "insulting remarks about Mexican immigrants" by Trump, a part owner of Miss Universe.
During his presidential campaign kick-off speech last week , Trump portrayed immigrants from Mexico as "bringing drugs, they're bringing crime, they're rapists, and some, I assume, are good people".
He also called for building a wall along the southern border of the US. The remarks drew condemnation from the Mexican government as "biased and absurd."
NBC is scheduled to air its own pageant coverage, as it has done since 2003, and has remained silent about the broadcast. But in a statement Thursday, the network sought to separate itself from Trump's remarks.
"Donald Trump's opinions do not represent those of NBC, and we do not agree with his positions on a number of issues, including his recent comments on immigration," NBC said.
Trump is part of another NBC programme, Celebrity Apprentice.
In an interview on Thursday, Trump said his criticism was directed against US politicians, not the Mexican people or government, adding that Univision would be defaulting on its contract if it does not air the pageant and he would take legal action.
 The Trump manifesto
"At Univision, we see first-hand the work ethic, love for family, strong religious values and the important role Mexican immigrants and Mexican-Americans have had and will continue to have in building the future of our country," said the New York-based Univision Communications Inc.
Puerto Rican actress-singer Roselyn Snchez, who was set to co-host the Univision broadcast of Miss USA, announced on Thursday that she was pulling out of the pageant. (AP)
Both co-hosts of the UniMas telecast also pulled out on Thursday, while Colombian singer J Balvin on Wednesday cancelled a planned performance at the pageant.
"The only thing I could do as a person, not only as an artist, but as a Latino that I am, was to cancel my show immediately," he told The Associated Press on Thursday.
Trump said Univision is submitting to pressure from Mexican leaders to punish him for positions he voices as a candidate on the campaign trail.
"They don't want me saying that Mexico is killing the United States in trade and killing the United States at the border," Trump said. "Univision is totally laying down for the Mexican government. ... They want to silence Donald Trump. And Donald Trump can't be silenced. ... I have great respect for Mexico and I love the Mexican people, but my loyalty is to the United States."
Univision declined to comment on Trump's remarks. The company also has the rights to air the Miss Universe pageant.
In an interview scheduled to air on Sunday on Telemundo's Enfoque con Jose Diaz-Balart, Trump said "many bad people are coming in" from Mexico and elsewhere.
"You're going to have terrorists coming through the southern border. There's no question about it," he said.
The host challenged Trump, contending there has been no act of terrorism committed by someone crossing the US-Mexico border.
"You don't know that," Trump replied, adding later: "See what happens tomorrow. See what happens in two weeks from now. You can't say that terrorists, and I'm not even talking about terrorists from this region. I'm talking about from the Middle East they can come in. The border is totally open."
In severing her ties with the Miss USA pageant, Puerto Rican actress Roselyn Sanchez, one of the two co-hosts, cited Trump's comments about immigrants.
"Since I heard Trump's speech, as a Latina I felt a lump in my stomach. 'It's got to be a joke,' I thought," the star of the Lifetime series Devious Maids told The Associated Press.
Chilean actor-producer Cristian de la Fuente, the show's other co-host, had strong words for Trump: "It's a shame that such an important institution as Miss USA is now in the hands of a clown."
Ricky Martin also took to Twitter to criticise Trump. "A lot of hatred and ignorance in his heart," he tweeted.
Mucho odio e ignorancia en tu corazn @realDonaldTrump . #LatinosUnidos
 Ricky Martin (@ricky_martin) June 25, 2015
Miss California USA Natasha Martinez was asked about Trump's comments during an interview on Thursday on Los Angeles TV station KCAL and said they were "a little bit tough to hear."
"But I know that this opportunity for me as Miss California-USA, and now competing for Miss USA, is a great bridge to kind of represent my community and let the world know that I am a proud Latino-American," she said.
This year's UniMas telecast would have been the first in a five-year contract that Trump said "has no termination rights". Univision's wholly owned Spanish-language UniMas network, founded in 2013, is available in 70 million US homes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:36:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Disgusting' FGM campaign wins prestigious advertising awards at Cannes</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd9/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cwomen0Cwomens0Elife0C1169960A30CFGM0EOgilvy0Ecampaign0Ewins0ECannes0ELion0Eawards0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A heavily criticised advertising campaign raising awareness about female genital mutilation has won Cannes Lion industry awards</Description>
        <MainBody>Follow
A heavily criticised campaign against female genital mutilation has won a top advertising award at Cannes.
Ogilvy and Mather London created the advertisements to raise awareness about FGM  a crime where a girl or womans genitalia is cut for cultural reasons  back in April, on behalf of anti-FGM charity 28 Too Many .
The adverts depict flags of western countries  such as the union jack  splattered with blood stains and with thick thread sewing them back together.
A message printed on the flag reads: "Female genital mutilation doesn't only happen in far away places. Over 50,000 girls in the UK are at risk."
The It happens here campaign was designed to raise awareness about the fact that FGM is still carried out in countries like the UK, even though it is illegal.
It attracted outrage from many FGM survivors and campaign groups. But the campaign this week won a Gold and Bronze award at the Cannes Lions  the most prestigious global advertising awards.
One campaigner, who has undergone the barbaric practice herself, said the ad was disgusting and should be taken down immediately.
Nimko Ali, who co-founded anti-FGM charity Daughters of Eve , said: Im shocked they won the award. [The flags are] disgusting.
Its so graphic and we have worked so hard to get the conversation about seeing [FGM] as violence against women and girls, and we need to work within that framework.
Were trying not to stigmatise and traumatise girls but this ad does."
Ali, who underwent FGM as a child, added: I shook when I saw it. It depicts the most invasive form of FGM and its what I had.
I think there are girls out there who will see it and feel the same way. It wont help them.
There are three 'types' of FGM : the partial or total removal of the clitoris; the partial or total removal of the clitoris and labia minora; and narrowing the vaginal orifice by cutting and repositioning the labia. The latter appears to be depicted on the posters.
The End FGM European Network agreed that the It Happens Here campaign could stigmatise FGM and was not helpful to survivors.
A spokesperson told Telegraph Wonder Women: We need campaigns which encourage a discussion around the fact that FGM is a reality in Europe and across the world.
Using images which empower and enhance the dignity of survivors and those at risk is vital to this discussion. Stigmatising imagery can alienate affected communities even more and we need to ensure that they are central to ending FGM.
Cheryl Giovannoni, chief executive officer of Ogilvy and Mather London, responded saying: "It Happens Here is designed to be a hard-hitting and provocative campaign to raise awareness of the horrific abuse suffered by hundreds of thousands of girls every year.
"The bold imagery is intended to shock and reach an audience typically unaware of the issues of FGM. The response to this campaign has been overwhelmingly positive and we hope it continues to raise awareness, and support 28 Too Many in their efforts to end female genital mutilation once and for all."
The charity 28 Too Many was unavailable for comment, but Dr Ann-Marie Wilson, executive director, previously spoke about the campaign, saying:
FGM is not just being performed in Africa, the Middle East and Asia but is taking place here, in Europe, on our very own door steps.
"This emotive campaign visually encompasses the concept that FGM is not an out of sight, out of mind problem but at present a risk to over 60,000 girls in the UK.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:58:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Isil attack on Kobane is 'second biggest massacre' of civilians by the group in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4797941d/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cislamic0Estate0C1170A0A4530CIsil0Eattack0Eon0EKobane0Eis0Esecond0Ebiggest0Emassacre0Eof0Ecivilians0Eby0Ethe0Egroup0Ein0ESyria0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Islamic State fighters killed 146 civilians in their attack on Kobane and a nearby village on Thursday, Syrian Observatory for Human Rights says</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State
Isil attack on Kobane is 'second biggest massacre' of civilians by the group in Syria
Islamic State fighters killed 146 civilians in their attack on Kobane and    a nearby village on Thursday, Syrian Observatory for Human Rights says
A picture taken from Suruc district of Turkey's Sanliurfa province shows a group of Syrians waiting on the Syrian side of the Turkish border during the clashes between Isil and Kurdish armed groups in Kobani Photo: 2015 Anadolu Agency
By Louisa Loveluck, Cairo
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:21:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japan mourns death of Tama, the train stationmaster cat</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753a1/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cjapan0C1170A0A3720CJapan0Emourns0Edeath0Eof0ETama0Ethe0Etrain0Estationmaster0Ecat0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The calico cat, who was also deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in 2013, has died aged 16</Description>
        <MainBody>Japan
Japan mourns death of Tama, the train stationmaster cat
The calico cat, who was also deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in    2013, has died aged 16
Tama was known as the stationmaster of Kishi station on the Wakayama Electric Railway in the city of KinokawaPhoto: AFP/Getty
By Danielle Demetriou, Tokyo
One of Japans best-loved cats , who won the heart of the nation working as a stationmaster in a rural train station , has died and the funeral will be held this weekend.
Tama, a 16-year-old calico cat, attracted thousands of tourists to tiny Kishi station in Wakayama prefecture after being appointed stationmaster in 2007.
Prior to her arrival, the regional railway line was losing money and the station had lost its last human employee the previous year.
Tama, who famously strolled around the station in her official railway cap uniform, quickly drew crowds of visitors, fuelling a thriving merchandising business and revitalising the local economy.
The cat was credited with boosting the number of people travelling along the Kishigawa Line by 55,000, adding an additional 1.1 billion yen (5.7million) to the local economy.
Tama was promoted to deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in 2013 (AFP/Getty)
The popular felines successes resulted in an award from the prefectural governor of Wakayama in 2008 and a promotion to deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in 2013.
Among those mourning her death from heart failure was Yoshinobu Nisaka, who said: Tama won a great popularity at home and abroad as a super star of tourism. At the news of her loss, I express my deep sorrow and great gratitude.
The railway company is planning to hold a funeral at the station this weekend for the late cat, who will reportedly be succeeded by her feline stationmaster apprentice Nitama.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:15:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Unarmed black man fatally shot by Baltimore police after domestic disturbance</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753a7/sc/42/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1170A0A370A0CUnarmed0Eblack0Eman0Efatally0Eshot0Eby0EBaltimore0Epolice0Eafter0Edomestic0Edisturbance0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Officers said they shot Spencer Lee McCain believing he had a weapon after being called to a home from which he was barred by court order</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Unarmed black man fatally shot by Baltimore police after domestic disturbance
Officers said they shot Spencer Lee McCain believing he had a weapon after    being called to a home from which he was barred by court order
Baltimore County Police officers at the scene in Owings MillsPhoto: NBC
By AP
9:15AM BST 26 Jun 2015
An unarmed black man was fatally shot on Thursday by officers in suburban Baltimore who thought he had a weapon when they were called to a home from which he was barred by protective order, the police chief said.
The death follows that of a 25-year-old black man, Freddie Gray, who died in April from an injury suffered in the custody of Baltimore city police, which prompted protests and rioting . And it comes amid a national debate over the treatment of African-Americans at the hands of police, after high-profile deaths of black men in Ferguson, Missouri, and New York City.
Spencer Lee McCain, 41, was shot about 1 am at the home in Owings Mills while a woman who said he threatened to beat her and her two young children were there, Baltimore County Police Chief Jim Johnson said at a news conference.
Three officers were on the scene, and all fired as McCain was in a "defensive position" and they thought he had a weapon, Chief Johnson said. But he said no weapon was found.Two of the officers are white, and one is black, police said. All are on administrative leave. Police said the incident began when one of the children in the home called his grandmother, who called 911 and asked police to go there.
An officer who arrived heard screams and called for backup, Chief Johnson said. He said 19 casings were found at the scene, but it wasn't clear how many times McCain was hit.
Police said the woman had head injuries, cuts, bruises and swelling. Chief Johnson said she told detectives that McCain said to her, "You're going to get the beating you deserve."
Sixteen to 20 domestic violence calls had been made to that home address since 2012, police spokesman Cpl. John Wachter said.
According to 2013 census figures, 27.5 percent of Baltimore County's population is black and 64.1 percent is white. The police chief and county executive are white.
As of February, black people made up less than 13 percent of the county's 1,868-member police force.
A medical examiner ruled this week that the death of Freddie Gray was a homicide, after he suffered a "high-energy injury," most likely caused when a Baltimore city police van he was riding in suddenly slowed down. A grand jury indicted six officers on various charges; one officer faces the most serious charge of second-degree "depraved-heart" murder. They have pleaded not guilty.
The report said Gray's death could not be ruled an accident and is instead a homicide because officers didn't follow safety procedures "through acts of omission."
Police and an attorney for the Gray family have said previously that Gray suffered a severe spine injury .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:42:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nine dead after plane crashes in Alaska</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47974dc3/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1170A0A2630CNine0Edead0Eafter0Eplane0Ecrashes0Ein0EAlaska0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Light aircraft carrying holidaymakers on a cruise crashes near Misty Fjords</Description>
        <MainBody>Nine dead after plane crashes in Alaska
Light aircraft carrying holidaymakers on a cruise crashes near Misty Fjords
A DeHavilland Beaver float plane flying the Alaska Coast Range (file photo)Photo:  Alamy
By David Millward , US Correspondent
7:42AM BST 26 Jun 2015
Nine people have been killed after a light aircraft crashed in Alaska , US police said.
The eight passengers were all holidaymakers who had been on a Holland America cruise.
The identity and nationality of those on board the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter single-engine prop plane was not disclosed. The plane crashed near Ketchikan, the Federal Aviation Administration said.
The Holland America Line cruise ship Westerdam sits in dock in Ketchikan, Alaska (AP)
Emergency crews were able to reach the aircraft that crashed against a granite rock face and confirm the deceased, but weather in the fjords prevented recovery efforts, Megan Peters from Alaska's department of public safety said.
"Due to inclement weather, the body recovery effort will not be attempted until tomorrow," she said in a statement.
According to local reports the weather in the region was heavily overcast.
An FAA webcam in Misty Fjords took this image around the time of the crash
The passengers had all been on board the MS Westerdam on an eight-day cruise which had departed from Seattle.
Promech Air confirmed in a statement that the eight passengers and pilot were killed when the plane went down during a tour of the Misty Fjords area near the town of Ketchikan on Thursday afternoon
 Alaska plane crash leaves four dead including infant
"We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those on board the plane and their families," Holland America said in a written statement.
The National Transportation Safety Board said on Twitter it was sending a "go-team" to the crash site to investigate.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:25:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Devoted couple married for 67 years die within two hours of each other</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47965b28/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Caustraliaandthepacific0Cnewzealand0C1170A0A2640CDevoted0Ecouple0Emarried0Efor0E670Eyears0Edie0Ewith0Etwo0Ehours0Eof0Eeach0Eother0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Hugh Nees, 94, died of cancer while his wife Joan, 92, suffered a stroke</Description>
        <MainBody>Devoted couple married for 67 years die within two hours of each other
Hugh Nees, 94,  died of cancer while his wife Joan, 92, suffered a stroke
Hugh and Joan Nees in their home in Paraparaumu, north of Wellington, New Zealand, in April 2014. Photo: Fairfax Media/Getty Images
By Paul Chapman, Wellington
Comments
A devoted couple who were married for 67 years have died of natural causes within two hours of each other, in the same room at a New Zealand rest home.
Family members said Hugh Nees, 94, and his wife Joan, 92, could not bear to spend even a day apart, and had told them they did not want to live without each other.
Mr Nees, who had cancer, died first in the double room they shared at Eldon Lodge rest home in Paraparaumu, north of Wellington. His wife suffered a stroke.
Hugh and Joan Nees on their wedding day
They had moved into the rest home from their house at nearby Waikanae just over two months ago, because of declining health.
Mr Nees was a retired Baptist minister.
 Couple married for 65 years die moments apart
"They were strong Christians and therefore they knew where they were going, and they had no problem about going there," their son Robert Nees said.
He told the New Zealand Herald that his mother would not have known that her husband had preceded her, even though the couple "were in the same room, lying beside each other", surrounded by family.
"Their departure, it's sad but happy. Life wasn't easy for the last little while and that's over, that's all good."
Asked whether they might have had any premonition of their close departure, their son said: "It's so hard to know. It almost seems like it, doesn't it?"
Their daughter Joy Reid said the timing of their deaths was a miracle.
They said they wanted to die together, and I didn't expect it to really happen. It was just perfect for them.
The couple had five children, two of whom died before them.
They also lost a grandson, 31-year-old Nicholas Heyward, who was shot dead by robbers on a motorcycle in Argentina last year.
Mr and Mrs Nees were both keen gardeners and played golf in their younger days.
A service to celebrate their lives will be held on June 30 at the Baptist church in Waikanae.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
