<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Telegraph">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:39:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why has France become a target for recent terror attacks?</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf01/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C1170A11640CWhy0Ehas0EFrance0Ebecome0Ea0Etarget0Efor0Erecent0Eterror0Eattacks0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Following the decapitation of a man in Grenoble, The Telegraph's Henry Samuel explains why France has become a target for terror attacks in recent months</Description>
        <MainBody>France
Why has France become a target for recent terror attacks?
Following the decapitation of a man in Grenoble, The Telegraph's Henry Samuel    explains why France has become a target for terror attacks in recent months
By Telegraph Video, contains video from APTN
1:39PM BST 26 Jun 2015
A man has been decapitated during a suspected Islamist terror attack in France .
A message in Arabic was reportedly found on the victim's head, which had been pinned to a fence.
Two attackers arrived at a gas factory near Grenoble in a car, bearing banners written in Arabic, and set off explosions.
Grenoble attack: Man found beheaded and Islamist flag raised above factory in France - latest
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier. Credit: AFP/Getty
France 's anti-terror prosecutor said the attack was carried out by "a terrorist group" and it is understood one man has been arrested.
The decapitation comes a few months after the Islamist attacks in and around Paris in which 17 people were killed.
The Telegraph's France correspondent Henry Samuel explains why France has become a target for terror attacks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Grenoble attack: Man found beheaded and Islamist flag raised above factory in France - latest</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dcf/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C1170A0A5130CGrenoble0Eattack0EMan0Efound0Ebeheaded0Eand0EIslamist0Eflag0Eraised0Eabove0EFrench0Efactory0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>There were explosions reportedly heard near the industrial gas factory near Grenoble, south-eastern France where one person is believed to be dead and several hurt</Description>
        <MainBody>This page will automatically update every 30 secondsOn Off
 A decapitated body was found near a gas factory in south-eastern France, near Grenoble
 There was Arabic writing on the head
 A man suspected has been arrested and identified
 An attacker is believed to have killed one person and injured several others
 The attacker set off several explosions, a legal source says
Latest
13.45
French anti-terror raid police are currently raiding the home of Yacine Sali, the suspect arrested this morning at the factory, Henry Samuel in Paris writes.
A second suspect said to be "close" to him has been arrested, the interior ministry says.
Anti-terror police currently raiding home of arrested France factory attack suspect Yacine Salhi #Isre
 Henry Samuel (@H_E_Samuel) June 26, 2015
"France has been struck again by terror," the country's prime minister, Manuel Valls, said as he was cutting short a trip to South America to return to Paris.
"The terrorists' threats and blind horrors spare no nation. My thoughts go to the victims of Isre and the victims in Tunisia," he said from Colombia.
13.30
Sgolne Royale, a French socialist politician, has been speaking to reporters, James Rothwell writes.
She said: "This was an abominable attack... my thoughts go first of all to the families of the victims and the employees of this factory, who have no doubt been profoundly traumatised.
"The French government and authorities have reacted by increasing security at other sensitive sites. I would like to also say, as a member of the government, that unity among the French at this tragic moment is absolutely essential."
French Gendarmes block the access road to the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier (Reuters)
13.17
France's prime minister said an attack on a factory Friday was "Islamist terrorism," announcing he was cutting short a visit to South America to deal with the crisis.
"Islamist terrorism has hit France again," Manuel Valls told a press conference in Colombia's capital Bogota, adding that he would take part by telephone in an emergency meeting called by M r Hollande, then rush back to France.
The suspect arrested is reportedly married with three kids.
"Brave" fireman "neutralised" suspect who placed him "out of harm's way" says int min Bernard Cazeneuve as "second man arrested". #Isere
 Henry Samuel (@H_E_Samuel) June 26, 2015
13.12
The Telegraph's James Rothwell has been looking at French media reaction:
Jean-Jack Queyranne, president of the Rhne-Alpes region, told Le Figaro: "I feel a sense of horror in the face of the barbarism that has just taken place in Isre in the heart of our region.
First of all I would like to express my solidarity with the victims, their families and those close to them.
"We must be careful to ensure that fear does not become widespread. As in January [during the Charlie Hebdo massacre] the nation must unite as a whole to face up to this danger. For it is the nation that must combat terror."
French police and firefighters gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier (AFP/Getty Images)
12.59
Germany stands united with France against "terror's blind hate" and in defence of "free society", Frank-Walter Steinmeier, the foreign minister, said
Mr Steinmeier said he was appalled by the "shocking news of a heinous murder and an assault with several injured", calling it an "act of terror and fanaticism which we condemn in the strongest terms".
Barack Obama has been briefed on the attack at a US gas company in France, a senior administration official said, providing no further details.
12.30
Mr Cazeneuve says the suspected accomplices in the attack are being held by police. The man arrested has been known to security services since 2006 but surveillance stopped in 2008. He has no criminal record.
The interior minister said he had been filed as possibly being radicalised.
The French attack suspect had 'link' to Salafist movement, AFP reports.
Suspect named as Yacine Sali, 30. "Others who may have been involved arrested", says int min Cazeneuve #Isre
 Henry Samuel (@H_E_Samuel) June 26, 2015
12.20
BREAKING: Bernard Cazeneuve has named the suspect arrested as Yacine Sali.
12.09
Mr Hollande learnt of the terrorist attack just as the European Council was reconvening before 10am, Matthew Holehouse in Brussels writes. Here are some more comments in full from Mr Hollande.
The interior minister and public prosecutor "immediately" went to the site. The plant is under further protection and "all measures" are being taken, he said.
Bernard Cazeneuve will speak later to provide limited "useful" information.
Our thoughts go to the victim. It is a matter of solidarity. The European Council has expressed solidarity.
"There is a lot of emotion but it cannot be the only answer. Other answers are protection, deterrence. And the necessity to spread our values and never give in to fear, and to shoulder our responsibilities in all circumstances.
"It is not about spreading suspicion, but doing our job, protecting our people while finding out the truth and the individuals responsible for such actions."
Mr Hollande is to hold a meeting at the Elysee at 3.30pm.
12.01
More detail from Mr Hollande's press conference just now from Matthew Holehouse in Brussels.
Mr Hollande confirmed one person has died and two injured. He said a suspect has been arrested and identified.
He explained some of what happened during the attack and said a car driven by one person, maybe two, to the factory and their target was a gas bottle factory.
"This attack was in a vehicle driven by one person, perhaps accompanied by another."
Their intention was to provoke an explosion, he said.
A body was found decapitated, and two injured as well as a message found. "It is a terrorist attack - there is no doubt about it," Mr Hollande said
He will return to Paris to oversee the operation and said "huge" numbers of troops have been deployed to protect other facilities
He said: "We will never give in to fear."
11.54
Donald Tusk, the European Council president, has offered his condolences.
I offer my sincere condolences and solidarity to @fhollande and the people of France following the attack in #Isre .
 Donald Tusk (@eucopresident) June 26, 2015
11.49
President Francois Hollande is speaking and says troops have been deployed in the region to prevent another attack.
Earlier he said the attacker had been identified but said there was an "ongoing investigation". He said there were one or two assailants.
"Our thoughts go to the victims. The European Council expressed his solidarity - we remember what happened in our country and other countries."
He also said: "The attack was of a terrorist nature given that a corpse with Islamist inscriptions were found."
11.48
Two men are believed to have driven into the main gate before 10am. The second suspect is an unconfirmed entity.
The car then drove around in circles and a person inside threw gas cylinders around the main yard, Mail Online reported.
Local prosecuting sources said a man jumped out of the car and then "decapitated a man".
Emergency personnel work at the scene of a suspected Islamist attack, outside the Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier (EPA)
11.38
Alain Jupp, the mayor of Bordeaux, has condemned the attacks saying that France "must make every effort to protect its citizens".
"The terrorist threat is at a maximum," he says.
La menace terroriste est maximum. L'attentat en Isre nous le rappelle hlas! L'Etat doit tout mettre en uvre pour protger ses citoyens.
 Alain Jupp (@alainjuppe) June 26, 2015
Mr Hollande is returning home early from the EU summit on Friday, officials said.
"He will return early this afternoon and is in constant contact with Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve and the security services," the official said, adding that he would make a statement to the press in Brussels before 1100 GMT.
"The president saw the first images of the attack on the 24-news channels with Angela Merkel, German chancellor, beside him, who was visibly shocked," an official added.
The two leaders had just ended a short meeting with Alexis Tsipras, the Greek prime minister.
(Pic: Le Dauphine )
11.32
The man arrested is refusing to talk, according to BFM TV reporters. The channel reports that the individual has no papers that can identify him thus police have not yet been able to either.
A security official said the torso was found near the site of the explosion but that the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
Two flags, one white and one black and both with Arabic inscriptions, were found at the scene, Associated Press reported.
11.30
David Cameron, the Prime Minister, has spoken to Mr Hollande to convey his sympathies, writes Steven Swinford, Deputy Political Editor.
The Prime Minister has spoken to Francois Hollande, the French President, at the EU summit in Brussels about the terror attack. A British official said:
He expressed his sympathies for what looks like an appalling incident there. It clearly looks like an extremely concerning situation and our thoughts are with all those that are affected by it."
The interior minister has now arrived at the factory as this pictures shows from Le Dauphine .
11.17
Francois Hollande is expected to return to France. Sky News are reporting that police are still looking for a man near the factory earlier today.
11.15
Some background from Josie Ensor about Air Products.
It is interesting to note that the president of the company targeted in the attack, Air Products, is a Shia Iranian named Seifi Ghasemi.
Iran supports Bashar al-Assad's regime in Syria, which is battling against Sunni Islamic State militants.
The scene in Grenoble via Le Dauphine .
11.10
A video from the scene via ledauphine.com.
France's anti-terror prosecutors have opened an inquiry for "murder and attempted murder in a group in relation to a terrorist organisation", writes Henry Samuel in Paris.
Itele cites police sources as describing as "false" reports that the man arrested is known to French intelligence services.
The 40-odd employees in the factory have been evacuated.
Witnesses at the scene said there was more than one attacker involved but this is unconfirmed.
11.05
What we know so far from AFP:
A suspected Islamist attacker pinned a decapitated head covered with Arabic writing to the gates of a gas factory in eastern France on Friday before being arrested, police say
The suspect entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices, the source said at around 10am local time
Police said it was unclear whether the attacker was acting alone, or had accomplices
A man thought to be the person who carried out the attack has been arrested - it is reported he is known to the security services
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minister said is on his way to the scene, his office say
11.02
The man arrested reportedly said he was a member of Islamic State.
10.56
France's president and prime minister are both currently abroad, but it looks like Franois Hollande, the president, may be returning prematurely from Brussels to handle the crisis, Henry Samuel writes.
10.55
This is the factory where the attack took place earlier today.
Banners with Arabic writing were found near the body, one official has told Associated Press.
10.52
French authorities have officially opened a terrorist investigation into today's attack.
10.48
Air Products, the American company targeted in the attack has 21,000 employees, according to its website, and sold industrial gases including nitrogen, oxygen, hydrogen, The Telegraph's Josie Ensor writes.
10.45
Francois Hollande, the president, is in Brussels for the EU summit but the meetings have begun without the leader.
We do not know yet if he will be returning to France.
Manuel Valls, the prime minister, has said that there will be tightened security measures on 'sensitive' sites after the attack.
Mr Valls also called for "heightened vigilance" at all sensitive sites in the Rhne-Alpes area.
"the head of the victim was found hanging on the fence of the Company enclosure" Oh damn... http://t.co/qfl2xan3MO #frankrijk #attack
 Rick Schipper (@Enoxiz) June 26, 2015
10.43
Sky News has said the arrested man is believed to be 30 years old and known to France's anti-terrorist police (DGSI).
There was Arabic writing on severed head pinned to French factory gates, a legal source tells AFP.
10.39
Here is what we know so far:
Two men brandishing what appears to be an Islamic State flag launched an attack on a chemical factoy in Isre, southeastern France, on Friday morning, Henry Samuel writes.
The Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier produces industrial gas and is considered a sensitive site, said a Erwann Binet, Socialist MP for the Isre dpartement. The factory is on the outskirts of Lyon.
The two assailants rammed a vehicle carrying bottles of gas into the Air Products factory in Saint Quentin, in the south-eastern Isre area.
One was brandishing what appears to be an Islamic State flag.
A strong explosion ensued. According to the interior ministry, two employees were injured in the blast. Another man was found decapitated near the factory. According to iTele, the rolling news channel, he was not a factory employee.
One man, thought to be one of the assailants, has been arrested, said the interior ministry.
France's elite GIGN anti-terror police have been sent to the site.
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minsiter, said he is on his way to the area "immediately".
We are all in a state of shock as we didnt expect any attack in our territory, said Mr Binet.
A police source cited by RTL radio said "other attacks cannot be ruled out".
10.33
Le Dauphin Liber reports that a man has been arrested but it is unknown if he is the suspected attacker. AFP cites a source saying that it is the attacker.
According to Sky News, there could be two attackers.
Meanwhile, the Local France reports that the decapitated man was not an employee at the factory.
The attack is believed to have taken place at 10am local time, 9am BST.
10.30
More from AFP's source:
"According to the initial findings of the enquiry, one or several individuals on board a vehicle, drove into the factory. An explosion then took place," said one of the sources.
"The decapitated body of a person was found nearby the factory but we do not yet know whether the body was transported to the place or not," added this source, adding that a "flag with Arabic writing on it was found on the scene."
According to a local French newspaper a man's head was chopped off and then hung on fence of the factory in St Quentin Fallavier. This remains unconfirmed.
BREAKING: Man arrested after "Islamist attack" in central France - http://t.co/pHSJoV49Ca pic.twitter.com/1yPISpnsFY
 The Local France (@TheLocalFrance) June 26, 2015
10.26
There are reports that the factory belongs to Air Products. French media report that the suspected attacker rammed his car into the factory.
10.23
The explosions are believed to have been set off in the factory using gas canisters.
10.20
Hello and welcome to the Telegraph's live coverage of the attack on a French factory where a decapitated body was found nearby.
An attacker carrying an Islamist flag killed one person and injured several others today at a gas factory in eastern France, according to a legal source, AFP reported.
The suspected attacker entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices, the source said.
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minister, said he would go "immediately" to the scene, his office said.
The attack comes six months after the Charlie Hebdo attack and the three-day siege in Paris during which 17 people were killed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:24:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italian grandfather finally completes middle school education - at the age of 91</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf02/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Citaly0C1170A0A7360CItalian0Egrandfather0Efinally0Ecompletes0Emiddle0Eschool0Eeducation0Eat0Ethe0Eage0Eof0E910Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A large family and a hard working life meant he never had time to complete his education</Description>
        <MainBody>Follow
In a case of better late than never, a grandfather in Italy has finished middle school with flying colours at the age of 91.
Nicola Torello, who as a 19-year-old served in the Italian army in Greece during the Second World War, made up for lost time by returning to school in his home town of Chieti in the mountainous Abruzzo region of central Italy.
A large family and a life of hard work as a tailor meant that he never finished his basic education as a child.
Mr Torello, who turns 92 in October, received top marks in his maths exam and even managed to learn some English for an oral test.
He also wrote an essay about his wartime experiences, when he served with an Italian army brigade in Greece.
He said he returned to school in part to help him get over the death of his wife, Licia.
His four children and six grand children turned up at the school to see him awarded his school certificate.
Even the mayor of Chieti came to offer his congratulations.
Buoyed by the success, Mr Torello now wants to learn how to use a computer.
He said he had remained fit and active by swimming twice a week and by continuing to drive a white Fiat 600 around town.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:20:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia attack: deadly shooting in front of tourist beach hotel in Sousse - latest</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf05/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1170A10A430CTunisia0Eattack0Edeadly0Eshooting0Ein0Efront0Eof0Etourist0Ebeach0Ehotel0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 27 dead after gunman opened fire in terrorist attack on popular beach resort in Sousse, Tunisia</Description>
        <MainBody>This page will automatically update every 30 secondsOn Off
 Gunmen killed in shoot-out
 Tourists gunned down on popular beach
 Pictures circulating on social media of bodies on the beach
 Attacks comes as 12 killed in Isil bomb on Kuwait mosque
Latest
13.46
One of the hotels targeted in the attack was the Imperial Marahaba. It's promoted by Thomson Holidays, among others, and has 366 rooms over five floors. It's an all-inclusive resort, described as a "grand beachside hotel".
13.42
Susan Rickett, who was staying at the Palm Marina Hotel near Sousse, said: 'My sister was talking to someone who had seen some people shooting and had shot someone on a sun bed but we don't know if that's true.
'It sounded like a machine gun going off... and there was a kind of explosion a little bit later.
'They're saying its going on in the hotel next to us. Police were chasing some men, that's all I know.'
13.40
The Interior Ministry has just revised the number of dead up to 27. Spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said security forces intervened immediately and killed one of the attackers, while the other fled the scene.
13.22
Another British tourist close to the scene of a deadly attack on a Tunisian beach resort has described his experiences.
Gary Pine said he was on the beach and heard what "we thought was firecrackers going off" 100 yards away, followed by an explosion from the next hotel complex along.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach," he said. He said his son said he had seen someone get shot on the beach.
He said guests at his hotel were first told to lock themselves in their rooms, and later to gather in the lobby.
Tunisia is popular with British tourists. The Foreign Office says 424,707 British nationals visited Tunisia in 2014.
13.22
Tunisia's Interior Ministry says two gunmen opened fire on a beach in the coastal resort of Sousse Friday, killing at least seven people.
Pictures posted on Instagram appeared to shot a couple dead on the beach with a couple dead with gunshot wounds to the head.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
It is one of the North African country's most popular beach resorts, drawing tourists from Europe and neighbouring countries. Tunisia has been high alert since Islamist gunmen attacked the Bardo museum in Tunis in March, killing a group of foreign visitors.
13.24
The body of one gunman lay at the scene with a Kalashnikov assault rifle after he was shot in an exchange of gunfire with police, the source said.
British tourist David Schofield told Sky News that he was by the pool when he heard "quite a large explosion" and guests started to run back towards the hotel. "We heard people saying there were guns on the beach. People were shooting on the beach," he said.
"People are running around the hotel. No-one has really been told what to do."
13.17
At least 27 people have been killed in an attack on a beach hotel in the Tunisian city of Sousse, and at least one gunman has been killed in a shoot-out.
The attack, which took place around 12pm local time, was said to have taken place outside the five-star hotel the Imperial Marhaba hotel.
"The operation was carried out in two hotels. There are seven dead, maybe more," ministry spokesman Mohamed Ali Aroui told Mosaique radio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:18:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Barack Obama came to raise his voice on race</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf06/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C116999470CHow0EBarack0EObama0Ecame0Eto0Eraise0Ehis0Evoice0Eon0Erace0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>As Barack Obama speaks in Charleston in the wake of one of the most vile racially motivated attacks in America's history, we look back at his previous remarks on race</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
How Barack Obama came to raise his voice on race
As Barack Obama speaks in Charleston in the wake of one of the most vile    racially motivated attacks in America's history, we look back at his    previous remarks on race
By Peter Foster, and David Lawler in Washington
1:18PM BST 26 Jun 2015
On Friday, President Obama will mourn with the city of Charleston, South Carolina, where nine people were killed last week at a historic black church. He'll deliver a eulogy at the funeral for Rev. Clementa Pinckney, a state lawmaker and pastor of Emanuel African Methodist Church.
Mr Obama made history when he became Americas first black president, but for much of his presidency he has walked a fine line on the contentious issue of race.
Mr Obama was careful to note he would be a president for all Americans and not simply a black president focusing on racial issues.
It was a position he first outlined in his 1995 memoir, Dreams from my Father, in which he wrote: My identity might begin with the fact of my race, but it didn't, couldn't end there. At least that's what I would choose to believe.
Mr Obama was criticised throughout his first term by some more traditional voices in the black community for failing to do more to root out Americas still-endemic racial discrimination.
However following his re-election in 2012 several high-profile incidents, starting with the shooting of the unarmed black teenager Trayvon Martin, have led Mr Obama to engage much more explicitly on the need to tackle Americas racial divide.
Here we chart the evolution of Mr Obamas public statements on the race issue since 2008.
March, 2008: A more perfect Union
In early 2008, during his first presidential campaign, Mr Obama came under fire for his links to the Rev Jeremiah Wright, a fiery black Chicago pastor who had exclaimed God damn America! in a sermon.
With his campaign suddenly reeling, Mr Obama delivered what became known as his more perfect union speech  a speech that is still widely ranked as one of his absolute best.
His message  embodied in his own candidacy and life story - was fundamentally hopeful.
I believe deeply that we cannot solve the challenges of our time unless we solve them together - unless we perfect our union by understanding that we may have different stories, but we hold common hopes; that we may not look the same and we may not have come from the same place, but we all want to move in the same direction - towards a better future for of children and our grandchildren.
July, 2013: Trayvon Martin  could have been my son
After Florida neighbourhood watch captain George Zimmerman was cleared of the murder of the unarmed black teenager Trayvon Martin in July 2013, Mr Obama respected the verdict, but spoke passionately about the black experience in what was widely seen as a departure from his typical language on race issues.
You know, when Trayvon Martin was first shot I said that this could have been my son. Another way of saying that is Trayvon Martin could have been me 35 years ago.... There are very few African American men in this country who haven't had the experience of being followed when they were shopping in a department store. That includes me. There are very few African American men who haven't had the experience of walking across the street and hearing the locks click on the doors of cars. That happens to me -- at least before I was a senator."
August, 2014: Ferguson shooting - "This is an issue for America"
The shooting of Michael Brown, an unarmed black teenager in Ferguson, Missouri prompted outbreaks of violence in cities across America, uniting protestors under the banner of black lives matter.
As the streets of Ferguson burned over the decision by a Grand Jury not to prosecute the officer involved, Mr Obama went on television to appeal for calm, but his lofty remarks were at stark odds with the passions unfolding on the streets.
We need to recognize that this is not just an issue for Ferguson, this is an issue for America. We have made enormous progress in race relations over the course of the past several decades. I've witnessed that in my own life. And to deny that progress I think is to deny Americas capacity for change."
June, 2015: Charleston- 'societies don't change overnight'
After nine people were left dead in a racially motivated attack on a black church in South Carolina, Mr Obama again found hope amid the horror.
The fact that this took place in a black church obviously also raises questions about a dark part of our history. This is not the first time that black churches have been attacked, and we know the hatred across races and faiths pose a particular threat to our democracy and our ideals.The good news is I am confident that the outpouring of unity and strength and fellowship and love across Charleston today, from all races, from all faiths, from all places of worship, indicates the degree to which those old vestiges of hatred can be overcome.
But in an interview more noted for the language he used, Mr Obama acknowledged the depth of the challenge.
It's not just a matter of it not being polite to say n----- in public That's not the measure of whether racism still exists or not. It's not just a matter of overt discrimination. Societies don't, overnight, completely erase everything that happened 200 to 300 years prior."
Barack Obama never pretended he could bring an end to racial prejudice in America. But he has confronted it with growing force in his second term, without abandoning his vision of the more perfect union to come.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:35:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japanese women go ape over 'handsome' gorilla named Shabani</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798a476/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cjapan0C1170A0A4270CJapanese0Ewomen0Ego0Eape0Eover0Ehandsome0Egorilla0Enamed0EShabani0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Japan
Japanese women go ape over 'handsome' gorilla named Shabani
Giant male gorilla Shabani, weighing around 180kg, at the Higashiyama Zoo in Nagoya in Aichi prefecture, central JapanPhoto: AFP/Getty
By Flynn Murphy, Sydney
Comments
An Australian-raised gorilla is winning hearts in Japan where his good-looks have made him a hit with female zoo-goers.
Shabani, a western lowland gorilla born in the Netherlands and raised in a Sydney zoo, is popular for his handsome looks and dramatic poses, with local admirers dubbing him an ikemen, or good-looking man.
Shabani is popular for his handsome looks (AFP/Getty)
The gorilla lives in Higashiyama Zoo and Botanical Gardens in Nagoya, Japan, where he moved in 2007 after spending his formative years at Taronga Zoo on the shores of Sydney Harbour.
And while the 18-year-old has local women enthralled, Shabani may have been a late bloomer.
I have seen quite an early photo of him and he's not the handsome man that he is today, Madeleine Smitham, a media relations officer at Taronga Zoo, told the Telegraph.
Shabani lives in Higashiyama Zoo and Botanical Gardens in Nagoya (AFP/Getty)
He certainly didnt have quite the same following here that he has in Japan.
On Twitter many Japanese women have tweeted praise and pictures of Shabani, Mail Online reported , including one women who wrote: "I went to Higashiyama Zoo. This hot Shabani ikemen was certainly handsome."
Another female visitor shared an image of the zoo with her friends and the caption: "The meeting of going to see the handsome gorilla Shabani... it was a fun holiday."
Shabani arrived at Taronga Zoo as a baby with another silverback, Kibabu, who is now living out his retirement at a zoo on the NSW south coast, explained another staffer, Paul Fahy.
Obviously western lowland gorillas are a critically endangered species, so Tarongas part of a coordinated breeding programme. The decision was made for Shabani to go to Japan as part of the breeding program, which is all about ensuring genetic diversity, Fahy said.
Shabani weighs around 180kg (AFP/Getty)
This is not the first time Shabani has gone viral. There was a video a couple of years ago of him tightrope walking at the zoo in Japan, Fahy said.
Back in Sydney, Shabani may have some competition. Weve now got a young aspiring silverback here now, who we like to think is quite dashing in his own way, Fahy said.
Thats Kibali, a French-born western lowland gorilla.
And in perhaps heartening news for the men of Japan, there is currently no plan to send Kibali overseas.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:17:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China warns Glastonbury organisers after Dalai Lama's invite</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798a477/sc/11/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Ctibet0C1170A0A90A50CChina0Ewarns0EGlastonbury0Eorganisers0Eafter0EDalai0ELamas0Einvite0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Tibet's spiritual leader has been invited to speak at the festival, much to the ire of China</Description>
        <MainBody>China warns Glastonbury organisers after Dalai Lama's invite
Tibet's spiritual leader has been invited to speak at the festival, much to    the ire of China
China is far from impressed with festival organisers for inviting the Dalai Lama to Glastonbury 2015Photo: Paul Faith/PA
The office of the Dalai Lama said on Thursday that the Dalai Lama would speak at the Glastonbury Festival during his trip to Britain. He is not due to meet any officials.
His Holiness the Dalai Lama is to visit Glastonbury Festival on Sunday http://t.co/Nm8irCL5jx pic.twitter.com/8y8kehepzu
 Glastonbury Festival (@GlastoFest) June 25, 2015
The Dalai Lama is also going to Britain again in September, just ahead of Chinese President Xi Jinping's trip to the country in October. Xi's state visit is the first to Britain in a decade by a Chinese head of state.
Beijing denounces the Dalai Lama as a dangerous separatist who wants an independent Tibet. He denies espousing violence and says he only wants genuine autonomy for his Himalayan homeland.
Foreign Ministry spokesman Lu Kang told a daily news briefing that he was not aware of the details of what the Dalai Lama was doing at the Glastonbury Festival.
Lu said, however, that China's position on the "international scuttling about of the 14th Dalai Lama to serve his political aims" is consistent.
"China resolutely opposes any country, organisation, body or individual giving any kind of platform to the 14th Dalai Lama to engage in anti-China splittist activities," Lu said.
"It's a decision for the festival-goers and the Dalai Lama," A British government source said, when asked about China's caution that inviting him to visit one of Europe's largest music festivals was tantamount to giving him a platform to engage in anti-China activities.
China routinely denounces any country that hosts the Dalai Lama. In 2012, British Prime Minister David Cameron had to put his trip to China on hold after Beijing took offence at him holding a meeting with the Dalai Lama.
China has ruled Tibet with an iron fist since troops "peacefully liberated" the region in 1950. The Dalai Lama fled into exile in India in 1959 after an abortive uprising against Chinese rule.
Representatives of the Nobel Peace laureate held rounds of talks with China until 2010, but formal dialogue has stalled amid leadership changes in Beijing and a crackdown in Tibet.
Organiser Emily Eavis welcomed the announcement (Rex)
 Glastonbury 2015: festival weather
The announcement has been welcomed by Emily Eavis, daughter of Mike, who founded the festival on his farm in Somerset.
"We're honoured to welcome the Dalai Lama to Glastonbury 2015, she said. He will be talking in the Green Fields and exploring the farm this Sunday as part of his trip to the UK.
What a special moment for the Festival!"
The Dalai Lama has visited Britain regularly since walking over the Himalayas into exile from Tibet as the 1959 uprising against Chinese rule was crushed.
However, meeting international leaders - including David Cameron, the prime minister - has become increasingly difficult, as China threatens retaliation against countries that give him a political presence on the world stage.
The Dalai Lama with David Cameron and Nick Clegg
Relations between Britain and Beijing are only just now recovering from a brief meeting at St Pauls Cathedral between the Dalai Lama, Mr Cameron and then deputy prime minister Nick Clegg in 2012.
Instead, he has concentrated on taking his message direct to supporters, including at events like Glastonbury. The Eavis family may now be considering what form Chinese retaliation against Somerset could take.
 Happy Glasto campers prepare for music and mud, in pictures
The Dalai Lama, whose birthday is on July 6, will probably be the oldest act to put in an appearance at Glastonbury - but not by much.
Patti Smith is 68, and Paul Weller 57, while Mick Jagger was almost 70 when he played at Glastonbury in 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:16:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>For sale: Tom Cruise's $59m ski lodge</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753a8/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctravel0Csnowandski0Cpicture0Egalleries0C116983380CFor0Esale0ETom0ECruises0E59m0Eski0Elodge0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Take a look around the Hollywood hero's glamorous ski pad, on the market for a cool $59m</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE...
Hollywood action man Tom Cruise is selling his seven-bedroom, nine-bathroom    luxury ski lodge in Telluride, Colorado. Advertised by a local estate agent    and boasting its own helipad and private airport, as well as money-cant-buy    views of the area's National Forest, let's see what a mere $59,000,000 will    get you.
--
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:25:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Celebrity Sightings: Kimye, Maria Sharapova and Reese Witherspoon</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd3/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Ccelebritynews0C1170A0A60A90CCelebrity0ESightings0EKimye0EMaria0ESharapova0Eand0EReese0EWitherspoon0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Starring: Kimye, Maria Sharapova and Reese Witherspoon</Description>
        <MainBody>Kim Kardashian and hubby Kanye West treated themselves to a fancy meal at Hakassan in London's swanky Mayfair ahead of him headlining the world-famous Glastonbury Festival in rural SomersetPicture: Rex Features

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:25:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pictures of the day: 26 June 2015</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753ad/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Cpicturesoftheday0C1170A0A40A70CPictures0Eof0Ethe0Eday0E260EJune0E20A150Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Today: A handsome gorilla, a flapping flamingo and a Glastonbury hotel</Description>
        <MainBody>A walrus wallows in shallow water off the coast of Svalbard in the ArcticPicture: Franco Banfi/Solent News

Comments are closed on this picture gallery.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:25:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suicide bomber blows up vehicle in Kobane</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd5/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctelegraphtv0C1170A0A7350CSuicide0Ebomber0Eblows0Eup0Evehicle0Ein0EKobane0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Video footage shows bomb exploding on Thursday in Kobane, Syria</Description>
        <MainBody>Suicide bomber blows up vehicle in Kobane
Video footage shows bomb exploding on Thursday in Kobane, Syria
By Sophie Jamieson, video source: APTN
11:25AM BST 26 Jun 2015
CCTV footage captured the moment a suicide bomber blew up a vehicle in Kobane, Syria .
Video from a surveillance camera shows a pick up truck driving down a road before exploding.
The attack came on Thursday as Islamic State forces re-entered Kobane at the Turkish border on Thursday and clashed with Kurdish YPG forces in the town.
At least 146 civilians are believed to have been killed in the latest violence in Kobane and a nearby village, making it the second-biggest massacre by the hardline group in the country, a conflict monitor said on Friday.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:20:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France terror attack in Grenoble - watch live</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd6/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C1170A0A6370CFrance0Eterror0Eattack0Ein0EGrenoble0Ewatch0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Watch live police response after explosions were reportedly heard at a gas factory near Grenoble, eastern France, where one person is believed to be dead and several hurt</Description>
        <MainBody>France
France terror attack in Grenoble - watch live
Watch live police response after explosions were reportedly heard at a gas    factory near Grenoble, eastern France, where one person is believed to be    dead and several hurt
By Telegraph Video, video source APTN
11:20AM BST 26 Jun 2015
An attacker carrying an Islamist flag has killed one person and injured several others today at a gas factory in eastern France , according to a French official.
The suspected attacker is understood to have entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices.
Grenoble attack: Man found beheaded and Islamist flag raised above French factory - latest
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minister, said he would go "immediately" to the scene, his office said.
The attack comes six months after the Charlie Hebdo attack and the three-day siege in Paris during which 17 people were killed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:18:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>School students caught selling salt to make lunch taste better</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd7/sc/26/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cfoodanddrink0Cfoodanddrinknews0C1170A0A6620CSchool0Estudents0Ecaught0Eselling0Esalt0Eto0Emake0Elunch0Etaste0Ebetter0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Secondary school pupils in America have been caught selling salt to their classmates to make their school dinners taste nicer</Description>
        <MainBody>Food and Drink News
School students caught selling salt to make lunch taste better
Secondary school pupils in America have been caught selling salt to their    classmates to make their school dinners taste nicer
Under new guidelines, high school students have taken to selling salt to make their lunches taste nicerPhoto: ALAMY
By Saffron Alexander
Comments
Since 2010, the lunches offered to American school students have changed drastically, thanks largely to Michelle Obama's "Let's Move!" childhood obesity initiative and the Healthy, Hunger-Free Kids Act.
Nutritional guidelines now state that students must be offered both fruits and vegetables every day of the week, only fat-free or low-fat milks can be available, and that calories must be limited based on children's ages.
The rules have not gone down well with either school cafeteria workers or students.
 #thanksMichelleObama: disgruntled students tweet photos of their school lunches
Students prefer unhealthy lunches (GETTY)
Now, students at schools in Indiana have been caught bringing salt, pepper and sugar with them to make their lunches taste better. Some have even been caught selling the seasonings to their classmates.
John Payne, president of the Blackford County School Board of Trustees, called for schools to be allowed more flexibility with the nutrition standards set by Congress. "This 'contraband' economy is just one example of many that reinforce the call for flexibility," he said.
"More students bring their lunch, and a few parents even 'check out' their child from campus, taking them to a local fast-food restaurant or home for lunch."
 US school dinner lady fired for handing out free lunches to poor kids
Critics of the rules have also said students are going to class hungry, because they don't like the food they are served and simply throw away the fruits and vegetables.
Todd Rokita told The Indy Star: "From firsthand experience, I can verify that despite the increased federal involvement in the school meals program, many students are still going to class hungry.
"I've stuck my head in a lot of garbage cans lately in school cafeterias and I've seen a lot of that."
Michelle Obama eating one of her healthy lunches with school children (AP)
Despite the criticism, Donna Martin, director of the school nutrition program in Burke County, believes the new rules are affecting her students positively.
 Want to lose weight? Become more right-wing
She told The Indy Star they are "gobbling up their whole-grain biscuits, and fresh Georgia peaches and blueberries.
"We have the opportunity to change a generation. We have an opportunity to raise kids that, when they go into McDonald's, they want a whole wheat hamburger bun."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:02:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Biggest US Spanish-language broadcaster to drop Miss USA pageant over Trump comments</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd8/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1170A0A3920CBiggest0EUS0ESpanish0Elanguage0Ebroadcaster0Eto0Edrop0EMiss0EUSA0Epageant0Eover0ETrump0Ecomments0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The network made the decision after the Republican candidate and businessman suggested Mexican immigrants "bring drugs, crime, [and] they're rapists"</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Biggest US Spanish-language broadcaster to drop Miss USA pageant over Trump comments
The network made the decision after the Republican candidate and businessman    suggested Mexican immigrants "bring drugs, crime, [and] they're rapists"
Donald Trump, co-owner of the Miss Universe Organization, poses with Miss Connecticut Erin Brady in Las Vegas in 2013 Photo: Reuters
By AP
Comments
A Univision network is dropping the Miss USA pageant in a spiralling controversy over comments Donald Trump made recently about Mexican immigrants.
Univision said on Thursday it would pull the plug on its Spanish-language coverage of the pageant July 12 by its UniMas network and the company said it will cut all business ties with the Republican presidential candidate.
It also severed its business relationship with the Miss Universe Organisation, which produces the Miss USA pageant , due to what it called "insulting remarks about Mexican immigrants" by Trump, a part owner of Miss Universe.
During his presidential campaign kick-off speech last week , Trump portrayed immigrants from Mexico as "bringing drugs, they're bringing crime, they're rapists, and some, I assume, are good people".
He also called for building a wall along the southern border of the US. The remarks drew condemnation from the Mexican government as "biased and absurd."
NBC is scheduled to air its own pageant coverage, as it has done since 2003, and has remained silent about the broadcast. But in a statement Thursday, the network sought to separate itself from Trump's remarks.
"Donald Trump's opinions do not represent those of NBC, and we do not agree with his positions on a number of issues, including his recent comments on immigration," NBC said.
Trump is part of another NBC programme, Celebrity Apprentice.
In an interview on Thursday, Trump said his criticism was directed against US politicians, not the Mexican people or government, adding that Univision would be defaulting on its contract if it does not air the pageant and he would take legal action.
 The Trump manifesto
"At Univision, we see first-hand the work ethic, love for family, strong religious values and the important role Mexican immigrants and Mexican-Americans have had and will continue to have in building the future of our country," said the New York-based Univision Communications Inc.
Puerto Rican actress-singer Roselyn Snchez, who was set to co-host the Univision broadcast of Miss USA, announced on Thursday that she was pulling out of the pageant. (AP)
Both co-hosts of the UniMas telecast also pulled out on Thursday, while Colombian singer J Balvin on Wednesday cancelled a planned performance at the pageant.
"The only thing I could do as a person, not only as an artist, but as a Latino that I am, was to cancel my show immediately," he told The Associated Press on Thursday.
Trump said Univision is submitting to pressure from Mexican leaders to punish him for positions he voices as a candidate on the campaign trail.
"They don't want me saying that Mexico is killing the United States in trade and killing the United States at the border," Trump said. "Univision is totally laying down for the Mexican government. ... They want to silence Donald Trump. And Donald Trump can't be silenced. ... I have great respect for Mexico and I love the Mexican people, but my loyalty is to the United States."
Univision declined to comment on Trump's remarks. The company also has the rights to air the Miss Universe pageant.
In an interview scheduled to air on Sunday on Telemundo's Enfoque con Jose Diaz-Balart, Trump said "many bad people are coming in" from Mexico and elsewhere.
"You're going to have terrorists coming through the southern border. There's no question about it," he said.
The host challenged Trump, contending there has been no act of terrorism committed by someone crossing the US-Mexico border.
"You don't know that," Trump replied, adding later: "See what happens tomorrow. See what happens in two weeks from now. You can't say that terrorists, and I'm not even talking about terrorists from this region. I'm talking about from the Middle East they can come in. The border is totally open."
In severing her ties with the Miss USA pageant, Puerto Rican actress Roselyn Sanchez, one of the two co-hosts, cited Trump's comments about immigrants.
"Since I heard Trump's speech, as a Latina I felt a lump in my stomach. 'It's got to be a joke,' I thought," the star of the Lifetime series Devious Maids told The Associated Press.
Chilean actor-producer Cristian de la Fuente, the show's other co-host, had strong words for Trump: "It's a shame that such an important institution as Miss USA is now in the hands of a clown."
Ricky Martin also took to Twitter to criticise Trump. "A lot of hatred and ignorance in his heart," he tweeted.
Mucho odio e ignorancia en tu corazn @realDonaldTrump . #LatinosUnidos
 Ricky Martin (@ricky_martin) June 25, 2015
Miss California USA Natasha Martinez was asked about Trump's comments during an interview on Thursday on Los Angeles TV station KCAL and said they were "a little bit tough to hear."
"But I know that this opportunity for me as Miss California-USA, and now competing for Miss USA, is a great bridge to kind of represent my community and let the world know that I am a proud Latino-American," she said.
This year's UniMas telecast would have been the first in a five-year contract that Trump said "has no termination rights". Univision's wholly owned Spanish-language UniMas network, founded in 2013, is available in 70 million US homes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:36:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Disgusting' FGM campaign wins prestigious advertising awards at Cannes</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd9/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cwomen0Cwomens0Elife0C1169960A30CFGM0EOgilvy0Ecampaign0Ewins0ECannes0ELion0Eawards0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A heavily criticised advertising campaign raising awareness about female genital mutilation has won Cannes Lion industry awards</Description>
        <MainBody>Follow
A heavily criticised campaign against female genital mutilation has won a top advertising award at Cannes.
Ogilvy and Mather London created the advertisements to raise awareness about FGM  a crime where a girl or womans genitalia is cut for cultural reasons  back in April, on behalf of anti-FGM charity 28 Too Many .
The adverts depict flags of western countries  such as the union jack  splattered with blood stains and with thick thread sewing them back together.
A message printed on the flag reads: "Female genital mutilation doesn't only happen in far away places. Over 50,000 girls in the UK are at risk."
The It happens here campaign was designed to raise awareness about the fact that FGM is still carried out in countries like the UK, even though it is illegal.
It attracted outrage from many FGM survivors and campaign groups. But the campaign this week won a Gold and Bronze award at the Cannes Lions  the most prestigious global advertising awards.
One campaigner, who has undergone the barbaric practice herself, said the ad was disgusting and should be taken down immediately.
Nimko Ali, who co-founded anti-FGM charity Daughters of Eve , said: Im shocked they won the award. [The flags are] disgusting.
Its so graphic and we have worked so hard to get the conversation about seeing [FGM] as violence against women and girls, and we need to work within that framework.
Were trying not to stigmatise and traumatise girls but this ad does."
Ali, who underwent FGM as a child, added: I shook when I saw it. It depicts the most invasive form of FGM and its what I had.
I think there are girls out there who will see it and feel the same way. It wont help them.
There are three 'types' of FGM : the partial or total removal of the clitoris; the partial or total removal of the clitoris and labia minora; and narrowing the vaginal orifice by cutting and repositioning the labia. The latter appears to be depicted on the posters.
The End FGM European Network agreed that the It Happens Here campaign could stigmatise FGM and was not helpful to survivors.
A spokesperson told Telegraph Wonder Women: We need campaigns which encourage a discussion around the fact that FGM is a reality in Europe and across the world.
Using images which empower and enhance the dignity of survivors and those at risk is vital to this discussion. Stigmatising imagery can alienate affected communities even more and we need to ensure that they are central to ending FGM.
Cheryl Giovannoni, chief executive officer of Ogilvy and Mather London, responded saying: "It Happens Here is designed to be a hard-hitting and provocative campaign to raise awareness of the horrific abuse suffered by hundreds of thousands of girls every year.
"The bold imagery is intended to shock and reach an audience typically unaware of the issues of FGM. The response to this campaign has been overwhelmingly positive and we hope it continues to raise awareness, and support 28 Too Many in their efforts to end female genital mutilation once and for all."
The charity 28 Too Many was unavailable for comment, but Dr Ann-Marie Wilson, executive director, previously spoke about the campaign, saying:
FGM is not just being performed in Africa, the Middle East and Asia but is taking place here, in Europe, on our very own door steps.
"This emotive campaign visually encompasses the concept that FGM is not an out of sight, out of mind problem but at present a risk to over 60,000 girls in the UK.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:58:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Isil attack on Kobane is 'second biggest massacre' of civilians by the group in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4797941d/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cislamic0Estate0C1170A0A4530CIsil0Eattack0Eon0EKobane0Eis0Esecond0Ebiggest0Emassacre0Eof0Ecivilians0Eby0Ethe0Egroup0Ein0ESyria0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Islamic State fighters killed 146 civilians in their attack on Kobane and a nearby village on Thursday, Syrian Observatory for Human Rights says</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State
Isil attack on Kobane is 'second biggest massacre' of civilians by the group in Syria
Islamic State fighters killed 146 civilians in their attack on Kobane and    a nearby village on Thursday, Syrian Observatory for Human Rights says
A picture taken from Suruc district of Turkey's Sanliurfa province shows a group of Syrians waiting on the Syrian side of the Turkish border during the clashes between Isil and Kurdish armed groups in Kobani Photo: 2015 Anadolu Agency
By Louisa Loveluck, Cairo
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:21:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japan mourns death of Tama, the train stationmaster cat</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753a1/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cjapan0C1170A0A3720CJapan0Emourns0Edeath0Eof0ETama0Ethe0Etrain0Estationmaster0Ecat0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The calico cat, who was also deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in 2013, has died aged 16</Description>
        <MainBody>Japan
Japan mourns death of Tama, the train stationmaster cat
The calico cat, who was also deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in    2013, has died aged 16
Tama was known as the stationmaster of Kishi station on the Wakayama Electric Railway in the city of KinokawaPhoto: AFP/Getty
By Danielle Demetriou, Tokyo
One of Japans best-loved cats , who won the heart of the nation working as a stationmaster in a rural train station , has died and the funeral will be held this weekend.
Tama, a 16-year-old calico cat, attracted thousands of tourists to tiny Kishi station in Wakayama prefecture after being appointed stationmaster in 2007.
Prior to her arrival, the regional railway line was losing money and the station had lost its last human employee the previous year.
Tama, who famously strolled around the station in her official railway cap uniform, quickly drew crowds of visitors, fuelling a thriving merchandising business and revitalising the local economy.
The cat was credited with boosting the number of people travelling along the Kishigawa Line by 55,000, adding an additional 1.1 billion yen (5.7million) to the local economy.
Tama was promoted to deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in 2013 (AFP/Getty)
The popular felines successes resulted in an award from the prefectural governor of Wakayama in 2008 and a promotion to deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in 2013.
Among those mourning her death from heart failure was Yoshinobu Nisaka, who said: Tama won a great popularity at home and abroad as a super star of tourism. At the news of her loss, I express my deep sorrow and great gratitude.
The railway company is planning to hold a funeral at the station this weekend for the late cat, who will reportedly be succeeded by her feline stationmaster apprentice Nitama.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:15:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Unarmed black man fatally shot by Baltimore police after domestic disturbance</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753a7/sc/42/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1170A0A370A0CUnarmed0Eblack0Eman0Efatally0Eshot0Eby0EBaltimore0Epolice0Eafter0Edomestic0Edisturbance0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Officers said they shot Spencer Lee McCain believing he had a weapon after being called to a home from which he was barred by court order</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Unarmed black man fatally shot by Baltimore police after domestic disturbance
Officers said they shot Spencer Lee McCain believing he had a weapon after    being called to a home from which he was barred by court order
Baltimore County Police officers at the scene in Owings MillsPhoto: NBC
By AP
9:15AM BST 26 Jun 2015
An unarmed black man was fatally shot on Thursday by officers in suburban Baltimore who thought he had a weapon when they were called to a home from which he was barred by protective order, the police chief said.
The death follows that of a 25-year-old black man, Freddie Gray, who died in April from an injury suffered in the custody of Baltimore city police, which prompted protests and rioting . And it comes amid a national debate over the treatment of African-Americans at the hands of police, after high-profile deaths of black men in Ferguson, Missouri, and New York City.
Spencer Lee McCain, 41, was shot about 1 am at the home in Owings Mills while a woman who said he threatened to beat her and her two young children were there, Baltimore County Police Chief Jim Johnson said at a news conference.
Three officers were on the scene, and all fired as McCain was in a "defensive position" and they thought he had a weapon, Chief Johnson said. But he said no weapon was found.Two of the officers are white, and one is black, police said. All are on administrative leave. Police said the incident began when one of the children in the home called his grandmother, who called 911 and asked police to go there.
An officer who arrived heard screams and called for backup, Chief Johnson said. He said 19 casings were found at the scene, but it wasn't clear how many times McCain was hit.
Police said the woman had head injuries, cuts, bruises and swelling. Chief Johnson said she told detectives that McCain said to her, "You're going to get the beating you deserve."
Sixteen to 20 domestic violence calls had been made to that home address since 2012, police spokesman Cpl. John Wachter said.
According to 2013 census figures, 27.5 percent of Baltimore County's population is black and 64.1 percent is white. The police chief and county executive are white.
As of February, black people made up less than 13 percent of the county's 1,868-member police force.
A medical examiner ruled this week that the death of Freddie Gray was a homicide, after he suffered a "high-energy injury," most likely caused when a Baltimore city police van he was riding in suddenly slowed down. A grand jury indicted six officers on various charges; one officer faces the most serious charge of second-degree "depraved-heart" murder. They have pleaded not guilty.
The report said Gray's death could not be ruled an accident and is instead a homicide because officers didn't follow safety procedures "through acts of omission."
Police and an attorney for the Gray family have said previously that Gray suffered a severe spine injury .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:42:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nine dead after plane crashes in Alaska</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47974dc3/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1170A0A2630CNine0Edead0Eafter0Eplane0Ecrashes0Ein0EAlaska0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Light aircraft carrying holidaymakers on a cruise crashes near Misty Fjords</Description>
        <MainBody>Nine dead after plane crashes in Alaska
Light aircraft carrying holidaymakers on a cruise crashes near Misty Fjords
A DeHavilland Beaver float plane flying the Alaska Coast Range (file photo)Photo:  Alamy
By David Millward , US Correspondent
7:42AM BST 26 Jun 2015
Nine people have been killed after a light aircraft crashed in Alaska , US police said.
The eight passengers were all holidaymakers who had been on a Holland America cruise.
The identity and nationality of those on board the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter single-engine prop plane was not disclosed. The plane crashed near Ketchikan, the Federal Aviation Administration said.
The Holland America Line cruise ship Westerdam sits in dock in Ketchikan, Alaska (AP)
Emergency crews were able to reach the aircraft that crashed against a granite rock face and confirm the deceased, but weather in the fjords prevented recovery efforts, Megan Peters from Alaska's department of public safety said.
"Due to inclement weather, the body recovery effort will not be attempted until tomorrow," she said in a statement.
According to local reports the weather in the region was heavily overcast.
An FAA webcam in Misty Fjords took this image around the time of the crash
The passengers had all been on board the MS Westerdam on an eight-day cruise which had departed from Seattle.
Promech Air confirmed in a statement that the eight passengers and pilot were killed when the plane went down during a tour of the Misty Fjords area near the town of Ketchikan on Thursday afternoon
 Alaska plane crash leaves four dead including infant
"We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those on board the plane and their families," Holland America said in a written statement.
The National Transportation Safety Board said on Twitter it was sending a "go-team" to the crash site to investigate.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:25:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Devoted couple married for 67 years die within two hours of each other</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47965b28/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Caustraliaandthepacific0Cnewzealand0C1170A0A2640CDevoted0Ecouple0Emarried0Efor0E670Eyears0Edie0Ewith0Etwo0Ehours0Eof0Eeach0Eother0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Hugh Nees, 94, died of cancer while his wife Joan, 92, suffered a stroke</Description>
        <MainBody>Devoted couple married for 67 years die within two hours of each other
Hugh Nees, 94,  died of cancer while his wife Joan, 92, suffered a stroke
Hugh and Joan Nees in their home in Paraparaumu, north of Wellington, New Zealand, in April 2014. Photo: Fairfax Media/Getty Images
By Paul Chapman, Wellington
Comments
A devoted couple who were married for 67 years have died of natural causes within two hours of each other, in the same room at a New Zealand rest home.
Family members said Hugh Nees, 94, and his wife Joan, 92, could not bear to spend even a day apart, and had told them they did not want to live without each other.
Mr Nees, who had cancer, died first in the double room they shared at Eldon Lodge rest home in Paraparaumu, north of Wellington. His wife suffered a stroke.
Hugh and Joan Nees on their wedding day
They had moved into the rest home from their house at nearby Waikanae just over two months ago, because of declining health.
Mr Nees was a retired Baptist minister.
 Couple married for 65 years die moments apart
"They were strong Christians and therefore they knew where they were going, and they had no problem about going there," their son Robert Nees said.
He told the New Zealand Herald that his mother would not have known that her husband had preceded her, even though the couple "were in the same room, lying beside each other", surrounded by family.
"Their departure, it's sad but happy. Life wasn't easy for the last little while and that's over, that's all good."
Asked whether they might have had any premonition of their close departure, their son said: "It's so hard to know. It almost seems like it, doesn't it?"
Their daughter Joy Reid said the timing of their deaths was a miracle.
They said they wanted to die together, and I didn't expect it to really happen. It was just perfect for them.
The couple had five children, two of whom died before them.
They also lost a grandson, 31-year-old Nicholas Heyward, who was shot dead by robbers on a motorcycle in Argentina last year.
Mr and Mrs Nees were both keen gardeners and played golf in their younger days.
A service to celebrate their lives will be held on June 30 at the Baptist church in Waikanae.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:33:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia gunman Seifeddine Rezgui captured on video breakdancing</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a47dad/sc/40/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1170A42870CTunisia0Egunman0ESeifeddine0ERezgui0Ecaptured0Eon0Evideo0Ebreakdancing0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A video from 2010 purports to show Tunisia gunman Seifeddine Rezgui breakdancing in a baseball cap almost five years before he murdered 38 people on a beach in Sousse</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia
Tunisia gunman Seifeddine Rezgui captured on video breakdancing
A video from 2010 purports to show Tunisia gunman Seifeddine Rezgui    breakdancing in a baseball cap almost five years before he murdered 38    people on a beach in Sousse
By Telegraph video, video source Facebook/Ezzouhour magique gaafour
2:33PM BST 28 Jun 2015
A video purporting to show Tunisia gunman Seifeddine Rezgui has been circulating on social media.
In the clip, which is around two and a half minutes long, a man believed to be Rezgui is seen breakdancing to techno music.
It was uploaded to Facebook on 28 December 2010, almost five years before Rezgui gunned down 38 people, including 15 British tourists, on a beach in Sousse.
The video is accompanied by the description: "Video of Seif Rezgui made by K.Maher".
According to Sky News, the Facebook group was set up in 2010 by a group of friends interested in rap music and breakdancing.
It has since taken on a more political nature since the Arab Spring.
The video appears to show the former engineering student performing some popular breakdancing moves in various locations.
On Saturday, photographs were obtained by Sky News which showed Seifeddine Rezgui walking along the beach carrying a gun.
(Sky News)
A picture was also released by the Islamic State, who have claimed responsibility for the shooting, of Rezgui sitting grinning, flanked by a pair of Kalashnikovs.
According to Tunisia's Prime Minister, Habib Essid, Rezgui was a 23-year-old student who originally hailed from Gaafour some 50 miles south-west of Tunis.
He had never travelled abroad, Mr Essid said, and was not known by the police to hold extremist views.
"He used to use hair gel and wear the nicest of clothes, and he used to break dancing," the killer's uncle Ali al Rezgui, said.
"He even used to go to competitions and things like that in Tunis, he was well known for that here. He didnt even have a beard, and Ive never seen him with anyone with a beard. We have extremists like that in Gaafour, but never have I seen him with them. Now hes shooting people with a Kalashnikov, its just so confusing."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:24:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia attack: Identities of dead revealed as up to 23 Brits killed in worst act of terrorism since 7/7 - latest</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a05c40/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1170A10A430CTunisia0Eattack0Eshooting0E150Ebritish0Etourists0Edead0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Isil release smiling image of gunman responsible for Tunisia attack that left at least 15 British tourists dead on popular beach resort in Sousse</Description>
        <MainBody>A British tourist captured the sound of gunshots from his hotel room in Sousse, Tunisia.
13.25
Hundreds of Britons have been arriving back in the UK today but others are still stuck in their hotels, waiting desperately for a flight out of the country.
Aaron Smith, 29, from Liverpool, is on holiday with his girlfriend Morgan, 23, from Burnley at the Marhaba Royal Salem Hotel down the road from where the attacks took place. They had booked the holiday through Thomas Cook.
Guests queue up to leave the terrorist hit hotel Imperial Marhaba in Sousse, Tunisia, on Friday night (Warren Allott/The Telegraph)
He told The Telegraph:
We have registered that we want to go home asap and we are on a waiting list. We are waiting to see if there available flights. All the customers are still trying to put on a happy place but we are nervous.
Everyone just wants to go home as soon as they can. Some are already booked on to flights tomorrow. Everyone else just wants to go home.
We were told possibly one to two hours but it will probably be more like five to six. I am calling them every hour or so to check.
There doesnt seem to be any extra security presence around the hotel, but the beach is off limits. And there is a restaurant on the beach which is closed.
People are either staying their rooms or congregating in the hotel lobby. Looking around now, almost all the people here have children, or elderly people with them so [leaving the hotel] is just not worth the risk.
People are going crazy, sitting inside waiting for nothing to happen. There are hundreds of Brits staying at the hotel, mainly English but also some Scottish and Welsh people. A lot of people only arrived yesterday and they want to go straight away.
13.15
Harriet Harman, acting Labour leader, said the party's "deepest sympathy and thoughts" go out to the families and friends of the victims. She said:
These shocking events, as well as the attacks in France and Kuwait, remind us of the constant threat the world faces from terrorism, and the need for constant vigilance.
It is disappointing that the impact of these crimes will also be felt by Tunisia's economy, not least its growing and important tourism industry.
We will back the Government as it works to help the families affected and counter these extremist ideologies which have so brutally taken the lives of the innocent.
13.13
A member of Norfolk Police staff and his wife were injured in the attacks.
The force said Tony Callaghan, who works at North Walsham, and his wife needed hospital treatment but their injuries are not life-threatening.
13.10
This is a video of David Cameron's statement following the Cobra meeting this morning.
He said: "There's no doubt we face a very severe threat in our country and we have done for many months and many years, but the level of the threat is identified independently of government and published in the proper way."
13.05
Assistant commissioner Mark Rowley, national policing lead for counter-terrorism, has just been speaking outside New Scotland Yard to discuss latest security arrangements in the UK following the attacks in Tunisia and France.
He said: "We've deployed a large number of officers out to Tunisia, both in terms of our own evidence gathering - forensic experts, helping the Tunisia authorities - and also we've got experts in family liaison assisting."
Mr Rowley said the UK's terror threat level remained at "severe", the second highest level, meaning a terrorist attack is "highly likely".
It was "fairly clear" the location of the Tunisian attack was chosen because of the number of Westerners present in the area, he added.
12.55
The Telegraph's Nicola Harley reports on Carly Lovett, the 24-year-old British beauty blogger and photographer believed to have been killed on the beach in Tunisia. Read her full report here:
Carly Lovett (Twitter)
12.35
A woman whose fiance was shot three times on the Tunisian beach as he used his body to shield her from harm says she has not yet told their two children about their father's heroic deed because she does not want them to worry.
Gas engineer Matthew James, 30, is recovering in hospital after being hit in the shoulder, chest and hip. His fiancee Sarah Wilson has contacted their family in Pontypridd, South Wales to tell them of Matthew's shooting injuries.
Welsh holiday maker Matthew James and his partner Sarah Wilson. Mathew was hit by a bullet a protecting his partner (Wales News Service)
Ms Wilson said: "We don't want the children to know anything about it and how daddy has been hurt.
"We've asked our families not to let them watch the television so they don't ask any questions.
"They know we are in Tunisia and we don't want them to worry. We just want to get back to them and give them a big hug."
Matthew James and his fiancee Sarah Wilson (Wales News Service)
Engaged couple Sarah and Matthew, left their two children Tegan, six, and Kaden, 14 months at home with their family when went to Sousse on June 21 for a two week break.
You can read the full story of Mr James' bravery here:
12.20
The UK faces a "severe terrorist threat", David Cameron has warned.
He said the most important thing is to "carry on" thanking the armed forces for their work "knowing that in our country we face a severe terrorist threat".
Here is the full text of the statement he made following the Cobra meeting this morning.
This morning I chaired a second Cobra meeting focusing on the attack in Tunisia. I will ensure we do all we can to help those affected and to protect people from this terrorist threat. Our thoughts and prayers are with the loved ones of those killed or injured in the attack.
We are working with the Tunisian authorities to identify a final number on the British casualties, but I'm afraid that the British public need to be prepared for the fact that many of those killed were British.
We are working hard to help those in Tunisia. We have a consular team on the ground in Sousse helping those there. A further team of consular staff, police and experts from the Red Cross are arriving today to provide further assistance.
We are working with the travel operators to establish if there is anything more we can do to assist them. We will do everything necessary to get people home, including those injured.
Last night, I spoke to President Essebsi to thank the Tunisian authorities for their assistance and to discuss what more we can do together to tackle this threat.
These were innocent holidaymakers, relaxing and enjoying time with their friends and families. Like the victims in France and Kuwait yesterday, they did not pose a threat to anybody.
These terrorists murdered them because the terrorists oppose people and countries who stand for peace, tolerance and democracy wherever they are in the world. But these terrorists will not succeed.
For as much as they try to divide people around the world, they will only unite us more strongly in our determination to defeat these Islamist extremists and all that they stand for.
We will keep working with our partners around the world. it will take time, vigilance and determination. But there is no place for these Islamist extremists in the modern world and we will defeat them. We will keep the public informed about further developments and I will make a statement to the Commons on Monday.
Mr Cameron was asked whether there were there whether British authorities were providing enough help to Britons in Tunisia, and whether the public were safe in the UK, at celebration events for Armed Forces Day today. He said:
First of all, on the consular assistance we give in Tunisia, one can only imagine the pain and anguish and agony of families that have been caught up in these terrible events.
We have a team on the ground in Sousse. They are working hard and I've been speaking with them on a video link this morning. A full deployment team will arrive later today to give even more help to the families. We will do whatever it takes to help them.
On the issue of Armed Forces Day - let's be clear, there is no doubt that we face a very severe threat in our country and we have done for many months and many years. The level of the threat is identified independently of Government and published in the proper way.
But today is about paying tribute to our Armed Forces and their families who do so much to keep us safe and we should proceed with those events. Of course, there will be heightened security at those events and, indeed, of course, at other commemorations and celebrations that are taking place today.
The most important thing is to carry on thanking our Armed Forces for the work that they do, knowing that in our country we face a severe terrorist threat.
But if we work together, if we are vigilant, if we back our police and anti-terrorism forces, If we combat this poisonous narrative of Islamist extremism that is radicalising too many young minds in our country, if we do all those things and show the persistence and the determination that I have talked about, then we will overcome. Thank you."
12.15
It has just been announced that Assistant Commissioner Mark Rowley will read a statement at 12.30 outside New Scotland Yard to discuss latest security arrangements in the UK following the attacks in Tunisia and France.
Britain's Senior National Co-ordinator of Counter Terrorism Investigations said last night that security would be stepped up at London Pride and Armed Forces day, both of which are taking place today.
Police in Guildford High Street ahead of Armed Forces Day (PA)
A policeman looks for faces as he watches the crowds in Guildford High Street in Surrey ahead of the Armed Forces Day parade.
11.55
Here are some pictures of Carly Lovett, the first named Briton believed to be among those killed in Tunisia.
Carly Jade Lovett (Twitter)
Carly Jade Lovett with her dad, Kev. Carly was a victim of the Tunisia terrorist attack
Carly Jade Lovett (Twitter)
11.50
Conor Fulford spoke just now on Sky news. He has still not heard from his mother, Sue Davey, who was on holiday with her partner Scott Chalkey, who he has also not heard from. They were on a Thomson holiday together, staying at the Imperial hotel.
He said he saw a phot of a woman on a stretcher being carried into a hospital who he believes might be her. He said his sisters were "adamant" it was his mother.
He said:
We thought maybe it was clutching at straws at he time.
We are just praying that she is at the hospital. Currently there is a woman who has been shot in the leg who is in theatre and she does match the decription of my mum, which is terrifying but it is good news.
Someone there at the hospital who is waiting for the woman having surgery, potentially mu mum. Until she comes out of surgery we won't know so we are literally just waiting.
I believe this is my mom on @SkyNews can everybody please RT as we have no contact since ! Please Help #FindSueDavey pic.twitter.com/ZFvz90A1CE
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
11.37
Tributes are pouring in for Carly Lovett, the first named Briton believed to be among those killed in Tunisia.
Absolutely awful knowing that somebody in the blogging community has been killed today in Tunisia after the territory attack. R.i.p Carly x
 emelye kate (@emelyekate_) June 26, 2015
@ceejayell_ I'm heartbroken as so many others are, that you're no longer with us Carly : ( R.I.P
 THE BLOGGERS POST! (@TheBloggersPost) June 27, 2015
11.25
In this video Defence Secretary Michael Fallon says the number of victims is likely to rise following Friday's beach attack in Sousse, Tunisia
11.20
Some information just in about the Tunisian authorities and how they are responding to the crisis.
Tunisia's Health Minister Said Aidi had sacked the head of the country's emergency ambulance service SAMU.
Nejib Karoui was reportedly dismissed after refusing an order to make all Sousse's emergency response ambulances available to transport the bodies of the massacre victims.
Dr Karoui told a TV station after his sacking he felt the Health Minister's request was "inadmissible" and funeral parlour cars should have been used instead of putting the lives of other potential users of the emergency medical service at risk.
Tunisia PM Habib Essid has also announced cash rewards will be paid to those who can provide information leading to the arrests of members of terrorist sleeper cells.
The bodies of those killed in the Sousse beach massacre are set to be transferred to the Charles Nicolle Hospital in the capital Tunis.
The transfer was authorised by Health Minister Said Aydi as part of measures designed to speed up the repatriation of the massacre victims.
11.13
Conor Fulford, who is appealing for information about his mother Sue Davey, said he believes he recognises her in a photo of an injured woman being carried on a stretcher.
I believe this is my mom on @SkyNews can everybody please RT as we have no contact since ! Please Help #FindSueDavey pic.twitter.com/ZFvz90A1CE
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
11.10
Carly Lovett, 24, who blogs as Carly Jade, had posted on Twitter how she was packing for her holiday.
She is believed to be have been killed in the Tunisian attack.
Her last post, just two days before the incident, she wrote: "Definitely leaving in like three hours and definitely am not finished packing..."
Definitely leaving in like three hours and definitely am not finished packing...
 Carly Jade (@ceejayell_) June 24, 2015
Earlier this year she had blog about changing her life and told her followers "2015 will be my year".
She got engaged to her fiance Liam Moore, 26, in December.
Miss Lovett had attended the University of Lincoln from 2010 to 2013 gaining a first class honours in Product Design and worked as a demonstrator at the campus.
Lincoln School of Film and Media tweeted: "Saddened to hear news reports of Carly Lovett in Tunisia - Graduate of our University 2013."
Saddened to hear news reports of Carly Lovett in Tunisia - Graduate of our University 2013
 Lincoln::Film&amp;Media (@LincolnMedia) June 26, 2015
Miss Lovett, of Gainsborough, had travelled to Tunisia on Tuesday.
Ms Lovett worked as a photographer at e-commerce company fizzco, who are based in Fillingham near Gainsborough.
She also volunteered for the National Art and Design Saturday Club to help youngsters.
Friends have paid tribute to her on social media.
Emelye Kate posted: "This is heartbreaking knowing how excited you were for this trip."
Megan Rex said: "So unbelievably sad. Rest in peace Carly :("
Carly Rowena wrote: "My heart is broken, RIP beautiful one"
Her blogs and Twitter posts have attracted dozens of followers since she started them from finishing university.
11.05
Carly Lovett, 24, an aspiring young beauty blogger and photographer from Gainsborough is believed to have been killed in the Tunisian attack while on holiday with her fiance.
10.55
David Cameron is speaking now, following the Cobra meeting. He says: "The British public need to be prepared for the fact that many of those killed were British".
Mr Cameron warned that the public needs to be prepared for the fact that "many of those killed" in the "savage" Tunisian shooting were Britons.
He spoke as reports from Tunisia suggested that the UK death toll had risen to eight out of 39 people killed in the popular resort of Sousse.
Mr Cameron said a "full deployment team" of consular staff, police and experts from the Red Cross would arrive in the North African country today to help the victims and their families and the Government was doing "all we can to" help them.
Speaking in Downing Street, he said: "These savage terrorist attacks in Tunisia, Kuwait and France are a brutal and tragic reminder of the threat faced around the world from these evil terrorists."
10.50
Defence Secretary Michael Fallon said the Government was ready to help the victims and their families "in any way that we can".
"The murders in Tunisia and the events in France and Kuwait are a very stark reminder that we can never take our security for granted," he told BBC Breakfast.
Security at major events being staged across the UK today, such as armed forces day celebrations and London's Pride march, has been reviewed.
"With big events like that of course the police look at the security arrangements again and make sure that we take every precaution," he added.
10.47
Breaking news: Tunisia Interior Ministry say that eight Britons, one German, one Belgian have been identified among beach massacre victims
10.45
A 25-year old Welsh woman believed dead on Friday night has been found alive.
Lena Tanti, from Cardiff, is currently on holiday in Tunisia with a friend. Her cousin, Chris Spiteri, 29, also from Cardiff, reported her missing.
But on Saturday morning, he told the Telegraph he had managed to establish contact with her.
He said: "I have spoken to her this morning and she's fine and that's all I care about."
Earlier he had told the BBC: "She's on holiday with her friend and I've tried calling her but her phone is dead," he said. "I've WhatsApped her but I haven't heard back.
Ms Tanti is at a resort two hours away from the epicentre of the terrorist attacks and she has no plans to return to the UK earlier.
10.35
The beach of the Riu Imperial Marhaba Hotel in Port el Kantaouiremains remains cordoned off.
(AFP)
10.30
Brits have been arriving home throughout the morning - some were scheduled to arrive back in the UK today anyway, while others opted to cut their holiday short amid the tragedy. But the scale of repatriation will be huge.
The Association of British Travel Agents (Abta) says there are around 20,000 visitors in the country at the moment, excluding those tourists who have travelled there independently.
10.25
Meanwhile, the UK has been placed on a heightened security alert. There are additional security measures in place at London Pride today and Armed Forces Day, which celebrates the work of the military at events across the country. Read our full report here:
Britain on heightened security alert in wake of France, Tunisia and Kuwait attacks
10.20
The Telegraph's graphic designer Thomas Shiel is on holiday in Sousse in a hotel near to where the attacks took place. He bring us this update from the Marhaba Palace hotel at Port Kantaoui.
Apparently there was chaos in the hotel last night because a Thompson rep announced over a microphone that there was was coaches outside to take all the Thompson guests to the airport and put them on a flight.
Other guests were furious at not being allowed on the coaches one person described it as 'bedlam' and said he saw someone spit at the rep.
I'm not sure if the Thompson guests would have been contacted if they were in their room but I can't imagine they would be best pleased about missing an opportunity to leave.
10.10
Thomson and First Choice have put out a statement. They said RIU Imperial Marhaba and the RIU Bellevue, where the attacks took place, are part of their holiday programme, adding: "We have had confirmation that a number of the fatalities and injuries are Thomson and First Choice customers".
Hotel Imperial Marhaba was one of those attacked (Alamy)
The full statement reads:
Thomson and First Choice can confirm that the RIU Imperial Marhaba and the RIU Bellevue, which were involved in the terrorist events in Tunisia are part of our holiday programme.
While the situation on the ground remains fluid, we have had confirmation that a number of the fatalities and injuries are Thomson and First Choice customers. We are working closely with the local authorities and government to confirm the exact details of those affected.
We would like to extend our deepest sympathies to the friends and families of those involved in this tragic event.
Hotel RIU Bellevue Park is a Thomson holiday destination
We are actively working with the families and friends affected to provide support in resort and a special assistance team is en route to Tunisia to assist our customers.
Anyone with concerns about friends and families should call 0800 0885372.
The whole of Thomson and First Choice are deeply shocked and truly saddened by the events and we are grateful to our staff on the ground and the emergency services who are working hard in an incredibly challenging environment.
Due to this terrible tragedy, Thomson and First Choice are repatriating customers staying in Port El Kantaoui and Sousse.
Ten Thomson Airways flights have travelled to Tunisia to repatriate Thomson and First Choice customers and additional flights will be added today and tomorrow to accommodate those wishing to return to the UK.
We will also be cancelling all Thomson and First Choice holidays to Tunisia for the next week.
Amendments can be made to bookings on holidays to Tunisia until 24th July and we are scheduling three extra flights to Cape Verde, Rhodes and Gran Canaria for customers wishing to change their holidays.
10.00
Ross Naylor, whose father is missing, is frantically seeking information. His father Scott Chalkley, 42, is on holiday with his partner Sue Davey, who is also missing.
Mr Naylor, 23, posted on Twitter a number of messages seeking information.
Haven't spoke to my Dad since the attack, please, please, please RT as he is missing along with his partner #Tunisia pic.twitter.com/s1Mp2loO1W
 A$AP ROSSI (@rossinaylor) June 26, 2015
Mr Naylor told the Mirror:
I last spoke to him on Tuesday and he told me he was having a good time - I only spoke to him for a couple of minutes.
Then he spoke to my mum yesterday because my little brother had a doctor's appointment and he wanted to see how it went.
But other than that we left him too it so he could enjoy his holiday.
Then today I saw all this stuff on the news.
I knew he was in Tunisia but I didn't know where so I though I'd give him a call, check he was alright. But he didn't answer
Please keep retweeting the images, thank you ? pic.twitter.com/A31oqgzyzM
 A$AP ROSSI (@rossinaylor) June 27, 2015
I rang his partner but she didn't answer either.
We kept trying and trying, and as time passes you start to think what's going on.
Then I spoke to Sue's daughter and daughter and found out he was staying at the the Imperial hotel where the attack happened. That's when I really started to worry.
We've heard nothing at all. No one's seen him at the hotel lobby, they've called his room but there's no answer.
But they were definitely on the beach when it happened. The hotel staff found there bags and brought them in - Sue's phone was there but not my dad's.
09.50
Peter Long, chief executive of the TUI group, said:
I am deeply, deeply shocked in terms of the events we have seen over the last 24 hours in Tunisia and our whole organisation is reeling with pain to see the suffering that has taken place in Tunisia with our customers.
We have all our directors at various locations in the UK and a huge team within the destination. I have recently come off one of the flights and spoken to all our customers returning and expressed my deep sympathies in terms of the trauma they have gone through.
We have a huge team within the destination and we feel so proud in terms of what our reps have done looking after our customers as we organise to repatriate them back to the UK.
The tragedy of the situation continues as we see families who have lost some of their loved ones, families who have some of their loved ones injured and our heartfelt feelings go out to them.
09.35
Peter Long, chief executive of the TUI group which owns Thomson and First Choice is speaking now outside TUI's UK and Ireland headquarters in Crawley, West Sussex. He says events in Tunisia are a "huge trauma for everybody".
Asked whether he sees a future for the business in Tunisia he said "it is not appropriate for us to comment", adding that the company follows the FCO's advice on whether the country is safe.
TUI UK &amp; Ireland, Jet Set House, Church Road Lowfield Heath, Crawley West Sussex RH11 0PQ
09.33
This video has emerged, showing people running on the beach and streets in Sousse, Tunisia, as gunshots are heard in the background
09.25
Conor Fulford, from Tamworth, Staffordshire, took to social media in a bid to find his mother, Sue Davey, who was staying at one of the hotels where the attack took place.
Mr Fulford tweeted photographs of her with the hashtag #FindSueDavey.
Still haven't got more information on my mom #FindSueDavey anybody in #Tunisia that can help please tweet me !?
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
He told BBC Radio 4's Today programme:
We've watched the news and my two sisters are adamant that they could see my mum on a stretcher. It looked like she had been shot in the leg which is obviously very disturbing.
"But she was moving so I guess it was a positive compared to the stories that we're hearing at the minute."
Mr Fulford said his family rang "every single hospital" but no-one knew where she was.
He also criticised the information being given by the Foreign Office, which was "no better than anything that I've got online".
Mr Fulford explained: "They just said if they find any leads then they will let us know. I'm at a loss for words at the minute."
He added: "It just comes across as rude and ignorant. They just don't want to talk to anyone. It's unbelievable."
09.15
ISIS social media accounts have this morning tweeted pictures of the alleged gunman, Saifeddine Rezgui, a 23-year-old engineering student. The man can be seen smiling in between two Kalashnikovs.
The refer to him by a nom-de-guerre, Abu Yahya AlQuirawani. - Quirawan, or Kairouan being the town in central Tunisia he is from.
"Soldier of the Khalifat, Abu Yahya AlQuirawani, may god accept him, a night of the Sousse invasion in the muslim Tunisia", the accounts tweeted, alongside the photograph.
 alkrke jordanian 10 (@isisisabdtero) June 26, 2015
09.05
The Telegraph's Defence Correspondent Ben Farmer in is Sousse. He has sent in this dispatch:
Hundreds of British holiday makers made their way home from the city of Sousse overnight as tour firms laid on special planes after the deadly hotel attack.
Visibly shocked package tourists told of the horror and panic of the attack as they boarded the early hours Thomson charter flights back to the UK.
Tourists leave Tunisia at the Enfidha International airport after a shooting attack at the Imperial hotel in the resort town of Sousse (AFP/KENZO TRIBOUILLARD)
Jaqueline and Stephen Walls, of Malton in North Yorks, were staying at the Imperial Marhaba hotel when the attack started on the beachfront.
Mr Walls, a former soldier, said: They just shot the people who were on their sun beds totally indiscriminately and they threw at least two grenades.
His wife had wondered away from him towards the beach when the gunfire erupted sometime after 11.30am on Friday.
He said: As people were running away, I was running towards it because I knew my wife was down there somewhere.
I saw a number of people badly hurt and came across a number of people who were dead on the beach.
In a 22-year career with the Royal Signals, he said he had never seen any thing as harrowing.
Hotel armed security guards on the roof added to the confusion, his wife said. She said: You couldnt tell who was protecting us and who was in on the plan.
Thomson gave all holidaymakers at the affected hotels the opportunity to fly home in the early hours of Saturday, tourists said. Hundreds arrived by coach to Enfidha airport throughout the night to board flights back to London, Manchester, Doncaster and the East Midlands.
Mr Walls said: We have got another eight days left of our holiday left, but every time we hear a door slam we are jumping.
Another holiday maker who declined to give his name, said: It was horrendous. There was gunfire and we knew straight away what it was. My wife was in the toilet and I was on a sun lounger waiting for her. She came up and said they are shooting on the beach, we have got to get out of here.
Another holidaymaker staying at the neighbouring Bellevue Park described the chaos as families were split up in the confusion and hotel staff tried to direct police to the attacker.
He said: We were in the pool just after aqua aerobics had finished and we heard what we thought was a burst of firecrackers. Then we heard a second wave and we suddenly realised it was gunfire. We got out and raced to reception. It was pure panic, the rep advised us to go to our rooms.
We looked out of the window and you could tell where the shooter was because staff were leaning out of windows while on their phones trying to give police directions.
The staff were fantastic. Reps were running to help.
There was one couple who said a little boy was missing of 7 or eight, they were absolutely hysterical. There was also children at the childrens club and parents couldnt get to them.
09.00
While some terrified British tourists are arriving back in the UK this morning, others remain injured in hospital in Sousse.
Criss Callaghan, 62, a British tourist who was injured during an attack on a beachside hotel, cries as she lies in bed at a hospital in Sousse (REUTERS/Zoubeir Souissi)
Tunisian women donate blood for the victims of an attack at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort town of al-Sousse (EPA/MOHAMED MESSARA)
08.30
The first wave of six morning flights from Enfidha to Manchester arrived early today.
A team of Thomson representatives greeted passengers as they entered the arrivals hall at the airport's Terminal 2 building.
Some appeared distressed as they were led away by staff within the airport, with one middle-aged woman in tears.
Two ambulances were parked outside the arrivals hall.
The airport's co-ordinating chaplain, the Rev George Lane, was on site, along with a police presence.
Police officers asked reporters not to approach passengers and told them - under instructions from press officials - to leave the grounds of the airport.
06.23
The Britsh death toll is set to rise well above the FCO-confirmed number of five, with Tunisia's prime minister today saying the "majority" of victims" are British, with the rest from Germany, Belgium and the rest from central Europe.
05.53
The British Embassy in Tunis has sent a crisis team to the area and has urged tourists to keep in touch with their tour operator. It has also provided an emergency contact number for anyone worried about friends or family in the area. It is +44 207 008 0000. The same number can be used by people in the country to provide reassurance to relatives and others who might be concerned back home. It has also set up an online form to provide details of anyone who might be affected.
05.05
Thomson Holidays is steppping up its evacuation of tourists from the area. It is now sending 10 aircraft, rather than the six it announced earlier to bring everyone home. It has also cancelled all holidays in Tunisia next week. At the same time the tour operator says it is laying on additional flights to alternative destinations in Cape Verde, Rhodes and Gran Canaria.
03.40
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:07:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russian MP urges Facebook block over gay rights rainbow flag</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a47daf/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Crussia0C1170A430A70CRussian0EMP0Eurges0EFacebook0Eblock0Eover0Egay0Erights0Erainbow0Eflag0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Vitaly Milonov, who sits in the regional parliament of Saint Petersburg, introduced a law in the city banning "propaganda" of gay relationships to minors</Description>
        <MainBody>Russia
Russian MP urges Facebook block over gay rights rainbow flag
Vitaly Milonov, who sits in the regional parliament of Saint Petersburg,    introduced a law in the city banning "propaganda" of gay    relationships to minors
Russian politician Vitaly MilonovPhoto: Getty Images
By Telegraph staff
2:07PM BST 28 Jun 2015
A Russian lawmaker, who has strongly backed anti-gay legislation, said Facebook should be shut down in Russia over its support for the US Supreme Court's decision to legalise same-sex marriage.
Lawmaker Vitaly Milonov said he would formally request Russia's telecoms oversight agency to shut down Facebook which has introduced a function allowing users to decorate their profiles with the rainbow flag of the gay rights movement.
"It is a crude violation of Russian legislation. Facebook has no age limits, it is impossible to control how many minors are there," Saint Petersburg lawmaker Milonov said on Russian radio Saturday evening.
"That is why it would be completely normal to pull the plug on Facebook in Russia."
Milonov, who sits in the regional parliament of Saint Petersburg, introduced a law in the city banning "propaganda" of gay relationships to minors before a similar federal law was adopted and came into force in 2013, sparking international controversy.
Milonov said he would petition Roskomnadzor, Russia's telecoms oversight agency, and if that does not help he would appeal to the FSB security service and President Vladimir Putin personally.
"I would call on thousands of people and we will write to the FSB and Putin," he said.
"Any normal person would not leave this unnoticed. If Roskomnadzor does then they play on the side of those who whish harm to our homeland."
In a show of support for the US Supreme Court's historic decision, many Russians added a rainbow filter to their Facebook profile photos.
Milonov's words drew disdain from activists, and a picture of Milonov superimposed against the rainbow flag was making the rounds on social media.
To celebrate the US Supreme Court's ruling, the White House was on Friday lit up in rainbow colours.
Some activists said that Russia, too, would one day uphold gay people's right to marry but they would unlikely live long enough to see that day.
"Mostly likely I will not live to see the day when some democratic, honestly-elected president illuminates the Kremlin in rainbow colours for one day," journalist and activist Anton Krasovsky said on Facebook.
"There will be happiness. For sure. Because love wins," wrote Elena Kostyuchenko, the openly gay correspondent for Russia's top opposition newspaper Novaya Gazeta.
In 2013, Russia passed a hugely controversial law banning the promotion or display of homosexuality in front of minors.
Russia has also adopted legislation banning adoptions by gay parents.
Homophobia remains widespread in the country, and almost no public figures have come out as gay.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:05:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than 500 injured in explosion at Taiwan water park party</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a05c3e/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Ctaiwan0C1170A35170CExplosion0Einjures0E20A0A0Eat0ETaiwan0Ewater0Epark0Eparty0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Taiwan police detain five people after coloured powder ignites into a fireball above crowds of revellers at a packed party at a water park</Description>
        <MainBody>Taiwan
More than 500 injured in explosion at Taiwan water park party
Taiwan police detain five people after coloured powder ignites into a fireball    above crowds of revellers at a packed party at a water park
Emergency rescue workers and concert spectators tend to injured victims at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei CityPhoto: AP
By Danielle Demetriou, Tokyo
2:05PM BST 28 Jun 2015
More than 500 young revellers were injured in a horrific fire that tore through a packed party in an amusement park in New Taipei City leaving Taiwan in a state of shock.
Five people, including the organiser of the event, were arrested for questioning by police following the fire, which is believed to have been caused by powder exploding in the air above the crowds.
Authorities launched an immediate investigation into the incident and imposed a nationwide ban on the coloured powder, which is suspected to have ignited due to the heat of the events lighting equipment.
A man carries an injured victim in taipei (AP)
Our initial understanding is this explosion and fire was caused by the powder spray. It could have been due to the heat of the lights on the stage, said a spokesman for the New Taipei City fire department.
In the aftermath of the event, the injury toll climbed to 524, with 419 people treated in 41 hospitals across the country following the fire, among them 194 in a serious condition.
In a reflection of the severity of the casualties injuries, Mao Chi-kuo, Taiwan prime minister, told reporters that the next few days will be a critical time for the injured.
Around 1,000 young revellers, many in their 20s or 30s and dressed in swimwear, gathered at Formosa Fun Coast water park to attend the Color Play Asia party when the fire broke out near the stage.
Amateur mobile phone footage captured scenes of dancing and loud music suddenly transforming into a panicked chaos, as sparks of flames ignited around the crowds before a large fireball engulfed the dancefloor.
One male partygoers told CTI, a local news channel: It started on the left side of the stage. At the beginning, I thought it was part of the special effects of the party but then I realised there was something wrong and people started screaming and running.
Following the fire, there were scenes of chaos throughout the venue, with hundreds of dazed injured placed in inflatable plastic doughnuts as friends collected cooling buckets of water while they waited to be seen by emergency services.
Other images depicted trails of bloodied footprints leaving the venue, with many of the injured suffering serious burns on their limbs and torsos as well as internally in their respiratory system having inhaled the powder, according to reports.
Among the seriously injured was Chu Li, an 18-year-old girl who suffered burns on 80 per cent of her body. Her whole life is ruined, her father sobbed, as president Ma Ying-jeou visited the injured in a Taipei hospital.
Taiwanese injured in a flash fire wait to be transferred to hospital at the Formosa Fun Coast park (EPA)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:04:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italy: EU request for powdered milk in mozzarella is 'attack' on cultural heritage</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a47db0/sc/26/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Citaly0C1170A43230CItaly0EEU0Erequest0Efor0Epowdered0Emilk0Ein0Emozzarella0Eis0Eattack0Eon0Ecultural0Eheritage0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>It is one of the country's most famous exports made using fresh buffalo milk but now agricultural producers fear it would lower the quality of the cheese</Description>
        <MainBody>Comments
Italy has accused the EU of "an attack" on its cultural heritage after Brussels demanded it consider producing mozzarella with powdered milk.
Mozzarella , traditionally made using fresh buffalo milk from southern Italy, is one of the country's most famous exports and is considered one of the most important symbols of Italy's passion for home-grown, natural produce.
But now the European Commission has sent an official letter to the ministry of agriculture, asking for an end of the ban on possession and use of milk powder, condensed milk and reconstituted milk in the manufacture of dairy products.
It considers the current ban "a restriction on the free movement of goods".
Dairy farm employees making buffalo mozzarella (Getty Images)
Roberto Moncalvo, president of Coldiretti, which represents agricultural producers, said the EU was forcing the country to lower its highly prized standards on food.
We are facing the umpteenth diktat from Europe," he said. "Even though the EU is wavering in front of unprecedented emergencies such as immigration , it is ready to support the lobbyists who want to force us to lower the quality of our food produce.
He described the call for change as an "attack" on one of the symbols of Italy.
It comes months after the European Commission allowed winemakers in the EU to use sugar to increase the alcohol content in their wine amid outrage from many producers.
Currently, no cheese or yogurt products made using powdered milk are allowed to enter the Italian market, under a 1974 law brought in to protect the quality of Italian produce.
However, the EU said the law is "a restriction on the free movement of goods, as milk powder and concentrated milk are used extensively in Europe".
Coldiretti said Italys reputation as a quality food producer would be damaged as a result of a change in the law. The export market for Italian cheeses and dairy products is thought to be worth more than 2 billion (1.42 billion).
Representatives from the EU Commission will meet with Italys ministry of agriculture on July 24 to discuss the situation.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:00:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Dalai Lama at Glastonbury: the atrocities of Isis are 'unthinkable'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a47b63/sc/38/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cculture0Cglastonbury0C1170A4260A0CThe0EDalai0ELama0Eat0EGlastonbury0Ethe0Eatrocities0Eof0EIsis0Eare0Eunthinkable0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The 80-year-old spiritual leader denounced the current violence in Iraq, Syria and Nigeria in his speech at Glastonbury's Stone Circle</Description>
        <MainBody>Glastonbury
The Dalai Lama at Glastonbury: the atrocities of Isis are 'unthinkable'
The 80-year-old spiritual leader denounced the current violence in Iraq, Syria    and Nigeria in his speech at Glastonbury's Stone Circle
The Dalai Lama takes to the stage at Glastonbury FestivalPhoto: Yui Mok / PA
By Rupert Hawksley
Comments
The Dalai Lama has publicly criticised the violence and murder carried out by Isis in Africa and the Middle East. Speaking at the Glastonbury festival on Sunday, the 80-year-old spiritual leader said, "A lot of problems we are experiencing are our own creations. Violence is being created this very moment in Syria, Iraq and Nigeria. Humans killing each other in the name of religious faith. Unthinkable. Carry the message of love and tolerance and forgiveness.
"There is nothing wrong with religious beliefs but some supporters of religions have a lack of moral principle and conviction.
 Glastonbury 2015 Sunday - today's highlights including Kanye West reaction, the Dalai Lama and more
"Yes, I'm Buddhist and Asian and I am his holiness the Dalai Lama but we are the same human being."
A crowd of more than 1,000 festival-goers gathered at the Stone Circle on Sunday morning to hear the Dalai Lama speak. As His Holiness arrived on stage, a spontaneous rendition of Happy Birthday rang out across Worthy Farm - even though it was not the Dalai Lama's birthday.
The Dalai Lama shelters from the rain at Glastonbury (Photo: Yui Mok / PA)
The Dalai Lama joked that he didn't get a great deal of pleasure from music but was enjoying his experience of Glastonbury nonetheless.
"Brothers and sisters, I noticed when I came in the car so many people, old and young, full of joy. My friend asked me to come to this festival of people, not necessarily a festival of government or politicians. This is about people.
"The very purpose of our life is a happy life. Nobody knows what will happen but hope is the basis of our life. Some individuals have lost hope but this mental attitude will shorten their life.
 Glastonbury 2015: mud, music and mayhem, in pictures
His pacifist address included a plea for an overhaul of the global education system saying that the "long-term solution to problems is introducing into education the message of warm heartedness and care."
"Whether you agree or not, I think the modern education system - and many scientists all have the same view - is very orientated around material values and external wealth.
"The gap between rich and poor is not only morally wrong but also the source of all problems. We need more money, so if the world demilitarised, the money freed up could be used to reduce this gap, as well as freeing up funds to help the environment.
"These things will not be achieved in my lifetime, perhaps not yours either, but the younger generation of the 21st century could make this a more peaceful world."
At a later discussion on climate change at William's Green, he nodded approvingly at the suggestion made by one panel member that it is "not too late" to change our ways and have a positive impact on the environment.
Asked for his opinion, the Dalai Lama said: "Cars and aeroplanes have negative side effects but they are also quite useful. But if this planet becomes like a desert there will be no hope. We can't settle in space so this is our only hope, we have to take great care of our planet."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:07:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Coach driver killed as bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a47b64/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cbelgium0C1170A410A80COne0Ekilled0Eas0Ebus0Ecarrying0EBritish0Eschoolchildren0Ecrashes0Ein0EBelgium0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>One person is killed after a bus carrying 34 from Brentwood School in Essex crashes in West Flanders</Description>
        <MainBody>Belgium
Coach driver killed as bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium
One person is killed after a bus carrying 34 from Brentwood School in Essex    crashes in West Flanders
Emergency service at the scene following the crash Photo: Rex Features
By Javier Espinoza , Education Editor
12:07PM BST 28 Jun 2015
Follow
A coach driver has been killed and his assistant and two children seriously injured after a vehicle carrying pupils and staff from a private school in Essex crashed in Belgium .
The bus was carrying 34 children from the 31,000 a year Brentwood School and eight adults when it overturned on the E40 Motorway in Middelkerke, near the Belgian coast.
One of the pupils is seriously injured and in intensive care, a spokesman for the school said. He is between the ages of 11 and 13.
The pupils had embarked on a language trip to Cologne on Sunday. Staff from the school are on their way to provide assistance.
"Everyone is accounted for," the spokesman said. It is not yet clear when they will return to the UK.
The accident happened around 9.45 am local time on the E40 Motorway section near Slijpe in West Flanders.
A rescue services worker carries students' backpacks at the site where a bus carrying 34 British schoolchildren crashed off the E40 highway in Middelkerke, Belgium (AFP)
The bus driver reportedly lost control of his vehicle and hit the pillar of a bridge. The vehicle went off the road and ended up on its side, in a ditch.
The 34 children are aged between 11 and 13 and are British nationals.
The school spokesman said: "A coach travelling to Cologne with thirty four first and second year pupils and six teachers from the School was involved in a collision with a bridge near Ostend in Belgium.
 Tom Marivoet (@TMarivoet) June 28, 2015
"All pupils walked off the coach and several pupils and teachers have been taken to local hospitals. One pupil is in intensive care receiving treatment for a head injury.
"We have informed all the parents of the thirty four pupils and the headmaster, Ian Davies, is holding a briefing for them at the School this morning.
"We have been informed that the driver was killed in the collision and his assistant has been severely injured. Our thoughts are clearly with his family and all the families of the pupils and teachers involved.
"Two senior members of staff have travelled to Belgium this morning, and as soon as we have more information we will inform everyone involved."
Not all children are in hospital. Several pupils and teachers are there and some are at a local swimming pool, the school said.
A man sitting next to the driver passed away, while the driver himself sustained heavy injuries. Various passengers have been brought to hospitals in the area.
Emergency services set up a mobile triage unit at the scene (nieuws.vtm.be)
A nurse in Sint-Jan Brugge in the city of Ostende - about 10 kilometres from where the accident took place - said the children were spread out in different A&amp;Es over nearby areas. She said their hospital had looked after two school children who suffered minor injuries.
"They are all right," she said. However, she would not reveal their ages or the name of their school.
Op E40 in #Middelkerke kantelde bus met kinderen. Wellicht 2 zwaar- en 42 lichtgewonden http://t.co/54eJq5RcD6 pic.twitter.com/dRzgkACpyQ
 Hubert De Meulder (@HubertDeMeulder) June 28, 2015
The children are being looked after at hospital and at local leisure centre, initial reports said.
The local paper Nieuwsblad has reported the person killed was one of the drivers of the bus, who was sitting beside the driver at the wheel.
According to local sources, the bus reportedly hit one of the pillars supporting the motorway bridge and fell over, landing on its side below the bridge.
An onlooker looks at the bus above the protection barrier from a bridge after a bus accident on the E40 highway in Middelkerke (Rex Features)
It is not yet clear how many people have been injured but some children have been taken to hospital, according to local news reports.
A spokesman from Richmond Coaches, of Ballinderry Road, Lisburn, in Northern Ireland, confirmed that one of its vehicles had been involved in the crash.
He said what had happened was "a tragedy" and the company was co-operating with the authorities.
He said the company's thoughts were with everyone involved.
The Foreign and Commonwealth Office said: "Following the crash of a British bus in Belgium, a British Embassy team is in the area providing consular assistance to those involved. We are working closely with the Belgian authorities to establish details of the incident."
A police spokesman said: "The injured have been taken to hospitals nearby. All non-injured passengers haven been transfered to a crisis centre to receive psychological assistance and help.
"The community of Middelkerke is setting up a support service including clothing, food and psychological assistance."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:00:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Families struggle to comprehend the loss of loved ones on holiday</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a3ae6c/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cislamic0Estate0C1170A37930CFamilies0Estruggle0Eto0Ecomprehend0Ethe0Eloss0Eof0Eloved0Eones0Eon0Eholiday0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Families mourn as the tragic stories of those who lost their lives are revealed</Description>
        <MainBody>Families struggle to comprehend the loss of loved ones on holiday
Families mourn as the tragic stories of those who lost their lives are revealed
Families mourn as they learn the details of their loved ones
By Patrick Sawer , and Nicola Harley
11:00AM BST 28 Jun 2015
They were grandparents enjoying a family holiday, students taking a deserved break over the summer and loving couples relishing some precious time together.
Now their grief-stricken families sit at home mourning the loss of their loved ones  gunned down on a Tunisian beach by an engineering student inspired by the jihadists of Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant.
The first Britain victim to be confirmed as dead was Carly Lovett, a 24-year-old who had travelled to the Tunisian resort with her fianc Liam Moore for a summer holiday.
The former University of Lincoln student had only recently launched her own blog writing about beauty products and treatments.
She had already built up a substantial following.
Carly Lovett
Before leaving for Tunisia on Tuesday, Miss Lovett, who had become engaged to her boyfriend Liam Moore, 26, in December, wrote on Twitter: Definitely leaving in like three hours and definitely am not finished packing.
Miss Lovett worked in her home town of Gainsborough, in Lincolnshire, as a photographer at the e-commerce company Fizzco.
She wrote on the profile page of her beauty blog: My name is Carly Im the beauty junkie/closet hoarder/design lover. Im not remotely a beauty expert and probably dont have much beauty knowledge at all, but so what.
I like beauty a lot, love trying new things and experimenting. I may not blend to perfection  and more often than not I apply eyeshadow with my fingers  but beauty doesnt have to mean conformity.
Kyle Leeman, 23, a childhood friend of Miss Lovett, said she was a kind and outgoing person.
He added: I am absolutely devastated. Its not something you expect. I knew her sister, her mum, her dad and her boyfriend.
She got me into a lot of the music I am in to. We always had really great times together. She was always one to express herself. I am really so sorry for all of her family. My thoughts are with them all. If theres anything I can do to help them, I will always be there to do it. They are a really close family, so I think it will hit them all very hard.
Dave Overton, another friend of Miss Lovett, said she was the kind of person who would have done her best to help others in an emergency.
He explained: Carly was an undergraduate student where I worked at the University of Lincoln, and I got to know her as she used the photographic facilities.
I found her not only friendly but also a tough character with a sensible and practical outlook on life.
The first Britain victim to be confirmed as dead was Carly Lovett, a 24-year-old who had travelled to the Tunisian resort with her fianc Liam Moore
The University of Lincolns media Twitter account posted on Friday night: Saddened to hear news reports of Carly Lovett in Tunisia  graduate of our University 2013.
Fellow bloggers have been shocked by the news of Miss Lovetts death. Claire Fearon tweeted: The horrors hit us all and though our community is small, we bloggers are strong. My thoughts go out to all other lives lost.
Laura Byrne wrote: Very sad to hear that beauty blogger @ceejayell [Miss Lovetts Twitter name] was sadly caught up in the terrible Tunisia shootings yesterday and lost her life. RIP Carly.
A Just Giving page has been set up by bloggers with a target to raise 500 for Carlys family.
A friend of Miss Lovetts fianc Liam, who did not want to be named, said: Its a real shock, Im still trying to get my head around it after hearing the news last night. Liam and I used to know each other from work, I think he had been with Carly for a long time.
One teenage boy witnessed two members of his family wiped out when Seifeddine Rezgui rampaged through the tourist resort of Sousse.
Owen Richards, 16, was on holiday with his brother Joel, 19, and his uncle Adrian Evans, 49, who were both gunned down and killed.
Owen managed to flee from the carnage but is believed to be in hospital.
Owen Richards, witnessed his brother Joel Richards, right, being gunned down
His grandfather Patrick Evans is feared dead.
Sandwell council in the West Midlands, which employed Mr Evans as a manager in its gas services department, described the news as horrendous and said their thoughts were with the family and council colleagues.
Mr Evans had been on his first day of his holiday and had been due to spend seven days in Tunisia before a weeks stay in France.
A council source said: When I heard about it, I was sickened. To have someone so close to you lost in such a way is terrible. He was a committed man who gave good service to the people of Sandwell.
Reece Watters, a family friend, paid tribute to Joel on Facebook, saying: Theres no status or no words I could put here that could describe to you how much of a kind guy Joel was. If you knew him personally, you would know how respected he was and how he played such a big part in many peoples lives.
He never had anything bad to say about anybody, people would never argue with him because of how likeable he was. He helped everyone he ever came in contact with, even when it involved putting others before himself.
Its so heartbreaking to think that he was on holiday in Tunisia with his brother and uncle when some scum decided to do what he did to all those people, including Joel.
James Connollys GFC, a Gaelic football club for which Joel played, said: He was an exceptionally talented footballer who represented both club and county.
On Saturday Sue Davey, 44, and her partner Scott Chalkley, 42, were confirmed as being among the victims by their children.
They were on the beach when the gunman opened fire. The couples belongings were found and brought back to their hotel, including their mobile phones.
Mr Chalkleys son, Ross Naylor, and Ms Daveys son, Conor Fulford, spent frantic hours waiting for news of them to emerge. Both men turned to social media in the hope someone would be able to provide news of the couple, who were staying at the Imperial Hotel in Sousse.
Scott Chalkley
Mr Chalkley's son Ross Naylor broke the news on Twitter that his father had been killed.
Mr Naylor, 23, said: "Tonight me and Brad lost our dad, unfortunately he was caught up in the sickening attacks in Tunisia and is no longer with us.
"I feel I had to put this message out as many of you have been asking about him and asking for an update.
"We are all trying to come to grips and process what has happened.
"I want to say thanks to everyone who has helped, you have all been amazing.
"One love to all and rest in peace dad."
Please take the time to read this ? pic.twitter.com/xXvcJ1J3yu
 A$AP ROSSI (@rossinaylor) June 27, 2015
Mr Fulford thanked people for their help as he announced the tragic news.
He tweeted: "Sorry to tell you we lost my mother Sue Davey tonight but i want to thank everybody that tried to help me and my family.
"My mom was a strong women who didn't take no crap from nobody so when you lie down tonight wish my mom goodnight as I know i sure will xxxxx
"Love you always Mom, I've got my teddy bear you got me tonight, Rest easy xxxx"
Hi Everyone, Sorry to tell you we lost my mother Sue Davey tonight but i want to thank everybody that tried to help me &amp; my family ...
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
My mom was a strong women who didn't take no crap from nobody so when you lie down tonight wish my mom goodnight as I know i sure will xxxxx
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
Love you always Mom, I've got my teddy bear you got me tonight, Rest easy xxxx
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
The 23-year-old from Tamworth, Staffs, had posted a series of messages on Twitter seeking information. He said: We have located her phone. It got brought back to the hotel where she is staying. But nobody knows where she is or her partner. We are still trying to find her, ringing hospitals and clinics  but nothing yet.
I am just hoping maybe she is in a hotel and she has got no internet and hasnt any way of contacting us.
We have rung loads and loads of different clinics but she is not on their lists.
I am just hoping for anything. We just want to get as much information as possible, anybody who can tell us where she is or how she is.
Mr Naylor had earlier written on Twitter: Havent spoken to my dad since the attack, please, please, please RT as he is missing along with his partner.
The 23-year-old said his fears had increased after hotel staff told him his father and Ms Davey were on the beach after finding some of their bags on the sand.
Mr Naylor, from Derby, described his father as a loving, typical bloke, adding: Hes a fun-loving guy.
Even though he is 20 years older than me, hes like a mate  thats how it is. They say no news is good news but I would just rather hear something. I dont know what to do with myself. I just want to hear that hes safe.
Owen Richards, Adrian Evans, Patrick Evans , and Joel Richards
John and Janet Stocker, a couple who were on holiday, were also feared dead. Mr Stockers son Mark appealed for help, saying: Weve spoken to every hospital in Sousse and the surrounding areas.
One of my brothers managed to speak to someone in the hotel  theyve gone and checked their room but their stuff is still in there. Its just trying to work out what we do.
Another of the victims was feared to be 60-year-old James McGuire, who was carried to a nearby hospital from the beach, where he had been sunbathing.
James McGuire
Adam Fisher, from Redhill, Surrey, has not spoken to his parents, Ray and Angela, since they left for their holiday.
He said he felt powerless over the situation, adding: Ive been in touch with the Foreign Office but they wont give any information. I dont know what to do.
Ray and Angela Fisher
John Welch, 74, from Corsham, Wilts, and his partner Eileen Swannack, 70, were also missing feared dead. The couple have not answered their phones since the attack. Mr Welchs grandson Daniel Welch, 29, from Swindon, said he had been told by the Foreign Office that officials had been unable to locate the pair.
He added: You know that were going to get some sort of news at some point, whether it be today, tomorrow or the next day, and you know its probably not going to be great, because they havent been able to make contact themselves by now.
Daniel said the hardest thing was not knowing. He added: We are at a bit of a loss and we can only expect the worst.
Eileen Swannack, 70 and her partner John Welch, 74
The family of Denis and Elaine Thwaites, from Blackpool, Lancs, are appealing for information about their whereabouts.
The retired couple, aged 70 and 69, arrived in Sousse on Wednesday and had been staying at the Hotel Riu Imperial Marhaba.
Danny Clifford, their son-in-law, said the family had heard from Tunisia that the couple were being treated in hospital.
He added: Were not 100 per cent certain but we believe they are injured in hospital.
Elaine and Denis Thwaite
Weve not had contact from the Foreign Office. We dont know which hospital or the extent of their injuries but its the best news weve had all day.
An Irish mother of two, Lorna Carty, from Robinstown, Co Meath, was confirmed as among the dead.
The nurse, in her 50s, was gunned down on the beach while getting some last-minute sunbathing just hours before she was due to return home from the resort along with her husband Declan. She had taken him on holiday to help him recover from heart surgery.
Charlie Flanagan, Irelands foreign affairs minister, warned that further Irish casualties could not be ruled out.
Lorna Carty
He said: The embassy team is also continuing to provide all possible consular support to the bereaved family of the Irish citizen who had been confirmed yesterday as being among the deceased. This is a tragic and difficult time for the families and loved ones of those concerned.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:57:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French Islamist killer may have sent selfie photo with decapitated head to Syria</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a3aaf3/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C1170A41190CFrench0EIslamist0Ekiller0Emay0Ehave0Esent0Eselfie0Ephoto0Ewith0Edecapitated0Ehead0Eto0ESyria0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Attacker beheaded his boss and posed as if it was a trophy</Description>
        <MainBody>French Islamist killer may have sent selfie photo with decapitated head to Syria
Attacker beheaded his boss and posed as if it was a trophy

Image1of2
Special forces of France's Research and Intervention Brigades (BRI) escort an unidentified woman and a child as they leave the building housing the appartment of a man suspected of carrying out an attack in Saint-Priest near LyonPhoto: PHILIPPE DESMAZES/AFP/Getty Images

Image1of2
French police and firefighters gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier Photo: AFP/Getty
By David Chazan, Paris
10:57AM BST 28 Jun 2015
An Islamist who beheaded his boss sent a picture of the decapitated head to a mobile rumoured to be in Syria, sparking speculation that he may not have been a lone wolf attacker.
Yassin Salhi, 35, took a selfie, posing beside the head as if it was a trophy minutes after the beheading in south-eastern France, according to a source close to the investigation. He sent the picture to a Canadian mobile phone number via the WhatsApp messaging service.
The number was recorded in Salhis mobile under a pseudonym that could be the nom de guerre of a young Frenchman who went to fight in Syria, according to Le Parisien newspaper.
Special forces of France's Research and Intervention Brigades (BRI) escort an unidentified woman and a child as they leave the building housing the appartment of a man suspected of carrying out an attack in Saint-Priest near Lyon
However, a security source said: The hypothesis that it was sent to Syria is more than tenuous and there is no evidence so far linking Salhi with terrorist groups. For now, investigators believe it is more likely he acted alone.
Immediately after sending the picture, Salhi, who Sunday confessed to the killing to police, tried to blow up a chemical factory in south-eastern France on Friday in what investigators believe was intended as a suicide attack. He was arrested before he could carry out the plan.
French police and firefighters gather at the entrance of the Air Products company
The location of the mobile phone he sent the picture to has not been established but investigators believe it may have been a relay number from which the photo could have been sent on to another recipient. There is speculation that he could have been taking orders from the person or persons he sent the photo to or perhaps he was simply inspired by them and wanted to show them what he had done, the security source said.
Salhi remained silent for 30 hours after his arrest before starting to talk to police in Lyon. He is to be transferred to Paris on Sunday. His wife and sister are also in custody and his three children, two boys and a girl, all under 10, have been taken into care.
His former martial arts instructor told Le Parisien that Salhi was a time bomb although the security services had ceased surveillance of him because they considered he posed no imminent danger. He was first flagged up as a potential terrorist in 2006.
When he was fighting, he allowed himself to be hit without reacting, without even protecting his face. Then after a few minutes, he exploded with anger and hit out in all directions with an incredible rage, according to the instructor, who taught him for more than two years. He was dangerous for himself and others. He didnt fight: he was waging war. The instructor said many others had refused to fight him, adding that he was an unusual figure at the gym, with a long beard.
A friend of the man he beheaded, Herv Cornara, 54, told Le Figaro he had witnessed several heated arguments between the delivery firm boss and his employee.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:48:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait attack: suicide bomber was Saudi</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a3a6e6/sc/11/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Ckuwait0C1170A40A760CKuwait0Eattack0EIslamic0EState0Esuicide0Ebombing0Eat0EShia0Emosque0Ekills0E130Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Fahd Suliman Abdul-Muhsen al-Qabaa flew into Kuwait's airport at dawn hours before he detonated explosives at a Shia Muslim mosque killing at least 27 people</Description>
        <MainBody>It said that he entered the country through Kuwait Airport at dawn on Friday, the same day of the bombing.
A handout photograph of Qaba'a showed a young bearded man wearing a traditional Saudi headdress.
Earlier on Sunday, the ministry said that security services arrested the driver of the car that transported the bomber to the Al-Imam Al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City.
An injured man cobered in blood is helped to an ambulance following the attack
He was named as Abdulrahman Sabah Eidan Saud and described as an "illegal resident" born in 1989.
Authorities on Saturday arrested the car owner, Jarrah Nimr Mejbil Ghazi, born in 1988, and also listed as a stateless person.
Authorities have also detained the owner of a house used as a hideout by the driver, describing the owner as a Kuwaiti national who subscribes to "extremist and deviant ideology".
 Were Tunisia, France, Kuwait attacks co-ordinated by Islamic State for Ramadan?
"Illegal resident" is the official term used in Kuwait to describe stateless people, locally known as bidoons, who number around 110,000 and claim the right to Kuwaiti citizenship.
Alleged IS executioner Mohammed Emwazi, who became known by media as "Jihadi John", was born in Kuwait to a stateless family of Iraqi origin which later moved to London.
Local media said 18 of those killed were Kuwaitis, three Iranians, two Indians, one each from Pakistan and Saudi Arabia and one bidoon.
The breakthroughs in the bombing probe came a day after thousands of Kuwaitis braved scorching summer heat on Saturday to attend the funerals of 18 victims.
Driver Abdulrahman Sabah Eidan Saud (left) and car owner Jarrah Nimr Mejbil Ghazi
Mourners turned out in large numbers for the funerals despite the Ramadan daylight fast and as temperatures hit 45 degrees Celsius (113 Fahrenheit).
"This crowd is the proof that the objectives of the criminal act have failed," parliament speaker Marzouk al-Ghanem told reporters.
The mourners, who included women clad in black Islamic dress, carried Kuwaiti flags and black and green banners bearing religious slogans.
The health ministry said that 40 wounded are still being treated in hospital.
In Iraq, relatives wept as the coffins of the eight remaining victims arrived and were taken inside the airport terminal at Najaf, an AFP journalist said.
They were buried at dawn on Sunday in Najaf's Wadi al-Salam cemetary, according to deputy provincial council head Luay al-Yasiri.
"We want to deliver a message to Daesh (an Arabic acronym for IS) that we are united brothers among the Sunnis and Shiites, and they cannot divide us," said Abdulfatah al-Mutawwia, a Kuwaiti living in Iraq who lost his brother in the bombing.
Tens of thousands of people headed by the emir offered condolences late Saturday to relatives of victims at Kuwait's Grand Mosque, the largest place of worship for Sunni Muslims, in a show of solidarity.
The cabinet announced after an emergency meeting on Friday that all security agencies and police had been put on alert to confront what it called "black terror".
Justice and Islamic Affairs Minister Yacoub al-Sane said additional security measures will be taken around mosques and places of worship.
The emir, government, parliamentary and political groups and clerics have all said Friday's attack aimed to stir up sectarian strife in the emirate.
The radical Sunni IS considers Shiites, which comprise a third of Kuwait's 1.3 million native population, to be heretics.
In the first working day after the bombing, Kuwait Stock Exchange dropped just 0.75 percent and was trading on 6,165.22 points after one hour of opening.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:00:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Syrian vineyard making the world's most dangerous wine</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a27f5d/sc/26/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Csyria0C1170A36230CSyrian0Evineyard0Emaking0Ethe0Eworlds0Emost0Edangerous0Ewine0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Chateau Bargylus's wine is on the menus of top Michelin-starred restaurants around the world, but the journey it takes to reach diner's glasses is a perilous one</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria
Syrian vineyard making the world's most dangerous wine
Chateau Bargylus's wine is on the menus of top Michelin-starred restaurants    around the world, but the journey it takes to reach diner's glasses is a    perilous one
Brothers Karim, and Sandro Saade, pictured at Chateau Marsyas in Lebanon Photo: bargylus.com
Follow
Chateau Bargylus is on the wine menu of Heston Blumenthal's Dinner in London, L'Atelier de Joel Robuchon, Gordon Ramsay and Marcus Wareing.
Reaching the Michelin-starred tables of the finest eateries of London and Paris might seem par for the course for a top Bordeaux or Burgundy, but for a bottle of Bargylus it is little short of miraculous.
That is because it is the only internationally recognised wine in the world today produced from grapes grown and picked in Syria - a country wracked for the past four years by a horrific and bloody civil war, and where for most the main goal is staying alive, not sipping syrah.
Despite the difficulties, this week, Bargylus became the first Syrian wine ever to be exhibited at the Vinexpo wine fair in Bordeaux  the worlds largest, which this year was opened by French president Franois Hollande in person  placing Syria well and truly on the international wine map.
The feat is all the more remarkable because in many parts of the country, those found drinking any kind of alcohol  let alone a boutique red - face 100 lashes or worse from fighters of the medieval-minded Islamic State and other jihadist groups seeking to create a self-styled caliphate.
Chateau Bargylus is on the wine menu of Heston Blumenthal's Dinner in London, L'Atelier de Joel Robuchon, Gordon Ramsay and Marcus Wareing
The Domaine de Bargylus comprises 12 hectares of vineyards on a tree-lined plateau in the Mediterranean province of Latakia, northwest Syria  some 900m into the hills above the countrys largest port. The Romans used the same verdant slopes of what used to be called Mount Bargylus  now Jabal Ansariya - for their own wineries two millennia ago, as did the Greeks and Phoenicians.
Today, it must be the most difficult wine to produce in the world and probably the most dangerous, said Sandro Saad, a Syrian-Lebanese 38-year-old who runs the wine estate along with his brother Karim, 41.
He should know. Last June, two stray mortars tore through one of his vineyards, pulverising 15 plants of the domains prized chardonnay.
We dont know where they came from but probably from a village around three kilometres away controlled by Isis kind of people, said Karim. The situation is not great we have to admit, but we have no choice but to continue.
Workers then took cover again when a fire fight last August between government forces and rebels broke out as close as 100 yards from the farm. Thankfully in both occasions there were no casualties, just a few bullet holes in fences, and the fighting appears to have moved off.
We have been lucky. We are in an area that is relatively preserved...most of the time, Sandro told the Sunday Telegraph.
The Saads, a Christian family with a wine-growing history, decided to plant grape vines in Latika in 2003, well before president Bashar al-Assads bloody repression of anti-government street protests in 2011 sparked civil conflict. They produced their first vintage in 2006.
Their grandfather had owned land there confiscated in1960 by Egypts Nasser regime when it briefly took over Syria. Returning was not just about wine making but reclaiming roots in what the French call terroir  the local soil - in a region increasingly hostile to Christians and other minorities. Wine ties you to the land, said Karim. You cannot just pack up and leave.
The Syrian coastal mountain range is the heartland of Assads Alawite community, and the wine estate is little more than an hours drive to Qardaha, hometown of the Assad family. Should he lose Damascus, it is likely the embattled president will retreat here, and possibly seek to establish a breakaway Alawite state, which would include much of the local range and the city of Latakia.
Although last month an explosion in the port killed four, the province has largely been shielded from the full force of the war's destructive power, protected by some of the Syrian military's most formidable units.
Founder Johnny R Saade and sons Karim Saade and Sandro Saade
Despite this, neither Saad brother, based in neighbouring Beirut, has set foot on the wine domain in four years due to the risk of being kidnapped by militants or brigands on the increasingly perilous roads crossing the Syrian-Lebanese border.
Wine making in a war-torn country is not just life threatening, it is a logistical nightmare.
Most of the time the brothers rely on 35 local workers, paid in dollars as the Syrian pound has gone through the floor.
These are Muslim, Alawite and Christian families, a little bit of everybody. The people who work at Bargylus are obviously open-minded and have no issues with that. Its not so rare. Most people want to live like as did before the war, and day to day activities continue as best they can, said Karim.
Staff are in constant contact with the brothers in Beirut. The tricky part, however, comes with the approach of harvest time, normally late September to mid October, when the brothers, along with renowned French wine consultant Stephane Derenoncourt, need to taste the grapes - particularly their skin - for maturity.
The only way to do so is to ferry the fruit on ice in a taxi across the border to Beirut, a trip that takes four hours if nothing goes wrong. But there have been many cases when the taxi couldnt get through and had to go back and fetch a new batch, either because the border was closed or due to a security issue either side, said Sandro.
It takes months to bring bottles, corks and labels from France. Once the wine is vinified and boxed, it takes another 45 days or so to ferry it from Latakia to a warehouse in Antwerp, Belgium via Egypts port Said.
The land itself is not easy to work. The limestone, flint and clay terrain is tough on the tractors, whose wheels need changing twice a year, and there is a lot of wind, but warm days and cool nights offer excellent conditions for maturing the grapes.
Despite all the challenges, the brothers insist the wine making that goes into producing 45,000 bottles annually matches top-notch Bordeaux or Californian estates, using techniques that are close to biodynamic.
The difference here is we do it in the middle of nowhere.
As for the wines, the reds are made mainly of syrah, with cabernet sauvignon and merlot  spicy with a hint of black olives, a hint of black truffle in the mouth, said Sandro. The pale whites, a mixture of chardonnay and sauvignon blanc, are crisp and citrous with good acidity and complexity and a lot of minerality and saltiness from the coastal wind.
Bottles cost around 36 euros for a red in Paris wine stores and 28 euros for a white. Britain, along with Dubai are the labels top markets, but it is now branching out to Hong Kong and Japan, and perhaps the US.
So far, this years grapes are doing well. A month and a half ago we had some frost, but it so far were ok and the next two months will be crucial, said Karim.
For a war-ravaged country in the sweltering Middle East, he said his biggest fear was that most British of blights: rain.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 06:10:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taiwan water park party explosion: number of injured jumps to 500</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a18147/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Ctaiwan0C1170A39150CTaiwan0Ewater0Epark0Eparty0Eexplosion0Enumber0Eof0Einjured0Ejumps0Eto0E50A0A0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>More than 180 remain in intensive care after a ball of fire tore through a crowd at a water park outside Taipei</Description>
        <MainBody>Taiwan
Taiwan water park party explosion: number of injured jumps to 500
More than 180 remain in intensive care after a ball of fire tore through a    crowd at a water park outside Taipei
By Agencies
4:10AM BST 28 Jun 2015
More than 500 people were injured, almost 200 of them seriously, when a ball of fire ripped through a crowd at a water park outside Taiwan's capital Taipei, authorities said Sunday.
The number of those injured in the blast, which came as coloured powder being sprayed on the partygoers ignited late on Saturday, more than doubled as authorities began to track down victims who had taken themselves to hospital or been ferried there by others.
Emergency rescue workers and concert spectators tend to injured victims (AP)
Footage on the Apple Daily newspaper website showed crowds dancing as music played and clouds of powder being sprayed out which suddenly turned into an inferno that tore through the spectators.
Terrified partygoers were shown running for their lives, screaming, as they were overtaken by flames. Some were dressed only in swimwear and covered in the coloured powder.
Ambulances had struggled to reach the scene, and the original figures had only counted those hospitalised by emergency services.
A man carries an injured victim in taipei (AP)
Victims were carried away on rubber rings and inflatable dinghies as friends desperately tried to get them out.
Bystanders poured bottles of water on the scorched skin of the injured. Trails of bloody footprints leading away from the stage remained, an AFP reporter at the scene said.
The fire was quickly extinguished, according to authorities.
Around 1,000 spectators had been at the Color Play Asia event at the Formosa Fun Coast water park, just outside the capital Taipei, according to officials.
One male witness told local news channel CTI: "It started on the left side of the stage. At the beginning I thought it was part of the special effects of the party but then I realised there was something wrong and people started screaming and running."
Lee Lih-jong, deputy chief of the health bureau of the New Taipei City government, said 509 people had been injured with 188 of them seriously hurt.
The severely wounded are being treated in intensive care units at 37 different hospitals.
"The reason why the burns were so severe was that in addition to burns to the skin, there were also injuries caused by burns to the respiratory organs from the large amount of colour powder inhaled," Lee told AFP.
Taiwanese injured in a flash fire wait to be transferred to hospital at the Formosa Fun Coast park (EPA)
"The next 24 hours will be critical for those severely injured."
Lee said that details of the ages of the victims were not yet available, "but all looked very young, in their 20s or even younger".
Media reports said some victims had suffered burns to more than 40 percent of their bodies.
"Our initial understanding is this explosion and fire... was caused by the powder spray. It could have been due to the heat of the lights on the stage," said a spokesman for the New Taipei City fire department.
Police said that event manager Lu Chung-chi and four other event workers had been detained.
"They will be transferred to prosecutors for further investigation on charges of offences against public safety and negligence of duties that caused severe injuries," New Taipei police spokesman Yen Po-ren said.
Officials said that ambulances had found it difficult to get near to the site and had to send in emergency workers with stretchers.
"We feel sad and regretful about the accident," said New Taipei Mayor Eric Chu who was reported as saying it was the municipality's worst ever incident of mass injury.
He said that extra doctors had been called in to help treat the victims.
"I've ordered the park to shut down immediately and be placed under a rigorous investigation," Chu added.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 03:34:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek parliament backs referendum on bailout</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a17c2f/sc/24/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cfinance0Ceconomics0C1170A39120CGreek0Eparliament0Ebacks0Ereferendum0Eon0Ebailout0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Controversial plan will go ahead after 179 out of 300 Greek MPs back referendum on bailout</Description>
        <MainBody>Greek parliament backs referendum on bailout
Controversial plan will go ahead after 179 out of 300 Greek MPs back    referendum on bailout
Greek prime minister Alexis Tsipras arriving for the second day of the EU summitPhoto: THIERRY CHARLIER/AFP
Agencies
Comments
The Greek parliament has voted in favour of prime minister Alexis Tsipras' controversial motion to hold a referendum on the country's creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans.
Mr Tsipras and his coalition government have urged people to vote against the deal, throwing into question the country's financial future.
Greece has to pay 1.6bn (1.1bn) to the IMF on Tuesday. Without new funds, there are fears Greece may leave the euro and its economy may collapse .
Speaking in parliament, Mr Tsipras said he was confident the Greek people would reject the "insulting" bailout offer.
He said the vote would go ahead "whether our partners like it or not".
The sudden move comes after five months of stalemated negotiations, with Mr Tsipras accusing creditors of trying to strong-arm his country into taking harsh austerity measures he says would hammer an economy already on its knees after five months of creditor-demanded spending cuts and tax hikes.
"They didn't ask us to agree, they asked us to surrender our political dignity," Mr Tsipras said during a tumultuous and nearly 13-hour parliamentary session that cumulated in a vote just before 3am on Sunday. Out of parliament's 300 MPs, 178 voted in favor and 120 against, with two people absent.
Mr Tsipras said the reforms proposed by Greece's creditor institutions - the International Monetary Fund, European Central Bank and European Commission, were an ultimatum and an insult.
"We exhausted every limit of concessions so there could be an agreement," he said. "Perhaps some saw that as a weakness."
The vote is to be held next Sunday, June 5. It has raised the question of whether Greece can remain in Europe's joint currency, the euro. Many Greeks alarmed by the announcement for the referendum early Saturday morning formed queues at ATM machines , putting a further strain on banking deposits.
European Council President Donald Tusk said on Sunday that Greece must remain part of the euro single currency area, adding that he was in touch with government leaders to prevent Athens dropping out of the monetary union.
"Greece is and should remain euro area member," he tweeted after euro zone finance ministers refused to extend bailout loans ahead of a looming Greek debt default on Tuesday.
"In contact with leaders to ensure integrity of euro area of 19 countries," he added after the other 18 finance ministers met without their Greek counterpart in Brussels.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 03:15:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fund for activist who took down Confederate flag raises $75,000 in eight hours</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a17c31/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1170A38980CFund0Efor0Eactivist0Ewho0Etook0Edown0EConfederate0Eflag0Eraises0E750A0A0A0Ein0Eeight0Ehours0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Campaign to raise money in support of Bree Newsome, who scaled a flagpole to remove the "stars and bars", gathers pace</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Fund for activist who took down Confederate flag raises $75,000 in eight hours
Campaign to raise money in support of Bree Newsome, who scaled a flagpole to    remove the "stars and bars", gathers pace
By Reuters, video source APTN
1:15AM BST 28 Jun 2015
An online fundraiser for Bree Newsome, the activist who is in custody after climbing a flagpole outside the South Carolina state capitol early on Saturday and taking down the Confederate flag, has raised more than $75,000 in eight hours.
Support for Miss Newsome is growing swiftly, helped by the hashtag #FreeBree on Twitter. Filmmaker Michael Moore has also offered to help pay her legal fees.
She is being hailed as a hero by opponents of the flag, her actions likened by the The National Association for the Advancement of Colored People to those of Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.
"As well as supporting the permanent removal of the flag legislatively, we commend the courage and moral impulse of Ms. Newsome as she stands for justice like many NAACP activists including Henry David Thoreau, Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. and numerous Americans who have engaged in civil disobedience," NAACP President Cornell William Brooks said in a statement.
 Rahiel Tesfamariam (@RahielT) June 27, 2015
#Bree just climbed up &amp; took it down #ConfederateFlag -belongs in a museum or your backyard #FreeBree #SouthCarolina pic.twitter.com/K72ylT6hgv
 Bonnie Greer (@Bonn1eGreer) June 27, 2015
The Civil War-era flag has been a focal point for soul-searching across the southern United States in the aftermath of the fatal shooting last week of nine African Americans during a Bible study session at a historic church in Charleston, South Carolina.
The suspect in the shootings, Dylann Roof, 21, had posed with a Confederate flag in photos posted on a website that also displayed a racist manifesto.
Following the removal of the flag in Columbia, Miss Newsome and James Tyson were arrested and charged with defacing a monument, the South Carolina Department of Public Safety said in a statement. The banner was replaced within an hour and no further damage was caused, it said.
Bree Newsome of Charlotte, is taken into custody after she removed the Confederate battle flag
A group of local activists said they organised the removal of the flag, which by law flies at a memorial on the State House grounds honouring soldiers who fought on the side of the pro-slavery Confederacy during the 1860-65 American Civil War.
"We could not sit by and watch the victims of the Charleston Massacre be laid to rest while the inspiration for their deaths continues to fly above their caskets," activists using the Twitter tag #KeepItDown said in a statement.
At a funeral for the slain pastor in Charleston on Friday , Mr Obama called the banner "a reminder of systemic oppression and racial subjugation".
"For too long we were blind to the pain that the Confederate flag stirred in too many of our citizens," Obama said in his eulogy for Reverend Clementa Pinckney, 41, of Charleston's Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church.
Police surround protestor as she climbs the flagpole
The South Carolina Legislature is expected to begin debate next week on a measure allowing the state to remove the flag from the memorial. It flies there in keeping with legislation passed in 2000 that removed the crimson-and-blue banner from the top of the capitol dome in response to the demands of protesters.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:13:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia terror: Up to 23 Britons killed by beach gunman in hotel attack</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a1410b/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1170A38690CTunisia0Eterror0EUp0Eto0E230EBritons0Ekilled0Eby0Ebeach0Egunman0Ein0Ehotel0Eattack0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dramatic pictures emerge of Islamist moments before massacre, as relatives speak of grief and identities of the victims are revealed</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia
Tunisia terror: Up to 23 Britons killed by beach gunman in hotel attack
Dramatic pictures emerge of Islamist moments before massacre, as relatives    speak of grief and identities of the victims are revealed
Photo: Sky News
By Patrick Sawer, Tim Ross, Robert Mendick, Nicola Harley and Ben Farmer in Sousse
12:13AM BST 28 Jun 2015
Families of the Britons killed or feared dead in the Tunisian terrorist attack last night spoke of their grief amid fears the toll of British citizens murdered by an Islamist gunman could rise to as high as 23.
The Foreign Office confirmed that at least 15 Britons were among the 38 tourists killed on Friday, with a further 20 injured in the attack, several of them critically.
It is the worst loss of British life in a terrorist atrocity since the London bombings on July 7, 2005, when 52 people were killed, said Tobias Ellwood, the Foreign Office minister.
He added: Sadly, I can confirm that at least 15 British nationals were killed in yesterdays atrocity, but I should stress that the number may well rise as several more have been seriously injured in this horrific attack.
David Cameron also said the country should expect the worst. We are working with the Tunisian authorities to identify a final number on the British casualties, but Im afraid that the British public need to be prepared for the fact that many of those killed were British.
The warnings came as pictures were released last night by Sky News showing the gunman, Seifeddine Rezgui, walking calmly along the foreshore of the resort in Sousse, his automatic rifle by his side, moments after he began shooting. It has since emerged he was also armed with grenades or homemade bombs which he threw at his victims, before he was shot dead by police.
British beauty blogger and photographer Carly Lovett
Among the Britons killed was Carly Lovett, 24, from Gainsborough, Lincs, who had travelled to the resort with her fianc.
Owen Richards, 16, lost his brother Joel, 19, and uncle Adrian Evans, 49, in the onslaught which left hundreds of tourists fleeing for their lives. The boys grandfather, Patrick Evans was also feared dead.
L-R Owen Richards, Adrian Evans, Patrick Evans and Joel Richards
Relations of missing British tourists have spoken of their despair at hearing nothing from them since news of the attack broke.
Tunisia attack: glasses case in handbag saved Britons life
Daniel Welch, whose grandfather John Welch, 74, from Corsham, Wilts, and his partner Eileen Swannack, 70, were staying at the Imperial Marhaba hotel when it was attacked, said his family can only expect the worst.
He said: Its just that not knowing. You then start thinking, Why that resort? Why the holidaymakers? Why this place? What was the reason? You get all sorts of things running through your mind.
Further details emerged about Rezgui, a 23-year-old electronics student and Real Madrid supporter from the town of Gaafour, who was a member of an Islamist society at university and is now known to have posted his support for Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (Isil) on social media.
Rafik Chelly, Tunisias secretary of state for security, said he was previously unknown to authorities. He entered by the beach, dressed like someone who was going to swim, and he had a beach umbrella with his gun in it, he said.
Mr Cameron led a meeting of the Cobra emergency committee on Saturday, attended by the heads of MI5 and MI6; George Osborne, the Chancellor; Theresa May, the Home Secretary; and Philip Hammond, the Foreign Secretary. He also spoke to Beji Caid Essebsi, the Tunisian president; Franois Hollande, the French President, and Angela Merkel, the German Chancellor. Many of the tourists caught up in the shootings were from Germany.
By Saturday night, a team of 20 British Red Cross, Foreign Office staff and police had arrived at the scene of the attack. British security experts may also be sent to Tunisia.
Intelligence chiefs decided not to raise the threat level to the UK, which remains set at severe, meaning that an attack is highly likely. However, security was stepped up at major public events over the weekend, including yesterdays Armed Forces Day celebrations and Londons gay Pride march.
Mr Cameron said after the Cobra meeting: These savage terrorist attacks in Tunisia, Kuwait and France are a brutal and tragic reminder of the threat faced around the world from these evil terrorists.
Theres no doubt we face a very severe threat in our country and we have done for many months and many years, but the level of the threat is identified independently of government and published in the proper way.
I will ensure we do all we can to help those affected and to protect people from this terrorist threat. Our thoughts and prayers are with the loved ones of those killed or injured in the attack.
He added: We will do everything necessary to get people home, including those injured. These were innocent holidaymakers, relaxing and enjoying time with their friends and families.
These terrorists murdered them because [they] oppose people and countries who stand for peace, tolerance and democracy wherever they are in the world. But these terrorists will not succeed.
As he spoke, astonishing stories of survival amid the carnage at Sousse emerged.
Rita Williams, 76, had a narrow escape as a bullet tore through her pink straw sun hat. Mrs Williams, of Maesteg, South Wales, suffered a graze on her skull. She said: Ive been so lucky  Im still shaking. It was all so frightening.
Tunisia gunman Seifeddine Rezgui: 'mixed a devotion for Isil with passion for Real Madrid football team'
Tony Callaghan, 63, from North Walsham, who works for Norfolk police, was hit in the left knee and his wife Christine was also shot. But the couples glasses case and bag took the impact of bullets, almost certainly saving her from far greater injury.
Tony Callaghan with the glasses case
Within hours of the attack, travel firms had begun repatriating thousands of British tourists from beach resorts in the area. The North African nation is bracing itself for a devastating blow to its tourism industry, as the Tunisian government announced plans to deploy troops at vulnerable sites.
According to ABTA, the travel association, there were about 20,000 British tourists on package holidays in Tunisia at the time of the attack.
Among those caught up in the massacre at the five-star Imperial Marhaba Hotel, in the popular resort of Port el Kantaoui, were tourists travelling with Thomson/First Choice. The company sent 10 planes yesterday to repatriate about 2,500 customers, and announced it was cancelling all its holidays to Tunisia this week.
Jet2.com, which has 1,244 passengers in Tunisia, also began sending planes to collect those who wished to travel home.
But while hundreds of Britons began arriving back on Saturday, others were still stuck in their hotels, waiting desperately for a flight out.
Aaron Smith, 29, from Liverpool, who was on holiday with his girlfriend Morgan, 23, from Burnley, at the Marhaba Royal Salem Hotel, close to where the attacks took place, said: Everyone just wants to go home as soon as they can. People are going crazy, sitting inside waiting.
Some tourists have decided to stay on, including Angela Chambers and Peter Phillips, from Wales. I think we feel safer here than last night going to the airport, said Ms Chambers. Mr Phillips added we want to see our holiday out.
British police are interviewing many of the returning tourists, looking in particular for any footage taken on mobile phones.
Metropolitan Police assistant commissioner Mark Rowley, the national policing lead for counter-terrorism, said it was fairly clear the location of the Tunisian attack was chosen because of the number of Europeans present in the area.
Interactive: Sousse hotels
Writing in the Telegraph, Mr Hammond says: The brutal slaughter of innocent British tourists on their sunloungers in Tunisia is a tragic reminder of the threat we face from Islamic extremism and those inspired by Isil.
Colonel Tim Collins, a former British Army officer who served in the Iraq war, urged governments not to overreact, but to pursue those responsible with the full force of the law.
He said: Had the world, led by the United States, kept its head after 9/11, and treated Ground Zero as a huge crime scene instead of blundering into a war on terror, I believe the scenes we are witnessing around the world now would not be happening.
James Brokenshire, the immigration minister, said there was a risk that extremists could try to gain entry to Britain through the camp of 3,000 migrants gathered at Calais.
It is not something we have seen to date but it is something that we remain absolutely vigilant over. We are calling on the Italians and other southern Mediterranean states to up their screening and the taking of biometrics and the like from those arriving on their shores.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:11:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Terror on the beach: The full story of the Tunisia beach terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a1410c/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1170A38170CTerror0Eon0Ethe0Ebeach0EThe0Efull0Estory0Eof0Ethe0ETunisia0Ebeach0Eterror0Eattack0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Incredible stories of horror and heroism at the resort that turned suddenly from paradise to killing ground</Description>
        <MainBody>Terror on the beach: The full story of the Tunisia beach terror attack
Incredible stories of horror and heroism at the resort that turned suddenly    from paradise to killing ground
A injured man is taken to hospital after the attck on sunbathers on Sousse beach, Tunisia Photo: APTN
By Robert Mendick, Javier Espinoza and Ben Farmer and James Badcock  in El    Kantaoui
12:11AM BST 28 Jun 2015
Owen Richards just kept running. Around him bodies fell to the ground as the lone gunman took aim and fired at the tourists on the crowded beach.
The 16-year-old was hit in the shoulder, the bullet grazing his flesh on its way into the skull of the adult stood beside him. Owens uncle and brother also died in the onslaught.
Owen Richards, left, with (l-r) Adrian Evans, Patrick Evans and Joel Richards, who are all believed to have died
Owens terrifying ordeal emerged on Saturday, relayed by the medical team who treated the teenager for his injuries at a clinic in Sousse, a five-minute drive from the El Kantaoui resort, an area dominated by four and five star hotels and miles of pristine white sand.
Other astonishing tales of heroics and of fortune were also disclosed as Britain and the world came to terms with the massacre.
The beach at El Kantaoui was largely deserted yesterday. A huge area of sand running up to the rear entrance of the Rui Imperial Marhaba Hotel was fenced off, with upturned sunloungers serving as temporary barriers. The day before they had been used as makeshift stretchers.
Nearby concrete paths remained stained with blood. The hotel itself was empty apart from staff. Occupants had been bussed out in the night in the aftermath of the worst terrorist atrocity committed against British citizens since the July 7 attacks on London a decade ago.
The day before it had all been so different.
Police officers control the crowd while surrounding a man suspected of being involved in the attack (Reuters)
The El Kantaoui beach had been crowded with sunseekers. So too the Imperial Marhaba hotels large pool area and the other hotels around it, the Bellevue Hotel, the Royal Kenz Hotel and the Palm Marina Hotel. With temperatures already touching 85F this was perfect holiday weather for lazing by the water and doing nothing.
Just before noon on Friday that calm was shattered; all hell would break loose.
At the Bellevue, the water aerobics class had just finished when a family swimming in the hotels pool heard what they thought was the sound of firecrackers being set off; back on the beach, sunbathers also recalled hearing what they first assumed to be fireworks.
At the Imperial Marhaba, perhaps the most popular of the hotels on that stretch of coastline, this was the start of the high season and the hotels 370 rooms were close to 75 per cent occupancy.
In the absence of armed security, the holidaymakers, packed on the beach and at the pool, were effectively sitting ducks.
Bodies on the beach in Tunisia
Nobody seems to have noticed Seifeddine Rezgui, 23, a Tunisian student, who had wandered on to the beach, wearing black T-shirt and shorts. He was clean shaven and dressed like a Western tourist. In the dense fug of confusion, some reports suggested he had arrived by boat; others that he had turned up on a jet ski. Whatever the reality, Rezgui had strolled along the sand, nobody noticing the Kalashnikov assault rifle concealed inside a parasol.
On Saturday, two young Tunisian locals, who organise parasailing and jet ski rides from the beach recalled that some time between 11.30am and 11.45am the gunman approached the sun loungers arranged along the beach.
I was sitting talking to some guests from the Imperial Marhaba hotel. We are all friends here, said one of the two men, who identified himself as Wael. He didnt think much of it when he heard the first bang.
I heard a kind of hissing clap sound and thought it must be someone messing around with fireworks for a joke, said Wael. Then the reality dawned.
The killer strolls on the beach, moments after opening fire on tourists (SKY NEWS)
Reports suggest that Rezgui first shot at a paraglider hovering above the Mediterranean. He then turned his Kalashnikov on the sunbathers.
Owen was on the beach with close relatives when Rezgui opened fire. He would later relay his terrible ordeal to the medical team that treated him and another 13 Britons at the Clinique les Oliviers.
He was so close to the gunfire that it had left him temporarily deafened in one ear. A bullet grazed his shoulder, leaving him with a flesh wound.
He was shocked. He was talking about a bullet coming over his shoulder, said Dr Fakher Benamor, a 54-year-old gynaecologist who was pressed into emergency work helping the wounded at the private clinic. The doctor said the bullet then hit a close relative.
As Owen fled the slaughter on the beach, he saw guests dropping around him in a hail of bullets.
He told doctors that, after the initial burst of gunfire, the beachgoers stampeded in panic and began running back towards the hotel. Dr Benamor said: They were running away. As he was running, he looked back and saw people being shot behind him. People were shouting Go! Go! Go! and they were just falling.
Mohammad Majmaji, chief nurse at the Clinique les Oliviers, said he found Owen at the scene when he was sent to collect victims by ambulance.
The teenager was distraught but still able to help another guest who was wounded.
He was helping the injured woman who had been shot in the back. He was crying, said Mr Majmaji.
Matthew James and his fiancee Sarah Wilson (Wales News)
The clinic was also treating Matthew James yesterday for life-threatening stomach injuries. Mr James, 30, from Cardiff, had been sunbathing on the beach with his fiance Saera Wilson, 26, when they came under attack. Mr James used his own body as a human shield to protect Miss Wilson. He took a bullet for me. I owe him my life because he threw himself in front of me when the shooting started, she said, He was covered in blood from the shots but he just told me to run away.
He told me: I love you babe. But just go  tell our children that their daddy loves them.
Others on the beach had fortunate escapes. Rita Williams, 76, was one of those. A bullet tore through her pink straw sun hat and narrowly missed her head.
Ive been so lucky  Im still shaking. It was all so frightening, Mrs Williams, of Maesteg, South Wales, told The Telegraph.
She and her husband Ken were on the way back to their hotel next door to the Imperial Marhaba when the shooting began.
We were walking back along the beach back to our hotel when we heard what sounded like fire crackers. Then I felt something hit my head  it just felt like I had been hit, she said, The force of it knocked me down on to the sand and I said to Ken, I think Ive been hit.
They followed a crowd of tourists to a neighbouring hotel and hid in the lobby for two hours.
Mr Williams said: It was like a war zone, we didnt know where the shots were coming from.
It makes you appreciate life. I came so close to a terrible situation. I was shaken for a long time.
Ellie Makin, 22, a former British tennis tour player, who was on holiday with her friend Debbie Horsfall, was another counting her blessings. She was close by when Rezgui pulled his gun from under his parasol. All of a sudden he dropped the umbrella and had a gun, and he started shooting everyone to the right of me, said Miss Makin.
Christopher and Paula Emery and their family also got lucky. They ran into the water, away from the gunman, before jumping into two speed boats that were passing by.
Gary Pine, 47, from Bristol, and his wife Nicola screamed at their 22-year-old son to get out of the sea. You could hear bullets whizzing around, said Mr Pine, My wife was shouting at my son to get out of the sea, and as he ran up the beach, he said: I just saw someone get shot.
Some tourists had no idea what was happening. One holidaymaker said later she thought a tsunami must have been approaching to explain the rush from the sea.
With bodies falling, Rezgui marched on. He was laughing and joking around, like a normal guy, said a Tunisian witness. He was choosing who to shoot. Some people he was saying to them, you go away. He was choosing tourists, British, French.
As the tourists fled, Rezgui went after them, entering the grounds of the Imperial Marhaba Hotel, reaching first the crowded figure of eight swimming pool.
By the pool was Tony Callaghan, 63, from North Walsham, Norfolk, who works for Norfolk police. He realised that the sound coming from the beach was gunfire not firecrackers. His actions probably saved a number of lives. I used to be in the Royal Air Force, said Mr Callaghan, I know the sound of gunfire. I shouted to everyone, this isnt a fireworks display, you need to get yourself to safety now.
Tony Callaghan with the glasses case (Warren Allott/The Telegraph)
Mr Callaghan made a run for it, passing four bodies covered in blood as he did so. He could hear his wife Christine screaming for help from inside the hotels reception area. The couple and another 20 guests scurried towards the rear of the hotel, breaking into offices to take cover. The gunman appears to have followed them.
Mrs Callaghan said: As I ran, I was shot, although I didnt know I had been. I wasnt in pain, just total shock.
I had been clutching my beach bag in front of me, against my middle, and inside were my glasses in a hard case. The bullet must have ricocheted off the glasses case, otherwise it would have hit my stomach.
Im just lucky to be alive. If it hadnt been for my glasses, I might not have survived.
Mrs Callaghan in hospital after the attack (Barcroft)
The firing was incessant; the level of fear hard to comprehend. At one point, as yet unclear timing-wise, Mr Callaghan was hit in the left knee; his wife was also shot. Neither had actually seen the gunman. Later the couple would be photographed hugging in the Sahloul University hospital thankful to be alive.
Piecing together the events of Friday, it appears Tom Richards, a 22-year-old civil engineering graduate, and his mother Sam were also in the party of 20 or so tourists trapped by Rezgui in the hotels back offices along with the Callaghans.
They too had been at the pool when they heard the shots, and ran for their lives. Hotel staff ushered them from the open space of the reception area, upstairs to the offices.
But the gunman followed them up to the first and then second floor. He shot two people through the head, said Mr Richards, who then found himself face to face with the killer, who was pointing the Kalashnikov assault rifle at him. He looked right at me  I thought I was dead, said Mr Richards. He was maybe 20 or 25, he had long black hair.
At that point, Rezgui fired, sending bullets seemingly in all directions. Mr Richards and his mother were wounded by shrapnel from the marble floor as it disintegrated. Mr Richards was hit in the wrist; his mother in the ankle.
I dont know why he stopped. He could have killed everybody, said Mr Richards, from Cheshire. The pair dashed to a toilet and locked themselves in a cubicle, using toilet roll as makeshift bandages. A young woman in the cubicle next door was covered in blood, a large fragment of marble stuck in her thigh. Mr Richards removed the marble and bandaged the womans leg. They remained in the cubicle for an hour, until rescued by the Tunisian military.
Ross Thompson and his girlfriend Rebecca Smith (Warren Allott /The Telegraph)
Other hotel holidaymakers had dashed for their rooms, barricading themselves in. Ross Thompson and his girlfriend Rebecca Smith, from Coventry, both suffered shrapnel wounds. Doctors later put his foot and arm in a cast.
We managed to get the room barricaded, got down low and just hid, said Mr Thompson.
Ms Smith, 22, said: I was peppered with grenade shrapnel. With one hit, I thought my jaw had come off.
Mr Thompson, a fire safety officer, said: We followed the majority of people to the second floor. Staff were saying come this way, But when we got to the end of a corridor it was a dead end. There was no way down but a 30ft drop.
He added: We managed to get into a room and barricaded the door. It happened that there were two British ex-military guys with us and they were telling us what to do. It felt like we were in there 45 minutes.
Then we could hear him coming up the stairs. He started firing down the corridor. We tried to escape but he caught us.
There was no way out, we were trapped at the end of the corridor, and then he started lobbing these home-made bombs at us.
People used Twitter and Facebook as the running gun battle continued, posting updates to reassure loved ones.
Hope it's enough pic.twitter.com/XaW4yTpplU
 John Yeoman (@johnyeo68) June 26, 2015
John Yeoman posted a picture from inside his hotel room  he was staying at a neighbouring hotel  of furniture rammed up against the door. Hope its enough, he posted on Twitter at 12.29pm.
Not everybody stayed put.
Alan Pembroke, 61, a British tourist from Essex staying at the nearby Muradi Palm hotel, first escorted his wife back to their hotel to keep her safe and then returned to the beach to help the wounded.
My wife and I were laying by the parasols, said Mr Pembroke yesterday. We heard noises, gunshots, automatic gunfire and then explosions. It sounded like a grenade going off.
We went back into the hotel quickly and I left my wife in the room and told her to stay locked in. I came back out to the beach and saw bodies lying around. I saw a woman crying. I asked her if she was British. She was German. Her wrist was half hanging off so I grabbed a scarf hanging from the parasol and tied it round that.
Then I saw she had a bullet wound in her leg. I tied a towel around it as tight as I could. She was saying my husband, my husband. I checked his pulse but there was nothing. He was lying on the sand and I told her she had to come with me. There was still the sound of gunfire further along.
She wouldnt leave him so I put a towel over her and just told her not to move. There was nothing more I could do.
Keith Hawkes, a 70-year-old former Gurkha and a regular holidaymaker in the area, also risked his own life to tend to the wounded, running towards the gunfire. It was my training we had to go and help them, he said. I saw the gunman; I almost passed within feet of him trying to get to all those dead bodies, Mr Hawkes, from Somerset, told The Times, Why he didnt shoot me, Ill never know.
Stephen Walls, of Malton in North Yorks, also told yesterday of running to rescue his wife, Jacqueline.
Mr Walls, a former soldier, said: As people were running away [from the gunfire], I was running towards it because I knew my wife was down there somewhere.
I saw a number of people badly hurt and came across a number of people who were dead on the beach.
In a 22-year career with the Royal Signals, he said he had never seen anything as harrowing.
By now, Rezgui had been on the rampage for around 25 to 40 minutes, judging by the live posts on Twitter. It seems to have gone quiet by about 12.26pm. By this stage, Rezgui appears to have been cornered in a street outside the Imperial Marhaba hotel. Shaky video images and still photographs show running gun battles with Tunisian special forces. A subsequent image showed Rezgui lying flat on his face, in black T-shirt and shorts, in a pool of blood.
Questions were being asked as to how the lone gunman had been able to kill so many people so quickly while unchallenged. Tunisia had already suffered a terrible terror attack at the Bardo Museum in Tunis in March.
On Saturday the beach at El Kantaoui was empty apart from the odd tourist, including Alan Pembroke, returning to the scene to reflect on what had happened.
A woman grieves as she lay flowers at the beach (Getty)
A young blonde woman in a white bikini walked alone through the now cleaned-up stretch of sand where yesterday the bodies had been strewn. One by one, she placed red and white roses in a floral tribute on an overturned sun lounger with a handwritten message in English and German that simply read Why? Warum?
Sobbing with grief she turned to nearby journalists and pleaded in German for respect before walking away.
In the night, most of the British tourists had gone, packed on to coaches and taken to the airport in a mass evacuation.
Back on home soil in Manchester, Olivia Leathley, 24, a chef, gave her father the tightest of hugs. Miss Leathley had been on the telephone to her father in her hotel room when the gunman had begun firing. She and her boyfriend Mike Jones, 24, had run for their lives. Ive never been so scared. Id called my dad and Im screaming down the phone to him saying Dad, I love you, she said.
In Tunisia, the tourist industry will find it hard to recover. We may have zero clients today, but we will keep our staff, said Mohammed Becheur, manager of the Imperial Marhaba hotel.
Meanwhile Wael, the Tunisian boat organiser who had watched in horror as his compatriot opened fire, told yesterday how he had helped Britons into speed boats. We had to save people, he said.
His colleague Hassan had grabbed four British guests who were swimming in the sea  three women and a man with a wounded shoulder - and helped them to safety in his boat. Ordinary Tunisians queued to give blood to show they too wanted to help.
Amdi, a friend of Hassan and Wael and who also works in the tourism industry, chipped in. Please tell people that we Tunisians helped the tourists, he told The Telegraph.  We like Europeans. This was just one crazy man.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:58:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CNN mistakes sex toy flag for Islamic State banner</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a1410f/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cuknews0C1170A38470CCNN0Emistakes0Esex0Etoy0Eflag0Efor0EIslamic0EState0Ebanner0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Flag mocking Islamic extremists, featuring white silhouettes of sex toys on a black background, is mistaken for the real thing at London gay pride event</Description>
        <MainBody>Scotland
CNN mistakes sex toy flag for Islamic State banner
Flag mocking Islamic extremists, featuring white silhouettes of sex toys on a    black background, is mistaken for the real thing at London gay pride event
The flag mistaken for an Isil flagPhoto: CNN
By Rob Crilly , New York
11:58PM BST 27 Jun 2015
Follow
To the casual observer, the black flag with unfamiliar white symbols looked out of place among the colourful outfits and banners at London's gay pride march.
Maybe the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant really had infiltrated what jihadists see as a symbol of Western sexual deviance and decadence.
CNN certainly thought so, running photographs of the flag above a banner headline, saying: Isis flag spotted at gay pride event.
The segment was billed as an exclusive and the network even lined up one of its top security analysts, Peter Bergen, to discuss its appearance.
Just one problem  the flag was a spoof, displaying what might politely be termed sex toys against a black background.
No wonder Lucy Pawle, a CNN journalist, was the only person at the parade to worry.
In the since deleted clip, she said she was surprised that no-one else had reacted to the flag.
This man dressed in black and white waving what appears to be a very bad mimicry of the Isis flag, but a clear attempt to mimic the Isis flag, the black and white flag with the distinctive lettering, she said, adding that she had alerted the police to its presence.
To his credit, Mr Bergen, who once met Osama bin Laden, tries to introduce a degree of scepticism suggesting the flag may be desigined to poke fun at Isil
"It could be some kind of almost parody - it's possible," he said. "After all one of Isil's principal goals in territories it controls is to murder gays."
Inevitably the mix-up has been ridiculed on Twitter.
@chrislhayes Call it what it is: a false flag dildo attack on CNN's rigorous journalistic standards.
CNN looking at an ISIS-mocking dildo flag and taking it seriously is the second-best flag news this month
 Kelsey D. Atherton (@AthertonKD) June 27, 2015
Its clearly not Arabic, says CNNs @lucypawle at #londonpride - yep, clearly not http://t.co/vpzT3FOasF
 Stuart Hughes (@stuartdhughes) June 28, 2015
The presence of the flag - or something similar - has frequently been one of the first indications that a terrorist attack has been carried out on behalf of Isil.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 00:31:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Quasi Modo named world's ugliest dog</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a13df6/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cnewstopics0Chowaboutthat0C1170A38360CQuasi0EModo0Enamed0Eworlds0Eugliest0Edog0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Hunchbacked pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix wins competition that applauds imperfection.</Description>
        <MainBody>Quasi Modo named world's ugliest dog
Hunchbacked pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix wins competition that applauds    imperfection.
Quasi Modo wins top honours in the World's Ugliest Dog Contest at the Sonoma-Marin Fair on Friday, June 26, 2015, in Petaluma, CaliforniaPhoto: AP
By AP
10:31PM BST 27 Jun 2015
A 10-year-old mutt named Quasi Modo, whose spinal birth defects left her a bit hunchbacked, is the winner of this year's World's Ugliest Dog contest.
The pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix and her owner took the $1,500 prize Friday night, besting 25 other dogs competing in the contest that applauds imperfection, organisers in the US said.
Quasi Modo was abandoned at an animal shelter before being adopted by a veterinarian in Loxahatchee, Florida, according to her biography posted on the contest's website.
"My appearance can be a little unsettling to some (I have had grown men jump on top of their cars to get away from me because they thought I was a hyena or Tasmanian devil) but once they get to know me I win them over with my bubbly personality," her biography said.
Two Chinese crested and Chihuahua mixes named Sweepee Rambo and Frodo took the second- and third-place prizes, respectively.
Entrant "Icky" Picture: World's Ugliest Dog/REX Shutterstock
An 8-year-old Chihuahua named Precious received the "spirit award," honoring a dog and owner who have overcome obstacles and/or are providing service to the community. Precious, who is blind in one eye, is trained to monitor smells related to low blood sugar levels and alert her owner, a disabled veteran, of the problem, her biography said.
The contest, held at the Sonoma-Marin Fairgrounds in Petaluma, California, is in its 27th year .
The dogs are scored by a three-judge panel in several categories, including special or unusual attributes, personality and natural ugliness.
Entrant "Frodo" Picture: World's Ugliest Dog/REX Shutterstock
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 00:31:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Families struggle to comprehend the loss of loved ones on holiday</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a13df7/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1170A37930CFamilies0Estruggle0Eto0Ecomprehend0Ethe0Eloss0Eof0Eloved0Eones0Eon0Eholiday0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Families mourn as the tragic stories of those who lost their lives are revealed</Description>
        <MainBody>Families struggle to comprehend the loss of loved ones on holiday
Families mourn as the tragic stories of those who lost their lives are revealed
Families mourn as they learn the details of their loved ones
By Patrick Sawer , and Nicola Harley
11:00AM BST 28 Jun 2015
They were grandparents enjoying a family holiday, students taking a deserved break over the summer and loving couples relishing some precious time together.
Now their grief-stricken families sit at home mourning the loss of their loved ones  gunned down on a Tunisian beach by an engineering student inspired by the jihadists of Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant.
The first Britain victim to be confirmed as dead was Carly Lovett, a 24-year-old who had travelled to the Tunisian resort with her fianc Liam Moore for a summer holiday.
The former University of Lincoln student had only recently launched her own blog writing about beauty products and treatments.
She had already built up a substantial following.
Carly Lovett
Before leaving for Tunisia on Tuesday, Miss Lovett, who had become engaged to her boyfriend Liam Moore, 26, in December, wrote on Twitter: Definitely leaving in like three hours and definitely am not finished packing.
Miss Lovett worked in her home town of Gainsborough, in Lincolnshire, as a photographer at the e-commerce company Fizzco.
She wrote on the profile page of her beauty blog: My name is Carly Im the beauty junkie/closet hoarder/design lover. Im not remotely a beauty expert and probably dont have much beauty knowledge at all, but so what.
I like beauty a lot, love trying new things and experimenting. I may not blend to perfection  and more often than not I apply eyeshadow with my fingers  but beauty doesnt have to mean conformity.
Kyle Leeman, 23, a childhood friend of Miss Lovett, said she was a kind and outgoing person.
He added: I am absolutely devastated. Its not something you expect. I knew her sister, her mum, her dad and her boyfriend.
She got me into a lot of the music I am in to. We always had really great times together. She was always one to express herself. I am really so sorry for all of her family. My thoughts are with them all. If theres anything I can do to help them, I will always be there to do it. They are a really close family, so I think it will hit them all very hard.
Dave Overton, another friend of Miss Lovett, said she was the kind of person who would have done her best to help others in an emergency.
He explained: Carly was an undergraduate student where I worked at the University of Lincoln, and I got to know her as she used the photographic facilities.
I found her not only friendly but also a tough character with a sensible and practical outlook on life.
The first Britain victim to be confirmed as dead was Carly Lovett, a 24-year-old who had travelled to the Tunisian resort with her fianc Liam Moore
The University of Lincolns media Twitter account posted on Friday night: Saddened to hear news reports of Carly Lovett in Tunisia  graduate of our University 2013.
Fellow bloggers have been shocked by the news of Miss Lovetts death. Claire Fearon tweeted: The horrors hit us all and though our community is small, we bloggers are strong. My thoughts go out to all other lives lost.
Laura Byrne wrote: Very sad to hear that beauty blogger @ceejayell [Miss Lovetts Twitter name] was sadly caught up in the terrible Tunisia shootings yesterday and lost her life. RIP Carly.
A Just Giving page has been set up by bloggers with a target to raise 500 for Carlys family.
A friend of Miss Lovetts fianc Liam, who did not want to be named, said: Its a real shock, Im still trying to get my head around it after hearing the news last night. Liam and I used to know each other from work, I think he had been with Carly for a long time.
One teenage boy witnessed two members of his family wiped out when Seifeddine Rezgui rampaged through the tourist resort of Sousse.
Owen Richards, 16, was on holiday with his brother Joel, 19, and his uncle Adrian Evans, 49, who were both gunned down and killed.
Owen managed to flee from the carnage but is believed to be in hospital.
Owen Richards, witnessed his brother Joel Richards, right, being gunned down
His grandfather Patrick Evans is feared dead.
Sandwell council in the West Midlands, which employed Mr Evans as a manager in its gas services department, described the news as horrendous and said their thoughts were with the family and council colleagues.
Mr Evans had been on his first day of his holiday and had been due to spend seven days in Tunisia before a weeks stay in France.
A council source said: When I heard about it, I was sickened. To have someone so close to you lost in such a way is terrible. He was a committed man who gave good service to the people of Sandwell.
Reece Watters, a family friend, paid tribute to Joel on Facebook, saying: Theres no status or no words I could put here that could describe to you how much of a kind guy Joel was. If you knew him personally, you would know how respected he was and how he played such a big part in many peoples lives.
He never had anything bad to say about anybody, people would never argue with him because of how likeable he was. He helped everyone he ever came in contact with, even when it involved putting others before himself.
Its so heartbreaking to think that he was on holiday in Tunisia with his brother and uncle when some scum decided to do what he did to all those people, including Joel.
James Connollys GFC, a Gaelic football club for which Joel played, said: He was an exceptionally talented footballer who represented both club and county.
On Saturday Sue Davey, 44, and her partner Scott Chalkley, 42, were confirmed as being among the victims by their children.
They were on the beach when the gunman opened fire. The couples belongings were found and brought back to their hotel, including their mobile phones.
Mr Chalkleys son, Ross Naylor, and Ms Daveys son, Conor Fulford, spent frantic hours waiting for news of them to emerge. Both men turned to social media in the hope someone would be able to provide news of the couple, who were staying at the Imperial Hotel in Sousse.
Scott Chalkley
Mr Chalkley's son Ross Naylor broke the news on Twitter that his father had been killed.
Mr Naylor, 23, said: "Tonight me and Brad lost our dad, unfortunately he was caught up in the sickening attacks in Tunisia and is no longer with us.
"I feel I had to put this message out as many of you have been asking about him and asking for an update.
"We are all trying to come to grips and process what has happened.
"I want to say thanks to everyone who has helped, you have all been amazing.
"One love to all and rest in peace dad."
Please take the time to read this ? pic.twitter.com/xXvcJ1J3yu
 A$AP ROSSI (@rossinaylor) June 27, 2015
Mr Fulford thanked people for their help as he announced the tragic news.
He tweeted: "Sorry to tell you we lost my mother Sue Davey tonight but i want to thank everybody that tried to help me and my family.
"My mom was a strong women who didn't take no crap from nobody so when you lie down tonight wish my mom goodnight as I know i sure will xxxxx
"Love you always Mom, I've got my teddy bear you got me tonight, Rest easy xxxx"
Hi Everyone, Sorry to tell you we lost my mother Sue Davey tonight but i want to thank everybody that tried to help me &amp; my family ...
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
My mom was a strong women who didn't take no crap from nobody so when you lie down tonight wish my mom goodnight as I know i sure will xxxxx
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
Love you always Mom, I've got my teddy bear you got me tonight, Rest easy xxxx
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
The 23-year-old from Tamworth, Staffs, had posted a series of messages on Twitter seeking information. He said: We have located her phone. It got brought back to the hotel where she is staying. But nobody knows where she is or her partner. We are still trying to find her, ringing hospitals and clinics  but nothing yet.
I am just hoping maybe she is in a hotel and she has got no internet and hasnt any way of contacting us.
We have rung loads and loads of different clinics but she is not on their lists.
I am just hoping for anything. We just want to get as much information as possible, anybody who can tell us where she is or how she is.
Mr Naylor had earlier written on Twitter: Havent spoken to my dad since the attack, please, please, please RT as he is missing along with his partner.
The 23-year-old said his fears had increased after hotel staff told him his father and Ms Davey were on the beach after finding some of their bags on the sand.
Mr Naylor, from Derby, described his father as a loving, typical bloke, adding: Hes a fun-loving guy.
Even though he is 20 years older than me, hes like a mate  thats how it is. They say no news is good news but I would just rather hear something. I dont know what to do with myself. I just want to hear that hes safe.
Owen Richards, Adrian Evans, Patrick Evans , and Joel Richards
John and Janet Stocker, a couple who were on holiday, were also feared dead. Mr Stockers son Mark appealed for help, saying: Weve spoken to every hospital in Sousse and the surrounding areas.
One of my brothers managed to speak to someone in the hotel  theyve gone and checked their room but their stuff is still in there. Its just trying to work out what we do.
Another of the victims was feared to be 60-year-old James McGuire, who was carried to a nearby hospital from the beach, where he had been sunbathing.
James McGuire
Adam Fisher, from Redhill, Surrey, has not spoken to his parents, Ray and Angela, since they left for their holiday.
He said he felt powerless over the situation, adding: Ive been in touch with the Foreign Office but they wont give any information. I dont know what to do.
Ray and Angela Fisher
John Welch, 74, from Corsham, Wilts, and his partner Eileen Swannack, 70, were also missing feared dead. The couple have not answered their phones since the attack. Mr Welchs grandson Daniel Welch, 29, from Swindon, said he had been told by the Foreign Office that officials had been unable to locate the pair.
He added: You know that were going to get some sort of news at some point, whether it be today, tomorrow or the next day, and you know its probably not going to be great, because they havent been able to make contact themselves by now.
Daniel said the hardest thing was not knowing. He added: We are at a bit of a loss and we can only expect the worst.
Eileen Swannack, 70 and her partner John Welch, 74
The family of Denis and Elaine Thwaites, from Blackpool, Lancs, are appealing for information about their whereabouts.
The retired couple, aged 70 and 69, arrived in Sousse on Wednesday and had been staying at the Hotel Riu Imperial Marhaba.
Danny Clifford, their son-in-law, said the family had heard from Tunisia that the couple were being treated in hospital.
He added: Were not 100 per cent certain but we believe they are injured in hospital.
Elaine and Denis Thwaite
Weve not had contact from the Foreign Office. We dont know which hospital or the extent of their injuries but its the best news weve had all day.
An Irish mother of two, Lorna Carty, from Robinstown, Co Meath, was confirmed as among the dead.
The nurse, in her 50s, was gunned down on the beach while getting some last-minute sunbathing just hours before she was due to return home from the resort along with her husband Declan. She had taken him on holiday to help him recover from heart surgery.
Charlie Flanagan, Irelands foreign affairs minister, warned that further Irish casualties could not be ruled out.
Lorna Carty
He said: The embassy team is also continuing to provide all possible consular support to the bereaved family of the Irish citizen who had been confirmed yesterday as being among the deceased. This is a tragic and difficult time for the families and loved ones of those concerned.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:45:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>We must not allow a few fanatics ruin this fledgling democracy</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a1754d/sc/15/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1170A37550CWe0Emust0Enot0Eallow0Ea0Efew0Efanatics0Eruin0Ethis0Efledgling0Edemocracy0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US and Europe must without delay help Tunisia make a successful transition and stay the course of moderation, says Diana Darke</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia
We must not allow a few fanatics ruin this fledgling democracy
US and Europe must without delay help Tunisia make a successful transition and    stay the course of moderation, says Diana Darke
A floral tribute lies on the beach in Tunisia where 38 tourists were murdered by terroristsPhoto: Jeff J. Mitchell/Getty Images
By Diana Darke
9:45PM BST 27 Jun 2015
As Tunisia agonises over whether Fridays horrific attack on western sunbathers at the Port El-Kantoui resort could have been avoided and as ISIS claims responsibility for the attack, much of the blame will inevitably turn to blow-back from the 3000 Tunisian fighters who left to join ISIS in Syria, Iraq and Libya.
Out of Tunisias population of over 11 million, these radicalised fighters represent a tiny albeit highly destructive fraction, who must not be allowed to destabilise the entire country. There is too much at stake.
Four months ago deep in the Tunisian desert I chanced upon Tunisias version of Glastonbury, Les Dunes Electroniques, a three-day festival of world music, where over 7000 Tunisian and foreign guests danced into the night in the vast open spaces of the Sahara. Parts of the original Star Wars film were shot here.
February in the desert can have its surprises, and this years ravers had their commitment levels tested to the full, not by an ISIS attack, but by torrential rain turning the sand into muddy rivers, forcing cancellations as water and electronics mixed.
Spirits undampened, Tunisias young at heart padded good-naturedly through puddles wearing plastic bags on their feet.
They also enlivened the spirits of the hoteliers, restaurateurs and shop-owners of the region, for whom the drop in tourism over the last four years has been hard.
Tunisians have a uniquely tolerant Islamic heritage.
Most are moderate Sunni Muslims and many have a natural affinity with mystical Islam or Sufism.
In the heart of Tunis stands a statue of the figure who embodies this, himself a Sufi - Ibn Khaldun, the worlds first sociologist philosopher.
Born there in 1332, he stands with his back to the historic old medina, gazing out to the new city and beyond towards the sea.
In modern Tunisia this heritage was personified by the Sufi poet/novelist Abdelwahab Meddeb (1946-2014).
His landmark work La Maladie dIslam (2002) explained: If, according to Voltaire, intolerance was Catholicisms sickness, if Nazism was Germanys sickness, fundamentalism is Islams sickness.
He wrote over 30 books advocating an Islam of Enlightenment and a dialogue between civilisations.
But when battling against fundamentalism, how do you get the balance right? How do you protect your citizens without also infringing their human rights? This is the question which faces us all in countries where freedom and democracy are valued.
Full protection for Tunisias Mediterranean beaches, lined as they are by strings of contiguous hotels  some reports say the attackers arrived by boat  can never be guaranteed, just as Londons British
Museum for example, could never be fully protected against random suicide bombers.
Rigorous airport-style security checks are dificult to put in place, leaving the priceless statues of the worlds cultural heritage, seen as idols by ISIS, an easy target.
Tunisias secularist government took the difficult path, the costly path, to aim for western-style freedom and democracy.
After the Bardo Museum massacre which left 24 dead on 18 March, their Cabinet proposed new anti-terrorism laws, seeking to enhance the powers of the security services and extend the period police can detain suspects from six to 15 days before they appear in court.
Human Rights Watch warned that the new law risks criminalising political dissent.
In Tunisia the army is generally respected by ordinary citizens, so it is significant that Prime Minister Habib Essid is sending army reservists to guard archaeological sites and resorts.
The army sided with the demonstrators at the outbreak of the Jasmine Revolution, helping them come through with less than 400 deaths. Compare that with Syrias death tally of 250,000 and rising.
The police and security services on the other hand are perceived by two thirds of Tunisian households to be corrupt, according to the Global Corruption Barometer.
They are mistrusted, with a bad track record of abuse and torture of detainees in prison, sometimes even leading to death.
Tunisians complain that, in the last year or two, police corruption has got worse, with a feeling that they see themselves as above the law.
Women feel especially vulnerable to intimidation. Bribery to avoid detention is often the only option.
Soon after the Jasmine Revolution I asked a Tunisian official how the country had dealt with its corrupt security forces. He told me about 10%, those that were too corrupt to stay, were forced to leave, most of them flying out to Italy. It seems a new layer has quickly replaced them.
Maybe Fridays attack and the world condemnation that has followed will be a wake-up call to reform Tunisias police.
Many Tunisians blame the police and security services for not doing more to prevent the Bardo Museum massacre.
They will blame them even more if, thanks to these failures, the Tunisian economy deteriorates further and the unemployment rates, already at 35% among the young, go higher.
The government has a long hard road ahead, trying to persuade secularists to coexist peacefully with religious conservatives, and trying to stop its Jasmine Revolution being hijacked by a minority of violent Islamists.
Tunisia is unique in the Arab world in having strong women who have campaigned hard for equal rights with men, and in having a strong middle class civil society and responsible trade unions.
All this would be lost were ISIS to gain a foothold, and everyone knows it.
Pictures of Tunisian women donating blood for Fridays victims say it all.
Tunisias fragile fledging democracy got more fragile on Friday. The coming weeks and months will test it further.
The US and Europe must without delay help the country make a successful transition and stay the course of moderation.
For if Tunisia fails there is no hope for all the rest.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
