<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Telegraph">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:46:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>One thousand Europeans still missing after Nepal quake</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45eae634/sc/11/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cnepal0C1157690A60COne0Ethousand0EEuropeans0Estill0Emissing0Eafter0ENepal0Equake0Esays0EEU0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Some 1,000 European citizens, mainly tourists, are not accounted for in Nepal nearly a week after a devastating earthquake, says EU ambassador</Description>
        <MainBody>Nepal
One thousand Europeans still missing after Nepal quake
Some 1,000 European citizens, mainly tourists, are not accounted for in Nepal    nearly a week after a devastating earthquake, says EU ambassador
Trapped hikers get on a helicopter of Nepal Army from affected areas of earthquake in RasuwaPhoto: Xinhua /Landov / Barcroft Media
By Reuters
12:46PM BST 01 May 2015
One thousand people from the European Union , mostly tourists, are missing in Nepal nearly a week after a devastating earthquake , the head of the EU delegation in Nepal said on Friday.
Twelve EU citizens have been confirmed dead in Nepal after the earthquake, said Ambassador Rensje Teerink.
"We don't know where they are, or they could be," Mr Teerink told reporters, adding that those unaccounted for were mostly tourists in the Langtang and Lukla areas.
"They are missing but we don't know what their status is," she said.
"Many were in the Langtang area and some were in the Lukla area," she added, referring to the small Himalayan airstrip known as the gateway to Everest.
Another EU official said on condition of anonymity that the majority were likely to be found safe and well but that their status was currently unknown given the difficult terrain and lack of access to affected regions.
The 7.8-magnitude quake that hit on Saturday triggered an avalanche at Everest base camp that left 18 people dead on the world's highest peak.
There have also been unconfirmed reports of large avalanches flattening villages in Langtang, a remote region north of Kathmandu that rescuers have struggled to reach.
Local newspaper reports say dozens of foreigners have been evacuated from Langtang.
Langtang is a trekking region to the north of Kathmandu that has been hit by a huge avalanche and mudslides, while Lukla is the jumping off point for walkers and climbers making the nine-day trek to Everest base camp.
More follows
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:40:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Graffiti artist uses drone to deface giant New York advert</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45eae638/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C115766970CGraffiti0Eartist0Euses0Edrone0Eto0Edeface0Egiant0ENew0EYork0Eadvert0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Six-storey Calvin Klein poster featuring Kendall Jenner defaced by paint sprayed from drone</Description>
        <MainBody>Graffiti artist uses drone to deface giant New York advert
Six-storey Calvin Klein poster featuring Kendall Jenner defaced by paint    sprayed from drone
Follow
To anyone passing through New York's Soho district, it may look like a piece of vulgar - if logistically impressive - vandalism.
But to Katsu, a Banksy-esque anonymous street artist, it is the world's first example of "drone art" graffiti.
Overnight on Wednesday, a cluster of red spray-painted lines appeared across the face of an oversized image of Kendall Jenner currently adorning one of Manhattan's biggest billboard advertisements.
The six-storey high poster on the corner of Houston and Lafayette streets would be near-impossible for a person to reach, even by climbing or rappelling.
Video has now emerged of the DJI Phantom drone - a type of miniature helicopter with four propellers that is commercially available - hovering at night in front of the poster, spraying paint from an attached aerosol can onto the poster.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:57:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Celebrity Sightings: Leonardo DiCaprio, Paris Hilton and Jared Leto</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45ea57c1/sc/26/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Ccelebritynews0C11576550A0CCelebrity0ESightings0ELeonardo0EDiCaprio0EParis0EHilton0Eand0EJared0ELeto0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Featuring Leonardo DiCaprio, Paris Hilton and Jared Leto</Description>
        <MainBody>Jared Leto wearing winter clothes on a sunny day in New YorkPicture: Rex

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:49:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lightning strike blows up street lamp</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45ea57c6/sc/23/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cchina0C115765730CLightning0Estrike0Eblows0Eup0Estreet0Elamp0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A dashcam on a car in China has captured the moment a lightening bolt strikes a street lamp</Description>
        <MainBody>China
Lightning strike blows up street lamp
A dashcam on a car in China has captured the moment a lightening bolt strikes    a street lamp
By Telegraph video
11:49AM BST 01 May 2015
Dramatic dashcam footage has emerged from China of the moment a streetlight was hit by a bolt of lightning.
In the video, captured on a dashboard camera in Jinan City of Shandong Province on Tuesday, the strikes at first appear slightly further away.
As the car continues its journey, a bolt of lightening actually strikes a street lamp not far from the car.
A loud bang can be heard upon impact as the bulb in the lamp blows.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:39:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Men's magazine uses ink containing HIV-positive blood for special issue</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45ea57c8/sc/19/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Caustria0C115763710CMens0Emagazine0Euses0Eink0Econtaining0EHIV0Epositive0Eblood0Efor0Especial0Eissue0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Austrian magazine Vanguardist uses ink containing infected blood to draw attention to plight of HIV sufferers</Description>
        <MainBody>Men's magazine uses ink containing HIV-positive blood for special issue
Austrian magazine Vanguardist uses ink containing infected blood to draw attention to plight of HIV sufferers
The publishers say they have followed strict medical guidelines, and the magazine is safe to handlePhoto: Vanguardist
By Justin Huggler, Berlin
11:39AM BST 01 May 2015
An Austrian men's magazine is planning to release a special issue printed with ink containing HIV-positive blood.
The stunt is intended to draw attention to the plight of HIV sufferers , Vangardist magazine claimed.
"This magazine has been printed with the blood of HIV+ people," an announcement on the otherwise plain cover of the magazine reads.
Blood for the issue has been donated by three people infected with the virus.
The publishers say they have followed strict medical guidelines, and the magazine is safe to handle.
The HIV virus cannot survive for long outside the human body, but for the more squeamish the magazine is being released in a clear plastic cover.
The blood has been donated by a 26-year-old gay man from Berlin, a heterosexual man who chose to remain anonymous, and a 45-year-old woman who was infected 20 years ago by her partner.
The stunt is an unusual move for a men's lifestyle magazine whose readership is generally online.
Vangardist claims a monthly readership of 100,000, mostly online, but is releasing a print run of just 3,000 copies of the HIV-positive edition.
"We believe that as a lifestyle magazine it is our responsibility to address the issues shaping society today," Julian Wiehl, Vangardist's CEO and publisher, said.
"With 80 per cent more confirmed cases of HIV being recorded in 2013 than 10 years previously, and an estimated 50 per cent of HIV cases being detected late due to lack of testing caused by social stigma associated with the virus, this felt like a very relevant issue for us to focus on."
The idea for the issue came from the advertising agency Saatchi &amp; Saatchi Switzerland.
"This is truly a 'Nothing Is Impossible' story  one we have been passionate about for a long time," Jason Romeyko, the agency's executive creative director, said.
"When Vangardist approached us to help them raise awareness of this important cause ... we knew we had met a brave client. With this unique project, we want to create a response in a heartbeat by transforming the media into the very root of the stigma itself  by printing every word, line, picture and page of the magazine with blood from HIV+ people.
"By holding the issue, readers are immediately breaking the taboo."
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:33:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israeli riot police clash with Ethiopian migrants outside Netanyahu's residence</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45ea57cb/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Cisrael0C115763410CIsraeli0Eriot0Epolice0Eclash0Ewith0EEthiopian0Emigrants0Eoutside0ENetanyahus0Eresidence0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Israeli PM appeals for calm as riot police to disperse 1,000 demonstrators marching over video showing officers beating Israeli soldier of Ethiopian origin</Description>
        <MainBody>Israel
Israeli riot police clash with Ethiopian migrants outside Netanyahu's residence
Israeli PM appeals for calm as riot police to disperse 1,000 demonstrators marching over video showing officers beating Israeli soldier of Ethiopian origin
Isarel police and protesters in Israel's Jaffa StreetPhoto: Robert Tait
By Robert Tait , Jerusalem
11:33AM BST 01 May 2015
Ethiopian immigrants clashed with Israeli security forces near prime minister Benjamin Netanyahu 's home in Jerusalem late on Thursday after a protest against police racism descended into violence.
Riot police equipped with water cannons cordoned off Mr Netanyahu's residence in Balfour Street after around 1,000 demonstrators marched there to voice anger over video footage showing officers beating an Israeli soldier of Ethiopian origin in an apparently unprovoked attack.
Protesters confront Israeli policemen during a demonstration in central Jerusalem (Alamy)
Mr Netanyahu issued an appeal for calm after police and demonstrators  many of them holding placards denouncing racism  fought in nearby Independence Park.
"I strongly condemn the beating of the Ethiopian IDF [army] soldier and those responsible will be held accountable," he said. " However, no one is allowed to take the law into their own hands. The immigrants from Ethiopia and their families are dear to us and the State of Israel is taking many steps to ease their integration into society.
"Nir Barkat, Jerusalem's mayor, arrived at the scene and tried to placate the crowd.
The interventions failed to produce a calming effect. After leaving the prime minister's residence, demonstrators marched down King George Street before turning into Jaffa Street  West Jerusalem's main thoroughfare  where they surrounded and pummeled a waiting police car.
A protester shouts at an Israeli policeman (Alamy)
After the vehicle sped off, there was a further tense standoff between demonstrators and riot police, with the two sides pushing each other violently as bystanders looked on. Some 13 protesters and three police officers were injured in the disturbances.
The demonstration had begun peacefully outside the national police headquarters in East Jerusalem's French Hill area, prompted by the emergence of a video showing two police officers attacking Demas Fekadeh, a soldier who had received an award for excellence from Shimon Peres, Israel's former president.
The attack took place in Holon, near Tel Aviv, last Sunday.
In the footage, Mr Fekadeh  wearing his army uniform  is seen standing next to his bicycle when an officer approaches him before pushing him violently to the ground. A second officer then joins in and the pair strike the soldier as he lies prone.
Mr Fekadeh is then released but picks up a large rock. The police respond by calling for reinforcements. The justice ministry has ordered an investigation into the incident.
Pnina Tamano-Shata, a participants in Thursday's protest and a former MP for the secular Yesh Atid party, said Mr Fekadeh's ordeal was typical of the discrimination experienced by many Ethiopian-Israelis.
"We are demonstrating because this is not the first time this has happened," she said. "This incident was captured on video but we think similar things happen a lot. We are calling for a stop to this violence."
The 120,000-strong Ethiopian community emigrated to Israel in two waves in 1984 and 1991. Despite being fully recognised as Jews, many complain of discrimination in the jobs market and at the hands of the authorities.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:07:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Quake survivor: 'the ground turned to water under us'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45ea4c44/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cnepal0C115763510CQuake0Esurvivor0Ethe0Eground0Eturned0Eto0Ewater0Eunder0Eus0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Holly Cowie was trekking in a remote part of Nepal with her boyfriend and a guide when the quake struck. She describes hanging onto a tree "for our lives" as an avalanche struck</Description>
        <MainBody>Nepal
Quake survivor: 'the ground turned to water under us'
Holly Cowie was trekking in a remote part of Nepal with her boyfriend and a    guide when the quake struck. She describes hanging onto a tree "for our    lives" as an avalanche struck
By Telegraph video, video source ITN
11:07AM BST 01 May 2015
British tourist Holly Cowie has described how she clung to a tree for dear life as a landslide came hurtling down the Nepalese valley she was trekking in after the earthquake hit on Saturday.
The 26 year old from London had arrived in Nepal ten days earlier as part of a three-month trip with her French boyfriend Axel Haudiquet, 29, when the earthquake struck as she walked through the popular Langtang Valley.
Accompanied by a guide, the couple had hiked 3,900ft through stunning scenery to Langtang Village where they visited one of the native tea houses before setting off back down.
It was then that the earthquake struck and they were forced to trek to a police checkpoint and wait to be rescued.
More than 6,000 people have been killed in the worst earthquake to hit the country in 80 years, and at least 14,000 have been injured.
Holly describes how lucky she was to escape with her life, and hopes to raise awareness of the plight of those stranded or injured in Nepal.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:06:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hillary and Tenzing's sons describe surviving the Everest avalanche</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45ea4c46/sc/16/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cnepal0C11574840A0CHillary0Eand0ETenzings0Esons0Edescribe0Esurviving0Ethe0EEverest0Eavalanche0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The sons of the two men who were the first to scale Everest were both on the mountain when the Everest avalanche hit following the Nepal earthquake</Description>
        <MainBody>Nepal
Hillary and Tenzing's sons describe surviving the Everest avalanche
The sons of the two men who were the first to scale Everest were both on the mountain when the Everest avalanche hit following the Nepal earthquake
By Richard Spencer , Kathmandu, Video by Will Wintercross
11:06AM BST 01 May 2015
Follow
Peter Hillary and Jamling Tenzing Norgay, whose fathers sent a wave of excitement through the world when they scaled Everest for the first time, were on the mountain and witnessed Saturday's devastating earthquake and avalanche at first hand, they revealed on Thursday.
The two men, old friends for decades, were unbeknown to each other leading separate trekking parties to Everest Base Camp when the earthquake hit.
By chance, they ended up taking refuge in the same monastery village, the two men told The Telegraph. "I pushed open the curtain that was in front of the door and he was sitting there in front of me," Mr Hillary said on Thursday afternoon, shortly after arriving back in Kathmandu.
"He was sitting in front of me. He jumped up and we gave each other a hug. We joshed with each other, as we do when we bump into each other."
The two men then spent the evening reminiscing and describing their experiences of the earthquake together.
Edmund Hillary with climb companion Tenzing Norgay in 1953
Mr Hillary was with a party of his old school-friends on a Himalayan get-together. They were about two hours' trek from Base Camp having lunch at a tea-shop in Gorakshep when the ground started shaking.
"It was very scary," he said. "We ran outside and under tables." Then when the earth stopped shaking, he heard an enormous, continuous roar, as the avalanche struck.
"It was very cloudy and we couldn't see the mountain, but there was no question the mountain was coming to pieces."
The avalanche swept through base camp, but the advance blast hit Gorakshep at full force.
"It was a jet blast ahead of the avalanche, full of ice particles and snow," he said. "It came to us I estimate at 100 miles an hour. It covered everything."
Mr Hillary decided to lead his team back down the mountain, reaching Tengboche monastery on the second day.
"We found it was a disaster zone," he said. "This very lovely monastery is seriously damaged, and the hotels around it were uninhabitable."
His party and other refugees from the earthquake camped out on the floor of one restaurant in town which had a solid concrete shell, and it was there a Sherpa member of his party told him he had heard Mr Tenzing was also in town.
He had been leading a group of ten young Indian women, winners of a competition whose prize was a trek to Base Camp. They had reached the bottom of the mountain beneath Tengboche on Saturday morning.
"We were at the bottom of the hill beside the river which was quite a difficult place to be," Mr Tenzing said. "I decided we should go up the hill to try to avoid the rocks and boulders coming down."
After scrambling to the top, they too sought refuge in a Tengboche lodge.
Jamling Tenzing Norgay on a previous climb
He stayed there for three nights  on the second of which, Mr Hillary's team arrived.
"That was a coincidence, though we usually bump into each other in the Himalayas, in different places," he said. "He described he avalanche to me as a tsunami of ice, rock and snow. "We had a good chat about what had happened."
Both men's parties were unharmed in the disaster. However, Mr Hillary suffered another loss when one of his group, Greg Kay, 61, died during the subsequent night, apparently of a heart attack.
"It was a terrible shock," Mr Hillary said. "We had had a wonderful night with Jamling. There was a lot of laughter and photographs and storytelling. Everyone was in a very good humour.
"The next morning he just didn't move. We were doing CPR (resuscitation) but to no avail."
After the aftershocks died down, both parties moved back down the mountain. With the family's approval, Mr Hillary organised a traditional local cremation pyre for Mr Kay, and combined a traditional Sherpa funeral with readings.
The party then flew back from Tenzing-Hillary Airport, the Everest landing strip named after the two men's fathers, Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay.
Peter Hillary and Jamling Tenzing Norgay. Credit: Will Wintercross
After their feat in 1953, the two men remained friends. Tenzing Norgay died in 1986, and Sir Edmund, who later wrote a moving description in his autobiography of attending his colleague's cremation, in 2008.
Tenzing Norgay was born in the Sherpa village of Thame in the Everest foothills, but ran away to India to seek work as a young man and was an Indian citizen at the moment of his greatest triumph.
His son said that Thame had been almost destroyed in the earthquake, along with many other villages and tourist lodges. Many of his family had lost their homes.
He said it was a second disaster for the community, after 16 Sherpas were killed in last year's avalanche. At least 12 Sherpas died when Base Camp was hit last week, along with an unknown number in the villages of the Himalayas.
Mr Tenzing said the loss of so many people was a personal disaster, while the destruction of the trekking and climbing industry's infrastructure was a disaster for the whole country.
"This will affect the whole region," he said. "We have lost 5,500 people, and so many more are homeless. It's a very sad situation for the future of Nepal. I never thought we would live to see something like this."
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:04:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why Putin remains Kim Jong-un's best friend despite Victory Day snub</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45ea4c48/sc/11/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cnorthkorea0C1157640A50CWhy0EPutin0Eremains0EKim0EJong0Euns0Ebest0Efriend0Edespite0EVictory0EDay0Esnub0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Kim Jong-un may have cancelled his Moscow visit, but Vladimir Putin has enjoyed remarkably warm relations with North Korea ever since he made his first foreign trip as president to Pyongyang</Description>
        <MainBody>Mr Putin made a historic two-day visit to Pyongyang in 2000 , in his first official foreign visit as president.
EPA/ITAR-TASS
That trip resulted in a joint declaration that was the first international document Kim Jong Il had ever signed - quite an achievement for a leader who had already been in office for six years.
Kim Jong Il visited Moscow by train in 2001 to meet with Mr Putin.
He also met then-president Dmitry Medvedev in Eastern Siberia in 2011, making the trip to Moscow down the trans-Siberian railway in his private train for talks - and a remarkably awkward photo opportunity.
KNS/AFP/Getty
Following that visit, Russia wrote off 90 percent of an 7 billion Soviet-era debt owed by Pyongyang.
For impoverished North Korea, that represented valuable financial relief.
From Moscows point of view, the benefits of the relationship are economic.
Russian Railways, the state rail monopoly, has unveiled ambitious plans to build a trans-Korean rail link to Seoul - part of a grander scheme for a Eurasian rail corridor
Meanwhile, Gazprom wants to build a gas pipeline from North Korea to South Korea, where it reckons it can sell 10 billion cubic meters of gas a year.
Both projects depend on delicate diplomacy in Pyongyang - which is technically still at war with the South.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:44:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Moscow basks in Soviet tradition as 100,000 march on May Day</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45ea4c4b/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Crussia0C115762570CMoscow0Ebasks0Ein0ESoviet0Etradition0Eas0E10A0A0A0A0A0Emarch0Eon0EMay0EDay0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Russians march through Red Square waving banners and proclaiming supremacy of worker's rights</Description>
        <MainBody>Moscow basks in Soviet tradition as 100,000 march on May Day
Russians march through Red Square waving banners and proclaiming supremacy of worker's rights
People walk with flags and artificial flowers at Red Square during a May Day rally in MoscowPhoto: Maxim Zmeyev/Reuters
10:44AM BST 01 May 2015
It could be a scene from the heyday of the Soviet Union.
Over 100,000 Russians marched through Red Square this morning, waving the banners of the ruling party and proclaiming the supremacy of worker's rights.
But the march was led not by Leonid Brezhnev, but Sergei Sobyanin  the technocratic Kremlin-backed mayor of Moscow  and the flags were not Communist red, but the blue of United Russia, Vladimir Putin's ruling party.
A Russian Trade Unions' member holds a portrait of Vladimir Putin during the May Day demonstration (AFP/Getty Images)
And the speeches, backed by grandiose marching music, were a mixture of praise for workers rights and calls for patriotic mobilisation in the face of an economic down turn.
"Moscow has survived many different crises in its history, but has always emerged from them stronger and more beautiful. So it will be this time," Mr Sobyanin told the crowd in his address.
The bizarre combination of socialist tradition, contemporary politics, and officially sanctioned entertainment is part and parcel of a revival of Soviet tradition overseen by Vladimir Putin's Kremlin.
But the chants of "Peace! Labour! Russia! May!" were a long way from the holiday's origins in the insurgent 19th-century American trade union movement.
On May 4, 1886, Chicago police shot and killed four workers demonstrating for an eight-hour working day.
In the West, trade unions and Left-wing movements adopted May 1 to commemorate the 1886 shooting of four strikers seeking an eight-hour working day by Chicago police.
Adopted as the unofficial holiday of the anti-establishment Left, the day has often seen activists clashing with the authorities.
Russian Trade Unions' members in Red Square (AFP Getty Images)
In the former Soviet Union and other communist countries, it became an officially sanctioned holiday, complete with banners, marches, and politburo appearances atop Lenin's tomb.
These days, the socialist holiday is overshadowed by Victory Day on May 9, the cult of the Second World War being the nearest thing Vladimir Putin's state has to an official ideology.
Mr Sobyanin and his fellow marchers did not wear red, but sported scarves in the orange and black St George's ribbons  a badge of Russian military valour that has been appropriated as both the symbol of the 1945 victory and the badge of Russian-backed separatists fighting in Eastern Ukraine.
The Soviet Union is 24 years dead, but the trade union leaders who chanted "yes to a living wage and safe working conditions!" did call for revolution or protest.
Instead, they stood alongside Mr Sobyanin as if celebrating a battle already won or calling for workers to unite with the authorities to win it.
For most Russians, however, the significance of May Day has little to do with international socialism, but the beginning of a week of days off and general skiving that is the highlight of the working calendar.
Each year, tens if not hundreds of thousands of Russians and citizens of other post-Soviet countries take advantage of the twin bank holidays of May Day and Victory Day on May 9 to head off on a spring break.
The savvy will have booked the intervening days off work months ago. Others will simply skive. Many will head to their dachas outside the city, marking the beginning of the season of weekend commutes to the countryside.
Everyone, however, will sit in traffic jams and spend too much money. Like bank holidays in every country, the roads will be clogged, hotel rooms scarce, and air and rail ticket prices through the roof.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:35:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chile's Calbuco volcano sends out new blasts of ash</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45ea4c4d/sc/42/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Csouthamerica0Cchile0C115761840CChiles0ECalbuco0Evolcano0Esends0Eout0Enew0Eblasts0Eof0Eash0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Thousands of nearby residents who had just returned home evacuated again as Chile's Calbuco volcano shoots out new eruption of ash</Description>
        <MainBody>Chile
Chile's Calbuco volcano sends out new blasts of ash
Thousands of nearby residents who had just returned home evacuated again as Chile's Calbuco volcano shoots out new eruption of ash
A man watches the erupting Calbuco volcano Photo: Rex Features
AP
10:35AM BST 01 May 2015
The Calbuco volcano erupted again on Thursday, sending dark bursts of ash and hot rock billowing 2.5 miles into the air and prompting Chilean officials to order a new evacuation of nearby residents.
Thick clouds boiled out of 6,500-foot cone, bringing the threat of new, heavy ash fall over villagers struggling to clean up from two huge blasts last week.
The surrounding area was evacuated after the volcano first erupted last Wednesday afternoon, but many people had begun to return to their ash-drowned homes.
"We were working, cleaning the ash and sand from our homes when this third eruption took place. I feel so much anger and impotence it just breaks me apart," Horacio Camano said sobbing after evacuating the town of Ensenada with his family.
Soldiers remove ash that fell from Calbuco Volcano in the town of Ensenada in Puerto Varas, Chile (Reuters)
"There are no words for having to live this over again - having our families worried about us, all phones collapsed. I just want this to calm down so we can return home."
The eruptions at Calbuco are the first in more than four decades.
More than 4,500 people have been evacuated since the Calbuco roared back to life April 22, sending ash about 11 miles into the sky. Hours later, it produced a second, spectacular outburst that turned the nighttime sky reddish orange.
The ash from those eruptions spread across the southern part of the continent, disrupting flights all the way to Argentina's capital, Buenos Aires, and causing widespread economic damage by turning cattle pastures barren and choking fish in one of the world's top salmon-producing countries.
"This latest eruption is much smaller than the other two," Deputy Interior Minister Mahmud Aleuy said at a news conference, but he said 1,500 people were being evacuated as a precaution.
Rodrigo Alvarez, director of the National Mining and Geology service, said that new eruptions stronger than those last week were not expected. But he warned that rains, which are expected to fall beginning Friday, could lead to devastating volcanic mud flows, known as lahars, which are capable of leveling anything in their path once in motion.
"Lahars are possible if we get heavy rains, so it's still a concern," Alvarez said.
Volcano expert Moyra Gardeweg said the wet weather also could mean acid rain that damages metal and plant life and pollutes water sources.
Last week, LATAM and other airline companies cancelled several flights since ash can severely damage jet engines. But LAN, the Chilean unit of LATAM, said its flights were not disrupted by the latest eruption.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:34:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Earthquake of magnitude 7.1 strikes off Papua New Guinea</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45e962b6/sc/32/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Caustraliaandthepacific0Cpapuanewguinea0C115760A770CEarthquake0Eof0Emagnitude0E70B10Estrikes0Eoff0EPapua0ENew0EGuinea0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US Geological Survey reports seismic activity near coastline of Rabaul, a town on East New Britain Island, Papua New Guinea</Description>
        <MainBody>Papua New Guinea
Earthquake of magnitude 7.1 strikes off Papua New Guinea
US Geological Survey reports seismic activity near coastline of Rabaul, a town    on East New Britain Island, Papua New Guinea
Rabaul lies in the shadow of Mount Tavurvur, an active volcanoPhoto: Alamy
By Agencies
10:34AM BST 01 May 2015
An earthquake of magnitude 7.1 struck off Papua New Guinea on Friday, 80 miles south-south-west of Rabaul, at a depth of 38 miles, the United States Geological Survey reported.
The quake hit at 08.06am GMT, 428 miles northeast of the Pacific nation's capital Port Moresby. There were no immediate reports of damages or casualties.
"It's a very uninhabited region off the island of New Britain," co-director of the Joint Australian Tsunami Warning Centre Daniel Jaksa told AFP.
"The earthquake was a measure of 7.1, so that's about 30 times smaller than the [recent] earthquake in Nepal. It should be like the one yesterday - no real impact."
The earthquake was recoreded at at 08.06am GMT
A hazardous tsunami warning was initally issued by the Pacific Tsunami Warning Centre, but soon lifted.
Rabaul, a town on East New Britain Island, lies in the shadow of Mount Tavurvur, an active volcano.
Rabaul was destroyed in 1994 during a severe eruption.
The area was struck by a 6.9 quake on Thursday.
More follows
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:20:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Secret Imperial Japan submarine 'aircraft carriers' mapped off Hawaii</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45e96a3e/sc/32/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cjapan0C115761620CSecret0EImperial0EJapan0Esubmarine0Eaircraft0Ecarriers0Emapped0Eoff0EHawaii0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>State-of-the-art Japanese vessels were designed to launch airborne attacks against west coast of US</Description>
        <MainBody>Secret Imperial Japan submarine 'aircraft carriers' mapped off Hawaii
State-of-the-art Japanese vessels were designed to launch airborne attacks against west coast of US
Footage taken shows a gun attached to the wreckPhoto: University of Hawaii
By Julian Ryall, Tokyo
10:20AM BST 01 May 2015
A new expedition has filmed the wreck of a top-secret submarine built by Japan during the Second World War that was designed to launch bombers against the west coast of the United States .
The last resting place of the I-400 submarine was confirmed in December 2013, but researchers from the University of Hawaii and the US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration were returning to the wreck  which lies at a depth of nearly 2,700 feet  for the first time.
They captured on video the vessel's massive hangar, the conning tower and ship's bell.
A bell which was filmed during the expedition (University of Hawaii)
At 400 feet long, the Imperial Japanese Navy's I-400 class were the largest submarines of the war and remained the largest constructed until the first nuclear ballistic missile boats rolled down slipways in the 1960s.
Designed as underwater aircraft carriers, they were able to stow three Aichi light bombers, with folded wings, in a hangar on the deck.
The recent footage was shot for a documentary
Aware of its inferiority in surface ships in the Pacific theatre, the Japanese Navy nevertheless wished to take the fight to the enemy and the vessel was given the task of approaching the US coast, surfacing, preparing and launching its aircraft within minutes. One of the earliest missions called for the aircraft to drop rats infected with bubonic plague and insects carrying cholera, dengue fever, typhus and other diseases on cities on the West coast of America.
 Korean sex slave calls on Japan to face up to its past
When the bacteriological weapons were not ready in time, the target switched to a conventional bombing attack against the Panama Canal. Japan surrendered before the raid could be carried out.
At the end of the war, five submarines were captured intact by the US and dispatched under a prize crew to Hawaii for inspection  and with their cavernous hangars reportedly filled with war booty.
The remains of the submarine are said to be remarkably well preserved (University of Hawaii)
The following year, the Soviet Union demanded access to the submarines but the US, which had already learned the technological secrets that they incorporated in their designs, did not want the same information falling into the hands of its new Cold War enemy. The five vessels were hastily sunk by torpedoes from the USS Cabezon off Oahu.
The recent footage was shot by NHK, Japan's national broadcaster, for a documentary that is to be aired on May 6. It revealed the relative positions of the aircraft hangar and conning tower, which had broken apart when the submarine was hit by torpedoes and sank.
"We didn't have detailed enough bottom-mapping data to help locate the hangar, conning tower and other signature features missing from the wreck of the I-400", said Terry Kerby, operations director and chief submarine pilot for the Hawaii Undersea Research Laboratory.
"With only one dive day to try to find anything, we knew there was a strong chance we might spend the dive looking at the barren sandy bottom.
"We made a lucky guess where to start when we approached the main hull of the I-400 from the north-west", Mr Kerby added. "Our guess started to pay off when the giant hangar door came into view, followed by the conning tower and hangar.
"Many items were amazingly intact for something that had ripped out of the hull of a sinking 400-foot-long submarine."
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:20:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Pacific island off Tonga is already 'disappearing' due to rain erosion</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45e962b9/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Caustraliaandthepacific0Ctongafrenchpolynesia0C115760A570CNew0EPacific0Eisland0Eoff0ETonga0Eis0Ealready0Edisappearing0Edue0Eto0Erain0Eerosion0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A voyage to a new unnamed island that formed off Tonga in January has reported it is showing signs of erosion ahead of its likely disappearance</Description>
        <MainBody>Tonga French Polynesia
New Pacific island off Tonga is already 'disappearing' due to rain erosion
A voyage to a new unnamed island that formed off Tonga in January has reported it is showing signs of erosion ahead of its likely disappearance
A photograph of the new Island off the coast of Nuku'alofaPhoto: Mosese Fakatou
By Jonathan Pearlman, Sydney
9:20AM BST 01 May 2015
A new island that formed in the Pacific after an underwater volcano eruption off Tonga has begun to erode and is "getting smaller".
The cone-shaped island - about half a mile wide and just under a mile long - formed in January about 40 miles north-west of Nuku'alofa, the capital, after an eruption at the Hunga Tonga volcano.
The newly formed Island is pictured on the left of the picture (Mosese Fakatou)
Scientists predicted that the land mass would be fragile and was likely to gradually disappear - a prediction that has now been borne out by an expedition by locals to examine the island.
A Tongan shipping firm, Friendly Island Shipping Agency, sent a boat to the island last week and carried local geologists who briefly went ashore.
Mosese Fakatou, a manager from the firm who travelled to the island, said the island was stable but its surface had begun to erode.
"The geologists think it is getting smaller," he told The Telegraph.
"It looks like streaks of erosion probably from rain in the past few weeks. We could see the marks on the island."
Mr Fakatou said the island "looks alright" and the volcano was no longer active.
View of eastern side of new island (Mosese Fakatou)
"We sent some people ashore - some geologists - and they took some measurements of the island," he said.
New islands have been known to form due to volcanic activity but tend to disappear, often within weeks.
The latest island, which has yet to be officially named , is believed to have formed after a volcano exploded underwater and then expanded.
The new island was first photographed earlier this year
"This is not the first time - it has happened before," Pesi Fonua, editor of the Matangi Tonga news website, told The Telegraph.
"It is still very much there but it is not what it was after the eruption was formed. It is slowly eroding into the sea. It is very slow."
Photographs of the island first emerged in March after a group of locals went ashore. They reported that the surface remained still hot and a green lake in the crater smelt strongly of sulphur.
The newly formed island is pictured on the right of the picture (Mosese Fakatou)
The island formed following a volcano explosion that began in December and lasted weeks.
Gianpiero Orbassano took this picture of crater on the island (file photo)
Its birth was recorded by Tonga's lands and natural resources ministry, which stated: "During our observations the volcano was erupting about every five minutes to a height of about [1,300 feet], accompanied by some large rocks."
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:06:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Awkward moment a schoolboy cuts off President Barack Obama for talking too much</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45e962ba/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cbarackobama0C115760A130CAwkward0Emoment0Ea0Eschoolboy0Ecuts0Eoff0EPresident0EBarack0EObama0Efor0Etalking0Etoo0Emuch0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At an event in Washington, President Barack Obama talks about the importance of reading and writing when a student moderator cuts him off</Description>
        <MainBody>Barack Obama
Awkward moment a schoolboy cuts off President Barack Obama for talking too much
At an event in Washington, President Barack Obama talks about the importance    of reading and writing when a student moderator cuts him off
By Telegraph video, video source APTN
9:06AM BST 01 May 2015
President Barack Obama announced Thursday that major book publishers will provide more than $250 million in free e-books to low-income students and that he is seeking commitments from local governments and schools nationwide to provide library cards to all students.
There was a lighthearted moment during the President's appearance as a student moderator interrupted Obama, saying, "I think you sort of covered everything about that question."
The president replied, "Guzman thinks I've been talking too long."
Obama announced the initiatives at a library in Washington's economically depressed Anacostia neighbourhood.
Obama told the students that how well they do in life is going to depend on whether they love reading and learning, and whether they know how to find information and use it.
Obama also appealed to library directors, local governments and school officials to work together to provide all students with a library card. The White House already has commitments from 30 cities and counties, ranging from Baltimore to San Francisco.
During a question-and-answer session with about 40 students in the room and others participating online, Obama declared his love for turning and marking up the pages of traditional books.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:46:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pictures of the day: 1 May 2015</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45e962bb/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Cpicturesoftheday0C115755390CPictures0Eof0Ethe0Eday0E10EMay0E20A150Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A licking lion, a rooftopping selfie and a city made from coins</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE...
&lt; &gt;
A lion trainer has her face washed by a lion during the filming of 'Stars and Starlets' at the National Circus in the Ukrainian capital of KievPicture: REUTERS/Gleb Garanich

Comments are closed on this picture gallery.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:19:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Confused seal pup found roaming the streets of San Francisco</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45e87326/sc/16/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cearth0Cwildlife0C11575980A0CConfused0Eseal0Epup0Efound0Eroaming0Ethe0Estreets0Eof0ESan0EFrancisco0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A baby California Sea Lion called "Rubbish", who was previously rescued by a local marine centre, is found hiding under a car in San Francisco's Marina district</Description>
        <MainBody>Wildlife
Confused seal pup found roaming the streets of San Francisco
A baby California Sea Lion called "Rubbish", who was previously    rescued by a local marine centre, is found hiding under a car in San    Francisco's Marina district
By Keely Lockhart , video source APTN
8:19AM BST 01 May 2015
A sea lion pup got into a pickle when he waddled ashore and was spotted on Thursday cowering under a car in San Francisco's Marina District.
The animal was spotted by residents on the road and local police and animal rescue were called.
Rubbish the seal
However this isn't the pup's first foray onto dry ground.
Local media reports the seal pup had previously been treated by the Marine Mammal Center in Sausalito, after being found suffering from pneumonia and malnutrition.
His carers, who decided to name him Rubbish, was released after gaining 17 pounds.
Rubbish the seal being treated at the the Marine Mammal Center
However it seems the little pup is in need of more TLC, after rescuers found he has lost all the weight he gained during his last visit.
Vets now plan to test Rubbish for any underlying health problems that have caused him to venture back on shore.
Stranded seal pups is becoming increasingly common in San Francisco - which has a large Sea Lion population - as warmer waters on the West Coast have diminished Sea Lion food supply for mothers and their pups.
Mendocino County Sheriff's Deputies with another lost California sea lion pup on the road (PHOTO: Mendocino County Sheriff/REX)
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:19:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British ambassador to Nepal recalls moment the embassy compound shook</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45e86f70/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cnepal0C1157590A70CBritish0Eambassador0Eto0ENepal0Erecalls0Emoment0Ethe0Eembassy0Ecompound0Eshook0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>John Rankin describes moment objects began flying around him in earthquake-proofed residence - and how much greater terror must have been for those more exposed outside walls</Description>
        <MainBody>Nepal
British ambassador to Nepal recalls moment the embassy compound shook
John Rankin describes moment objects began flying around him in    earthquake-proofed residence - and how much greater terror must have been    for those more exposed outside walls
The British ambassador's residence in Nepal Photo: Tom Phillips/Telegraph
Follow
Britains ambassador to Nepal has described the moment when last Saturdays 7.8 magnitude rattled Kathmandu, sending lamps crashing off tables inside his home and his security detail diving onto the ground outside.
John Rankin had just returned to his official residence after taking a morning stroll around Kathmandu and was reading a local newspaper when the earthquake struck.
The alarms went off immediately and the ground shook, the 58-year-old diplomat said.
I was able to look out of the window to see my security team lying on the ground which is the recommended thing to do.
The immediate thing you do is to hold onto something that is going to stop you falling over.
Britains ambassador to Nepal John Rankin (Nepal Foreign Affairs)
Then, as I was sitting there, lamps were crashing around me, things were falling off the table and [there was] a lot of noise. But Im lucky. The building I am in is retrofitted against earthquake damage. Although the main embassy building has suffered some damage we have still been able to operate.
 Sons of Hillary and Norgay took refuge in same village by chance during Nepal earthquake
When the shaking subsided and Mr Rankin had been able to assess the situation in and around the embassy compound, he headed out onto the streets of Kathmandu where more than 1,100 people are reported to have died.
I think first of all you saw some buildings intact and some places where the walls had fallen down and you saw the damage, the veteran diplomat said. But the initial thing was seeing people: seeing people in a confused condition, people standing there not really knowing what had happened, people trying to get themselves to open ground.
A member of the public ushers people away from a collapsed building in Kathmandu (EPA)
"When you do see what has happened to some people  the fact that I was in a retrofitted building, the fact that I have got a security team to assist puts us in a position where hopefully it means we can help people. But I can appreciate how terrifying it must have been for people who were in a more exposed situation.
The hours and days after the earthquake saw scores of British citizens flock to the embassy compound seeking help. They were given shelter in tents erected just inside the entrance in an area dubbed Camp Sterling.
At one point we were looking after 158 people, including citizens of Ireland and Commonwealth nations, the ambassador said. By Thursday consular officials had helped more than 300 British nationals and evacuated 120.
We have assisted 300 British Nationals &amp; evacuated 120. Our focus is to help all those still in need. #Nepal pic.twitter.com/qhEsoDK2Yr
 British Embassy (@UKinNepal) April 30, 2015
Aid workers and rescue teams composed of British medics and fire fighters are now living on the lawn outside the ambassadors residence and are sleeping in dozens of orange tents.
Bricks and rubble are cleared from Durbar Square in Kathmandu (Rex Features)
We will offer support and be here for as long as were needed, said Mark Coleman, a 49-year-old officer from the Cheshire Fire and Rescue Service who is camping in the ambassadors garden.
Mr Coleman, who is part of a 67-strong team from the International Search and Rescue Service (ISAR), said there was still hope of finding survivors even more than five days after the disaster.
Today they pulled out a 15-year-old [alive]  because the climate is good. If someone is buried its ideal for keeping someone alive, he said on Thursday.
Gail Marzetti, the head of the Department for International Development (DFID) in Nepal, said the short-term priorities were rescuing people, getting dead people cremated, hospitals operating properly, medical care to people and food.
The longer term challenge is going to be the rebuilding of Nepal.
DFID has released 15m in initial assistance.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:00:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>I want to be Spain's Boris Johnson, says Madrid mayor hopeful Esperanza Aguirre</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45e86f72/sc/13/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cspain0C11547550A0CI0Ewant0Eto0Ebe0ESpains0EBoris0EJohnson0Esays0EMadrid0Emayor0Ehopeful0EEsperanza0EAguirre0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Esperanza Aguirre, campaigning to be the next mayor of Madrid, tells The Telegraph why she thinks she can become a Spanish blend of Margaret Thatcher and Boris</Description>
        <MainBody>Spain
I want to be Spain's Boris Johnson, says Madrid mayor hopeful Esperanza Aguirre
Esperanza Aguirre, campaigning to be the next mayor of Madrid, tells The    Telegraph why she thinks she can become a Spanish blend of Margaret Thatcher    and Boris
By James Badcock, Madrid
Comments
In Spain she is often referred to as the country's answer to Margaret Thatcher , a Spanish iron lady.
Esperanza Aguirre, a flame-haired former minister and Senate speaker with the conservative Popular Party (PP), is openly admiring of Britain's only woman prime minister and, like Thatcher, is used to being at odds with many of her political colleagues.
"I identify with her in practically every sense," said Mrs Aguirre, speaking to The Telegraph in her office at the PP's Madrid headquarters  from where she is plotting a return to office as Madrid mayor in local elections on May 24.
The campaign in Spain's capital marks a return to front-line politics for Mrs Aguirre, who stepped down as Madrid regional premier in 2012  a decision taken partly due to her battle with breast cancer. But not even serious illness kept the 63-year-old politician out of the public eye as she went through a successful cancer treatment.
"I think I should talk about my cancer as much as possible so that the public realises that it is a disease which can be cured," she said.
"It is just as curable as other illnesses if it is treated in time. I talk about it so that people take the preventive measures."
Mrs Aguirre is a survivor, both in politics and life itself.
Born into an aristocratic Spanish family, in 1974 she married Fernando Ramrez de Haro, the Count of Bornos. The couple have two sons. She studied law before becoming a civil servant in the ministry of tourism, and then entered politics.
In 2005 she walked away from a helicopter crash when, along with current prime minister, Mariano Rajoy , the aircraft they were in spiralled out of the sky after taking off from a bullring. Later she would spend several anxious hours hiding in Mumbai's Oberoi Hotel as Islamist terrorists perpetrated their 2008 massacre in the Indian city.
Mayor of London Boris Johnson is licked by a dog as he meets members of the public and local business owners after launching the Conservative London campaign at Hartley Hall in Mill Hill, London
Now, despite a troubled relationship with PP leader Mr Rajoy, Mrs Aguirre  known to all, detractors and admirers alike, as simply "Espe"  is perhaps facing her toughest challenge yet amid a turbulent political environment after years of economic crisis and austerity in Spain.
"I don't know if it is the hardest challenge I have ever faced but it is certainly going to be very difficult because of the disenchantment that exists in Spain. People feel distanced from their political representatives," Mrs Aguirre said.
The PP has held both the regional and city governments of Madrid for the past two decades, but Mrs Aguirre says that a combination of corruption, the crisis and the defects of Spain's electoral system have opened the way for new political forces to dispute power with the conservatives and the Socialist Party in next month's countrywide polls.
While the new formation called Citizens is for Mrs Aguirre a respectable "centre-left" option, she is scathing about Podemos, the leftist anti-austerity party headed by intellectuals such as its pony-tailed leader Pablo Iglesias .
Mrs Aguirre accuses them of being in corrupt thrall to the Venezuelan government and determined to end democracy as Spain knows it.
"Podemos is a dangerous option," she says. "They are not like Syriza in Greece , whose objective was to get into government. Podemos don't want to become the government; they want to overthrow the regime. If it is true that they are the leading political force as some opinion polls say, this could be the last time we vote freely as we are used to doing in Western democracies."
Mrs Aguirre says Podemos will sweep away the system of representative democracy and replace it with a participatory system, condemning all opposition to virtual irrelevance as she claims the Hugo Chavez regime did in Venezuela .
Podemos is committed to governing according to the results of referendums, including a pledge to offer Spaniards the chance to vote on whether to continue being a monarchy or not.
Margaret Thatcher
Mrs Aguirre argues that Podemos has already had corruption scandals of its own , citing money paid to one of the party's leaders, Juan Carlos Monedero, by the Venezuelan government for consultancy work which he did not initially declare as personal income. But she accepts that Spain's traditional parties like the PP, whose former treasurer Luis Barcenas is at the centre of a massive slush-fund probe, do not have a perfect record.
"Corruption must be eradicated, cut off at the first sign," she said, adding that changes to Spain's electoral system of closed party lists would help to restore credibility to the nation's politics.
"Here politicians are mainly concerned with being liked by the party leaders who decide whether they should be in the list or not. In Britain representatives vote for what they think their electorate want them to vote for, whereas here deputies do as the party tells them."
Although she criticises Podemos for labelling the entire political class as "la casta" or the caste  concerned only with feathering their own nests of privilege  Mrs Aguirre at times seems to share a comparable reformist zeal.
"Whether they win or lose elections, parties get very big public subsidies. And the higher echelons of some parties feel more comfortable in opposition than in government. You can earn the salaries you like, while in government you have to renounce all other income, and you don't have to make difficult decisions".
If she succeeds in replacing the outgoing Ana Botella as PP mayor of Madrid , Mrs Aguirre says she plans to strike a new note of openness and transparency, inspired by London mayor Boris Johnson .
"I am a great admirer of the British, and the first time I read that Boris was going to put online all the meals he has and with whom, I decided that I would do the same in Madrid city hall. And not only for meals and small costs, which are headline grabbers, but all major tenders and contract processes will be explained online. Sadly, in Spain government opacity has led on many occasions to corruption."
She also praises Mr Johnson for his pro-cycling stance, but upbraids the Conservatives for bringing the Tube back under public control. "That was not in accordance with our shared ideology".
Esperanza Aguirre and adimirer of Boris Johnson
Besides her adoration of Thatcher for her liberal economics, patriotism and being a pioneer woman leader, Mrs Aguirre is at pains to point out her connections to Britain, deepened by her having gone to an English-language school in Madrid. She says that the introduction of bilingual English-Spanish education at state schools in the Madrid region "is one of her proudest achievements," and in 2004 she was appointed Honorary Dame Commander of the Order of the British Empire.
In a speech last year to the Anglo-Spanish Society, held inside the House of Commons, she spoke of her "anglophilia"  especially in reference to the more direct style of politics in Britain and "the fact that lies are not tolerated".
Always outspoken, Mrs Aguirre has said that this month's King's Cup football final should be suspended if fans of the two teams, Barcelona and Athletic Bilbao, boo the Spanish national anthem as has occurred on previous occasions.
"It is unimaginable that 'God Save The Queen' would be booed in a stadium in Britain. And for a Catalan, Basque or Galician, it is equally inconceivable for their region's anthem to be booed," she said.
"And yet when it comes to Spain's national anthem, everyone finds it quite normal that there are jeers and whistles for the king. It is a demonstration of hatred towards Spaniards and that includes many Catalans who consider themselves Spaniards."
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:00:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Esperanza Aguirre: I'm a great admirer of Margaret Thatcher</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/45e86f74/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cspain0C115276640CEsperanza0EAguirre0EIm0Ea0Egreat0Eadmirer0Eof0EMargaret0EThatcher0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Former head of Madrid's regional government, Esperanza Aguirre, known as the "Spanish Iron Lady", speaks of her admiration of the British political system as way of preventing corruption</Description>
        <MainBody>Spain
Esperanza Aguirre: I'm a great admirer of Margaret Thatcher
Former head of Madrid's regional government, Esperanza Aguirre, known as the "Spanish    Iron Lady", speaks of her admiration of the British political system as    way of preventing corruption
By Telegraph Video
7:00AM BST 01 May 2015
In Spain she is often referred to as the country's answer to Margaret Thatcher , a Spanish iron lady. Esperanza Aguirre, a flame-haired former minister and Senate speaker with the conservative Popular Party (PP), is openly admiring of Britain's only woman prime minister and, like Thatcher, is used to being at odds with many of her political colleagues.
"I identify with her in practically every sense," said Mrs Aguirre, speaking to The Telegraph in her office at the PP's Madrid headquarters  from where she is plotting a return to office as Madrid mayor in local elections on May 24.
The campaign in Spain's capital marks a return to front-line politics for Mrs Aguirre, who stepped down as Madrid regional premier in 2012  a decision taken partly due to her battle with breast cancer. But not even serious illness kept the 63-year-old politician out of the public eye as she went through a successful cancer treatment.
"I think I should talk about my cancer as much as possible so that the public realises that it is a disease which can be cured," she said.
"It is just as curable as other illnesses if it is treated in time. I talk about it so that people take the preventive measures."
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
