<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Telegraph">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:48:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear talks enter 'difficult phase' as deadline extended again</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7d5c2/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Ciran0C117234920CIran0Enuclear0Etalks0Eenter0Edifficult0Ephase0Eas0Edeadline0Eextended0Eagain0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Negotiations will continue for the next couple of days but we are not extending our deadline, claims Ms Mogherini</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran
Iran nuclear talks enter 'difficult phase' as deadline extended again
Negotiations will continue for the next couple of days but we are not    extending our deadline, claims Ms Mogherini
European Union foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini arrives for a press briefing outside Palais Coburg, the venue for nuclear talks in Vienna, Austria Photo: AFP/Getty
By Agencies
1:48PM BST 07 Jul 2015
Iran and major powers will continue negotiations on a historic nuclear deal past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term agreement, European Union foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days. This does not mean we are extending our deadline," Ms Mogherini told reporters.
The deal under discussion between Iran, Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days," Ms Mogherini told reporters (Reuters)
"We might see some ministers leaving in the next hours and then ready to come back," Ms Mogherini said.
"We are interpreting in a flexible way our deadline, which means that we are taking the time, the days we still need, to finalise the agreement," she said, adding that there remained several difficult issues to resolve .
Iran said that it has no target date for completing a nuclear deal with world powers.
Sergei Lavrov, Russian foreign minister, said on Tuesday that around eight issues remained to be "finalised" before a nuclear deal between Iran and six powers is reached, Interfax news agency reported.
Iran and the major powers will continue negotiations on an historic nuclear deal past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term agreement.
"We have no deadline," a spokesman for the Iranian delegation in talks with major powers in Vienna told AFP.
The negotiators missed a June 30 deadline for a final agreement and then gave themselves until Tuesday.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:39:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why has France become a target for recent terror attacks?</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf01/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C1170A11640CWhy0Ehas0EFrance0Ebecome0Ea0Etarget0Efor0Erecent0Eterror0Eattacks0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Following the decapitation of a man in Grenoble, The Telegraph's Henry Samuel explains why France has become a target for terror attacks in recent months</Description>
        <MainBody>France
Why has France become a target for recent terror attacks?
Following the decapitation of a man in Grenoble, The Telegraph's Henry Samuel    explains why France has become a target for terror attacks in recent months
By Telegraph Video, contains video from APTN
1:39PM BST 26 Jun 2015
A man has been decapitated during a suspected Islamist terror attack in France .
A message in Arabic was reportedly found on the victim's head, which had been pinned to a fence.
Two attackers arrived at a gas factory near Grenoble in a car, bearing banners written in Arabic, and set off explosions.
Grenoble attack: Man found beheaded and Islamist flag raised above factory in France - latest
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier. Credit: AFP/Getty
France 's anti-terror prosecutor said the attack was carried out by "a terrorist group" and it is understood one man has been arrested.
The decapitation comes a few months after the Islamist attacks in and around Paris in which 17 people were killed.
The Telegraph's France correspondent Henry Samuel explains why France has become a target for terror attacks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Grenoble attack: Man found beheaded and Islamist flag raised above factory in France - latest</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dcf/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C1170A0A5130CGrenoble0Eattack0EMan0Efound0Ebeheaded0Eand0EIslamist0Eflag0Eraised0Eabove0EFrench0Efactory0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>There were explosions reportedly heard near the industrial gas factory near Grenoble, south-eastern France where one person is believed to be dead and several hurt</Description>
        <MainBody>This page will automatically update every 30 secondsOn Off
 A decapitated body was found near a gas factory in south-eastern France, near Grenoble
 There was Arabic writing on the head
 A man suspected has been arrested and identified
 An attacker is believed to have killed one person and injured several others
 The attacker set off several explosions, a legal source says
Latest
13.45
French anti-terror raid police are currently raiding the home of Yacine Sali, the suspect arrested this morning at the factory, Henry Samuel in Paris writes.
A second suspect said to be "close" to him has been arrested, the interior ministry says.
Anti-terror police currently raiding home of arrested France factory attack suspect Yacine Salhi #Isre
 Henry Samuel (@H_E_Samuel) June 26, 2015
"France has been struck again by terror," the country's prime minister, Manuel Valls, said as he was cutting short a trip to South America to return to Paris.
"The terrorists' threats and blind horrors spare no nation. My thoughts go to the victims of Isre and the victims in Tunisia," he said from Colombia.
13.30
Sgolne Royale, a French socialist politician, has been speaking to reporters, James Rothwell writes.
She said: "This was an abominable attack... my thoughts go first of all to the families of the victims and the employees of this factory, who have no doubt been profoundly traumatised.
"The French government and authorities have reacted by increasing security at other sensitive sites. I would like to also say, as a member of the government, that unity among the French at this tragic moment is absolutely essential."
French Gendarmes block the access road to the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier (Reuters)
13.17
France's prime minister said an attack on a factory Friday was "Islamist terrorism," announcing he was cutting short a visit to South America to deal with the crisis.
"Islamist terrorism has hit France again," Manuel Valls told a press conference in Colombia's capital Bogota, adding that he would take part by telephone in an emergency meeting called by M r Hollande, then rush back to France.
The suspect arrested is reportedly married with three kids.
"Brave" fireman "neutralised" suspect who placed him "out of harm's way" says int min Bernard Cazeneuve as "second man arrested". #Isere
 Henry Samuel (@H_E_Samuel) June 26, 2015
13.12
The Telegraph's James Rothwell has been looking at French media reaction:
Jean-Jack Queyranne, president of the Rhne-Alpes region, told Le Figaro: "I feel a sense of horror in the face of the barbarism that has just taken place in Isre in the heart of our region.
First of all I would like to express my solidarity with the victims, their families and those close to them.
"We must be careful to ensure that fear does not become widespread. As in January [during the Charlie Hebdo massacre] the nation must unite as a whole to face up to this danger. For it is the nation that must combat terror."
French police and firefighters gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier (AFP/Getty Images)
12.59
Germany stands united with France against "terror's blind hate" and in defence of "free society", Frank-Walter Steinmeier, the foreign minister, said
Mr Steinmeier said he was appalled by the "shocking news of a heinous murder and an assault with several injured", calling it an "act of terror and fanaticism which we condemn in the strongest terms".
Barack Obama has been briefed on the attack at a US gas company in France, a senior administration official said, providing no further details.
12.30
Mr Cazeneuve says the suspected accomplices in the attack are being held by police. The man arrested has been known to security services since 2006 but surveillance stopped in 2008. He has no criminal record.
The interior minister said he had been filed as possibly being radicalised.
The French attack suspect had 'link' to Salafist movement, AFP reports.
Suspect named as Yacine Sali, 30. "Others who may have been involved arrested", says int min Cazeneuve #Isre
 Henry Samuel (@H_E_Samuel) June 26, 2015
12.20
BREAKING: Bernard Cazeneuve has named the suspect arrested as Yacine Sali.
12.09
Mr Hollande learnt of the terrorist attack just as the European Council was reconvening before 10am, Matthew Holehouse in Brussels writes. Here are some more comments in full from Mr Hollande.
The interior minister and public prosecutor "immediately" went to the site. The plant is under further protection and "all measures" are being taken, he said.
Bernard Cazeneuve will speak later to provide limited "useful" information.
Our thoughts go to the victim. It is a matter of solidarity. The European Council has expressed solidarity.
"There is a lot of emotion but it cannot be the only answer. Other answers are protection, deterrence. And the necessity to spread our values and never give in to fear, and to shoulder our responsibilities in all circumstances.
"It is not about spreading suspicion, but doing our job, protecting our people while finding out the truth and the individuals responsible for such actions."
Mr Hollande is to hold a meeting at the Elysee at 3.30pm.
12.01
More detail from Mr Hollande's press conference just now from Matthew Holehouse in Brussels.
Mr Hollande confirmed one person has died and two injured. He said a suspect has been arrested and identified.
He explained some of what happened during the attack and said a car driven by one person, maybe two, to the factory and their target was a gas bottle factory.
"This attack was in a vehicle driven by one person, perhaps accompanied by another."
Their intention was to provoke an explosion, he said.
A body was found decapitated, and two injured as well as a message found. "It is a terrorist attack - there is no doubt about it," Mr Hollande said
He will return to Paris to oversee the operation and said "huge" numbers of troops have been deployed to protect other facilities
He said: "We will never give in to fear."
11.54
Donald Tusk, the European Council president, has offered his condolences.
I offer my sincere condolences and solidarity to @fhollande and the people of France following the attack in #Isre .
 Donald Tusk (@eucopresident) June 26, 2015
11.49
President Francois Hollande is speaking and says troops have been deployed in the region to prevent another attack.
Earlier he said the attacker had been identified but said there was an "ongoing investigation". He said there were one or two assailants.
"Our thoughts go to the victims. The European Council expressed his solidarity - we remember what happened in our country and other countries."
He also said: "The attack was of a terrorist nature given that a corpse with Islamist inscriptions were found."
11.48
Two men are believed to have driven into the main gate before 10am. The second suspect is an unconfirmed entity.
The car then drove around in circles and a person inside threw gas cylinders around the main yard, Mail Online reported.
Local prosecuting sources said a man jumped out of the car and then "decapitated a man".
Emergency personnel work at the scene of a suspected Islamist attack, outside the Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier (EPA)
11.38
Alain Jupp, the mayor of Bordeaux, has condemned the attacks saying that France "must make every effort to protect its citizens".
"The terrorist threat is at a maximum," he says.
La menace terroriste est maximum. L'attentat en Isre nous le rappelle hlas! L'Etat doit tout mettre en uvre pour protger ses citoyens.
 Alain Jupp (@alainjuppe) June 26, 2015
Mr Hollande is returning home early from the EU summit on Friday, officials said.
"He will return early this afternoon and is in constant contact with Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve and the security services," the official said, adding that he would make a statement to the press in Brussels before 1100 GMT.
"The president saw the first images of the attack on the 24-news channels with Angela Merkel, German chancellor, beside him, who was visibly shocked," an official added.
The two leaders had just ended a short meeting with Alexis Tsipras, the Greek prime minister.
(Pic: Le Dauphine )
11.32
The man arrested is refusing to talk, according to BFM TV reporters. The channel reports that the individual has no papers that can identify him thus police have not yet been able to either.
A security official said the torso was found near the site of the explosion but that the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
Two flags, one white and one black and both with Arabic inscriptions, were found at the scene, Associated Press reported.
11.30
David Cameron, the Prime Minister, has spoken to Mr Hollande to convey his sympathies, writes Steven Swinford, Deputy Political Editor.
The Prime Minister has spoken to Francois Hollande, the French President, at the EU summit in Brussels about the terror attack. A British official said:
He expressed his sympathies for what looks like an appalling incident there. It clearly looks like an extremely concerning situation and our thoughts are with all those that are affected by it."
The interior minister has now arrived at the factory as this pictures shows from Le Dauphine .
11.17
Francois Hollande is expected to return to France. Sky News are reporting that police are still looking for a man near the factory earlier today.
11.15
Some background from Josie Ensor about Air Products.
It is interesting to note that the president of the company targeted in the attack, Air Products, is a Shia Iranian named Seifi Ghasemi.
Iran supports Bashar al-Assad's regime in Syria, which is battling against Sunni Islamic State militants.
The scene in Grenoble via Le Dauphine .
11.10
A video from the scene via ledauphine.com.
France's anti-terror prosecutors have opened an inquiry for "murder and attempted murder in a group in relation to a terrorist organisation", writes Henry Samuel in Paris.
Itele cites police sources as describing as "false" reports that the man arrested is known to French intelligence services.
The 40-odd employees in the factory have been evacuated.
Witnesses at the scene said there was more than one attacker involved but this is unconfirmed.
11.05
What we know so far from AFP:
A suspected Islamist attacker pinned a decapitated head covered with Arabic writing to the gates of a gas factory in eastern France on Friday before being arrested, police say
The suspect entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices, the source said at around 10am local time
Police said it was unclear whether the attacker was acting alone, or had accomplices
A man thought to be the person who carried out the attack has been arrested - it is reported he is known to the security services
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minister said is on his way to the scene, his office say
11.02
The man arrested reportedly said he was a member of Islamic State.
10.56
France's president and prime minister are both currently abroad, but it looks like Franois Hollande, the president, may be returning prematurely from Brussels to handle the crisis, Henry Samuel writes.
10.55
This is the factory where the attack took place earlier today.
Banners with Arabic writing were found near the body, one official has told Associated Press.
10.52
French authorities have officially opened a terrorist investigation into today's attack.
10.48
Air Products, the American company targeted in the attack has 21,000 employees, according to its website, and sold industrial gases including nitrogen, oxygen, hydrogen, The Telegraph's Josie Ensor writes.
10.45
Francois Hollande, the president, is in Brussels for the EU summit but the meetings have begun without the leader.
We do not know yet if he will be returning to France.
Manuel Valls, the prime minister, has said that there will be tightened security measures on 'sensitive' sites after the attack.
Mr Valls also called for "heightened vigilance" at all sensitive sites in the Rhne-Alpes area.
"the head of the victim was found hanging on the fence of the Company enclosure" Oh damn... http://t.co/qfl2xan3MO #frankrijk #attack
 Rick Schipper (@Enoxiz) June 26, 2015
10.43
Sky News has said the arrested man is believed to be 30 years old and known to France's anti-terrorist police (DGSI).
There was Arabic writing on severed head pinned to French factory gates, a legal source tells AFP.
10.39
Here is what we know so far:
Two men brandishing what appears to be an Islamic State flag launched an attack on a chemical factoy in Isre, southeastern France, on Friday morning, Henry Samuel writes.
The Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier produces industrial gas and is considered a sensitive site, said a Erwann Binet, Socialist MP for the Isre dpartement. The factory is on the outskirts of Lyon.
The two assailants rammed a vehicle carrying bottles of gas into the Air Products factory in Saint Quentin, in the south-eastern Isre area.
One was brandishing what appears to be an Islamic State flag.
A strong explosion ensued. According to the interior ministry, two employees were injured in the blast. Another man was found decapitated near the factory. According to iTele, the rolling news channel, he was not a factory employee.
One man, thought to be one of the assailants, has been arrested, said the interior ministry.
France's elite GIGN anti-terror police have been sent to the site.
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minsiter, said he is on his way to the area "immediately".
We are all in a state of shock as we didnt expect any attack in our territory, said Mr Binet.
A police source cited by RTL radio said "other attacks cannot be ruled out".
10.33
Le Dauphin Liber reports that a man has been arrested but it is unknown if he is the suspected attacker. AFP cites a source saying that it is the attacker.
According to Sky News, there could be two attackers.
Meanwhile, the Local France reports that the decapitated man was not an employee at the factory.
The attack is believed to have taken place at 10am local time, 9am BST.
10.30
More from AFP's source:
"According to the initial findings of the enquiry, one or several individuals on board a vehicle, drove into the factory. An explosion then took place," said one of the sources.
"The decapitated body of a person was found nearby the factory but we do not yet know whether the body was transported to the place or not," added this source, adding that a "flag with Arabic writing on it was found on the scene."
According to a local French newspaper a man's head was chopped off and then hung on fence of the factory in St Quentin Fallavier. This remains unconfirmed.
BREAKING: Man arrested after "Islamist attack" in central France - http://t.co/pHSJoV49Ca pic.twitter.com/1yPISpnsFY
 The Local France (@TheLocalFrance) June 26, 2015
10.26
There are reports that the factory belongs to Air Products. French media report that the suspected attacker rammed his car into the factory.
10.23
The explosions are believed to have been set off in the factory using gas canisters.
10.20
Hello and welcome to the Telegraph's live coverage of the attack on a French factory where a decapitated body was found nearby.
An attacker carrying an Islamist flag killed one person and injured several others today at a gas factory in eastern France, according to a legal source, AFP reported.
The suspected attacker entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices, the source said.
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minister, said he would go "immediately" to the scene, his office said.
The attack comes six months after the Charlie Hebdo attack and the three-day siege in Paris during which 17 people were killed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:24:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italian grandfather finally completes middle school education - at the age of 91</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf02/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Citaly0C1170A0A7360CItalian0Egrandfather0Efinally0Ecompletes0Emiddle0Eschool0Eeducation0Eat0Ethe0Eage0Eof0E910Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A large family and a hard working life meant he never had time to complete his education</Description>
        <MainBody>Follow
In a case of better late than never, a grandfather in Italy has finished middle school with flying colours at the age of 91.
Nicola Torello, who as a 19-year-old served in the Italian army in Greece during the Second World War, made up for lost time by returning to school in his home town of Chieti in the mountainous Abruzzo region of central Italy.
A large family and a life of hard work as a tailor meant that he never finished his basic education as a child.
Mr Torello, who turns 92 in October, received top marks in his maths exam and even managed to learn some English for an oral test.
He also wrote an essay about his wartime experiences, when he served with an Italian army brigade in Greece.
He said he returned to school in part to help him get over the death of his wife, Licia.
His four children and six grand children turned up at the school to see him awarded his school certificate.
Even the mayor of Chieti came to offer his congratulations.
Buoyed by the success, Mr Torello now wants to learn how to use a computer.
He said he had remained fit and active by swimming twice a week and by continuing to drive a white Fiat 600 around town.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:20:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia attack: deadly shooting in front of tourist beach hotel in Sousse - latest</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf05/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1170A10A430CTunisia0Eattack0Edeadly0Eshooting0Ein0Efront0Eof0Etourist0Ebeach0Ehotel0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 27 dead after gunman opened fire in terrorist attack on popular beach resort in Sousse, Tunisia</Description>
        <MainBody>This page will automatically update every 30 secondsOn Off
 Gunmen killed in shoot-out
 Tourists gunned down on popular beach
 Pictures circulating on social media of bodies on the beach
 Attacks comes as 12 killed in Isil bomb on Kuwait mosque
Latest
13.46
One of the hotels targeted in the attack was the Imperial Marahaba. It's promoted by Thomson Holidays, among others, and has 366 rooms over five floors. It's an all-inclusive resort, described as a "grand beachside hotel".
13.42
Susan Rickett, who was staying at the Palm Marina Hotel near Sousse, said: 'My sister was talking to someone who had seen some people shooting and had shot someone on a sun bed but we don't know if that's true.
'It sounded like a machine gun going off... and there was a kind of explosion a little bit later.
'They're saying its going on in the hotel next to us. Police were chasing some men, that's all I know.'
13.40
The Interior Ministry has just revised the number of dead up to 27. Spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said security forces intervened immediately and killed one of the attackers, while the other fled the scene.
13.22
Another British tourist close to the scene of a deadly attack on a Tunisian beach resort has described his experiences.
Gary Pine said he was on the beach and heard what "we thought was firecrackers going off" 100 yards away, followed by an explosion from the next hotel complex along.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach," he said. He said his son said he had seen someone get shot on the beach.
He said guests at his hotel were first told to lock themselves in their rooms, and later to gather in the lobby.
Tunisia is popular with British tourists. The Foreign Office says 424,707 British nationals visited Tunisia in 2014.
13.22
Tunisia's Interior Ministry says two gunmen opened fire on a beach in the coastal resort of Sousse Friday, killing at least seven people.
Pictures posted on Instagram appeared to shot a couple dead on the beach with a couple dead with gunshot wounds to the head.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
It is one of the North African country's most popular beach resorts, drawing tourists from Europe and neighbouring countries. Tunisia has been high alert since Islamist gunmen attacked the Bardo museum in Tunis in March, killing a group of foreign visitors.
13.24
The body of one gunman lay at the scene with a Kalashnikov assault rifle after he was shot in an exchange of gunfire with police, the source said.
British tourist David Schofield told Sky News that he was by the pool when he heard "quite a large explosion" and guests started to run back towards the hotel. "We heard people saying there were guns on the beach. People were shooting on the beach," he said.
"People are running around the hotel. No-one has really been told what to do."
13.17
At least 27 people have been killed in an attack on a beach hotel in the Tunisian city of Sousse, and at least one gunman has been killed in a shoot-out.
The attack, which took place around 12pm local time, was said to have taken place outside the five-star hotel the Imperial Marhaba hotel.
"The operation was carried out in two hotels. There are seven dead, maybe more," ministry spokesman Mohamed Ali Aroui told Mosaique radio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:18:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Barack Obama came to raise his voice on race</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798cf06/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C116999470CHow0EBarack0EObama0Ecame0Eto0Eraise0Ehis0Evoice0Eon0Erace0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>As Barack Obama speaks in Charleston in the wake of one of the most vile racially motivated attacks in America's history, we look back at his previous remarks on race</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
How Barack Obama came to raise his voice on race
As Barack Obama speaks in Charleston in the wake of one of the most vile    racially motivated attacks in America's history, we look back at his    previous remarks on race
By Peter Foster, and David Lawler in Washington
1:18PM BST 26 Jun 2015
On Friday, President Obama will mourn with the city of Charleston, South Carolina, where nine people were killed last week at a historic black church. He'll deliver a eulogy at the funeral for Rev. Clementa Pinckney, a state lawmaker and pastor of Emanuel African Methodist Church.
Mr Obama made history when he became Americas first black president, but for much of his presidency he has walked a fine line on the contentious issue of race.
Mr Obama was careful to note he would be a president for all Americans and not simply a black president focusing on racial issues.
It was a position he first outlined in his 1995 memoir, Dreams from my Father, in which he wrote: My identity might begin with the fact of my race, but it didn't, couldn't end there. At least that's what I would choose to believe.
Mr Obama was criticised throughout his first term by some more traditional voices in the black community for failing to do more to root out Americas still-endemic racial discrimination.
However following his re-election in 2012 several high-profile incidents, starting with the shooting of the unarmed black teenager Trayvon Martin, have led Mr Obama to engage much more explicitly on the need to tackle Americas racial divide.
Here we chart the evolution of Mr Obamas public statements on the race issue since 2008.
March, 2008: A more perfect Union
In early 2008, during his first presidential campaign, Mr Obama came under fire for his links to the Rev Jeremiah Wright, a fiery black Chicago pastor who had exclaimed God damn America! in a sermon.
With his campaign suddenly reeling, Mr Obama delivered what became known as his more perfect union speech  a speech that is still widely ranked as one of his absolute best.
His message  embodied in his own candidacy and life story - was fundamentally hopeful.
I believe deeply that we cannot solve the challenges of our time unless we solve them together - unless we perfect our union by understanding that we may have different stories, but we hold common hopes; that we may not look the same and we may not have come from the same place, but we all want to move in the same direction - towards a better future for of children and our grandchildren.
July, 2013: Trayvon Martin  could have been my son
After Florida neighbourhood watch captain George Zimmerman was cleared of the murder of the unarmed black teenager Trayvon Martin in July 2013, Mr Obama respected the verdict, but spoke passionately about the black experience in what was widely seen as a departure from his typical language on race issues.
You know, when Trayvon Martin was first shot I said that this could have been my son. Another way of saying that is Trayvon Martin could have been me 35 years ago.... There are very few African American men in this country who haven't had the experience of being followed when they were shopping in a department store. That includes me. There are very few African American men who haven't had the experience of walking across the street and hearing the locks click on the doors of cars. That happens to me -- at least before I was a senator."
August, 2014: Ferguson shooting - "This is an issue for America"
The shooting of Michael Brown, an unarmed black teenager in Ferguson, Missouri prompted outbreaks of violence in cities across America, uniting protestors under the banner of black lives matter.
As the streets of Ferguson burned over the decision by a Grand Jury not to prosecute the officer involved, Mr Obama went on television to appeal for calm, but his lofty remarks were at stark odds with the passions unfolding on the streets.
We need to recognize that this is not just an issue for Ferguson, this is an issue for America. We have made enormous progress in race relations over the course of the past several decades. I've witnessed that in my own life. And to deny that progress I think is to deny Americas capacity for change."
June, 2015: Charleston- 'societies don't change overnight'
After nine people were left dead in a racially motivated attack on a black church in South Carolina, Mr Obama again found hope amid the horror.
The fact that this took place in a black church obviously also raises questions about a dark part of our history. This is not the first time that black churches have been attacked, and we know the hatred across races and faiths pose a particular threat to our democracy and our ideals.The good news is I am confident that the outpouring of unity and strength and fellowship and love across Charleston today, from all races, from all faiths, from all places of worship, indicates the degree to which those old vestiges of hatred can be overcome.
But in an interview more noted for the language he used, Mr Obama acknowledged the depth of the challenge.
It's not just a matter of it not being polite to say n----- in public That's not the measure of whether racism still exists or not. It's not just a matter of overt discrimination. Societies don't, overnight, completely erase everything that happened 200 to 300 years prior."
Barack Obama never pretended he could bring an end to racial prejudice in America. But he has confronted it with growing force in his second term, without abandoning his vision of the more perfect union to come.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:35:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japanese women go ape over 'handsome' gorilla named Shabani</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798a476/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cjapan0C1170A0A4270CJapanese0Ewomen0Ego0Eape0Eover0Ehandsome0Egorilla0Enamed0EShabani0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Japan
Japanese women go ape over 'handsome' gorilla named Shabani
Giant male gorilla Shabani, weighing around 180kg, at the Higashiyama Zoo in Nagoya in Aichi prefecture, central JapanPhoto: AFP/Getty
By Flynn Murphy, Sydney
Comments
An Australian-raised gorilla is winning hearts in Japan where his good-looks have made him a hit with female zoo-goers.
Shabani, a western lowland gorilla born in the Netherlands and raised in a Sydney zoo, is popular for his handsome looks and dramatic poses, with local admirers dubbing him an ikemen, or good-looking man.
Shabani is popular for his handsome looks (AFP/Getty)
The gorilla lives in Higashiyama Zoo and Botanical Gardens in Nagoya, Japan, where he moved in 2007 after spending his formative years at Taronga Zoo on the shores of Sydney Harbour.
And while the 18-year-old has local women enthralled, Shabani may have been a late bloomer.
I have seen quite an early photo of him and he's not the handsome man that he is today, Madeleine Smitham, a media relations officer at Taronga Zoo, told the Telegraph.
Shabani lives in Higashiyama Zoo and Botanical Gardens in Nagoya (AFP/Getty)
He certainly didnt have quite the same following here that he has in Japan.
On Twitter many Japanese women have tweeted praise and pictures of Shabani, Mail Online reported , including one women who wrote: "I went to Higashiyama Zoo. This hot Shabani ikemen was certainly handsome."
Another female visitor shared an image of the zoo with her friends and the caption: "The meeting of going to see the handsome gorilla Shabani... it was a fun holiday."
Shabani arrived at Taronga Zoo as a baby with another silverback, Kibabu, who is now living out his retirement at a zoo on the NSW south coast, explained another staffer, Paul Fahy.
Obviously western lowland gorillas are a critically endangered species, so Tarongas part of a coordinated breeding programme. The decision was made for Shabani to go to Japan as part of the breeding program, which is all about ensuring genetic diversity, Fahy said.
Shabani weighs around 180kg (AFP/Getty)
This is not the first time Shabani has gone viral. There was a video a couple of years ago of him tightrope walking at the zoo in Japan, Fahy said.
Back in Sydney, Shabani may have some competition. Weve now got a young aspiring silverback here now, who we like to think is quite dashing in his own way, Fahy said.
Thats Kibali, a French-born western lowland gorilla.
And in perhaps heartening news for the men of Japan, there is currently no plan to send Kibali overseas.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:17:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China warns Glastonbury organisers after Dalai Lama's invite</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4798a477/sc/11/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Ctibet0C1170A0A90A50CChina0Ewarns0EGlastonbury0Eorganisers0Eafter0EDalai0ELamas0Einvite0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Tibet's spiritual leader has been invited to speak at the festival, much to the ire of China</Description>
        <MainBody>China warns Glastonbury organisers after Dalai Lama's invite
Tibet's spiritual leader has been invited to speak at the festival, much to    the ire of China
China is far from impressed with festival organisers for inviting the Dalai Lama to Glastonbury 2015Photo: Paul Faith/PA
The office of the Dalai Lama said on Thursday that the Dalai Lama would speak at the Glastonbury Festival during his trip to Britain. He is not due to meet any officials.
His Holiness the Dalai Lama is to visit Glastonbury Festival on Sunday http://t.co/Nm8irCL5jx pic.twitter.com/8y8kehepzu
 Glastonbury Festival (@GlastoFest) June 25, 2015
The Dalai Lama is also going to Britain again in September, just ahead of Chinese President Xi Jinping's trip to the country in October. Xi's state visit is the first to Britain in a decade by a Chinese head of state.
Beijing denounces the Dalai Lama as a dangerous separatist who wants an independent Tibet. He denies espousing violence and says he only wants genuine autonomy for his Himalayan homeland.
Foreign Ministry spokesman Lu Kang told a daily news briefing that he was not aware of the details of what the Dalai Lama was doing at the Glastonbury Festival.
Lu said, however, that China's position on the "international scuttling about of the 14th Dalai Lama to serve his political aims" is consistent.
"China resolutely opposes any country, organisation, body or individual giving any kind of platform to the 14th Dalai Lama to engage in anti-China splittist activities," Lu said.
"It's a decision for the festival-goers and the Dalai Lama," A British government source said, when asked about China's caution that inviting him to visit one of Europe's largest music festivals was tantamount to giving him a platform to engage in anti-China activities.
China routinely denounces any country that hosts the Dalai Lama. In 2012, British Prime Minister David Cameron had to put his trip to China on hold after Beijing took offence at him holding a meeting with the Dalai Lama.
China has ruled Tibet with an iron fist since troops "peacefully liberated" the region in 1950. The Dalai Lama fled into exile in India in 1959 after an abortive uprising against Chinese rule.
Representatives of the Nobel Peace laureate held rounds of talks with China until 2010, but formal dialogue has stalled amid leadership changes in Beijing and a crackdown in Tibet.
Organiser Emily Eavis welcomed the announcement (Rex)
 Glastonbury 2015: festival weather
The announcement has been welcomed by Emily Eavis, daughter of Mike, who founded the festival on his farm in Somerset.
"We're honoured to welcome the Dalai Lama to Glastonbury 2015, she said. He will be talking in the Green Fields and exploring the farm this Sunday as part of his trip to the UK.
What a special moment for the Festival!"
The Dalai Lama has visited Britain regularly since walking over the Himalayas into exile from Tibet as the 1959 uprising against Chinese rule was crushed.
However, meeting international leaders - including David Cameron, the prime minister - has become increasingly difficult, as China threatens retaliation against countries that give him a political presence on the world stage.
The Dalai Lama with David Cameron and Nick Clegg
Relations between Britain and Beijing are only just now recovering from a brief meeting at St Pauls Cathedral between the Dalai Lama, Mr Cameron and then deputy prime minister Nick Clegg in 2012.
Instead, he has concentrated on taking his message direct to supporters, including at events like Glastonbury. The Eavis family may now be considering what form Chinese retaliation against Somerset could take.
 Happy Glasto campers prepare for music and mud, in pictures
The Dalai Lama, whose birthday is on July 6, will probably be the oldest act to put in an appearance at Glastonbury - but not by much.
Patti Smith is 68, and Paul Weller 57, while Mick Jagger was almost 70 when he played at Glastonbury in 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:16:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>For sale: Tom Cruise's $59m ski lodge</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753a8/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctravel0Csnowandski0Cpicture0Egalleries0C116983380CFor0Esale0ETom0ECruises0E59m0Eski0Elodge0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Take a look around the Hollywood hero's glamorous ski pad, on the market for a cool $59m</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE...
Hollywood action man Tom Cruise is selling his seven-bedroom, nine-bathroom    luxury ski lodge in Telluride, Colorado. Advertised by a local estate agent    and boasting its own helipad and private airport, as well as money-cant-buy    views of the area's National Forest, let's see what a mere $59,000,000 will    get you.
--
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:25:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Celebrity Sightings: Kimye, Maria Sharapova and Reese Witherspoon</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd3/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Ccelebritynews0C1170A0A60A90CCelebrity0ESightings0EKimye0EMaria0ESharapova0Eand0EReese0EWitherspoon0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Starring: Kimye, Maria Sharapova and Reese Witherspoon</Description>
        <MainBody>Kim Kardashian and hubby Kanye West treated themselves to a fancy meal at Hakassan in London's swanky Mayfair ahead of him headlining the world-famous Glastonbury Festival in rural SomersetPicture: Rex Features

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:25:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pictures of the day: 26 June 2015</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753ad/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Cpicturesoftheday0C1170A0A40A70CPictures0Eof0Ethe0Eday0E260EJune0E20A150Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Today: A handsome gorilla, a flapping flamingo and a Glastonbury hotel</Description>
        <MainBody>A walrus wallows in shallow water off the coast of Svalbard in the ArcticPicture: Franco Banfi/Solent News

Comments are closed on this picture gallery.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:25:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suicide bomber blows up vehicle in Kobane</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd5/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctelegraphtv0C1170A0A7350CSuicide0Ebomber0Eblows0Eup0Evehicle0Ein0EKobane0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Video footage shows bomb exploding on Thursday in Kobane, Syria</Description>
        <MainBody>Suicide bomber blows up vehicle in Kobane
Video footage shows bomb exploding on Thursday in Kobane, Syria
By Sophie Jamieson, video source: APTN
11:25AM BST 26 Jun 2015
CCTV footage captured the moment a suicide bomber blew up a vehicle in Kobane, Syria .
Video from a surveillance camera shows a pick up truck driving down a road before exploding.
The attack came on Thursday as Islamic State forces re-entered Kobane at the Turkish border on Thursday and clashed with Kurdish YPG forces in the town.
At least 146 civilians are believed to have been killed in the latest violence in Kobane and a nearby village, making it the second-biggest massacre by the hardline group in the country, a conflict monitor said on Friday.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:20:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France terror attack in Grenoble - watch live</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd6/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C1170A0A6370CFrance0Eterror0Eattack0Ein0EGrenoble0Ewatch0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Watch live police response after explosions were reportedly heard at a gas factory near Grenoble, eastern France, where one person is believed to be dead and several hurt</Description>
        <MainBody>France
France terror attack in Grenoble - watch live
Watch live police response after explosions were reportedly heard at a gas    factory near Grenoble, eastern France, where one person is believed to be    dead and several hurt
By Telegraph Video, video source APTN
11:20AM BST 26 Jun 2015
An attacker carrying an Islamist flag has killed one person and injured several others today at a gas factory in eastern France , according to a French official.
The suspected attacker is understood to have entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices.
Grenoble attack: Man found beheaded and Islamist flag raised above French factory - latest
Bernard Cazeneuve, the interior minister, said he would go "immediately" to the scene, his office said.
The attack comes six months after the Charlie Hebdo attack and the three-day siege in Paris during which 17 people were killed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:18:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>School students caught selling salt to make lunch taste better</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd7/sc/26/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cfoodanddrink0Cfoodanddrinknews0C1170A0A6620CSchool0Estudents0Ecaught0Eselling0Esalt0Eto0Emake0Elunch0Etaste0Ebetter0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Secondary school pupils in America have been caught selling salt to their classmates to make their school dinners taste nicer</Description>
        <MainBody>Food and Drink News
School students caught selling salt to make lunch taste better
Secondary school pupils in America have been caught selling salt to their    classmates to make their school dinners taste nicer
Under new guidelines, high school students have taken to selling salt to make their lunches taste nicerPhoto: ALAMY
By Saffron Alexander
Comments
Since 2010, the lunches offered to American school students have changed drastically, thanks largely to Michelle Obama's "Let's Move!" childhood obesity initiative and the Healthy, Hunger-Free Kids Act.
Nutritional guidelines now state that students must be offered both fruits and vegetables every day of the week, only fat-free or low-fat milks can be available, and that calories must be limited based on children's ages.
The rules have not gone down well with either school cafeteria workers or students.
 #thanksMichelleObama: disgruntled students tweet photos of their school lunches
Students prefer unhealthy lunches (GETTY)
Now, students at schools in Indiana have been caught bringing salt, pepper and sugar with them to make their lunches taste better. Some have even been caught selling the seasonings to their classmates.
John Payne, president of the Blackford County School Board of Trustees, called for schools to be allowed more flexibility with the nutrition standards set by Congress. "This 'contraband' economy is just one example of many that reinforce the call for flexibility," he said.
"More students bring their lunch, and a few parents even 'check out' their child from campus, taking them to a local fast-food restaurant or home for lunch."
 US school dinner lady fired for handing out free lunches to poor kids
Critics of the rules have also said students are going to class hungry, because they don't like the food they are served and simply throw away the fruits and vegetables.
Todd Rokita told The Indy Star: "From firsthand experience, I can verify that despite the increased federal involvement in the school meals program, many students are still going to class hungry.
"I've stuck my head in a lot of garbage cans lately in school cafeterias and I've seen a lot of that."
Michelle Obama eating one of her healthy lunches with school children (AP)
Despite the criticism, Donna Martin, director of the school nutrition program in Burke County, believes the new rules are affecting her students positively.
 Want to lose weight? Become more right-wing
She told The Indy Star they are "gobbling up their whole-grain biscuits, and fresh Georgia peaches and blueberries.
"We have the opportunity to change a generation. We have an opportunity to raise kids that, when they go into McDonald's, they want a whole wheat hamburger bun."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:02:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Biggest US Spanish-language broadcaster to drop Miss USA pageant over Trump comments</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd8/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1170A0A3920CBiggest0EUS0ESpanish0Elanguage0Ebroadcaster0Eto0Edrop0EMiss0EUSA0Epageant0Eover0ETrump0Ecomments0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The network made the decision after the Republican candidate and businessman suggested Mexican immigrants "bring drugs, crime, [and] they're rapists"</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Biggest US Spanish-language broadcaster to drop Miss USA pageant over Trump comments
The network made the decision after the Republican candidate and businessman    suggested Mexican immigrants "bring drugs, crime, [and] they're rapists"
Donald Trump, co-owner of the Miss Universe Organization, poses with Miss Connecticut Erin Brady in Las Vegas in 2013 Photo: Reuters
By AP
Comments
A Univision network is dropping the Miss USA pageant in a spiralling controversy over comments Donald Trump made recently about Mexican immigrants.
Univision said on Thursday it would pull the plug on its Spanish-language coverage of the pageant July 12 by its UniMas network and the company said it will cut all business ties with the Republican presidential candidate.
It also severed its business relationship with the Miss Universe Organisation, which produces the Miss USA pageant , due to what it called "insulting remarks about Mexican immigrants" by Trump, a part owner of Miss Universe.
During his presidential campaign kick-off speech last week , Trump portrayed immigrants from Mexico as "bringing drugs, they're bringing crime, they're rapists, and some, I assume, are good people".
He also called for building a wall along the southern border of the US. The remarks drew condemnation from the Mexican government as "biased and absurd."
NBC is scheduled to air its own pageant coverage, as it has done since 2003, and has remained silent about the broadcast. But in a statement Thursday, the network sought to separate itself from Trump's remarks.
"Donald Trump's opinions do not represent those of NBC, and we do not agree with his positions on a number of issues, including his recent comments on immigration," NBC said.
Trump is part of another NBC programme, Celebrity Apprentice.
In an interview on Thursday, Trump said his criticism was directed against US politicians, not the Mexican people or government, adding that Univision would be defaulting on its contract if it does not air the pageant and he would take legal action.
 The Trump manifesto
"At Univision, we see first-hand the work ethic, love for family, strong religious values and the important role Mexican immigrants and Mexican-Americans have had and will continue to have in building the future of our country," said the New York-based Univision Communications Inc.
Puerto Rican actress-singer Roselyn Snchez, who was set to co-host the Univision broadcast of Miss USA, announced on Thursday that she was pulling out of the pageant. (AP)
Both co-hosts of the UniMas telecast also pulled out on Thursday, while Colombian singer J Balvin on Wednesday cancelled a planned performance at the pageant.
"The only thing I could do as a person, not only as an artist, but as a Latino that I am, was to cancel my show immediately," he told The Associated Press on Thursday.
Trump said Univision is submitting to pressure from Mexican leaders to punish him for positions he voices as a candidate on the campaign trail.
"They don't want me saying that Mexico is killing the United States in trade and killing the United States at the border," Trump said. "Univision is totally laying down for the Mexican government. ... They want to silence Donald Trump. And Donald Trump can't be silenced. ... I have great respect for Mexico and I love the Mexican people, but my loyalty is to the United States."
Univision declined to comment on Trump's remarks. The company also has the rights to air the Miss Universe pageant.
In an interview scheduled to air on Sunday on Telemundo's Enfoque con Jose Diaz-Balart, Trump said "many bad people are coming in" from Mexico and elsewhere.
"You're going to have terrorists coming through the southern border. There's no question about it," he said.
The host challenged Trump, contending there has been no act of terrorism committed by someone crossing the US-Mexico border.
"You don't know that," Trump replied, adding later: "See what happens tomorrow. See what happens in two weeks from now. You can't say that terrorists, and I'm not even talking about terrorists from this region. I'm talking about from the Middle East they can come in. The border is totally open."
In severing her ties with the Miss USA pageant, Puerto Rican actress Roselyn Sanchez, one of the two co-hosts, cited Trump's comments about immigrants.
"Since I heard Trump's speech, as a Latina I felt a lump in my stomach. 'It's got to be a joke,' I thought," the star of the Lifetime series Devious Maids told The Associated Press.
Chilean actor-producer Cristian de la Fuente, the show's other co-host, had strong words for Trump: "It's a shame that such an important institution as Miss USA is now in the hands of a clown."
Ricky Martin also took to Twitter to criticise Trump. "A lot of hatred and ignorance in his heart," he tweeted.
Mucho odio e ignorancia en tu corazn @realDonaldTrump . #LatinosUnidos
 Ricky Martin (@ricky_martin) June 25, 2015
Miss California USA Natasha Martinez was asked about Trump's comments during an interview on Thursday on Los Angeles TV station KCAL and said they were "a little bit tough to hear."
"But I know that this opportunity for me as Miss California-USA, and now competing for Miss USA, is a great bridge to kind of represent my community and let the world know that I am a proud Latino-American," she said.
This year's UniMas telecast would have been the first in a five-year contract that Trump said "has no termination rights". Univision's wholly owned Spanish-language UniMas network, founded in 2013, is available in 70 million US homes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:36:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Disgusting' FGM campaign wins prestigious advertising awards at Cannes</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47989dd9/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cwomen0Cwomens0Elife0C1169960A30CFGM0EOgilvy0Ecampaign0Ewins0ECannes0ELion0Eawards0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A heavily criticised advertising campaign raising awareness about female genital mutilation has won Cannes Lion industry awards</Description>
        <MainBody>Follow
A heavily criticised campaign against female genital mutilation has won a top advertising award at Cannes.
Ogilvy and Mather London created the advertisements to raise awareness about FGM  a crime where a girl or womans genitalia is cut for cultural reasons  back in April, on behalf of anti-FGM charity 28 Too Many .
The adverts depict flags of western countries  such as the union jack  splattered with blood stains and with thick thread sewing them back together.
A message printed on the flag reads: "Female genital mutilation doesn't only happen in far away places. Over 50,000 girls in the UK are at risk."
The It happens here campaign was designed to raise awareness about the fact that FGM is still carried out in countries like the UK, even though it is illegal.
It attracted outrage from many FGM survivors and campaign groups. But the campaign this week won a Gold and Bronze award at the Cannes Lions  the most prestigious global advertising awards.
One campaigner, who has undergone the barbaric practice herself, said the ad was disgusting and should be taken down immediately.
Nimko Ali, who co-founded anti-FGM charity Daughters of Eve , said: Im shocked they won the award. [The flags are] disgusting.
Its so graphic and we have worked so hard to get the conversation about seeing [FGM] as violence against women and girls, and we need to work within that framework.
Were trying not to stigmatise and traumatise girls but this ad does."
Ali, who underwent FGM as a child, added: I shook when I saw it. It depicts the most invasive form of FGM and its what I had.
I think there are girls out there who will see it and feel the same way. It wont help them.
There are three 'types' of FGM : the partial or total removal of the clitoris; the partial or total removal of the clitoris and labia minora; and narrowing the vaginal orifice by cutting and repositioning the labia. The latter appears to be depicted on the posters.
The End FGM European Network agreed that the It Happens Here campaign could stigmatise FGM and was not helpful to survivors.
A spokesperson told Telegraph Wonder Women: We need campaigns which encourage a discussion around the fact that FGM is a reality in Europe and across the world.
Using images which empower and enhance the dignity of survivors and those at risk is vital to this discussion. Stigmatising imagery can alienate affected communities even more and we need to ensure that they are central to ending FGM.
Cheryl Giovannoni, chief executive officer of Ogilvy and Mather London, responded saying: "It Happens Here is designed to be a hard-hitting and provocative campaign to raise awareness of the horrific abuse suffered by hundreds of thousands of girls every year.
"The bold imagery is intended to shock and reach an audience typically unaware of the issues of FGM. The response to this campaign has been overwhelmingly positive and we hope it continues to raise awareness, and support 28 Too Many in their efforts to end female genital mutilation once and for all."
The charity 28 Too Many was unavailable for comment, but Dr Ann-Marie Wilson, executive director, previously spoke about the campaign, saying:
FGM is not just being performed in Africa, the Middle East and Asia but is taking place here, in Europe, on our very own door steps.
"This emotive campaign visually encompasses the concept that FGM is not an out of sight, out of mind problem but at present a risk to over 60,000 girls in the UK.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:58:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Isil attack on Kobane is 'second biggest massacre' of civilians by the group in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/4797941d/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cislamic0Estate0C1170A0A4530CIsil0Eattack0Eon0EKobane0Eis0Esecond0Ebiggest0Emassacre0Eof0Ecivilians0Eby0Ethe0Egroup0Ein0ESyria0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Islamic State fighters killed 146 civilians in their attack on Kobane and a nearby village on Thursday, Syrian Observatory for Human Rights says</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State
Isil attack on Kobane is 'second biggest massacre' of civilians by the group in Syria
Islamic State fighters killed 146 civilians in their attack on Kobane and    a nearby village on Thursday, Syrian Observatory for Human Rights says
A picture taken from Suruc district of Turkey's Sanliurfa province shows a group of Syrians waiting on the Syrian side of the Turkish border during the clashes between Isil and Kurdish armed groups in Kobani Photo: 2015 Anadolu Agency
By Louisa Loveluck, Cairo
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:21:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japan mourns death of Tama, the train stationmaster cat</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753a1/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cjapan0C1170A0A3720CJapan0Emourns0Edeath0Eof0ETama0Ethe0Etrain0Estationmaster0Ecat0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The calico cat, who was also deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in 2013, has died aged 16</Description>
        <MainBody>Japan
Japan mourns death of Tama, the train stationmaster cat
The calico cat, who was also deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in    2013, has died aged 16
Tama was known as the stationmaster of Kishi station on the Wakayama Electric Railway in the city of KinokawaPhoto: AFP/Getty
By Danielle Demetriou, Tokyo
One of Japans best-loved cats , who won the heart of the nation working as a stationmaster in a rural train station , has died and the funeral will be held this weekend.
Tama, a 16-year-old calico cat, attracted thousands of tourists to tiny Kishi station in Wakayama prefecture after being appointed stationmaster in 2007.
Prior to her arrival, the regional railway line was losing money and the station had lost its last human employee the previous year.
Tama, who famously strolled around the station in her official railway cap uniform, quickly drew crowds of visitors, fuelling a thriving merchandising business and revitalising the local economy.
The cat was credited with boosting the number of people travelling along the Kishigawa Line by 55,000, adding an additional 1.1 billion yen (5.7million) to the local economy.
Tama was promoted to deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in 2013 (AFP/Getty)
The popular felines successes resulted in an award from the prefectural governor of Wakayama in 2008 and a promotion to deputy president of Wakayama Electric Railway in 2013.
Among those mourning her death from heart failure was Yoshinobu Nisaka, who said: Tama won a great popularity at home and abroad as a super star of tourism. At the news of her loss, I express my deep sorrow and great gratitude.
The railway company is planning to hold a funeral at the station this weekend for the late cat, who will reportedly be succeeded by her feline stationmaster apprentice Nitama.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:15:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Unarmed black man fatally shot by Baltimore police after domestic disturbance</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/479753a7/sc/42/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1170A0A370A0CUnarmed0Eblack0Eman0Efatally0Eshot0Eby0EBaltimore0Epolice0Eafter0Edomestic0Edisturbance0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Officers said they shot Spencer Lee McCain believing he had a weapon after being called to a home from which he was barred by court order</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Unarmed black man fatally shot by Baltimore police after domestic disturbance
Officers said they shot Spencer Lee McCain believing he had a weapon after    being called to a home from which he was barred by court order
Baltimore County Police officers at the scene in Owings MillsPhoto: NBC
By AP
9:15AM BST 26 Jun 2015
An unarmed black man was fatally shot on Thursday by officers in suburban Baltimore who thought he had a weapon when they were called to a home from which he was barred by protective order, the police chief said.
The death follows that of a 25-year-old black man, Freddie Gray, who died in April from an injury suffered in the custody of Baltimore city police, which prompted protests and rioting . And it comes amid a national debate over the treatment of African-Americans at the hands of police, after high-profile deaths of black men in Ferguson, Missouri, and New York City.
Spencer Lee McCain, 41, was shot about 1 am at the home in Owings Mills while a woman who said he threatened to beat her and her two young children were there, Baltimore County Police Chief Jim Johnson said at a news conference.
Three officers were on the scene, and all fired as McCain was in a "defensive position" and they thought he had a weapon, Chief Johnson said. But he said no weapon was found.Two of the officers are white, and one is black, police said. All are on administrative leave. Police said the incident began when one of the children in the home called his grandmother, who called 911 and asked police to go there.
An officer who arrived heard screams and called for backup, Chief Johnson said. He said 19 casings were found at the scene, but it wasn't clear how many times McCain was hit.
Police said the woman had head injuries, cuts, bruises and swelling. Chief Johnson said she told detectives that McCain said to her, "You're going to get the beating you deserve."
Sixteen to 20 domestic violence calls had been made to that home address since 2012, police spokesman Cpl. John Wachter said.
According to 2013 census figures, 27.5 percent of Baltimore County's population is black and 64.1 percent is white. The police chief and county executive are white.
As of February, black people made up less than 13 percent of the county's 1,868-member police force.
A medical examiner ruled this week that the death of Freddie Gray was a homicide, after he suffered a "high-energy injury," most likely caused when a Baltimore city police van he was riding in suddenly slowed down. A grand jury indicted six officers on various charges; one officer faces the most serious charge of second-degree "depraved-heart" murder. They have pleaded not guilty.
The report said Gray's death could not be ruled an accident and is instead a homicide because officers didn't follow safety procedures "through acts of omission."
Police and an attorney for the Gray family have said previously that Gray suffered a severe spine injury .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:42:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nine dead after plane crashes in Alaska</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47974dc3/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1170A0A2630CNine0Edead0Eafter0Eplane0Ecrashes0Ein0EAlaska0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Light aircraft carrying holidaymakers on a cruise crashes near Misty Fjords</Description>
        <MainBody>Nine dead after plane crashes in Alaska
Light aircraft carrying holidaymakers on a cruise crashes near Misty Fjords
A DeHavilland Beaver float plane flying the Alaska Coast Range (file photo)Photo:  Alamy
By David Millward , US Correspondent
7:42AM BST 26 Jun 2015
Nine people have been killed after a light aircraft crashed in Alaska , US police said.
The eight passengers were all holidaymakers who had been on a Holland America cruise.
The identity and nationality of those on board the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter single-engine prop plane was not disclosed. The plane crashed near Ketchikan, the Federal Aviation Administration said.
The Holland America Line cruise ship Westerdam sits in dock in Ketchikan, Alaska (AP)
Emergency crews were able to reach the aircraft that crashed against a granite rock face and confirm the deceased, but weather in the fjords prevented recovery efforts, Megan Peters from Alaska's department of public safety said.
"Due to inclement weather, the body recovery effort will not be attempted until tomorrow," she said in a statement.
According to local reports the weather in the region was heavily overcast.
An FAA webcam in Misty Fjords took this image around the time of the crash
The passengers had all been on board the MS Westerdam on an eight-day cruise which had departed from Seattle.
Promech Air confirmed in a statement that the eight passengers and pilot were killed when the plane went down during a tour of the Misty Fjords area near the town of Ketchikan on Thursday afternoon
 Alaska plane crash leaves four dead including infant
"We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those on board the plane and their families," Holland America said in a written statement.
The National Transportation Safety Board said on Twitter it was sending a "go-team" to the crash site to investigate.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:25:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Devoted couple married for 67 years die within two hours of each other</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47965b28/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Caustraliaandthepacific0Cnewzealand0C1170A0A2640CDevoted0Ecouple0Emarried0Efor0E670Eyears0Edie0Ewith0Etwo0Ehours0Eof0Eeach0Eother0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Hugh Nees, 94, died of cancer while his wife Joan, 92, suffered a stroke</Description>
        <MainBody>Devoted couple married for 67 years die within two hours of each other
Hugh Nees, 94,  died of cancer while his wife Joan, 92, suffered a stroke
Hugh and Joan Nees in their home in Paraparaumu, north of Wellington, New Zealand, in April 2014. Photo: Fairfax Media/Getty Images
By Paul Chapman, Wellington
Comments
A devoted couple who were married for 67 years have died of natural causes within two hours of each other, in the same room at a New Zealand rest home.
Family members said Hugh Nees, 94, and his wife Joan, 92, could not bear to spend even a day apart, and had told them they did not want to live without each other.
Mr Nees, who had cancer, died first in the double room they shared at Eldon Lodge rest home in Paraparaumu, north of Wellington. His wife suffered a stroke.
Hugh and Joan Nees on their wedding day
They had moved into the rest home from their house at nearby Waikanae just over two months ago, because of declining health.
Mr Nees was a retired Baptist minister.
 Couple married for 65 years die moments apart
"They were strong Christians and therefore they knew where they were going, and they had no problem about going there," their son Robert Nees said.
He told the New Zealand Herald that his mother would not have known that her husband had preceded her, even though the couple "were in the same room, lying beside each other", surrounded by family.
"Their departure, it's sad but happy. Life wasn't easy for the last little while and that's over, that's all good."
Asked whether they might have had any premonition of their close departure, their son said: "It's so hard to know. It almost seems like it, doesn't it?"
Their daughter Joy Reid said the timing of their deaths was a miracle.
They said they wanted to die together, and I didn't expect it to really happen. It was just perfect for them.
The couple had five children, two of whom died before them.
They also lost a grandson, 31-year-old Nicholas Heyward, who was shot dead by robbers on a motorcycle in Argentina last year.
Mr and Mrs Nees were both keen gardeners and played golf in their younger days.
A service to celebrate their lives will be held on June 30 at the Baptist church in Waikanae.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:33:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia gunman Seifeddine Rezgui captured on video breakdancing</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a47dad/sc/40/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1170A42870CTunisia0Egunman0ESeifeddine0ERezgui0Ecaptured0Eon0Evideo0Ebreakdancing0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A video from 2010 purports to show Tunisia gunman Seifeddine Rezgui breakdancing in a baseball cap almost five years before he murdered 38 people on a beach in Sousse</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia
Tunisia gunman Seifeddine Rezgui captured on video breakdancing
A video from 2010 purports to show Tunisia gunman Seifeddine Rezgui    breakdancing in a baseball cap almost five years before he murdered 38    people on a beach in Sousse
By Telegraph video, video source Facebook/Ezzouhour magique gaafour
2:33PM BST 28 Jun 2015
A video purporting to show Tunisia gunman Seifeddine Rezgui has been circulating on social media.
In the clip, which is around two and a half minutes long, a man believed to be Rezgui is seen breakdancing to techno music.
It was uploaded to Facebook on 28 December 2010, almost five years before Rezgui gunned down 38 people, including 15 British tourists, on a beach in Sousse.
The video is accompanied by the description: "Video of Seif Rezgui made by K.Maher".
According to Sky News, the Facebook group was set up in 2010 by a group of friends interested in rap music and breakdancing.
It has since taken on a more political nature since the Arab Spring.
The video appears to show the former engineering student performing some popular breakdancing moves in various locations.
On Saturday, photographs were obtained by Sky News which showed Seifeddine Rezgui walking along the beach carrying a gun.
(Sky News)
A picture was also released by the Islamic State, who have claimed responsibility for the shooting, of Rezgui sitting grinning, flanked by a pair of Kalashnikovs.
According to Tunisia's Prime Minister, Habib Essid, Rezgui was a 23-year-old student who originally hailed from Gaafour some 50 miles south-west of Tunis.
He had never travelled abroad, Mr Essid said, and was not known by the police to hold extremist views.
"He used to use hair gel and wear the nicest of clothes, and he used to break dancing," the killer's uncle Ali al Rezgui, said.
"He even used to go to competitions and things like that in Tunis, he was well known for that here. He didnt even have a beard, and Ive never seen him with anyone with a beard. We have extremists like that in Gaafour, but never have I seen him with them. Now hes shooting people with a Kalashnikov, its just so confusing."
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:47:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pictures of the day: 7 July 2015</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e5b593/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Cpicturesoftheday0C117220A720CPictures0Eof0Ethe0Eday0E70EJuly0E20A150Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A Stonehenge sunrise, running with bulls and protesting 'nuns'</Description>
        <MainBody>The sun rises over Salisbury Plain as it's light illuminates the mist shrouding Stonehenge in WiltshirePicture: Robin Morrison / SWNS.com

Comments are closed on this picture gallery.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:40:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pamplona running of the bulls: San Fermin Festival begins in Spain, in pictures</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e4df10/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctravel0Cfestivalsandevents0C117224770CPamplona0Erunning0Eof0Ethe0Ebulls0ESan0EFermin0EFestival0Ebegins0Ein0ESpain0Ein0Epictures0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In pics: The annual San Fermin bull-running festival in northern Spain</Description>
        <MainBody>Three    men were gored and 10 others taken to hospital on the first day of    Pamplona's week-long San    Fermin festival in the northern Spanish city where bulls chase runners    in red scarves through the streets
Picture: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez/Getty Images

Comments are closed on this picture gallery.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:36:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Spanish pharmacy wins right to refuse to sell morning after pills</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7d5c5/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cspain0C117235110CSpanish0Epharmacy0Ewins0Eright0Eto0Erefuse0Eto0Esell0Emorning0Eafter0Epills0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Seville pharmacy had been fined 3,000 in 2008 for refusing to sell emergency contraceptive, but Spanish constitutional court overturns decision on appeal</Description>
        <MainBody>Spain
Spanish pharmacy wins right to refuse to sell morning after pills
Seville pharmacy had been fined 3,000 in 2008 for refusing to sell emergency    contraceptive, but Spanish constitutional court overturns decision on appeal
Spanish pharmacies are required by law to provide morning-after pills and condomsPhoto: Alamy
By Guy Hedgecoe, Madrid
1:36PM BST 07 Jul 2015
A Spanish pharmacy that was fined for refusing to sell women morning-after pills has been told that its right to ideological freedom was violated by the sanction.
The regional health authorities of Andalusia, in southern Spain, fined the pharmacy in Seville 3,000 (2,130) in 2008, because it sold neither the emergency contraceptive morning-after pill nor condoms.
Spanish pharmacies are required by law to provide both, with no prescription required.
However, the constitutional court has overturned the decision on appeal.
It took into account the fact that the owners of the pharmacy in question were officially registered as conscientious objectors on issues where they see a professional conflict between the law and their own beliefs.
Apparently drawing a parallel between the morning-after pill and abortion, the court ruled in its sentence that in this case, legally obligating the vendor to sell the product clashed with the concept advocated by [the pharmacist] regarding the right to life.
However, the court upheld the sanction related to the pharmacys refusal to sell condoms, stating that it saw there no conflict of conscience with constitutional relevance.
It was a tight decision by the court, with several magistrates disagreeing with the final ruling.
The judge overseeing the vote, Andres Ollero, admitted that it was a grey area and that he and his colleagues could not be spiritual directors of citizens, instructing them on which areas of their conscience are protected by fundamental rights and which should be forgotten because they are twisted scruples.
Judge Adela Asua voted against the ruling, arguing that rather than protecting beliefs, the courts sentence itself was tainted by ideology. She also warned that it set a dangerous precedent, which could bring ill-fated consequences for our state and our coexistence.
Spain has seen an intense debate over the issue of abortion in recent year. In 2010, the previous, Socialist government introduced a law allowing abortion until the 14th week of pregnancy.
However, last year the current conservative administration proposed only allowing terminations following rape or if the mothers health was in danger, before withdrawing its reform bill in the face of political and social opposition.
Many Spanish doctors avoid performing abortions by declaring themselves ideologically opposed to the operation.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:32:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dozens of witnesses found dead in India multi-million dollar bribery case</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7d5c8/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cindia0C117234180CDozens0Eof0Ewitnesses0Efound0Edead0Ein0EIndia0Emulti0Emillion0Edollar0Ebribery0Ecase0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 36 people connected to fraud case involving alleged exam cheating for government jobs and medical degrees found dead</Description>
        <MainBody>India
Dozens of witnesses found dead in India multi-million dollar bribery case
At least 36 people connected to fraud case involving alleged exam cheating for    government jobs and medical degrees found dead
Indian Youth Congress workers scuffle with police as they protest against Madhya Pradesh Chief Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan against the series of deaths in Madhya Pradesh Professional Examination Board or VYAPAM scam in Bhopal, IndiaPhoto: EPA
By Reuters
1:32PM BST 07 Jul 2015
Dozens of witnesses in a massive fraud case in India surrounding cheating at college and government jobs have been found dead, including four in the past two days.
Investigators say thousands of people got jobs or medical degrees from systematic exam cheating that generated millions of dollars in bribes in the state of Madhya Pradesh.
At least 36 people connected to the case in the state, run by the ruling Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), have died since the scam was first brought to light in 2013. More than 2,000 have been arrested in relation to the scam.
Four more people connected to the case have died since the weekend, just days before a Supreme Court hearing and amid opposition accusations that a regional unit of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's party was protecting the accused.
"They are not arresting the real culprits," said Vivek Tankha, a lawyer representing three whistleblowers who exposed the scam.
The case has become the latest source of discomfort for India's ruling party, already on the defensive over influence trafficking allegations.
Shivraj Singh Chouhan, Chief Minister of Madhya Pradesh state (Reuters)
State chief minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan, a popular BJP leader, denies wrongdoing.
But on Tuesday he buckled to pressure and said the inquiry should be handed to the Central Bureau of Investigation to avoid suspicion of political meddling.
The latest deaths included a national television journalist who began foaming at the mouth soon after interviewing the parents of Namrata Damor, a student who had obtained a college seat as part of the scam and was herself later found dead on train tracks in January 2012. The journalist died in hospital.
In the past few days, a policeman was found hanging from a ceiling fan, a trainee policewoman was found dead in a pond, and the dean of a college involved in the scam was found dead, with a half empty liquor bottle in a hotel room.
Activists from India's opposition Congress party protest, demanding resignation of Shivraj Singh Chouhan (Reuters)
Mr Chouhan denies accusations made by the opposition Congress party that he and other officials benefited from the fraud.
"There are very powerful big people involved in this," said the Congress party's Digvijaya Singh, a former Madhya Pradesh chief minister who wants the case be investigated by federal agents monitored by the Supreme Court.
On Tuesday, the Supreme Court said it would consider his petition along with several other relating to the case, at a hearing on July 9.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:20:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Poland should join euro only after referendum, says president-elect's adviser</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7d5ca/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cpoland0C117233650CPoland0Eshould0Ejoin0Eeuro0Eonly0Eafter0Ereferendum0Esays0Epresident0Eelects0Eadviser0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Poland will fight EU green policies and the decision to stop using a nation's own currency should be decided by the nation, says Krzysztof Szczerski, foreign affairs adviser to president-elect Andrzej Duda</Description>
        <MainBody>Poland
Poland should join euro only after referendum, says president-elect's adviser
Poland will fight EU green policies and the decision to stop using a nation's    own currency should be decided by the nation, says Krzysztof Szczerski,    foreign affairs adviser to president-elect Andrzej Duda
Andrzej Duda was the surprise winner of a presidential election in MayPhoto: Reuters
By Reuters
Comments
Poland should hold a referendum before joining the euro, a senior adviser to its incoming president said, heralding a more cautious approach to European integration from the European Union 's biggest eastern economy.
Krzysztof Szczerski, foreign affairs adviser to president-elect Andrzej Duda , also signalled Poland would resist giving up more sovereignty to Brussels, and said it would fight EU green policies that harm the Polish economy by forcing it to burn less coal.
Poland has been a major beneficiary of EU funds and a supporter of integration, but that is shifting with the rise to prominence of the Law and Justice party, which is allied to the Conservative party of David Cameron.
Law and Justice candidate Mr Duda was the surprise winner of a presidential election in May , and opinion polls show the right-wing party, now in opposition, will form the next government after a parliamentary election in October.
"The decision on ceasing to mint one's own currency must be ... the nation's decision," Mr Szczerski told Reuters in an interview, saying that this required a "direct vote."
"This realistically means that a discussion about introducing the euro in Poland during President Duda's current term is pointless."
Poland has committed itself to joining the eurozone one day, but there is no legal requirement for it to hold a referendum on the issue. Opinion polls show if there was a vote on accession, it would be firmly rejected.
Echoing views expressed by Mr Cameron's government , and Hungary's ruling Fidesz party, Mr Szczerski said the EU should return more powers to national capitals instead of constantly moving towards ever-greater integration.
"The metaphor of European integration being like a bike is well-known: you can only go forward, there is no reverse gear. Which means we're in a conceptual trap," Mr Szczerski said. "In my view, now is the time for common sense to return to Europe."
Carbon emissions are a sticking point between Brussels, which wants to limit greenhouse gases, and Poland, which depends on coal to generate most of its electricity.
Mr Szczerski said Mr Duda's administration will be "more decisive" than its predecessors in blocking moves on emissions which are unfavourable for the Polish economy.
Countering Russian threat
Mr Szczerski signalled the new administration would take an assertive stance on Russia, despite fears among some of Warsaw's Nato allies about antagonising Moscow.
Mr Szczerski said Poland would continue the existing policy of seeking Nato combat bases on its territory, and would aim to build a coalition of central European countries backing that in time for the alliance's 2016 summit in Warsaw.
Russia said deployment of significant Nato forces close to its borders would violate the 1997 Nato-Russia Founding Act.
Mr Szczerski said this agreement needed to be reviewed, as circumstances have made the limits on Nato's military presence in the region "no longer valid".
Poland will also seek stronger bilateral security ties with the United States, ultimately looking to set up permanent, joint US-Polish military bases on Polish territory, he said.
On Ukraine, Szczerski said the new administration would aim to establish visa-free travel for Ukrainians to Poland and will defend Kiev's right to eventually join Nato and the EU, a prospect that Moscow fiercely opposes.
"The (Nato) membership offer is in itself already a very important political instrument," Mr Szczerski said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:01:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Drone drops burgers for the homeless</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7d5cb/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cnewstopics0Chowaboutthat0C117234750CDrone0Edrops0Eburgers0Efor0Ethe0Ehomeless0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Watch this ingenious video of a man who sets up a drone to deliver free hamburgers to the homeless in San Francisco</Description>
        <MainBody>How about that?
Drone drops burgers for the homeless
Watch this ingenious video of a man who sets up a drone to deliver free    hamburgers to the homeless in San Francisco
By Telegraph Video, video source Jukin
1:01PM BST 07 Jul 2015
A man has helped out the homeless by attaching hamburgers to his drone and dropping them on various people around San Francisco.
In the video, the hobbyist flies his drone around the city, looking for people who might be hungry.
The man fixes the detachable burgers to the drone (Jukin)
The burgers fall off the drone with a detachable device.
People below reach out when they see the drone approaching (Jukin)
Watch the video as the drone burgers bring delight for the hungry people below
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:00:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gaza one year on: The two sisters caught in the crossfire of Israel's war with Hamas</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3f5/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Cgaza0C117179640CGaza0Eone0Eyear0Eon0EThe0Etwo0Esisters0Ecaught0Ein0Ethe0Ecrossfire0Eof0EIsraels0Ewar0Ewith0EHamas0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Twelve months after the bloody 50-day Gaza war, the deaths of Hakema and Nadjah Abu Adwan after being identified as 'terrorists' highlights the hazy rules of engagement in the conflict</Description>
        <MainBody>Gaza
Gaza one year on: The two sisters caught in the crossfire of Israel's war with Hamas
Twelve months after the bloody 50-day Gaza war, the deaths of Hakema and    Nadjah Abu Adwan after being identified as 'terrorists' highlights the hazy    rules of engagement in the conflict
Nada Abu Adwan with her nephew EzzatPhoto: Robert Tait/The Telegraph
By Robert Tait , Morabah, Gaza Strip
1:00PM BST 07 Jul 2015
The three women already sensed danger but there was no warning shot or loud explosion to signal the fatal moment was at hand.
Instead a roaring, howling wind followed by billowing white smoke was all that told the Abu Adwan sisters that their lives were in imminent peril.
The Palestinian Bedouin women were walking away from their ramshackle farm along a lonely dirt track beside an orchard in broad daylight when their bucolic surroundings were transformed into a killing zone during last summer's Gaza conflict .
Moments later, two of them were dead after being identified by Israeli commanders as "terrorists" in an episode that highlights question marks over the army's targeting rules in a 50-day conflict that saw more than 2,200 Palestinians killed, along with 73 on Israel's side.
"There was a hot wind, like a storm or a whirlwind," recalled Nada Abu Adwan, 35. "I thought something had happened. I looked back at my two sisters, Hakema and Nadjah, who were about 30 yards behind me, and they seemed OK.
Nada Abu Adwan, sister of Hakema and Nadjah (Robert Tait/The Telegraph)
"I told them that if the Israelis hit once, they will for sure hit again, so I said, let's get on the ground and move. We moved crawling along the ground and stopped next to a big white rose bush. A few moments later, I heard something and saw my leg was bleeding.
"Then I looked back again at my sisters and told them to follow me. But they said no, just go and get us an ambulance. Nadjah was hurt. But both were still alive."
Not for long - although exactly what happened next is unclear.
Whatever the details, Hakema and Nadjah - aged 45 and 30 according to Nada, although their death certificates indicate they may have been older - were found dead hours later, just yards from where their sister left them, crawling under a wire mesh fence, in a vain effort to find help.
By the time other family members and the Red Crescent were able to reach the scene - sealed off for two hours by Israeli tanks - it was too late.
Hakema's body had been blown to pieces while Nadjah's had several wounds, according to their nephew Ezzat, 21, who discovered them close to a locked gate. The gate and a nearby wall show at least 30 small holes apparently caused by bullets or shrapnel. The bodies of two brothers, Khairy and Khaleel Abu Snaima, 18 and 22, were found nearby - killed after they tried to help Hakema and Nadjah, the family believe.
Ezzat stands at the gate where he found the bodies of his aunts Hakema and Nadjah (Robert Tait)
The two women, who were unmarried, eked out a living breeding chickens, sheep and pigeons and growing olives, grapes and figs at an impoverished family farm where they lived a traditional Bedouin pastoral lifestyle along with Nada, another sister, Masua, 39, and their mother Mansura, 79.
They were implicated as "terrorists" after Israeli forces - stationed in the remote area south-east of Rafah in a search for Hamas tunnels - suspected they were military scouts after expressing astonishment at the presence of human beings in an area that had been designated a combat zone and cleared of its inhabitants days earlier.
In fact, the women had returned to the farm close to the Israeli border from a temporary shelter west of Salaheddin Street, Gaza's main north-south road, to feed livestock and collect belongings after mistakenly believing a ceasefire was under way. They were leaving after realising that Israeli forces were still in the area when the missile strike occurred.
As the first anniversary of last summer's bloody 50-day conflict approaches, the July 22 incident - four days after Israel launched a ground invasion - shines a light on military rules of engagement that have already been questioned in a United Nations report and by several Israeli human rights groups.
Last month's UN human rights commission report - which accused both Israel and the Palestinian factions of multiple breaches of international law - specifically urges Israel to provide more details of its "targeting decisions", noting the often lethal targeting of residential homes and the heavy shelling of civilian areas.
The Abu Adwan case is different because it happened in remote countryside, far from population centres.
The women were initially spotted by Israeli look-out teams stationed in three different locations, one of them on the roof of a requisitioned house more than half a mile away.
Commanders ordered an air force strike after first sending a drone to carry out surveillance. The drone operatives "implicated" the sisters after reporting that the footage showed them "with phones, talking, walking", according to testimony revealed in a recent report published by Breaking the Silence , an Israeli veterans soldiers' organisation that scrutinises Israel's military practices.
An army report listed the women as "terrorists", even though soldiers sent to check on the bodies afterwards found that they were unarmed and not carrying mobile phones or other possible scouting equipment such as binoculars.
One soldier quoted in Breaking the Silence's testimony described the implicating of the women as "bulls***", adding pointedly: "They were fired at, so of course they must have been terrorists."
Even troops who justify last summer's military offensive, codenamed Operation Protective Edge, are critical of the procedure followed leading up to the killing.
While none would agree to be interviewed by the Telegraph, at least one soldier involved is understood to believe there was insufficient evidence justifying the strike.
"They could just see a figure running," said one source. "It could have been a goat or a donkey.
"The area of operation was supposed to have been evacuated and was totally empty, so when you see people come into a war zone after three days, it makes you suspicious.
"The soldiers call it the two indications rule. If you have two indications, you have the green light to strike. The first indication is that they were in a war zone where they weren't supposed to be. Second, there was a figure running and the drone saw what it saw. That's the thinking behind it. I didn't think there was enough evidence but under the rules, nobody thought there was something wrong [with what we did]."
Soldiers deployed in the mission to find and destroy Hamas' tunnel network say it was unlike any previous Gaza operation - involving setting up camp in requisitioned houses for several days at a time. One described the fear of encountering Palestinian militants and recalled being inspired by claims from Shin Bet, Israel's domestic intelligence agency, that it had uncovered a Hamas plot to infiltrate by tunnel from Gaza and kill 1,000 Israelis on Rosh Hashanah, the Jewish new year.
None of this is any consolation to the remaining Abu Adwan women, who are marking this week's anniversary of the conflict by preparing to leave a farm that has always been home - fearing they will otherwise be caught up once more in a future conflict.
"We have spent all our lives here but now we have decided to sell everything and leave," said Nada. "We are going to the west of Salaheddin Street. It is too dangerous here." Her sole surviving sister, Masua, weeps as Nadjah describes the family's plight. A year on, Mansura, the women's mother - having suffered a stroke after the deaths of her daughters - still believes they are alive and regularly calls out for them.
Standing at the spot where he found their bodies, Ezzat Abu Adwan smiled wryly at the thought that either of his aunts were "terrorists".
"You've seen the rest of the family, do you think either of these ladies could have been a fighter," he asked a reporter. "They brought me up and everything I remember about them was good. Everywhere I go I still see them in my imagination."
The Telegraph has contacted the Israel Defence Force who said that they are "looking into these cases".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:59:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Images of 7/7 bombings used to promote Tunisia tourism</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7bacc/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctravel0Cdestinations0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C117233960CImages0Eof0E770Ebombings0Eused0Eto0Epromote0ETunisia0Etourism0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A provocative advertising campaign is using images of the 7/7 bombings in London and the 9/11 attacks in New York to encourage tourists to return to Tunisia</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia
Images of 7/7 bombings used to promote Tunisia tourism
A provocative advertising campaign is using images of the 7/7 bombings in    London and the 9/11 attacks in New York to encourage tourists to return to    Tunisia following last month's beach resort massacre
The posters, created by a Tunisian communications firm, aim to rally support behind the north African country Photo:  Selim Ben Hadj Yahia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:32:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US military tests laser cannon to destroy unexploded bombs</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7bace/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cuknews0Cdefence0C117230A890CUS0Emilitary0Etests0Elaser0Ecannon0Eto0Edestroy0Eunexploded0Ebombs0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The high-powered laser will be able to detonate munitions and makeshift bombs at 300 yards</Description>
        <MainBody>US military tests laser cannon to destroy unexploded bombs
The high-powered laser will be able to detonate munitions and makeshift bombs    at 300 yards
By Ben Farmer , Defence Correspondent
12:32PM BST 07 Jul 2015
Follow
The American military is testing a laser cannon mounted on an armoured truck, to clear air fields of unexploded bombs and booby-traps.
The high-powered laser will be able to detonate unexploded ordnance and makeshift bombs at 300 yards. A robotic arm fitted to the vehicle can also dig around bombs and haul up 50lb of earth and debris at a time.
Developers believe the new vehicle will be quicker and safer for clearing areas than more traditional methods such as shooting at unexploded bombs with a heavy machine gun, or sending in bomb disposal experts and their robots.
Col Jeffry Gates, of the US Air Force, told Army Times that using the new Recovery of Airbase Denied by Ordnance (RADBO) vehicle was a lot more reliable than having a bullet bounce off it.
A weapons operator aims and fires the 3KW laser with a games console-style controller.
"Once you have an idea where these targets are ... you can sit in one location and pretty much cook off dozens of these without even having to move the vehicle, without having to get out of the vehicle," Col Gates said. "I think that'll be a huge savings in time."
Up to 15 vehicles could be ready for use as early as 2017. The RADBO is made from modified Cougar armoured trucks that were rushed into service to protect troops in Afghanistan and Iraq from roadside bombs.
Hundreds of millions of pounds is being poured into developing laser weapons across the US military.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:59:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vain fugitive requests new mugshot from police via Facebook in Australia</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3ea/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Caustraliaandthepacific0Caustralia0C11722630A0CVain0Efugitive0Erequests0Enew0Emugshot0Efrom0Epolice0Evia0EFacebook0Ein0EAustralia0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Daniel Damon, wanted for failing to answer bail, criticised the mugshot used by police appealing for information on his whereabouts</Description>
        <MainBody>Australia
Vain fugitive requests new mugshot from police via Facebook in Australia
Daniel Damon, wanted for failing to answer bail, criticised the mugshot used    by police appealing for information on his whereabouts
Wanted notice for Daniel DamonPhoto: Victoria Police
Follow
A wanted Australian man has contacted police to request they use a "better" mugshot in their appeal for information about his whereabouts.
Daniel Damon, wanted for not answering bail for traffic and drug matters, contacted Victoria Police via Facebook to ask if they could use a "better photo".
His strange request comes after the force put out an appeal on Monday via the social networking website to locate Mr Damon.
You better come down to the station house
Mr Damon, 25, replied soon after asking: "Can you use a better photo tho. This is a horrible mugshot."
"Hi Daniel, please visit your nearest police station and we'll arrange for a new photo to be taken!" the force replied.
Not letting his request be the last word, the wanted man told the police he would attend the police station once he had found a lawyer and "organised" himself.
"Yea I plan on it once I get a few things in order... just gotta organise myself a lawyer and get everything organised."
It is believed that Daniel may be living in St Kilda.
The police appeared to have users on their side after more than 1,200 likes on the comment compared with nearly 800 for Mr Damon's cheeky reply on Tuesday morning.
Although many users appeared amused by the situation, many also criticised Mr Damon.
"Smart***! Hope they catch you...," said Laura Moore.
Earlier on Tuesday, Melissa Seach told the BBC Mr Damon had yet to show up at a police station.
She explained how social media had sometimes yielded positive results for the police as part of their investigations.
"This may encourage someone that may know him to call us and provide information anonymously to crime stoppers," she said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:48:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Celebrity Sightings: Kendall Jenner, Pippa Middleton and Emily Blunt</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3ed/sc/19/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Ccelebritynews0C1172320A30CCelebrity0ESightings0EKendall0EJenner0EPippa0EMiddleton0Eand0EEmily0EBlunt0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Starring: Kendall Jenner, Pippa Middleton and Emily Blunt</Description>
        <MainBody>Kendall Jenner and Karl Lagerfeld at the Autumn Winter 2015 Chanel show at Haute Couture Paris Fashion Week... Others included in the show were...Picture: Rex

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:20:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>2,120-passenger cruise ship to be based in Cuba</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3ef/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctravel0Ccruises0Ccruise0Enews0C117230A790C2120A0Epassenger0Ecruise0Eship0Eto0Ebe0Ebased0Ein0ECuba0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MSC Opera will become the largest ship based in Cuba when it moves there this winter</Description>
        <MainBody>Comments
MSC Cruises has announced plans to base a 2,120-passenger ship in Havana, Cuba .
The company will become the largest cruise line to offer sailings from the Caribbean island, offering one-week voyages from the capital on board MSC Opera, starting on December 22 and concluding on April 12, 2016. They will include two nights in Havana, with shore excursions offered by Cubanacan, a local travel firm. Their itineraries will also feature Montego Bay, Jamaica; Cozumel, Mexico; and Georgetown in the Cayman Islands.
Fly-cruise packages will be available to passengers in Spain, France, Italy, Germany, Canada, Brazil and Argentina, the company said. MSC Operas original winter schedule, featuring the Canary Islands, Madeira and Morocco, has been cancelled  all of those affected will be offered a refund or a new holiday.
The largest cruise ship currently based in Cuba is the 1,200-capacity Celestyal Cristal, which is operated by the Canadian company Cuba Cruise from the island each winter.
Several cruise lines, such as Thomson, Saga, Fred Olsen, Swan Hellenic and Noble Caledonia, include stops in Cuba in their Caribbean itineraries.
The move further highlights the growing popularity of the country following the easing of trade and travel restrictions with the United States earlier this year.
A vintage car in Havana Photo: AP/FOTOLIA
Barack Obama recently announced that the US Embassy in Havana would soon reopen, more than 50 years after the US and Cuba broke off diplomatic relations.
Many have predicted that Cuba could be transformed by the changes , with greater investment leading to improved infrastructure, new buildings and hotels, more American tourists and fewer vintage cars, and many have reportedly been rushing to visit the island before it loses its traditional character.
Fred Mawer, Telegraph Travels Caribbean expert, describes Cuba as a heady mix of faded Spanish colonial cities, sputtering Fifties Cadillacs, wonderful live music, world-class cigars and an arcane communist system.
Cuba is renowned for its cigars Photo: AP/FOTOLIA
On the downside, he adds. Often things dont work as they should or go to plan, and the service in hotels and the food, though improving, are not on a par with other Caribbean destinations.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:03:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greeks remain surprisingly optimistic over prospects of new deal</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3f1/sc/25/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cgreece0C117228390CGreeks0Eremain0Esurprisingly0Eoptimistic0Eover0Eprospects0Eof0Enew0EEU0Edeal0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>With their PM headed to Brussels for emergency talks, a large proportion of the Greek population is confident that an accord will be hammered out</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece
Greeks remain surprisingly optimistic over prospects of new deal
With their PM headed to Brussels for emergency talks, a large proportion of    the Greek population is confident that an accord will be hammered out
Greeks celebrate the 'No' votePhoto: Christopher Furlong/Gety Images
Follow
As Alexis Tsipras heads to Brussels to try to restart talks with Greece s exasperated creditors, many Greeks remain surprisingly optimistic about the chances of a new deal being forged , despite grave warnings from Berlin and Brussels that patience has been exhausted and no further concessions will be offered.
 Greece crisis: Latest updates live
In spite of clear indications that the Germans, in particular, have had enough of Mr Tsipras brinkmanship, a large proportion of the Greek population is confident that an accord will be hammered out and Greece will not be abandoned.
They say that Sundays referendum, in which nearly 62 per cent of voters opted to reject more austerity measures for a fresh bail-out, strengthened their prime ministers hand and reinforced his mandate.
We are now in a stronger position to fight with Europe for a deal, said Marios, 29, a newspaper kiosk owner in central Athens who declined to give his surname.
I accept that we must pay our debts, but we must have our human rights as well. We cant pay tomorrow. The economy has to start growing again  if we dont make money, we cant pay the debt.
But there are others who fear that European leaders will finally call Mr Tsipras bluff and tell Greece that it would be better off outside the euro zone.
The divergence of opinions is splitting families, couples and business partners.
In a traditional barbers shop in Athens historic district of Plaka, a jumble of streets beneath the Acropolis, hairdresser George Panaiotaras, 80, believes Mr Tsipras will come back from Brussels with a deal.
George Kollaros, left, and his colleague George Panaiotaras, in their barbers' shop in Plaka, near the Acropolis (NICK SQUIRES)
Hes very strong and I think he will fight on behalf of us Greeks, he said, cutting a customers hair amid jars of Brylcreem and pomade.
But his boss, George Kollaros, also 80, thinks Mr Tsipras has played entirely the wrong game since being elected in January, unnecessarily antagonising Greeces lenders and setting the stage for a disastrous confrontation that could see the country reverting to the drachma.
Vagelis Charatsis, 52, a stockbroker, believes the radical Leftist Syriza government will struggle to find sympathy from the rest of Europe.
The trust between the negotiating partners has been badly damaged and I dont know whether it can be repaired, he said.
Tspiras will demand some renegotiation of our debt. But Im afraid that if the hardliners in Europe win, they will tell him to take the existing deal or face an exit from the euro. I think the possibility of a Grexit has increased substantially.
Senior citizens talk to bank staff as they queue up to collect their pensions outside a National Bank of Greece branch in Kotzia Square in Athens (GETTY)
Analysts agree with him. Fitch, the credit ratings agency Fitch, said the victory for the No camp in Sundays referendum "dramatically increases" the risk of the country leaving the euro zone. The agency said a deal was still possible, but that time was running out.
Jeroen Dijsselbloem, the euro zones top official, said he wanted Greece to remain in the euro zone, but warned: There are no easy solutions."
Germany, meanwhile, reiterated that it will not contemplate debt restructuring until the Greeks present a package of credible reforms and budgetary cuts.
"Our position is well-known ... a debt cut is not an issue for us," said Martin Jaeger, a spokesman for the German finance ministry.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:01:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russell Brand confronted by friend of Tunisia victims</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3f2/sc/6/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C117230A220CRussell0EBrand0Econfronted0Eby0Efriend0Eof0ETunisia0Evictims0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Russell Brand asked to explain his stance on the minute's silence for those killed in Tunisia by a man who lost two friends in the attack</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia
Russell Brand confronted by friend of Tunisia victims
Russell Brand asked to explain his stance on the minute's silence for those    killed in Tunisia by a man who lost two friends in the attack
Russell Brand was forced to defend his position on the one minute's silence for the victims of the Tunisia beach massacre by a man who lost two friends in the attack.
The comedian previously described last week's silence as "absolute bull****".
Confronted by van-driver Rob, Brand repeated his argument that the government is hypocritical to honour the Sousse victims at the same time as engaging in the arms trade.
Rob questions Russell Brand on his controversial Tunisia comments (YouTube / Russell Brand)
In an encounter broadcast on the comic's YouTube channel , Rob, who knew Adrian and Patrick Evans , says: "I just wanted to ask you a question, what you meant behind your comments regarding the minute's silence."
Brand then responds with a lengthy diatribe about government policy, saying: "Our government's got loads of countries, it has a human rights abusers list, where it says these countries are dangerous countries, you shouldn't go there, they're dodgy, there's dangerous terrorists there.
"And then our actual government helps arms companies to sell weaponry to those countries."
Russell Brand pontificates on government policy (YouTube / Russell Brand)
By the end of the video, Rob seems to have come round to Brand's point of view.
Asked by Brand what he thinks of his argument, Rob says: "I agree, with the government funding the terrorists with the arms and all that, but they sweep all that under the carpet don't they?"
Watch the exchange in the video above.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:00:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bill Cosby admitted buying drugs to give women for sex</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e34fcb/sc/17/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Ccelebritynews0C117223880CBill0ECosby0Eadmitted0Ebuying0Edrugs0Eto0Egive0Ewomen0Efor0Esex0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Court documents show actor and comedian obtained sedatives to give to women he wanted to have sex with</Description>
        <MainBody>Celebrity news
Bill Cosby admitted buying drugs to give women for sex
Court documents show actor and comedian obtained sedatives to give to women he    wanted to have sex with
By AP, video source ITN
11:00AM BST 07 Jul 2015
American actor and comedian Bill Cosby admitted in 2005 that he obtained drugs with the intent of giving them to young women he wanted to have sex with, and that he gave quaaludes, a sedative, to at least one woman and "other people".
That woman and a second woman testified in the same case that they knowingly took quaaludes from him, according to the unsealed documents.
The Associated Press had gone to court to compel the release of the documents from the deposition in a sexual abuse lawsuit filed by former Temple University employee Andrea Constand  the first of a series of sexual abuse lawsuits against him . Cosby's lawyers had objected on the grounds that it would embarrass their client.
Cosby, who is best known for playing Dr. Cliff Huxtable on the hit TV series "The Cosby Show" in the 1980s and '90s, settled that lawsuit under confidential terms in 2006. His lawyers in the Philadelphia case did not immediately return phone calls on Monday. Ms Constand consented to be identified but did not want to comment, her lawyer said on Monday.
Cosby's lawyers did not want the documents made public
Cosby, 77, has been accused by more than two dozen women of sexual misconduct , including allegations by many that he drugged and raped them in incidents dating back decades. Cosby has never been criminally charged, and most of the accusations are barred by statutes of limitations, but his career has suffered in the past year with TV projects and live shows being cancelled. He also stepped down last year from the board of trustees at Temple University, his alma mater.
A representative for Cosby did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Monday.
The new documents show that Cosby, giving sworn testimony in the lawsuit accusing him of sexually assaulting Ms Constand at his home in Pennsylvania in 2005, said he got seven quaalude prescriptions in the 1970s. The lawyer for Ms Constand asked if he had kept the sedatives through the 1990s  after they were banned  but was frustrated by objections from Cosby's lawyer.
"When you got the quaaludes, was it in your mind that you were going to use these quaaludes for young women that you wanted to have sex with?" lawyer Dolores M. Troiani asked.
"Yes," Cosby answered on Sept 29, 2005.
"Did you ever give any of these young women the quaaludes without their knowledge?"
Cosby's lawyer again objected, leading Ms Troiani to petition the federal judge to force Cosby to cooperate.
Cosby later said he gave Constand three half-pills of Benadryl, although Ms Troiani in the documents voices doubt that was the drug involved. The two other women who testified on Ms Constand's behalf said they had knowingly been given quaaludes.
Cosby had fought efforts to unseal the testimony, with his lawyer arguing the deposition could reveal details of Cosby's marriage, sex life and prescription drug use.
"It would be terribly embarrassing for this material to come out," lawyer George M. Gowen III argued in June. He said the public should not have access to what Cosby was forced to say as he answered questions under oath from the accuser's lawyer nearly a decade ago.
"Frankly ... it would embarrass him, (and) it would also prejudice him in eyes of the jury pool in Massachusetts," Mr Gowen said.
US District Judge Eduardo Robreno asked last month why Cosby was fighting the release of his sworn testimony, given that the accusations in the Temple woman's lawsuit were already in the public eye.
"Why would he be embarrassed by his own version of the facts?" Judge Robreno said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:22:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nick Kyrgios accuses Olympic great Dawn Fraser of being a 'blatant racist'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e6d0a6/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Caustraliaandthepacific0Caustralia0C1172250A50CNick0EKyrgios0Eaccuses0EOlympic0Egreat0EDawn0EFraser0Eof0Ebeing0Ea0Eblatant0Eracist0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Fraser said tennis players should set a better example to young Australians or go back to where their parents came from</Description>
        <MainBody>Australia
Nick Kyrgios accuses Olympic great Dawn Fraser of being a 'blatant racist'
Fraser said tennis players should set a better example to young Australians or    go back to where their parents came from
By Flynn Murphy, Sydney, video source APTN
10:22AM BST 07 Jul 2015
Australian tennis player Nick Kyrgios has accused Olympic great Dawn Fraser of being a "blatant racist" after the former champion swimmer said tennis players should "go back to where their parents came from" if they did not set a better example to Australian youth.
Four-time Olympic gold medallist Dawn Fraser criticised Kyrgios behaviour during his fourth-round defeat by Frenchman Richard Gasquet in a local breakfast television interview.
Fraser, who has been one of Australia's best known sporting figures since she won the 100 metres freestyle at three successive Olympic Games from 1956 to 1964, accused Kyrgios of tanking in his final Wimbledon match, saying: Its absolutely disgusting. I am so shocked to think that he went out there to play and he tanked  thats terrible."
Fraser then said 20-year-old Kyrgios and fellow Aussie top seed Bernard Tomic - who at the weekend used a post-match press conference to attack Australia's tennis body - should be "setting a better example for the younger generation of this great country of ours" .
She added: "If they dont like it go back to where their fathers or their parents come from.
Kyrgios returned fire, accusing the 77-year-old of being a blatant racist.
"Throwing a racket, brat. Debating the rules, disrespectful. Frustrated when competing, spoilt. Showing emotion, arrogant. Blatant racist, Australian legend, Kyrgios posted on Facebook on Tuesday.
Throwing a racket, brat. Debating the rules, disrespectful. Frustrated when competing, spoilt. Showing emotion,...
Posted by Nick Kyrgios on Monday, 6 July 2015
The 26th seed was jeered by the crowd when he appeared to make no effort to return serves in the third game of the second set of Monday's match.
He has previously been penalised for swearing and for throwing a racket with such force that it bounced into the air and narrowly missed a spectator.
Kyrgios' mother Nill accused Fraser of a "nasty racist attack", tweeting that she was "out of line".
I have no comments on Dawn Frasers nasty racist attack...but she is out of line. #unaustralianbehaviour
 nill kyrgios (@nillkyrgios) July 7, 2015
But Fraser later stood by the tirade claiming she was not a racist person.
"I said, 'If they don't want to be Australians then maybe they should go back to the country where their parents come from'. That's not being racist," she told Fairfax Media.
"I can see it being interpreted that way ... but it wasn't intended that way."
Kyrgios, who was born and raised in Canberra, has a Greek-born father and a Malaysia-born mother.
Late on Tuesday afternoon Fraser issued a statement apologising for the controversial comments, and saying she had been taken out of context.
"I want to unreservedly apologise for any comments that I made this morning which may have caused [offence] to my fellow Australians including Nick and his family," Fraser said in a statement.
"My intended message, which was not delivered as articulately as it could have been, was on a purely sporting level rather than meant as an attack on Nick's ethnicity."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:56:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Briton among three gored by bulls in Pamplona</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e5b58f/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cspain0C117225910CMan0Egored0Eby0Ebull0Eamong0Eseven0Erushed0Eto0Ehospital0Ein0EPamplona0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Start of annual Running of the Bulls festival in Spain on Tuesday sees 13 people taken to hosptial</Description>
        <MainBody>Spain
Briton among three gored by bulls in Pamplona
Start of annual Running of the Bulls festival in Spain on Tuesday sees 13    people taken to hosptial
A Jandilla bull charges at a participant during the first "encierro" (bull-run) Photo: ANDER GILLENEA/AFP/Getty Images
By Our Foreign Staff
9:56AM BST 07 Jul 2015
Three men including one Briton were gored on Tuesday at the start of the annual Running of the Bulls festival in Spain .
The British man, 30, was gored "between the anus and genitals", a local government official said. His injuries were not thought to be life-threatening.
Another man was gored in the chest near the famous Mercaderes corner on the half-mile course, and was in a stable condition, a doctor at the event said.
Ten others were taken to hospital with injuries, including at least six who fell as they were chased down by bulls in the streets of Pamplona.
A Jandilla bull leaves a participant after charging at him (AFP/Getty)
Red Cross workers were pictured taking several bloodied runners away on stretchers.
The run lasted 2 minutes and 23 seconds.
Tuesday's run included six bulls from the Jandilla ranch in the rural western region of Extremadura, known for the ferocity of its bulls.
It was the first of the eight morning runs that form the highlight of the annual festival - known as San Fermin in Spanish.
The bulls took two minutes and 23 seconds to complete the course through the cobbled streets of Pamplona's old town.
A steer jumps over a fallen runner (Reuters)
Fifteen people have been killed at the annual festival, made famous by 1926 Ernest Hemingway novel 'The Sun Also Rises', since records began in 1911.
The most recent death was in 2009 when 27-year-old Daniel Jimeno, from Madrid, was gored in the neck by a bull called Capuchino.
Several foreigners, from Australians to Americans through to Brits and Irish, are normally among the injured .
Virtually all the revellers wear red and white during the festival.
A spokesman for the hospital to which Tuesday morning's injured were taken said: "We have one person who has been gored in the chest, who is stable and will be operated on.
"The others have suffered facial traumas or injuries to arms and legs."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:48:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al-Shabaab gunmen kill Kenyan workers in their sleep</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e5b591/sc/40/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ckenya0C117226890CAl0EShabaab0Egunmen0Ekill0EKenyan0Eworkers0Ein0Etheir0Esleep0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 14 quarry workers killed as they slept in northeast Kenya in attack claimed by Somalia-based Islamic militant group</Description>
        <MainBody>Kenya
Al-Shabaab gunmen kill Kenyan workers in their sleep
At least 14 quarry workers killed as they slept in northeast Kenya in attack    claimed by Somalia-based Islamic militant group
Kenya Red Cross officials help a mourner at Nairobi City mortuary after Al-Shabaab gunmen slaughtered 36 people in a quarry near Mandera in 2014. The terror group have struck the area again, killing at least 14 quarry workers in their sleep.Photo: AFP/Getty
By Reuters
9:48AM BST 07 Jul 2015
Al-Shabaab gunmen killed at least 14 quarry workers as they slept in an overnight attack in northeast Kenya.
The Somalia-based Islamic militant group claimed responsibility for the assault on a residential complex in Mandera town, saying in a statement it had killed "more than 10 Christians".
"We are behind the Mandera attack. We killed over 10 Kenyan Christians," Sheikh Abdiasis Abu Musab, the group's military operations spokesman, told Reuters. "This is part of our ongoing operations against Kenya."
Al-Shabaab has in the past carried out similar attacks, including one in December in the same county in which 36 quarry workers were killed.
"The area they attacked is a plot where quarry workers live. They attacked at around 1 am. Most of those killed are workers from upcountry. In total 14 people are dead," Alex Nkoyo, commissioner for Mandera county, told Reuters by telephone.
Abbas Gullet, secretary general of Kenya Red Cross, said the workers were attacked as they slept.
Mr Nkoyo said that among the dead was a woman who had tried to plead with the gunmen before being shot.
Al-Shabaab, which aims to topple Somalia's government and impose its own strict version of Islamic law, has carried out frequent attacks in Kenya in recent years to try to force Nairobi to pull its troops out of Somalia, where they are part of an African Union peacekeeping mission.
In the most deadly, the group killed 148 people at a university in eastern Kenya's Garissa County in April.
At least 11 people were also wounded in Tuesday's assault, Gullet told Citizen Television.
Edited for Telegraph.co.uk by Andrew Marszal
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:25:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant dies in Channel Tunnel trying to reach Britain, say French authorities</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e5b596/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C117227130CMigrant0Edies0Ein0EChannel0ETunnel0Eto0EBritain0Esay0EFrench0Eauthorities0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The news agency AFP reports a migrant has died trying to reach Britain through the Channel Tunnel</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrant dies in Channel Tunnel trying to reach Britain, say French authorities
The news agency AFP reports a migrant has died trying to reach Britain through    the Channel Tunnel
A migrant has died on a freight shuttle trying to reach BritainPhoto: AFP
By Henry Samuel , Paris and agencies
9:25AM BST 07 Jul 2015
Follow
A migrant died on Tuesday trying to reach Britain through the Channel Tunnel, French authorities in the Pas-de-Calais region have confirmed.
One of the six sections of the tunnel was closed for investigation, but train traffic had not stopped. It was as yet unclear how the migrant died.
Following the detection of migrants on a freight shuttle early this morning, the shuttle was immediately stopped, said the Pas-de-Calais prefecture, the local state authority.
During a security inspection by border police, a deceased migrant was found in the tunnel, it said in a statement.
Gilles Debove, of the police union Unit SGP-Police FO, said: "Around 400 migrants arrived and besieged the tunnel, as they do almost every night. One managed to board a freight shuttle and unfortunately fell off, losing his life."
Eurostar announced that "trains are subject to delays" in another tweet without further detail, while Eurotunnel said the shuttle on which the incident took place had now left the tunnel on the French side.
Update: Trains are subject to delays this morning due to the closure of a section of the Eurotunnel.
 Eurostar UK (@EurostarUK) July 7, 2015
Last month, a 26-year old Eritrean migrant was killed on the French side of the Channel Tunnel after trying to board a moving freight train. He was thrown off and collided with a concrete pylon.
Days later, a female migrant was found dead on the A16 motorway after being crushed by a vehicle.
Confirmation that due to migrants found on freight shuttle, we expect delays to Passenger service of 3hrs from UK &amp; 60mins from France. ^LE
 Eurotunnel LeShuttle (@LeShuttle) July 7, 2015
Local police have warned that migrants are now breaking into restricted areas on the French side of the Eurotunnel terminal almost nightly.
A Eurotunnel spokesman said: "Services are partly suspended, and the disruption is principally affecting freight services. Passenger services are running with slight delays.
"We are working very hard to restore full services as soon as possible."
The incident comes days after around 150 migrants caused delays and cancellations when they tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.
There have been increased calls for a resolution to the migrant crisis in Calais.
Kent Police said delays were building around junction 11a of the M20, where lorries are queued as part of Operation Stack when cross-Channel services hit disruption.
The migrant crisis in Calais has escalated in recent months , with around 3,000 people displaced from countries including Eritrea, Syria and Afghanistan setting up camp near the port.
Last week more than 3,000 truckers had to queue for several days in high temperatures on the M20 following a wildcat strike by ferry workers in France.
Industrial action by ferry workers this summer has come on top of the problems faced by hauliers with migrants desperately trying to clamber on board their HGVs to the UK .
French authorities have faced claims they are not doing enough to safeguard lorry drivers from intimidation, violence and attempts by migrants to climb on.
The Road Haulage Association (RHA) has suggested deployment of the French military to boost security in Calais amid fears that a fatality could occur.
The Fresh Produce Consortium estimates that 10 million of fresh fruit and vegetables have been thrown away since the start of the year as a result of the problems in Calais.
And Port of Dover officials said last week's ferry strike cost the UK economy 1 billion.
They have joined calls for "robust contingency plans" to be introduced to ensure the port - a 100 billion trade route - can work unimpeded by others.
Home Secretary Theresa May and her French counterpart Bernard Cazeneuve last week agreed to increase the joint intervention fund to improve security around the port and the Channel Tunnel.
French aid workers have reported a "catastrophic" situation, with predictions that 2,000 more migrants could arrive over the summer at the camp, dubbed Jungle II.
Volunteers from L'Auberge Des Migrants say up to 50 new migrants are arriving every day at the camp, and there are not enough tents, blankets or food.
Dover Conservative MP Charlie Elphicke has said the problems underlined the need to consider expanding the port at Dunkirk, 45 miles from Calais.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:45:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>We must not allow a few fanatics ruin this fledgling democracy</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47a1754d/sc/15/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C1170A37550CWe0Emust0Enot0Eallow0Ea0Efew0Efanatics0Eruin0Ethis0Efledgling0Edemocracy0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US and Europe must without delay help Tunisia make a successful transition and stay the course of moderation, says Diana Darke</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia
We must not allow a few fanatics ruin this fledgling democracy
US and Europe must without delay help Tunisia make a successful transition and    stay the course of moderation, says Diana Darke
A floral tribute lies on the beach in Tunisia where 38 tourists were murdered by terroristsPhoto: Jeff J. Mitchell/Getty Images
By Diana Darke
9:45PM BST 27 Jun 2015
As Tunisia agonises over whether Fridays horrific attack on western sunbathers at the Port El-Kantoui resort could have been avoided and as ISIS claims responsibility for the attack, much of the blame will inevitably turn to blow-back from the 3000 Tunisian fighters who left to join ISIS in Syria, Iraq and Libya.
Out of Tunisias population of over 11 million, these radicalised fighters represent a tiny albeit highly destructive fraction, who must not be allowed to destabilise the entire country. There is too much at stake.
Four months ago deep in the Tunisian desert I chanced upon Tunisias version of Glastonbury, Les Dunes Electroniques, a three-day festival of world music, where over 7000 Tunisian and foreign guests danced into the night in the vast open spaces of the Sahara. Parts of the original Star Wars film were shot here.
February in the desert can have its surprises, and this years ravers had their commitment levels tested to the full, not by an ISIS attack, but by torrential rain turning the sand into muddy rivers, forcing cancellations as water and electronics mixed.
Spirits undampened, Tunisias young at heart padded good-naturedly through puddles wearing plastic bags on their feet.
They also enlivened the spirits of the hoteliers, restaurateurs and shop-owners of the region, for whom the drop in tourism over the last four years has been hard.
Tunisians have a uniquely tolerant Islamic heritage.
Most are moderate Sunni Muslims and many have a natural affinity with mystical Islam or Sufism.
In the heart of Tunis stands a statue of the figure who embodies this, himself a Sufi - Ibn Khaldun, the worlds first sociologist philosopher.
Born there in 1332, he stands with his back to the historic old medina, gazing out to the new city and beyond towards the sea.
In modern Tunisia this heritage was personified by the Sufi poet/novelist Abdelwahab Meddeb (1946-2014).
His landmark work La Maladie dIslam (2002) explained: If, according to Voltaire, intolerance was Catholicisms sickness, if Nazism was Germanys sickness, fundamentalism is Islams sickness.
He wrote over 30 books advocating an Islam of Enlightenment and a dialogue between civilisations.
But when battling against fundamentalism, how do you get the balance right? How do you protect your citizens without also infringing their human rights? This is the question which faces us all in countries where freedom and democracy are valued.
Full protection for Tunisias Mediterranean beaches, lined as they are by strings of contiguous hotels  some reports say the attackers arrived by boat  can never be guaranteed, just as Londons British
Museum for example, could never be fully protected against random suicide bombers.
Rigorous airport-style security checks are dificult to put in place, leaving the priceless statues of the worlds cultural heritage, seen as idols by ISIS, an easy target.
Tunisias secularist government took the difficult path, the costly path, to aim for western-style freedom and democracy.
After the Bardo Museum massacre which left 24 dead on 18 March, their Cabinet proposed new anti-terrorism laws, seeking to enhance the powers of the security services and extend the period police can detain suspects from six to 15 days before they appear in court.
Human Rights Watch warned that the new law risks criminalising political dissent.
In Tunisia the army is generally respected by ordinary citizens, so it is significant that Prime Minister Habib Essid is sending army reservists to guard archaeological sites and resorts.
The army sided with the demonstrators at the outbreak of the Jasmine Revolution, helping them come through with less than 400 deaths. Compare that with Syrias death tally of 250,000 and rising.
The police and security services on the other hand are perceived by two thirds of Tunisian households to be corrupt, according to the Global Corruption Barometer.
They are mistrusted, with a bad track record of abuse and torture of detainees in prison, sometimes even leading to death.
Tunisians complain that, in the last year or two, police corruption has got worse, with a feeling that they see themselves as above the law.
Women feel especially vulnerable to intimidation. Bribery to avoid detention is often the only option.
Soon after the Jasmine Revolution I asked a Tunisian official how the country had dealt with its corrupt security forces. He told me about 10%, those that were too corrupt to stay, were forced to leave, most of them flying out to Italy. It seems a new layer has quickly replaced them.
Maybe Fridays attack and the world condemnation that has followed will be a wake-up call to reform Tunisias police.
Many Tunisians blame the police and security services for not doing more to prevent the Bardo Museum massacre.
They will blame them even more if, thanks to these failures, the Tunisian economy deteriorates further and the unemployment rates, already at 35% among the young, go higher.
The government has a long hard road ahead, trying to persuade secularists to coexist peacefully with religious conservatives, and trying to stop its Jasmine Revolution being hijacked by a minority of violent Islamists.
Tunisia is unique in the Arab world in having strong women who have campaigned hard for equal rights with men, and in having a strong middle class civil society and responsible trade unions.
All this would be lost were ISIS to gain a foothold, and everyone knows it.
Pictures of Tunisian women donating blood for Fridays victims say it all.
Tunisias fragile fledging democracy got more fragile on Friday. The coming weeks and months will test it further.
The US and Europe must without delay help the country make a successful transition and stay the course of moderation.
For if Tunisia fails there is no hope for all the rest.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
