<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Telegraph">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:41:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nobel winner puts prize medal up for auction</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46ab1cf7/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C116319450CNobel0Ewinner0Eputs0Eprize0Emedal0Eup0Efor0Eauction0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US physicist Leon Lederman says prize has been sitting on a shelf for 20 years</Description>
        <MainBody>Nobel winner puts prize medal up for auction
US physicist Leon Lederman says prize has been sitting on a shelf for 20 years
Leon LedermanPhoto: Getty Images
AP
12:41AM BST 27 May 2015
A retired experimental physicist has put his 1988 Nobel Prize medal up for auction, and the minimum bid is $325,000 (210,000).
"The prize has been sitting on a shelf somewhere for the last 20 years," 92-year-old Leon Lederman said in a phone conversation from his home in eastern Idaho. "I made a decision to sell it. It seems like a logical thing to do."
The online auction being conducted by Nate D. Sanders Auctions closes on Thursday evening, but only when the final bid has stood unchallenged for half an hour.
Mr Lederman won the Nobel Prize in physics with two other scientists for discovering a subatomic particle called the muon neutrino. He used the prize money to buy a log cabin near the tiny town of Driggs in eastern Idaho as a vacation retreat.
Mr Lederman retired from Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory in Batavia, Illinois, near Chicago in June 2012 and moved to Idaho full time.
"No one is more respected in the Fermilab community than Leon Lederman," said Christopher T. Hill, a theoretical physicist, using a shortened version of the lab's name. "He could easily have won three or four Nobel Prizes."
The auction house has sold two other Nobel Prize medals, both earlier this year. In February, it sold for $390,848 the Nobel Prize in Economics won by Simon Kuznets in 1971. In April, it sold for $395,000 the Nobel Prize in Chemistry won by Heinrich Wieland in 1927. Both those medals were offered for auction by descendants.
Laura Yntema, auction manager for Nate D. Sanders Auctions, said research by the company found Lederman's medal is only the second to be auctioned while the winner is still alive. The company also found that only 10 Nobel Prizes have ever been auctioned , Ms Yntema said.
The people who buy them in some ways have a similar mindset to people who buy sports memorabilia, Ms Yntema said.
"It would just be an honor to own it," she said. "What these people have accomplished, it's mindboggling how they advanced society."
Ms Yntema said it's not clear what a Nobel Prize won by an experimental physicist will sell for, though she said the auction house has received a fair amount of interest.
"It's not exact what the market is," she said. "That's why they go to auction."
Lederman's wife, Ellen, said they've enjoyed having the medal. "It's really a wonderful thing. But it's not really anything we need in our log cabin in Driggs, Idaho," she said.
For Leon Lederman, at 92, the details of the work that went into discovering a subatomic particle have become hazy over the decades.
"I don't have any real stories to tell about it," he said. "I sit on my deck and look at the mountains."
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:13:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Actor Sam Shepard arrested for drink driving</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46ab1cf8/sc/26/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Ccelebritynews0C11631860A0CActor0ESam0EShepard0Earrested0Efor0Edrink0Edriving0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Actor detained by police after restaurant staff noticed him, apparently intoxicated, trying to drive away in his pick-up truck</Description>
        <MainBody>Celebrity news
Actor Sam Shepard arrested for drink driving
Actor detained by police after restaurant staff noticed him, apparently    intoxicated, trying to drive away in his pick-up truck
Sam Shepard's police mugshot taken at Santa Fe County Jail
AP
12:13AM BST 27 May 2015
US actor and Pulitzer Prize-winning playwright Sam Shepard was arrested on Monday on suspicion of drunk driving after a Santa Fe restaurant's security complained about a possibly intoxicated driver.
The 71-year-old told a police officer that he had two tequila drinks and was planning to drive home, Santa Fe police Lt. Andrea Dobyns said on Tuesday. "Our officer could smell alcohol on his breath, and he had bloodshot, watery eyes," she said.
Shepard was arrested on a charge of aggravated driving while intoxicated outside the La Choza restaurant in downtown Santa Fe.
The restaurant's security called police at about 7:45pm on Monday concerned about an intoxicated driver, Lt Dobyns said. The man was trying to leave in a pick-up truck, but the vehicle's emergency brake was engaged.
Shepherd declined to take a breath test, but he did perform a field sobriety test, which he failed, Lt Dobyns said.
Actor Sam Shepard at the Sundance Film Festival in 2014 (Getty Images)
It wasn't immediately clear if Shepard had a lawyer. Santa Fe jail records show that Shepard was released Tuesday afternoon after posting bail.
The office of Shepard's agent said Tuesday that it had no comment.
Shepard won the Pulitzer Prize for his 1979 three-act play "Buried Child." His film credits, among others, include "Baby Boom," "Steel Magnolias," "Thunderheart," "Black Hawk Down," "The Notebook," and "Walker Payne," according to the website of the Santa Fe Institute, a transdisciplinary research community, which lists the actor as a Miller Scholar.
Monday's arrest appears to be Shepard's second on charges of drunken driving . In January 2009, he was arrested on charges of speeding and drunken driving in the central Illinois town of Normal. Shepard was driving 16 mph over the 30 mph speed limit, police said. A breath test then indicated his blood-alcohol level was double the legal limit. The actor told police then that he had been at a tavern in nearby Bloomington and was heading to a hotel.
Shepard pleaded guilty and was fined $600 and court costs and was placed on 24 months supervision. He also had to finish an alcohol treatment program and perform 100 hours of community service.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:00:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Amnesty International report details 'spine-chilling' Hamas killings and torture</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46ab1cf9/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Cpalestinianauthority0C116318650CAmnesty0EInternational0Ereport0Edetails0Espine0Echilling0EHamas0Ekillings0Eand0Etorture0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>'Strangling Necks' report details war crimes against Palestinians during in Gaza during last summer's war with Israel</Description>
        <MainBody>Palestinian Authority
Amnesty International report details 'spine-chilling' Hamas killings and torture
'Strangling Necks' report details war crimes against Palestinians during in    Gaza during last summers war with Israel
The Amnesty International report on the 2014 Gaza/Israel conflictPhoto: Anmesty International
By Inna Lazareva, Tel Aviv
12:00AM BST 27 May 2015
Hamas forces carried out harrowing extrajudicial killings, abductions and arrests of Palestinians in Gaza during last summers war with Israel , according to a new report by Amnesty International which also details violent interrogations that took place inside the grounds of the largest hospital in the coastal enclave.
The report, entitled "Strangling Necks: Abduction, torture and summary killings of Palestinians by Hamas forces during the 2014 Gaza/Israel conflict" also details the executions of at least 23 Palestinians, some of whom were accused of acting as Israeli collaborators in the 2014 conflict, despite the fact that many of them were in prison even before the war broke out.
There were marks of torture and bullet shots on his body, the brother of Atta Najjar was quoted as saying in the report. Atta was an ex-Palestinian Authority policeman serving a 15 year sentence since 2009 for alleged collaboration with Israel when he was tortured and killed in August 2014.
A picture showing a man referred to as A.R. after he was released from prison with the marks of torture plainly visible on his body.
His arms and legs were broken  his body was as if youd put it in a bag and smashed it ... His body was riddled with about 30 bullets. He had slaughter marks around his neck, marks of knives  And from behind the head - there was no brain. Empty It was difficult for us to carry him  He was heavy, like when you put meat in a bag; no bones. His bones were smashed. They broke him in the prison., his brother said.
On one day alone - 22nd August 2014 - at least 17 extrajudicial executions were carried out, notes the report, in the crackdown following Israeli airstrikes which killed three Hamas commanders. This included 11 inmates from Katiba prison who were executed despite the fact that they all had either pending appeals or undergoing military trials.
Hamass actions are spine-chilling and in some cases amount to war crimes, said Philip Luther, Amnesty Internationals Middle East and North Africa Director.
In the chaos of the conflict, the de facto Hamas administration granted its security forces free rein to carry out horrific abuses including against people in its custody.
Part of the Amnesty International report
The abandoned areas of the al-Shifa hospital in Gaza City  including the outpatients clinic area, were used to detain, interrogate, torture and otherwise ill-treat suspects, even as other parts of the hospital continued to function as a medical centre, the report also notes.
One 43-year old Fatah activist, identified only as A.H. for protection, described being tortured for about two hours at the hospitals outpatients wing, hands tied behind his back, blindfolded and beaten with hammer and plastic pipes.
Suddenly I felt my whole body being hit, this time with sharp objects, which led to fractures to both my hands. They also used the sharp objects on my legs, I dont know what they were as I was still blindfolded. Those objects caused holes of about one centimetre in both my feet., AH said.
At the end, his phone was thrown back to him with the words: Here is your mobile and here is a message to relay to the intelligence service in Ramallah.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:47:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Artist sells other people's Instagram photos for $90,000 each</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46aa664a/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1163140A20CArtist0Esells0Eother0Epeoples0EInstagram0Ephotos0Efor0E90A0A0A0A0Eeach0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Richard Prince enlarged the photos and sold them at a New York gallery</Description>
        <MainBody>Artist sells other people's Instagram photos for $90,000 each
Richard Prince enlarged the photos and sold them at a New York gallery
A woman makes a note on her tablet in the Gagosian Gallery, which showed Richard Prince's workPhoto: Demotix
By David Lawler, Washington
Comments
Pablo Picasso once said that good artists 'copy', while great artists 'steal'. By those standards, an American artist has put together a phenomenal new exhibition.
Richard Prince named his collection "New Portraits", but it is actually made up of enlarged versions of existing photographs posted to Instagram by other people.
Many of the photographs show women posing in sexually suggestive fashions.
Mr Prince's primary contributions appear to have been enlarging them to six feet in height, and adding comments under the username richardprince1234.
The photographs were displayed at the Frieze Art Fair in New York, and according to Vulture almost all of them fetched the asking price of $90,000 each.
Mr Prince has made a lucrative career of editing photographs taken by other people.
Some of his preview works were modified versions of images in magazines and advertisements.
In 2008 he was sued for copyright infringement by French photographer Patrick Cariou. Mr Cariou's suit was successful at first, but the ruling was later reversed on appeal.
Jonathan Turner, a barrister specialising in intellectual property, told the Telegraph that the judge in that case ruled that Mr Prince had made fair use of Mr Carious photographs and so did not infringe.
"But in these cases he had changed the photographs considerably," he said. "The works in the new collection could infringe if they are not regarded as 'transformative' versions of the photographs."
Bradley Shear, an American attorney who specialises in social media and privacy law, said that any lawsuits emerging from "New Portraits" could prove "difficult" for Mr Prince.
"It sounds like he is going to have a very difficult time trying to defend himself if he ends up being sued, because in general when you're claiming fair use you're taking bits and pieces of someone's work and then you're commenting about it, or you're taking something and changing it," he said. "Here he took whole images and just wrote a one-liner."
"New Portraits" has been widely criticised, with some taking to social media to call Mr Prince a "thief" and calling for lawsuits. He, in turn, has called his critics "idiots" and "morons".
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:41:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French utilities company EDF to cut employees' 10 weeks leave entitlement</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46aa6319/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C116318220CFrench0Eutilities0Ecompany0EEDF0Eto0Ecut0Eemployees0E10A0Eweeks0Eleave0Eentitlement0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Generous holiday allowance to be scaled back as bosses try to bring company in line with rest of the country</Description>
        <MainBody>France
French utilities company EDF to cut employees' 10 weeks leave entitlement
Generous holiday allowance to be scaled back as bosses try to bring company in    line with rest of the country
Steam rises at night from the cooling towers of the Electricite de France (EDF) nuclear power station in Dampierre-en-Burly, FrancePhoto: REUTERS
Bonnie Malkin
10:41PM BST 26 May 2015
French company EDF has announced it will stop offering its 30,000 employees 10 weeks of holiday a year  a working condition that is envied around the world.
The state-owned energy utility has announced it will offer employees a one-off payment of 10,000 (7000) in return for them agreeing to take seven weeks leave each year instead.
Executives who earn more than 51,600 can also opt for a 4-6 per cent payrise. However, the company's union has reportedly said it is seeking a lump sum payment of E80,000.
Jean-Bernard Levy, chief executive officer of Electricite de France SA (EDF)
Currently EDF employees work just 196 days a year, but are expected to put in an average of 39.5 hours a week, instead of the 35 hour legal limit that applies to the rest of the country.
The move from EDF bosses to cut back on the extraordinary holiday allowance reflects a wider trend in France to loosen strict labour market rules.
We are no longer in the same market as in 1999, wrote Philippe Torrion, the group strategy director, in an internal message to employees this month, according to the FT .
It is also a question of credibility. We cannot be out of step with the world.
The 35-hour law was introduced by Socialist prime minister Lionel Jospin in 1998 with the aim of creating more jobs.
But it has affected labour costs and created staffing problems in some sectors that operate around the clock, such as hospitals.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:31:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Libyan PM survives assassination attempt after leaving parliament session</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46aa631a/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Clibya0C116317370CLibyan0EPM0Esurvives0Eassassination0Eattempt0Eafter0Eleaving0Eparliament0Esession0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The country's internationally-recognised prime minister survived the attack after leaving a parliamentary session</Description>
        <MainBody>Libyan PM survives assassination attempt after leaving parliament session
The country's internationally-recognised prime minister survived the attack    after leaving a parliamentary session
Libyan Prime Minister Abdullah al-Thinni speaking to the media at the Carthage PalacePhoto: EPA
By Reuters
10:31PM BST 26 May 2015
Libya 's internationally recognised prime minister Abdullah al-Thinni said on Wednesday he had survived an assassination attempt after leaving a session of the anarchic country's elected parliament.
The incident highlighted the unravelling of state authority in the North African country in which two governments and parliaments allied to armed factions are fighting for control four years after rebels overthrew Muammar Gaddafi .
Mr Thinni has faced increasing criticism for running an ineffective rump state in the east since losing the capital Tripoli in the west to a rival faction that now controls ministries and key state bodies based there.
Mr Thinni told pan-Arab news channel al-Arabiya that after he left parliament in the town of Tobruk and drove off, gunmen in several cars followed his entourage and opened fire.
"We were surprised by a lot of bullets... Thank God, we managed to escape," Mr Thinni said. He did not elaborate.
Aqila Saleh, parliament speaker, had asked Mr Thinni to leave the assembly for his safety after protesters opposed to his government gathered outside the naval base where the parliament meets, two politicians told Reuters.
A burning car could be seen outside the gated venue, they said. The session resumed after Me Thinni's departure. Mr Thinni works out of Bayda, near Tobruk to the west.
It was the latest disruption in a tumultuous year for the House of Representatives, which has like Mr Thinni struggled to stamp its authority over an increasingly fragmented country.
Mr Thinni's government had originally planned to set up parliament in the main eastern city of Benghazi but relocated to Tobruk near the Egyptian border after Benghazi turned into a battleground between the government and Islamist militants.
Parliament initially opened in a Tobruk hotel but moved to the naval base after a suicide bomber detonated a car in front of the hotel in December.
The House of Representatives is being challenged by a Tripoli-based assembly known as General National Congress set up after a rival faction seized the capital in August.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:58:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Part of Texas submerged as wild weather kills several in US and Mexico</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46aa6647/sc/11/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C116317430CPart0Eof0ETexas0Esubmerged0Eas0Ewild0Eweather0Ekills0Eseveral0Ein0EUS0Eand0EMexico0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Fans were trapped at a basketball game as torrential rain and violent weather kills nearly 20 people</Description>
        <MainBody>Part of Texas submerged as wild weather kills several in US and Mexico
Fans were trapped at a basketball game as torrential rain and violent weather    kills nearly 20 people
A garden shed behind a home along the bank of the Blanco River in Wimberly, Texas, USA,Photo: EPA
By AFP
Comments
Torrential rain left large parts of Houston submerged on Tuesday and trapped fans at an NBA basketball game, in savage weather that has killed nearly 20 people in the United States and Mexico .
The southern US states of Texas and Oklahoma, and northern Mexico, have borne the brunt of several days of violent weather, including tornadoes, which have left scores dead, missing and injured on both sides of the border .
More than 10 inches of rain fell in just a few hours in the Texas city of Houston, triggering the worst flooding there in at least a decade and stranding at an arena a Houston Rockets player and spectators who had gone to see the basketball team Monday night.
Debris is collected in front of Rio Bonito Resort May 26, 2015 in Wimberley, Texas. Central Texas
Hundreds of vehicles, some fully under water, were abandoned on Houston's roads. Some people were trapped in their cars, others marooned in their homes, as flood waters rose menacingly up around them.
Two people died overnight in the flooding in the city, Mayor Annise Parker said, with the toll expected to rise. Both had drowned.
"I want to ask and urge people to continue to be safe and recognise that we may have more rain later today," she said, encouraging people to stay at home in America's fourth-largest city.
"We have cars littered all over the city," she told a press conference, adding that emergency crews were attempting to reach the abandoned vehicles to see if anyone had been trapped inside.
Nayeli Cervantes carries her friend's daughter Sophia Aviles through the floodwaters outside their apartment in Houston
Downtown Houston, where the Toyota Center is located, was not under water, said Parker. But about 200 fans had been unable to get home from the NBA game for several hours after the deluge and a few settled down for the night in the arena.
At least one Rockets player, center Dwight Howard, was among those stranded into the night after learning of the treacherous road conditions.
"There's no need to try to push it," the Houston Chronicle reported him as saying.
"I don't think it's smart for anybody to try to be out in this weather."
President Barack Obama called the flooding in Texas "terrible" and said he had offered urgent assistance to state governor Greg Abbott.
Vehicles are left stranded on Interstate 45 in Houston, Texas
Fears were growing meanwhile for at least 12 people still missing in Hays County, also in Texas.
One person was already confirmed dead there and two more died in Oklahoma, which is located to the north of Texas.
Many of the dozen missing in Hays County were from one house that was torn from its foundations during a terrifying flash flood over the weekend.
There were two families staying at the A-frame house in the picturesque town of Wimberley for the long Memorial Day weekend, NBC News reported. Among them were three children.
A little girl looks at a flooded car downtown in Houston.
Inside was Laura McComb, who was on the phone with her sister when the house, built on stilts, broke off and was swept away.
"We are in a house that is now floating down the river," she reportedly told her sister, Julie Shields. "Call Mum and Dad. I love you. And pray."
Ms Shields told the NBC affiliate KXAN that the phone call ended when Ms McComb thought she saw a light from a helicopter that had come to rescue them.
She has not been heard from since Saturday night.
South of the border, Mexico has also felt nature's wrath.
A savage twister roared through the border city of Ciudad Acuna at dawn Monday, killing at least 14 people and flattening hundreds of homes in a deadly six-second blast.
Among the victims of the tornado's 168-186 mph winds was a baby boy who was ripped from the grasp of his desperate parents and flung into the air.
His body was found on Tuesday after a frantic search.
The child was "catapulted by the tornado," Ciudad Acuna mayor Evaristo Lenin Perez said.
"It was horrible. It started raining in the morning. Very early, the wind came and everything started to fly around and then it all fell to the ground," Ciudad Acuna resident Juanita Perez said tearfully.
The federal government said the tornado destroyed 247 homes and damaged another 450.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rwandan parliament petitioned for third term for president Paul Kagame</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46aa6648/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Crwanda0C116317250CRwandan0Eparliament0Epetitioned0Efor0Ethird0Eterm0Efor0Epresident0EPaul0EKagame0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MPs will be asked whether to change the constitution to allow Mr Kagame to run again amid condemnation by rights groups of African leaders extending their terms in office</Description>
        <MainBody>Rwanda
Rwandan parliament petitioned for third term for president Paul Kagame
MPs will be asked whether to change the constitution to allow Mr Kagame to run    again amid condemnation by rights groups of African leaders extending their    terms in office
Paul Kagame, the president of RwandaPhoto: Bloomberg
Comments
Paul Kagame, the president of Rwanda , could seek a controversial third term in office after his supporters petitioned the countrys parliament to remove a clause from the constitution limiting him to two terms.
Hundreds of petitioners queued outside parliament singing songs in praise of the former Tutsi rebel commander on Monday, calling on the house speaker to propose a motion he be allowed to run again in the 2017 elections.
If the plan is approved, Mr Kagame would join others in the region seeking a third term contrary to their constitutions including Joseph Kabila, president of the Democratic Republic of Congo, and Burundis Pierre Nkurunziza , whose plans caused mass protests and an attempted coup this month.
The news of Mr Kagames possible term extension came as Afrobarometer released a poll which is said showed 75 per cent of Africans supported presidential term limits.
In Rwanda, presidential terms are restricted to two, seven-year mandates under the present constitution.
Mr Kagame has been in power since 2000 following the resignation of his predecessor, and won two elections in 2003 and 2010.
He has criticised Mr Nkurunziza for forcing himself on his unwilling populace , but indicated he would consider standing for office again if the electorate wanted it, and hit out at Western powers who have called for third terms in office to be blocked under any circumstances.
 Burundi's Catch-22: retribution at home and disease over the border
Tony Blair and Rwandan President Paul Kagame
I think at some point we need to leave countries and people to decide their own affairs," he said in a speech at Tufts University in Boston last year. "Why I'm saying that is because I'm asked when and whether I plan to leave office  right from the start of my first political term in office. It is as if I am here just to leave. I'm here to do business on behalf of Rwandans."
The bespectacled Rwandan president, whom former Prime Minister Tony Blair cites as a close personal friend, is one of Africas most polarising leaders.
His supporters, two million of whom have petitioned parliament, cite his strong record on developing Rwandas economy after coming to power following the 1994 genocide that left more than 800,000 people dead, along with improvements in electricity provision, medical care, education and security.
Robert Mutunda, a member of his party's youth wing who was among those presenting his petition and addressing the house of deputies this week, said Rwanda had moved from a state of hopelessness to a point of take-off and promise.
When we were born, there was death in front of us, the Africa Review reported him as saying. Remove any obstacle that stands in the way of Paul Kagame to stand because we still need him.
However, critics of Mr Kagames regime claim he has presided over an often brutal crackdown on the free media and political opponents. The security forces of several countries have now linked his regime to a string of assassinations and threats to the lives of his exiled opponents, including the death last year in a Johannesburg hotel room of his exiled former spy chief.
The international community also suspected direct aid to the Rwandan government in 2013 was going elsewhere amid reports that his regime was funding insurgency in the neighbouring Democratic Republic of Congo .
Donatilla Mukabalisa, the parliamentary speaker, said a motion to alter the constitution would be tabled when the house next sits on June 6.
Thierry Vircoulon, International Crisis Groups project director for Central Africa, said Mr Kagame was unlikely to encounter any of the opposition of Mr Nkurunziza.
He is popular because of his record on economic and social delivery but the Rwandan political system is also a one-man show. Theres no space for opposition or protests, he said.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:39:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heavy gunfire and multiple blasts strike Kabul diplomatic area</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46aa6649/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cafghanistan0C116316970CHeavy0Egunfire0Eand0Emultiple0Eblasts0Estrike0EKabul0Ediplomatic0Earea0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The target may have been a guesthouse in the diplomatic quarter, owned by a prominent political family</Description>
        <MainBody>Heavy gunfire and multiple blasts strike Kabul diplomatic area
The target may have been a guesthouse in the diplomatic quarter, owned by a    prominent political family
Afghan police patrol Photo: AP
By Reuters
Comments
Heavy gunfire and a series of explosions were heard in central Kabul late on Tuesday.
Teams of Afghan security forces were deployed to the Wazir Akbar Khan area, an upscale part of the capital where many embassies and government buildings are located.
More than a dozen explosions were heard in the first hour..
 British national killed by Taliban suicide bomb targeting EU in Kabul named
Most of the blasts sounded like rockets, but several more powerful detonations could have been suicide bombers, one Afghan security source said.
"We have surrounded the area and cornered them," Kabul police spokesman Ebadullah Karimi told AFP, adding that no casualties have been reported.
"The attackers wanted to get into Heetal Hotel but failed. They have now taken position among the trees behind the hotel and are firing at security forces."
The manager of the Heetal Hotel, owned by the family of Foreign Minister Salahuddin Rabbani and known for housing foreigners, said all guests were in safe rooms and no one was hurt.
"Heetal is very well fortified. After one or two initial explosions, our guards started firing on attackers who were unable to get inside," manager Beizhan told AFP by telephone from inside the guesthouse.
"Gunshots and blasts can still be heard from a distance," he added, without specifying if there were any foreign guests inside.
The guest house was damaged in 2009 when a suicide bomber blew himself up outside the gate, killing eight people and wounding another 40.
The Taliban could not immediately be reached for comment.
One witness said the attack began at 11pm local time when a single shot rang out over the neighbourhood. Explosions followed soon after.
Franz J. Marty lives across the road from the compound that was attacked.
"[My landlord] saw a pick-up parked diagonally across the street with at least four attackers (16 to 17 years old only), wearing traditional Afghan clothes (no headscarfs or hats or anything), suicide vests and armed with AK 47s. They unloaded RPG rounds and IEDs."
Mr Marty, who took shelter in the basement of his building, counted at least 15 explosions.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:12:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Spanish nuns accused of exploiting wards to boost conservative vote</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46aa664b/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cspain0C1163140A40CSpanish0Enuns0Eaccused0Eof0Eexploiting0Ewards0Eto0Eboost0Econservative0Evote0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Podemos and Socialist party representatives say the nuns take voters who are unaware of whom they voted for</Description>
        <MainBody>Spain
Spanish nuns accused of exploiting wards to boost conservative vote
Podemos and Socialist party representatives say the nuns take voters who are unaware of whom they voted for
Lader of Spanish party Podemos (We Can), Pablo IglesiasPhoto: EPA
By James Badcock, Madrid
9:12PM BST 26 May 2015
Spanish Left-wing parties have accused nuns who run an elderly persons' home of exploiting their wards in order to boost the conservative vote.
Podemos and Socialist party (PSOE) representatives in Cceres, Extremadura, claimed rival Popular Party (PP) volunteers took elderly people to the polling station during Sunday's local elections .
In a complaint lodged with a Cceres court, the representatives even accuse the director of Extremadura's Sepad social services unit of being involved.
 All across Europe, the dissatisfaction is clear
The representatives pointed to a video that they claimed showed just three out of "dozens and dozens" of elderly and disabled people taken to the station. In the video, people are queuing, despite not appearing to know which party they wished to vote for.
According to the local newspaper Hoy, the complaint said that the old people were residents of Sisters of the Poor residence run by nuns.
"Did you tell the nun how you wanted to vote?" one frail-looking lady clutching a ballot envelope is asked by a political representative. "The nun put the paper in," she answers before stating a little later that she did not know who she was voting for.
In Spanish elections, voters choose one of the parties' printed lists of candidates which is dropped into the ballot box inside an envelope. These lists are sent out by parties during electoral campaigns, although most people pick them up once at their polling station.
A second old lady can be heard saying that she wanted to vote and that the nun had helped her with the envelope in the video. "Whatever" was her answer when asked if she knew who she was voting for, but then later clarified that she did know.
Another political representative can be heard asking a man in a wheelchair whether he made a conscious decision to vote. The man seemed unable to answer.
Basilia Pizarro, the Sepad director accused by Podemos and PSOE, told EFE news agency that she had accompanied some residents of the home to the polling station "in my capacity as a volunteer". She said she had "no idea how each person was going to vote".
Carlos Martnez-Blay, a Podemos polling representative, said the electoral officer and the police officers present had ignored his complaints.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:48:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hassan Rouhani's glaring failure to curb human rights abuses in Iran</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46aa1e1f/sc/24/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Ciran0C11631210A0CHassan0ERouhanis0Eglaring0Efailure0Eto0Ecurb0Ehuman0Erights0Eabuses0Ein0EIran0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Analysis: the trial of Jason Rezaian, the Washington Post journalist, shows how the president lacks the power - or perhaps the will - to improve Iran's human rights record</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran
Hassan Rouhani's glaring failure to curb human rights abuses in Iran
Analysis: the trial of Jason Rezaian, the Washington Post journalist,    shows how the president lacks the power - or perhaps the will - to improve    Iran's human rights record
Jason Rezaian, an Iranian-American correspondent for the Washington PostPhoto: EPA
By David Blair , Chief Foreign Correspondent
8:48PM BST 26 May 2015
Follow
The promises made before cheering crowds were ambitious and sweeping. During his campaign to secure Irans presidency , Hassan Rouhani won over reformers by pledging to create a new atmosphere of openness and tolerance.
Anyone who wants to speak in a society should be able to come out and speak their mind, he told supporters on May 27, 2013. Criticise and critique without hesitation, he added.
Buoyed by the votes of young Iranians, Mr Rouhani won the presidency a few weeks later. This softly-spoken diplomat has now held office for almost two years.
Iranian President Hassan Rouhani speaks with media during a press conference last week
Yet the trial of Jason Rezaian, the Washington Post journalist , betrays Mr Rouhanis glaring failure to improve Iran s human rights record. In one vital respect, the situation has actually become worse during his presidency.
No less than 721 Iranians were executed in 2014 - Mr Rouhanis first full year in power - representing the highest such total since 2002. Under Mr Rouhani, Iran has kept its unenviable status as the country which executes more of its citizens than anywhere else in the world, apart from China .
In total, 1,119 Iranians have been put to death since Mr Rouhani became president on 4 August 2013, according to the Iran Human Rights Documentation Centre. The pace of executions has increased since the days of his predecessor, Mahmoud Ahmadinejad .
As for political prisoners, Mr Rouhanis government flatly denies the presence of any. Mohammad Javad Zarif, the Iranian foreign minister, declared last month: We do not jail people for their opinions.
But Human Rights Watch (HRW) begs to differ. Its research suggests that Iran holds several hundred political prisoners, including 62 in three jails in a single city. Many are members of the Bahai faith, who are persecuted with special fervour.
Jason Rezaian and his wife Yeganeh Salehi
Meanwhile, two former pillars of the regime - Mir-Hossein Mousavi, an ex-prime minister, and Mehdi Karroubi, once the speaker of parliament - are still under house arrest. The two men have been confined since 2009 when they contested a presidential election and dared to say the poll had been rigged, thereby drawing huge crowds on to the streets.
As for Mr Rezaian, his ordeal is far from unique: last month, 46 journalists or social media activists languished behind bars in Iran.
Almost two years after President Rouhanis electoral victory and a campaign in which he promised to address serious rights abuses by the government, Irans human rights situation remains dire, said Faraz Sanei, the Iran researcher at HRW.
"Irans security, intelligence and judicial bodies, which are largely beyond the presidents control, perpetrate egregious rights violations.
This raises the most central question of all: in a country where the intelligence agencies and the Revolutionary Guard answer not to the president but to the Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, does Mr Rouhani have the power to curb these abuses, even if he has the will?
Perhaps he is waiting for the moment when a nuclear deal is signed and sanctions are lifted. For now, however, it appears that Mr Rouhanis election promises are simply impossible to fulfill.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:40:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Warnings of bloody sectarian conflict as Shia militias fight back against Isil in Ramadi</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46aa1e21/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cislamic0Estate0C116315950CWarnings0Eof0Ebloody0Esectarian0Econflict0Eas0EShia0Emilitias0Efight0Eback0Eagainst0EIsil0Ein0ERamadi0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Shia militias have taken charge of the fightback against the Islamic State in the Sunni heartland province of Anbar, sparking warnings of bloody sectarian conflict</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State
Warnings of bloody sectarian conflict as Shia militias fight back against Isil in Ramadi
Shia militias have taken charge of the fightback against the Islamic State in    the Sunni heartland province of Anbar, sparking warnings of bloody sectarian    conflict
A displaced Iraqi child who fled Anbar Photo: Reuters
By Ruth Sherlock , Beirut and Louisa Loveluck, Cairo
8:40PM BST 26 May 2015
Comments
Iraq opened an offensive to drive the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (Isil) from Ramadi on Tuesday, sending in troops to cut off supply lines to jihadists controlling the provincial capital.
The advance into the Sunni heartland province of Anbar is this time led by the Hashid Shaabi, an alliance of predominantly Shia paramilitaries, who have proven to be both a more effective fighting force than Iraqi troops, but also, at times, ruthlessly sectarian in their behaviour.
The paramilitaries did little to assuage the fears of sectarian enmity on Tuesday, provocatively dubbing the mission We are at your service, Hussein; a reference to one of the most revered imams in Shia Islam, which is likely to infuriate local Sunni leaders.
The Iraqi government has been scrambling to reverse the loss of Ramadi, its biggest military setback in almost a year .
The Shia militiamen, supported by a smaller cadre of government troops, advanced on Tuesday to within a few miles of a university on Ramadis south-western edge, police sources and Sunni tribal fighters allied to the government said.
Iraqi security forces and paramilitaries deploy, during an operation aimed at cutting off Islamic State (IS) jihadists in Anbar
A policeman who recently fled Ramadi, who spoke to the Telegraph on condition of anonymity, said jihadists inside the city were nervous of air strikes from the US-led international coalition: Isil are worried. They are not driving their vehicles in the streets anymore and government buildings are empty, he said.
Shia militias had until now stayed out of Anbar province, whose Sunni tribal leaders have traditionally been overtly hostile to outsiders.
The United States had pressured Baghdad not to rely on the manpower of Shia fighters, fearing that the sectarian enmity would only drive local support to the Isil occupiers. But with its own troops in a beleaguered state, under equipped and under prepared Baghdad appears to have decided that has no other choice.
The Iraqi government has succeeded in persuading some Sunni tribal leaders to accept help from the Shia fighters, but mistrust runs deep after years of sectarian war in which atrocities were committed on both sides.
One Sunni tribal leader in the area told the Telegraph that his men were still participating in the fight against Isil and that reinforcements had been sent to aid his tribes last stand against the jihadists in the east of the city.
But though the tribesmen have taken heavy casualties in recent days, they remain wary of the involvement of Shia militias, he said.
The Ramadi policeman grudgingly accepted the Shia paramilitaries were probably the only hope to remove Isil but said he expected their advance to be followed by looting and killings.
Iraqi forces luanch a major offensive to retake the city of Ramadi
My cousins are civilians trapped in Ramadi. They dont support Isil but I am afraid the Hashid will accuse them of being as such because they are Sunnis who stayed under their rule and so kill them.
Experts warned that battle for Ramadi itself could be among the bloodiest of the war .
If there is a big offensive, a lot of blood will be shed and its unclear who will control the place when this is all over, said Patrick B. Johnston, a political scientist at RAND Corporation.
Criticism from the US government of the Shia militia dominating the offensive was more muted, with Col Steve Warren, a spokesman of the Pentagon calling the sectarian code name the fighters have given to the operation unhelpful.
The US-led coalition continued to pound Isil positions in Iraq and Syria from the air , dropping 19 payloads on tactical units, vehicles, heavy machine guns and buildings in a 24-hour period ending on Tuesday, a coalition statement said.
The Syrian government said it had killed as many as 140 Isil combatants in an air raid on a jihadist headquarters in their provincial capital of Raqqa.
But local residents denied the claims, saying the attacks had killed less than a dozen men.
Despite the attacks, the jihadists have continued to make gains deep inside Syrian territory, putting the Syrian military ever on the back foot.
On Tuesday Isil Twitter accounts posted pictures of the jihadists taking control of Khunayfis, a phosphate mine some 45 miles south of the central city of Palmyra, located on the long highway to Damascus .
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:35:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vienna airport staff 'smuggling illegal immigrants to Britain' arrested</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46aa1e23/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Caustria0C11630A7140CVienna0Eairport0Estaff0Esmuggling0Eillegal0Eimmigrants0Eto0EBritain0Earrested0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Austrian police have arrested several security employees at Vienna airport over their alleged role in smuggling illegal immigrants</Description>
        <MainBody>Austria
Vienna airport staff 'smuggling illegal immigrants to Britain' arrested
Austrian police have arrested several security employees at Vienna airport    over their alleged role in smuggling illegal immigrants
Vienna international airportPhoto: Alamy
By Justin Huggler, Berlin
8:35PM BST 26 May 2015
Police in Austria have broken up an operation to smuggle illegal immigrants into Britain through Vienna airport.
Two members of airport security staff are being held in custody on suspicion of allowing passengers without visas or proper travel documents onto flights to the UK and US.
A further 11 security staff members are being questioned by police in connection with what appears to have been a sophisticated trafficking operation.
The suspects are believed to be employees of more than one private security company responsible for different areas of airport security.
The British company G4S confirmed that one of those being held in custody is a former employee who was fired over the case.
Friedrich Khl, a spokesman for the local prosecutors office, said that the two men being held in custody are a Sri Lankan and a Polish citizen.
The suspicion is that they allowed an unknown number of foreigners to travel abroad from Austria illegally, he said.
Police are investigating around ten separate instances of security staff allowing passengers on board flights without the proper documentation, he said.
Most of those under suspicion are Sri Lankan , as were most of the illegal immigrants involved.
The smuggling was conducted entirely by the employees, and none of the companies involved are suspected of any wrongdoing, Mr Khl stressed.
 Bizarre smuggling attempts that went wrong, in pictures
According to unconfirmed Austrian press reports, the smugglers charged 7,000 (5,000) to 9,000 (6,400) per head to get illegal migrants through airport security.
The suspects are believed to have worked for different companies allowing them to pass illegal migrants through several different layers of airport security.
G4S, for instance, was only involved as a contractor for Austrian airlines carrying out hand baggage and passport checks at the departure gate.
An illegal migrant would have to pass through checks conducted by another company before he reached them.
I can confirm that in compliance with Austrian labour law, an employee responsible for checking visa documentation at Vienna Airport on a contract with Austrian Airlines was dismissed in March following his arrest, Graham Levinsohn, G4S regional chief executive for Europe said.
He added that he could not comment further as the case was in the hands of prosecutors.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:09:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French farmer on trial for 'truffle thief' murder in southern France</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46a99c27/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C116313490CFrench0Efarmer0Eon0Etrial0Efor0Etruffle0Ethief0Emurder0Ein0Esouthern0EFrance0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Laurent Rambaud faces 30 years for shooting dead a man allegedly stealing his prized black truffles in case that stoked tensions in "black diamond war"</Description>
        <MainBody>France
French farmer on trial for 'truffle thief' murder in southern France
Laurent Rambaud faces 30 years for shooting dead a man allegedly stealing his    prized black truffles in case that stoked tensions in "black diamond    war"
Laurent Rambaud, is accused of shooting Ernest PardoPhoto: AFP
Follow
A French farmer went on trial on Tuesday for murdering a man he thought was stealing his prized truffles in a case that has lifted the lid on a black diamond war over one of the worlds most expensive delicacies .
Laurent Rambaud, 37, faces a maximum 30 years in prison for killing Ernest Pardo, 42, a hospital worker who he blasted twice with a pump-action shotgun after surprising him digging in his truffle patch with a dog in December, 2010.
The shooting took place just before Christmas in Grignan, a small town in the Rhne valley near one of Frances largest truffle markets , at a time when the knobbly fungi can fetch up to 1,000 (700) a piece.
Mr Rambauds arrest on murder charges sparked fury in the southern Drome region, where locals backed the farmer saying he was only defending his livelihood and felt threatened.
Ernest Pardo
Mr Rambaud, from a respected local family and head of the young farmers association in the southern Drome region, allegedly sat in wait for the suspected thief. He surprised Mr Pardo with a small pick in his hand, which the farmer mistook for a weapon.
Mr Rambaud opened fire but insists he had no intention of killing the alleged poacher, who local police said was an experienced truffle hunter who sold his finds at local markets.
I thought he was armed, I shot first. I committed the irreparable. Even with a gun on your own land, at night you get frightened to death, he told the court in Valence.
His arrest sparked angry protests from fellow truffle farmers, many of whom said they were facing a near-impossible task defending their black truffles from thieves bent on swiping not just the fungi but their prized dogs.
Friends of Mr Pardot, known locally as Nn, staged their own protest in nearby Saint-Parul-Trois-Chteaux, saying he didnt deserve to be killed like a dog.
Alain Fort, Mr Rambauds lawyer said his client was the antithesis of a person who would deliberately shoot someone over a handful of truffles.
This is a man who felt in danger at night in his truffle patch. He was scared, he said.
The wife of Ernest Pardo waits for the start of the trial of farmer
The shooting, he added, took place during a veritable truffle war, with local farmers fighting a losing battle to guard their warty fungi round the clock or face losing the lot to thieves, in some cases armed.
Bruno Durieux, the mayor of Grignan, told the court that truffle theft was an increasing problem in the region, even if wasnt Chicago.
Over the previous five years, there had been a clear rise in the number of thefts with professional methods, he said.
A court psychologist said the accused was an ordinary man who committed an extraordinary act.
But Stphane Simonin, lawyer for Mr Pardos widow and three children, that night, at that time, Rambaud went to that spot because he knew he was likely to cross someone who people had been talking about for some time.
Its not insignificant to go blacked up in camouflage clothes and armed to the teeth, then open fire twice, he said.
Mr Pardo was looking for truffles for others. It is done in the region, he said.
Truffles, which only grow wild around the roots of oak, hazel and lime trees, are one of the most expensive foods in the world by weight.
Mr Rambauds father, who replaced the unlicensed shotgun with his hunting rifle, also faces charges of tampering with a crime scene.
The trial continues.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:41:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India's tallest man struggling to find love: 'I have never found anyone to look up to'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46a99c29/sc/15/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cindia0C116312240CIndias0Etallest0Eman0Estruggling0Eto0Efind0Elove0EI0Ehave0Enever0Efound0Eanyone0Eto0Elook0Eup0Eto0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dharmendra Singh, 8ft 1in, says the difficulty is finding someone tall enough for me, which he added was probably impossible</Description>
        <MainBody>Comments
India s tallest man is struggling to find love because of his height.
At 8ft 1in tall  only two inches shy of the world record  Dharmendra Singh stands head and shoulders above his fellow countrymen .
But because of his height the 32-year-old, from Meerut, Uttar Pradesh, he has yet to find The One.
Mr Singh said: In terms of marriage, the main problem is my height. It will be very difficult to find someone who is tall enough for me. I think it is impossible.
At over 8ft tall Dharmendra Singh can not find a match
So this is also the reason why I havent had a girlfriend. Women are very much interested in me. They talk to me and giggle but I have never met anyone who I could look up to.
In college I was a very shy person. Like other boys, I never approached girls to have a chat. I had great respect for them but never met the woman of my dreams.
 World's tallest man comes eye to eye with world's smallest man for Guinness World Records' Day
Mr Singhs height has also made it hard for him to find paying work.
He said: Whenever I went for interviews for jobs, people asked how will do the work if I was so tall.
Reluctantly, he took up work as a freak show performer at a local amusement park, where he spends his days in a cage-like structure selling photographs to paying punter for 10p per pop.
After completing my studies, when I could not get a regular job, I got an offer saying that I will be paid 30 pence per day at the amusement park, he said.
I charge 10 pence for one picture. Some people pay, some run away without paying. I get hurt when people run away without paying me.
Mr Singh also gets a monthly salary of 10,000 rupees (100) which enables him to survive.
With that kind of money, I manage by life, he added.
While most of Mr Singhs family are a normal height, his maternal grandfather was 7ft 3in, suggesting his size could be genetic.
As a child he was always taller than his peers and was often bullied in his youth.
He said: I was ill-treated by many people who would call me names like giraffe or camel.
Some people would say that I have grown too tall and I have become useless. People would say I have become hopeless. I used to feel bad about these things.
I was not very friendly with the children in my neighbourhood and I didnt make many friends. I have a problem  I cant make friends. And that holds true for women also.
Dharmendra Pratap Singh poses for a picture with Suman Devi, a relative
Mr Singh, who holds a master's degree in Hindi, said his height poses some real problems for him.
I have to face a lot of problems in my day to day life because of my height. I need a helper to help me with smaller things. I have trouble even walking, he said.
"I need someone to go to market and buy things for me. I dont go to the market very because it is very crowded and people harass me.
"I have to face a lot of hardships which a normal person does not have to. It is a terrible feeling when I am unable to do normal things."
Nevertheless, he said being tall was not completely terrible.
He said: I feel great when people look at me and get happy. I make their day. They want to know about me and get photos clicked. I am immensely popular and it is all because of my height.
Mr Singh said his height did cause health problems.
I few months back, I had fractured my hip bone. I got myself treated in Delhi. I have a plate in my hip, and I have to bear pain because of it. I have to use a stick for support, he said.
Suman, Mr Singh's neighbour, said: Neighbours used to talk a lot about his height as they had never seen someone like him before but he never paid any heed to what people said. He was always a very optimistic and cheerful person.
He is like a son to me and I wish he finds a suitable girl for himself and gets married.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:13:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Benjamin Netanyahu 'calls for West Bank settlement talks with Palestinians'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46a95ab8/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Cisrael0C116311620CBenjamin0ENetanyahu0Ecalls0Efor0EWest0EBank0Esettlement0Etalks0Ewith0EPalestinians0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In response to mounting EU pressure, Netanyahu says he's ready to talk with the Palestinians - and discuss possible West Bank settlement annexation - for first time since coming to power in 2009, according to reports</Description>
        <MainBody>Israel
Benjamin Netanyahu 'calls for West Bank settlement talks with Palestinians'
In response to mounting EU pressure, Netanyahu says hes ready to talk with    the Palestinians - and discuss possible West Bank settlement annexation -    for first time since coming to power in 2009, according to reports
Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin NetanyahuPhoto: AP
By Inna Lazareva, Tel Aviv
7:13PM BST 26 May 2015
Benjamin Netanyahu, Israel's prime minister, has called for peace talks with the Palestinians on West Bank settlements for the first time since he came to power in 2009, according to Israeli daily Haaretz.
Mr Netanyahu told EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini that he wants to restart the peace talks with the Palestinians and reach understandings concerning land swaps and annexations of some of the West Bank settlements, the newspaper reported.
The reports, which cited an unnamed Israeli source based on the meetings held last week, would be the first time Mr Netanyahu has agreed to discuss the borders of settlement blocks in the West Bank, considered illegal under international law, since he became Prime Minister in 2009.
Mr Netanyahus comments are seen as a response to mounting pressure from the European Union for progress in the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.
The purported talks would set out to delineate the borders of the Israeli settlements in the West Bank which would be annexed to Israel in a future agreement with the Palestinians.
Its clear there are areas that will remain under Israeli control under any agreement, just as its clear there are areas that will remain under Palestinian control under any agreement, Mr Netanyahu was quoted by the source as saying.
Therefore, we can advance toward understandings on which areas we can continue building in, since in any case, theyll remain under Israeli control.
France is spearheading a UN Security Council resolution that would set down the core parametres for a peaceful resolution of the decades-long conflict.
Meanwhile, Brussels is pursuing the initiative to label settlement produce in supermarkets across the EU, after the foreign ministers from 16 out of 28 European Union countries sent a letter to Ms Mogherini last month insisting the the EU pushes forward with the move.
In Israel and Palestine, Mr Netanyahus comments immediately stirred controversy amongst lawmakers.
Israeli agriculture minister Uri Ariel of the pro-settlement Jewish Home party said that the comments set a dangerous precedent that are contrary to existing government guidelines.
But the newly installed minister of public security Gilad Erdan played said that the prime ministers comments were not surprising. [I]if there will ever be a partner for peace, it is clear that there will be territorial concessions, he said.
Palestine Liberation Organisation Executive Committee member Saeb Erekat who acted as the chief Palestinian negotiator in talks with the Israelis denounced Mr Netanyahus comments as a request to continue illegal settlement construction with Palestinian consent.
If Mr Netanyahu wants to have meaningful negotiations ending the occupation that began in 1967, he should recognise a Palestinian State on the 1967 border and honour Israels obligations including a halt of settlement construction and the release of the Palestinian prisoners., Mr Erekat said.
Yet the full significance of the move appears to be a double-edged sword: while some say that this could pave the way for an eventual two-state solution, the step would also serve to legitimise the continued construction in settlement blocks which will be annexed to Israel in the future, if the Palestinians agree.
The leaked comments also made no mention of land swaps in exchange for the annexed West Bank territories - another thorny issue in Israeli-Palestinian negotiations.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:58:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Extreme India heatwave kills 800 as capital's roads melt</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46a95abb/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cindia0C116311310CExtreme0EIndia0Eheatwave0Ekills0E80A0A0Eas0Ecapitals0Eroads0Emelt0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Hospitals are on alert for heatstroke victims as New Delhi roads melt away in 122F temperatures</Description>
        <MainBody>Extreme India heatwave kills 800 as capital's roads melt
Hospitals are on alert for heatstroke victims as New Delhi roads melt away in    122F temperatures
Indian fishermen catch fish in a dryed up pond in the village of Phaphamau on the outskirts of AllahabadPhoto: AFP
By AFP
Comments
At least 800 people have died in a major heatwave that has swept across India , melting roads in New Delhi as temperatures neared 122F (50C).
Hospitals were on alert to treat victims of heatstroke and authorities advised people to stay indoors, with no end in sight to the searing conditions.
India's meteorological department said it had issued heat warnings to several states where temperatures were forecast to top 113F over the next few days.
"As of now, we don't predict any respite from the extreme heatwave for the next few days ," said B. P. Yadav, department spokesman.
An Indian labourer takes a break as he drinks water to get respite from the heat
Hundreds of people - mainly from the poorest sections of society - die at the height of summer every year across the country , while tens of thousands suffer power cuts from an overburdened electricity grid.
Streets were deserted in Hyderabad, capital of the worst-hit state of Andhra Pradesh in southern India where 551 people have died in the last week.
"The state government has taken up education programmes through television and other media to tell people not to venture into the outside without a cap, to drink water and other measures," said P. Tulsi Rani, special commissioner for disaster management in the state.
"We have also requested NGOs and government organisations to open up drinking water camps so that water will be readily available for all the people in the towns."
P. Gangamma, Hyderabad street vendor, said the heat was making her head pound, but she had no choice but to stay outside.
"For the past three days hot wind has been coming in," said the 65-year-old, who sells cigarettes on a busy intersection.
"I am a diabetes patient, but I have no husband and no sons, so I have to stay here and keep shop."
An Indian boy takes a bath at a fountain at India Gate in New Delhi
Large parts of India, including the capital New Delhi, have endured days of sweltering heat , prompting fears of power cuts as energy-guzzling air conditioners work overtime.
The Hindustan Times daily said the maximum temperature in the capital hit a two-year high of 113F on Monday - five degrees higher than the seasonal average.
The paper carried a front-page photo of a main road in the city melting in the heat, with the white pedestrian crossing stripes curling and spreading into the black asphalt.
"It's baking hot out here - our outing has turned into a nightmare," said Meena Sheshadri, a 37-year-old tourist from the western city of Pune who was visiting Delhi's India Gate monument with her children.
"My throat is parched, even though I've been constantly sipping water."
Hari Om, Delhi street food vendor, said business was slow, with few people venturing out in the furnace-like conditions.
"All the food is getting spoilt even though I prepared it fresh in the morning. It's bad business but what to do," he said.
"People are not coming out and they also don't feel like eating. All they want is to sip cold water all day."
In Telangana state, which borders Andhra Pradesh in the south, 231 people have died in the last week as temperatures hit 118F over the weekend.
In the western state of Orissa 11 people were confirmed to have died from the heat.
Another 13 people have died in the eastern state of West Bengal, where unions urged drivers in the city of Kolkata to stay off the roads during the day.
India's power industry has long struggled to meet rapidly rising demand in Asia 's third largest economy, with poorly maintained transmission lines and overloaded grids.
The Hindustan Times warned that some of the hot, dry conditions could plunge the worst-affected states into drought before monsoon rains arrive.
The monsoon is forecast to hit the southern state of Kerala towards the end of this month before sweeping across the country , but it will be weeks before the rains reach the arid northern plains.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:43:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Isil video purportedly shows undamaged historic ruins of Palmyra</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46a95abd/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cislamic0Estate0C116313870CIsil0Evideo0Epurportedly0Eshows0Eundamaged0Ehistoric0Eruins0Eof0EPalmyra0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Footage appears to show the ancient ruins of Palmyra still intact after capture by the Islamic State last week</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State
Isil video purportedly shows undamaged historic ruins of Palmyra
Footage appears to show the ancient ruins of Palmyra still intact after    capture by the Islamic State last week
By Telegraph video, and agency, video source APTN
6:43PM BST 26 May 2015
A video released by a media arm of the Islamic State group on Tuesday purportedly shows the archaeological ruins of Palmyra have been left undamaged.
The video was released by the pro-Islamic State Aamaq News Agency.
The video, which is the first released since the extremist group captured Palmyra earlier this month, purportedly shows the majestic Roman-era colonnades and amphitheatre have not been damaged.
Black smoke can be seen billowing from behind the ruins but there is no mention of when the video was filmed.
At one point in the video a voice can be heard saying:
"In the name of God, and peace be upon his messenger, by the grace of God we have defeated the Alawites today, by the grace of God we have conquered Jezel, by the grace of God we have conquered Jezel, by the grace of God we have conquered Jezel."
The capture of Palmyra has stoked fears that the militants might try to destroy one of the Middle East's most spectacular archaeological sites - a well-preserved, 2,000-year-old Roman-era city on the town's edge - as they have destroyed others in Syria and Iraq.
Syria's antiquities chief Maamoun Abdulkarim said he was still afraid the jihadist group would blow up Palmyra's 2,000-year-old Roman ruins at Palmyra including tombs and the Temple of Bel, which could be viewed as idolatrous in its puritanical vision of Islam.
Still, Abdulkarim said "the historic city is fine. There is no damage so far".
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:17:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Danish radio station DJ kills baby rabbit live on air</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46a95abf/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cdenmark0C11630A7480CGalapagos0Evolcano0Eerupts0Efor0Efirst0Etime0Ein0E30A0Eyears0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>DJ said he bashed rabbit to death with bicycle pump to 'highlight the hypocrisy' of animal rights campaigners who eat meat</Description>
        <MainBody>Denmark
Danish radio station DJ kills baby rabbit live on air
DJ said he bashed rabbit to death with bicycle pump to 'highlight the    hypocrisy' of animal rights campaigners who eat meat
By AFP, video source ITN
6:17PM BST 26 May 2015
This video does not contain the moment the rabbit is killed.
A Danish radio station killed a baby rabbit with a bicycle pump live on air, prompting a storm of criticism on Tuesday despite claims it had simply wanted to highlight cruelty in farming.
"We didn't do it for the sake of entertainment," talk radio station Radio24syv wrote on Twitter.
"Thousands of animals die each day so that people can eat them," it added.
Image of Asger Juhl with the baby rabbit at the radio station
The broadcaster said radio host Asger Juhl on Monday killed baby rabbit Allan with repeated blows to the head to highlight "hypocrisy" in Danes' attitudes towards animal welfare.
"We buy and eat animals that have had an awful life. And animals that have been killed under the same controlled conditions as the rabbit in the studio," it wrote in a statement.
Is the on air slaughter of a bunny rabbit something Ofcom might view as being unacceptable to hear when children might be listening ?
 John Myers (@johnmyersteam) May 26, 2015
Reality TV show star and animal rights activist Linse Kessler tried to grab the animal and chased Juhl around the studio several times before being asked to leave.
"They wanted to see if they could kill him in the end or if they had gotten too attached to him," she said in a video clip on her Facebook page.
Kessler said she thought she was capable of wresting the animal from Juhl but feared it would die a more painful death if she grabbed it.
"I hit it hard over the neck twice so that the cervical vertebrae fractured," Juhl told broadcaster TV 2.
Presenter Asger Juhl
"I was instructed by a zookeeper from Aalborg Zoo who hits several baby rabbits every week (to feed) the snakes," he added.
"I knew that we would spark debate. We were provocative, on purpose. Of course there are some misunderstandings we need to deal with. People are saying we didn't do it in a humane way - we did."
"What I did, I called up a zoo in Denmark - a guy who kills rabbits, to feed them to the predators in the zoo. He uses an iron stick. I didn't have a stick but I did have a bicycle pump made out of iron. It's the exact same thing.
Juhl said he had brought the dead rabbit to his home - where he skinned and cut it up with his children, aged six and eight - and that he later would have rabbit stew for dinner with fellow morning host Kristoffer Eriksen.
A Copenhagen zoo prompted international outrage last year by putting down a healthy giraffe, known as Marius, and then dissecting it in front of children.
The Rabbit as seen in the clip
That incident, just like the radio station's stunt, drew a mixed response in Denmark where agriculture is a key export industry.
"To provoke and to promote itself," Twitter user Steffen Andersen in Aarhus wrote, while journalist Brian Esbensen tweeted: "What if people were just as outraged over drowned refugees."
Radio24syv said it wanted to put more focus on "one of the world's most industrialised agriculture sectors."
Danish farming "allows 25,000 piglets to die every day because farming has been streamlined and (breeds) pigs that give birth to far more offspring than the mother pig can handle," it said.
International reactions on social media were overwhelmingly negative, with users calling the radio host "sick" and "sadistic", even after the station issued a statement in English.
"Denmark is one of the top countries in the world when it comes to consumption of meat products and consumers do not hesitate to buy cheap meat in stores without asking questions," it said.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:31:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Leaked EU documents warn of Islamic State terrorists crossing the Mediterranean</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46a8e5b1/sc/24/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cislamic0Estate0C116295910CLeaked0EEU0Edocuments0Ewarn0Eof0EIslamic0EState0Eterrorists0Ecrossing0Ethe0EMediterranean0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The EU's political leaders must do more to cope with the influx of migrants across the Mediterranean, according to leaked internal documents</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State
Leaked EU documents warn of Islamic State terrorists crossing the Mediterranean
The EU's political leaders must do more to cope with the influx of migrants    across the Mediterranean, according to leaked internal documents
An Italian Coast Guard ship carrying migrants arrives at Pozzallo's harbor, ItalyPhoto: AP
By Harriet Alexander , and Nick Squires, Rome
5:31PM BST 26 May 2015
Europe s politicians do not have a coherent strategy for dealing with the huge influx of migrants from North Africa , according to confidential EU documents prepared by military experts.
The politicians failure to devise a workable plan is set against warnings that Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (Isil) fighters could be among the thousands entering Europe through the Mediterranean, and that European military boats sent close to Libya could become targets for Isil.
Prepared earlier this month, the papers set out how the European Union should respond to the current crisis in the Mediterranean , and support the suggestions from EU leaders that the emphasis should be on breaking up smuggling networks and saving lives  while avoiding encouraging migrants to set out at sea.
More than 40,000 people have landed in Italy this year according to research
Almost 40,000 people have landed in Italy this yea r, according to the International Organisation of Migration, which puts 2015 on course to break all records for migrant arrivals. Countless thousands have died during the perilous crossing  on April 18, an estimated 800 people died in one single sinking.
The EU called an emergency summit on April 23 and the two documents, published on Tuesday by WikiLeaks, were drawn up in response to that summit. The EU announced that it was sending warships to monitor the Mediterranean and pick up survivors from floundering ships, but is still waiting for a UN resolution that will allow it to destroy boats belonging to people smugglers in Libyan waters  the epicentre of the humanitarian disaster.
The documents, prepared for the European Council by the Politico-Military Group, warn that the potential presence of hostile forces, extremists or terrorists such as Daesh (Islamic State) should also be taken into consideration when confronting smugglers ships.
They also warn that the Europeans and their boats could become targets for Isil.
Migrants wait to disembark from a Migrant Offshore Aid Station ship in the port of Messina
"The threat to the force should be acknowledged, especially during activities such as boarding and when operating on land or in proximity to an unsecured coastline, or during interaction with non-seaworthy vessels."
The military experts who form the PMG criticised the EU for failing to agree a plan, and said that the absence of identified political strategic objectives was hampering their work in providing military solutions.
The political End State is not clearly defined in the CMC (Crisis Management Concept). Therefore, an additional political guidance from the PSC (Political &amp; Security Committee) would be desirable, the reports authors state.
They also say that the EU member states must agree how to process migrants once they have landed in Europe  something they have so far failed to do. Britain has led the way in refusing to accept quotas of migrants to resettle in their countries, and EU leaders are yet to agree what to do with the thousands of new arrivals.
The documents, presented on May 12, do however accept that the EU is in a difficult situation: while they must act to prevent more deaths at sea, they do not want to encourage migrants to make the crossing.
The PMG considers that a visible EU naval presence in the vicinity of the embarkation areas could have a counterproductive effect in preventing human smuggling, due to the possible increase in smuggling activity that could be drawn to the EU presence, the report states.
And they acknowledge that a PR campaign is essential to ensure that both EU citizens and prospective migrants do not misinterpret their actions.
The information strategy should avoid suggesting that the focus is to rescue migrants at sea but emphasise that the aim of the operation is to disrupt the migrants smuggling business model, they write. By doing so the operation will indirectly contribute to reduce loss of life at sea. The target audience should include Libya and North African regional neighbours.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
