<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Telegraph">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:10:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fifa corruption scandal live: Sepp Blatter says 'I'm not to blame'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46b7d11d/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Csport0Cfootball0Cfifa0C116356540CFifa0Ecorruption0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Fifa crisis: UK Prime Minister adds his voice to growing criticism of Fifa president</Description>
        <MainBody>This page will automatically update every 30 secondsOn Off
Latest
02.56
As delegates prepare to vote. Prince Ali, the rival to Sepp Blatter has won the backing of USA and Canada. But the Africans look certain to back the incumbent.. ;
01.10
American satirist, Jon Stewart, has his own take on the Fifa scandal. He seems to have rather enjoyed what he described as the "perp walk" undertaken by those embroiled the scandal. Given the row over "deflategate" in which the New England Patriots were accused of tampering with the ball on the way to the Super Bowl, there seems to be a pretty large chunk of schadenfreude here.
00.39
Mihir Bose, a long-standing observer of Fifa has an interesting take on how things could develop if there is an impasse between Uefa and Blatter.
Platni has for the first time spoken of UEFA's nuclear option that UEFA could leave FIFA. So could they make the Euros a rival World Cup?
 Mihir Bose (@mihirbose) May 28, 2015
23.40
Former Fifa vice president Jack Warner has left a jail in Trinidad by ambulance a day after he was indicted by US investigators. Judicial officer Abraham Ali said Warner had complained of exhaustion and was not able to face questions from reporters gathered outside the jail.
Jack Warner transfered from jail in an ambulance after complaining of exhaustion
22.46
The crisis in Zurich is escalating with Sepp Blatter showing no inclination to step down and Michel Platini, the Uefa president refusing to rule out European boycott of the World Cup if Blatter does not step down. Ben Rumsby has more on another dramatic day in Zurich here.
Michel Platini warns European countries could boycott World Cup if Blatter does not step down
22.10
Right, it's time for me to sign off now and leave you with our US Correspondent, David Millward, who is keeping on top of the latest reaction
, .
21.58
The scandal is having wide-ranging implications in last year's World Cup host country Brazil. The country's justice minister, Jose Eduardo Cardozo, has asked federal police to see if the US probe into Fifa could help identify crimes that may have been committed by Brazilian sport officials and businessmen.
After being visited by police agents, the Rio de Janeiro-based Klefer Sports Marketing company has said it has turned over all the documents requested pertaining to its contract with the Brazilian football confederation for marketing rights to the domestic football championship.
Klefer signed the contract together with Traffic - a Brazilian sports marketing company that US officials are investigating.
In Rio de Janeiro, meanwhile, the Brazilian confederation has ordered the removal of the name of Jose Maria Marin from its lavish building.
Marin (pictured below) was one of the 14 men charged on Wednesday.
21.42
Fifa's response to charge that it is the most corrupt, dishonest sporting body on planet was leaden-footed choreography, pathetic beat boxers and crooning Hugo Chvez lookalike, says Jim White .
One thing we can be sure about regarding where Fifas money has gone: none of it was spent on the opening ceremony of its 65th annual congress.
As seven of its senior executives await extradition to the United States on charges of racketeering, wire fraud and money-laundering conspiracy, Fifa responded by seemingly attempting to restage the Eurovision Song Contest circa 1983.
21.22
Millesh Mohankumar. a reader, has got in touch with this point.
When animals in a circus act violently, it is the circus master who has to take a share of the blame, for losing control over the animals, rather than slamming the animals. Sepp Blatter is trying to hide in broad daylight. Funny how power and greed seizes control over a man's wits.
21.03
It's time for a spot of light-hearted entertainment among all this corruption drama.
While many accusations and arrests have been made something that hasn't happened - or not to our knowledge - was Sepp Blatter visiting a local convenience store and attempting to hide in the stock room - although it does in this cartoon.
&amp;lt;noframes&amp;gt; Sepp Blatter wants to hide somewhere &amp;lt;/noframes&amp;gt;
20.44
A judge in Buenos Aires has ordered the arrest of three Argentine businessmen in connection with the Fifa corruption scandal following a US extradition request.
Judge Marcelo Martinez de Giorgi says he has issued arrest orders for Alejandro Burzaco, the president of Argentine sports marketing firm Torneos y Competencias, as well as Mariano and Hugo Jinkis, the owners of Argentina-based sports media business Full Play.
The judge added that Interpol "is working" on his request.
The three men are accused of bribing officials at the Conmebol and CONCACAF confederations for TV and marketing rights of continental tournaments.
20.26
The United Nations says it is reviewing its partnerships with Fifa and monitoring "very carefully" the ongoing situation.
A spokesman for the UN secretary-general said the UN had not been contacted in any way relating to the US and Swiss federal investigations.
Stephane Dujarric said the UN has had a number of one-time partnerships with Fifa and that all have been pro bono. He says the UN does not have an exclusive partnership with the organisation.
He says the partnerships are based on "ensuring that the UN's message on peace, on tolerance are seen and heard within these major sports events."
20.10
Jim White has reflected on a time when the English FA were happy to play Fifa's game.
Watching the Three Lions play a month ago, watching the efforts of the eager but hopelessly outmanoeuvred trio to do their bit for their country, was to be reminded of one of the least edifying episodes in English football history. This was the time we tried to play Sepp Blatters game and lost.
Three Lions reminds us it was the FA who encouraged the Prince, Prime Minister and Posh Spouse to embarrass themselves by shaking hands with the most venal bunch of sporting administrators since the Emperor Caligulas Coliseum Organising Committee. You can only hope they counted their fingers afterwards.
Prince William, David Cameron and David Beckham tried to bring the World Cup back to England
The most revolting truth of all: Prince William  naively keen to do his bit for his country  gave a private audience to Jack Warner. The future monarch was thus plunged into the grotesque circus of sycophancy designed to bolster the swollen egos of Blatters former right-hand mobster. How thrilled must Warner have been to look a representative of his former colonial masters in the eye and lie to him about supporting the English bid. He would have enjoyed that almost as much as he loves counting his ill-gotten lucre.
19.49
There are still a few calls for tomorrow's presidential election to be postponed - although at this stage now it seems highly unlikely.
So @nacional president Eduardo Ache says #Uruguay will look to propose a delay in the FIFA vote.
 Juan Arango (@JuanG_Arango) May 28, 2015
19.35
One of the lawyers acting for Nicolas Leoz doesn't appear to be convinced of his client's innonence. Instead of coming out with a line saying how his man will clear his name or something else along those lines, Ricardo Preda has instead claimed Leoz, the ailing ex-president of the South American Football Confederation, can't go to prison because of his poor health!
Leoz is said to have been hospitalised in his native Paraguay on Wednesday after learning of the case against him. The 86-year-old has heart problems and Parkinson's disease.
A Paraguayan judge began processing the US extradition request for Leoz yesterday, asking prosecutors to set a date for an initial court hearing.
19.13
There's plenty of people within football who are still willing to openly support Sepp Blatter including Miroslav Blaevi Bosnian Croat football manager .
?iro Bla?evi? defends Blatter and calls him positive character. Not surprised.
 Saa Ibrulj (@sasaibrulj) May 28, 2015
19.07
This scandal hasn't only shocked and engulfed the world of football. Tennis' super heavyweight players have been having their say on all things Sepp Blatter and it's not happy reading for Mr President.
Rafael Nadal , who is attempting to win a 10th French Open title in Paris, believes that for Blatter to have been Fifa president since 1998 breeds an unhealthy environment in the sport.
My thought is it is good to have combinations, in politics, in sport, in the world in general," he said.
"It's good to have the right people in every place. It's good to have people who know about what they are doing, in football, in tennis, in countries.
"I cannot say that if you are in the same place for a long time you will not be honest, but it's true that history says that is easier to be honest if you are in shorter periods of time.
"You are there and you come back later. The alternating is good in every place of the world, I think."
Murray has had his say on Sepp Blatter and the crisis at Fifa
Britain's No 1 Andy Murray said he wasn't all too surprised about the developments this week.
"I don't know what's going to happen over the next few days. But when I read the stories, I haven't had anyone come up to me and say it was very surprising.
"But I think it's good for sport in a way when that stuff happens, because people have kind of talked about it for a long time.
"People have suggested that there was some corruption going on there. So now they are going to do a proper investigation into it and see what happens after that."
18.56
With Fifa sponsors reconsidering their positions in light of the last 36 hours, here's a recap on who Fifa still have standing by their side. Which ones will remain in the coming days though?
18.42
CONCACAF have appointed senior vice president Alfredo Hawit in place of provisionally suspended Jeffrey Webb.
Webb was THE highest-profiled executive arrested in the dawn raids at a Zurich hotel yesterday.
CONCACAF has also formed a three-man special committee composed of Sunil Gulati, Justino Compean and Victor Montaglianithe presidents of USA, Mexico and Canadian federations, to oversee its business operations in the wake of the indictments.
Hawit has been a caretaker manager before. Four years ago he stepped in after CONCACAF suspended acting president Lisle Austin for trying to fire then-General Secretary Chuck Blazer.
Webb has been provisionally suspended by CONCACAF
18.26
Thomas Bach, who knows a thing or two about heading up a powerful organisation, has urged Fifa to shed "full light" on the corruption allegations they are facing.
Bach, the president of the International Olympic Committee (IOC), acknowledged these are "sad and difficult days" when he spoke at congress earlier.
"I would very much like to encourage you to continue and strengthen your co-operation with the relevant authorities to shed full light on the concerned methods and to take all necessary measures to address such grave allegations," he said.
18.15
So with the presidential election still going ahead tomorrow, let's have a look at how the voting process works.
First and foremost Sepp Blatter the main man, the favourite to retain his post despite this week's developments, should address the Fifa Congress. His rival Prince Ali Bin Al Hussein, whose support is starting to gather pace, will also have an opportunity to speak.
Each of Fifa's 209 associations should have a vote, although a few can face disqualification for reasons such as not playing in competitions.
If either candidate wins two thirds of the vote in the first round they win outright. If there are 209 votes, 139 will be the key number for victory.
If there's no outright winner in round one, the winner will be whoever gains more votes in the second round. Got it?
The stage is getting set for election day
17.55
So with Ollie having computer difficulties it's up to me, Vicki Hodges to take over proceedings for the next few hours at least. I've been liveblogging Andy Murray's French Open win, so what have I missed? Ah, Sepp Blatter saying how the events have cast a shadow over Fifa. Haven't we heard that one before. It was certainly a different line to the one the Fifa spokesman was rattling out yesterday about how it was "good for Fifa". How in the world can you spin this one, really?
17.50
Intriuguingly, investigative journalist, Andrew Jennings, says that Sepp Blatter is in the FBI's crosshairs:
I gave the FBI the crucial documents that triggered yesterday's arrests. There will be more to come. Blatter is a target.
 Andrew Jennings (@AAndrewJennings) May 28, 2015
17.50
Having a few technical issues, apologies about lack of updates in the last 30 minutes.
17.15
Never heard of Sepp Blatter? Where have you been? Still, I'm sure if you have you could still find out something new in this handy box out:
17.10
This just in from the Telegraph's chief US Correspondent, Philip Sherwell.
Chuck Blazer, the former Fifa executive whose reported role as FBI informant is believed to be central to the US investigation, may have co-operated with law enforcement, but he has nothing to say publicly right now.
The New York Times tracked down the seriously-ill 70-year-old to his Manhattan hospital room. Blazer was following the drama in Switzerland via emails on his smartphone, but did not want to discuss his role in the drama .
I cant talk, he mouthed to the reporter. In a follow-up a phone call, a lawyer for Blazer confirmed: We have no comment.
Blazer faces up to 15 years in prison after secretly pleading guilty in 2013 to a series of charges, including racketeering, wire fraud, money laundering and income tax evasion. But his sentence is likely to be substantially reduced in return for his role as a co-operating witness in the plea deal.
Blazer was the long-time deputy to Jack Warner at Concacaf, footballs regional governing body, but the two men later fell out. He allegedly received $750,000 from the South African government in return for backing its 2010 World Cup bid.
Blazer was a larger than life figure who enjoyed the high life, renting an apartment for his cats next to his Manhattan penthouse, as he earned a reported $21 million in fees, commissions and pay from Concacaf.
He was confronted over unpaid taxes by federal agents as he made his way to a meal in 2011 at a celebrity restaurant on one of the motorised scooters that he used to transport his bulky frame. We can take you away in handcuffs now or you can co-operate, the agents told him, according to the New York Daily News .
16.57
So what do people think on social media? Well, put it this way: Blatter doesn't have many fans.
Blatter going with the '14 rogue officials' defence which has proven so successful in the past in other industries
 Neil Watkins (@Neil_Watkins) May 28, 2015
Blatter says he "wasn't aware of any corruption". Even if that is true (which it isn't) he should still resign for being unfit to do the job
 Triangle Passing (@TrianglePassing) May 28, 2015
The next FIFA cover has been released http://t.co/C0E8need8b | https://t.co/dEq176ioy1 pic.twitter.com/DMYuID880P
 Global_00 Comedy (@illucomedy_00) May 28, 2015
OK, he has one fan (with tongue firmly in cheek, one suspects):
Give a Blatter another 4 years he's great
 Liam Red (@ginge_lfc_5) May 28, 2015
16.50
Want that Blatter transcript in full? Read it here .
16.37
Some reaction on Twitter now
Vintage Blatter this: blaming others, blaming society, even though #fifa scandal is taking place on his watch.
 Henry Winter (@henrywinter) May 28, 2015
Groucho Marx would have had a field day with a deluded president like Sepp Blatter. "For the world! For peace!" For heaven's sake. #fifa
 Henry Winter (@henrywinter) May 28, 2015
Reminder of Blatter response to media reports of corruption after 2018/22 vote: "There are no rotten eggs. We are financially clean &amp; clear"
 Oliver Kay (@OliverKayTimes) May 28, 2015
16.39
Ben Rumsby has banged out an almost complete transcript,
You will agree with me, these are unprecedented and difficult times for Fifa. The events of yesterday have cast a long shadow over football and over this weeks congress. Actions of individuals, if proven, bring shame and humiliation on football and demand action and change from us all. We cannot allow the reputation of football and Fifa to be dragged through the mud any longer. It has to stop here and now. I know many people hold me ultimately responsible for the actions and reputation of the global football community, whether its a decision for the hosting of the World Cup, or a corruption scandal.
We, or I, cannot monitor everyone all of the time. If people want to do wrong, they will also try to hide it. But it must fall to me to bear the responsibility for the reputation and wellbeing of our organisation and to find a way forward to fix things. I will not allow the actions of a few to destroy the hard work and integrity of the vast majority of those who work so hard for football. I must stress that those who are corrupt in football are in a thin minority, like in society. But, like in society, they must be caught and held responsible for their actions.
Football cannot be the exception to the rule. That is our responsibility as Fifa and we will co-operate with all authorities to make sure than anyone involved in wrongdoing, from top to bottom, is discovered and punished. There can be no place for corruption of any kind. The next few months will not be easy for Fifa. Im sure more bad news may follow. But it is necessary to begin to restore trust in our organisation. Let this be the turning point. More needs to be done to make sure everyone in football to make sure everyone behaves responsibility and ethically, and everywhere also outside of the field of play, where there is no referee, no boundaries and no time limit.
Football, the fans, the players, the clubs, the world, deserves so much more and we must respond. Tommorrow, the congress, we have the opportunity to begin on what will be a long and difficult road to rebuilding trust. We have lost that trust, at least a part of it, and we must now earn it back. We must earn it back through the decisions we make, through the expectations we place on each other and through the way we behave individually. The vast majority, we are all in football and we like this game, not for greed, not for exploitation, not for power, but the cause of love for the game, for this game.
16.29
Seemingly Blatter, washing his hands of any involvement, thinks that it is his duty to fix the situation, rather than resign / not run for election tomorrow:
Actions of individuals bring shame and humiliation on football and demand action and change from us all. We cannot allow the reputation of Fifa and football to be dragged through the mud, it has to stop here and now. I know many people hold me ultimately responsible for actions of football's governing community. I cannot monitor everyone all of the time, if people want to do wrong they will also try to hide. But it must fall to me for the responsibility for organisation and find a way to fix things. I cannot monitor everyone all of the time.
16.25
Blatter, who evidently has no intention of stepping down, finishes up by saying let's "enjoy the show". Wow.
On other subjects, in comments which will not appease critics, he said: "We have lost trust, we must now earn it back.
"I'm sure more bad news will follow ... but we must restore trust. Let this be the turning point."
You've got to hand it to Blatter. It's like we've never been here before. #fifa
 Ben Rumsby (@ben_rumsby) May 28, 2015
16.20
16.16
Blatter is on, he is speaking to the congress ...
He starts: "Dear friends, you will agree with me that these are unpresendented and difficult times for Fifa. The events of yesterday have cast a long shadow over Fifa and football."
IOC president Thomas Bach is present in the room. Wonder what he makes of all this...?
 Ben Rumsby (@ben_rumsby) May 28, 2015
Earlier the scene was rather celebratory:
Blatter now speaking: We are all united tonight for the opening of the 65th congress of Fifa. Erm... #fifa
 Ben Rumsby (@ben_rumsby) May 28, 2015
16.11
More news on sponsors ...
According to Bloomberg's Gerrit De Vynck "BCE Inc. and Bank of Nova Scotia, two Canadian sponsors of Fifa, said they are keeping a close eye on the U.S. corruption probe with just a week to go before the Womens World Cup kicks off in Canada".
De Vynck adds: "BCE, known by its brand name Bell, has broadcast rights to the womens tournament as well as the 2018 and 2022 mens World Cups. Scotiabank sponsors events held by FIFAs North American and Caribbean organizing body, known as CONCACAF."
16.07
More from Gill. After Platini did not rule out the possibility of a World Cup boycott by European countries if Blatter wins tomorrow's election, but Gill said that it would be wrong to make the fans suffer.
He said: "That's a discussion to be had by everyone in Uefa.
"All the options will be looked at but ultimately it's for the fans. The fans like the World Cup, the fans like the big games so that's to me a measure of last resort and I don't think we will get there.
"We should ensure the World Cup goes on, we had a great World Cup last summer - apart from for England - and we need to move on so let's see what other avenues are open. Why should the fans and the players suffer because of maladministration - I don't think they should."
15.50
And Blatter, who is supposed to be addressing Fifa to open the congress later on today, has just been spotted getting out of a car. No luxury bed clothes around him. At least not yet. Will he speak publically? We shall see.
15.45
Big news from Zurich as David Gill the FA vice-chairman and former Manchester United chief executive, confirms he will refuse to take up Britain's Fifa vice-presidency if Sepp Blatter is re-elected as president tomorrow. ,
"Seismic events happened yesterday and if he [Blatter] can't see the enormity of what has happened and resign then I recognise that to be on that body would be futile," he said.
"I don't think that is right for me and more importantly I don't think that's right for UEFA and football."
Gill believes the only other challenger in Friday's election - Prince Ali Bin Al Hussein of Jordan - is a worthy candidate.
"In Prince Ali we have a very credible and plausible candidate who can take FIFA forward and I would be delighted to work for him in a new FIFA," Gill added.
15.39
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:48:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baghdad bombs kill at least 10</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bda2d3/sc/11/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0C116374840CBaghdad0Ebombs0Ekill0Eat0Eleast0E10A0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Suicide bombs explode near two of Baghdad's leading hotels</Description>
        <MainBody>Baghdad bombs kill at least 10
Suicide bombs explode near two of Baghdad's leading hotels
Smoke rises from the site of a car bomb attack in BaghdadPhoto: REUTERS
By AFP
12:48AM BST 29 May 2015
Car bombs exploded Thursday near two of Baghdad's most high-profile hotels, killing at least 10 people and wounding another 27.
The explosions occurred just before midnight (2100 GMT) and were heard across the city centre. According to police and an interior ministry source, at least 13 people were also wounded.
The first explosion went off near the Babylon hotel, a refurbished hotel overlooking the Tigris river.
Then a second car bomb exploded a few minutes later in an area close to the Ishtar - another recently renovated hotel that is still often referred to as the Sheraton - and a popular club which is usually crowded at that time on a Thursday.
Smoke rises from the site of a car bomb attack in Baghdad (REUTERS)
The Palestine hotel - which has been hit by various deadly attacks over the years - is also close to the site of the second blast.
Police said security forces found another car bomb in the Babylon hotel car park and were attempting to defuse it.
A years-old midnight curfew was lifted in February after Iraqi forces retook areas around Baghdad from the Islamic State (IS) jihadist group and a huge car bomb-making cell was dismantled.
Attacks have continued since but are less frequent than the previous year.
The Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (Isil), which is still battling government forces barely 30 kilometres (18 miles) west of the capital, has claimed many of the biggest attacks in Baghdad and elsewhere in the country.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:19:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New York Socialite jailed for 18 years for killing autistic son</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bda2d4/sc/42/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C116374660CNew0EYork0ESocialite0Ejailed0Efor0E180Eyears0Efor0Ekilling0Eautistic0Eson0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Gigi Jordan convicted of first degree manslaughter for killing son in Manhattan hotel</Description>
        <MainBody>New York Socialite jailed for 18 years for killing autistic son
Gigi Jordan convicted of first degree manslaughter for killing son in    Manhattan hotel
Gigi Jordan, a wealthy New York socialitePhoto: REUTERS
By Reuters
12:19AM BST 29 May 2015
A wealthy New York socialite was sentenced to 18 years in prison on Thursday after being convicted of killing her young autistic son at a luxury Manhattan hotel room in 2010.
Gigi Jordan, 54, was convicted of first-degree manslaughter in November after admitting that she administered an overdose of prescription pills to eight-year-old Jude Mirra at the Peninsula Hotel on Fifth Avenue, using a crusher and syringe.
Jordan's attorneys argued throughout the two-month trial that she had killed the boy in an act of mercy to prevent the boy's biological father from sexually abusing him, a scenario that prosecutors said was based on fiction.
Judge Charles Solomon of the state Supreme Court in Manhattan handed down a sentence that was close to the maximum of 25 years in prison under New York guidelines, saying he was mystified by the mother's lack of remorse.
"It's very difficult for me to understand the defendant," Solomon said. "I certainly would think that I would hear something from the defendant expressing remorse about what she did - something."
In a 30-minute statement read to the court, Jordan appealed for leniency and again said she had been acting in her son's best interests.
Gigi Jordan (REUTERS)
"I love Jude more than anything in this world," the former pharmaceuticals executive and self-made millionaire said in a 30-minute statement. "I believe that he lived and died in unbelievable agony."
At her trial last year, the jury accepted the defense's claim that Jordan had acted under extreme emotional distress, finding her guilty of manslaughter rather than the top murder charge sought by prosecutors.
Even though Mirra was unable to express himself well, Jordan's attorneys argued, he had told his mother that he was being sexually abused by his father, Emil Tzekov.
Tzekov, a yoga instructor who became Jordan's second ex-husband, has denied the accusations.
Jordan said she feared she would be unable to protect her boy because her first husband, Philadelphia businessman Raymond Mirra Jr., planned to have her killed or institutionalized, and Tzekov would gain custody of her son.
Prosecutors argued that Jordan carefully planned the death of her son after traveling the country to find a cure for his autism. They said that Jordan killed her son because she could not accept that he was disabled and she could not fix his medical condition.
Outside of court, Jordan's attorney, Norman Siegel, expressed disappointment with the sentence and said Jordan would appeal.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:09:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Royal Navy ship HMS Bulwark rescues 300 migrants</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bce2e0/sc/40/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cuknews0C116373820CRoyal0ENavy0Eship0EHMS0EBulwark0Erescues0E30A0A0Emigrants0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>British Naval ship HMS Bulwark has rescued over 300 migrants crammed into a wooden boat</Description>
        <MainBody>Royal Navy ship HMS Bulwark rescues 300 migrants
British Naval ship HMS Bulwark has rescued over 300 migrants crammed into a    wooden boat
By Telegraph video, and PA, video source Ministry    of Defence
10:09PM BST 28 May 2015
A British naval ship has rescued more than 300 migrants crammed into a wooden boat in the Mediterranean.
HMS Bulwark intercepted the endangered ship as it attempted to cross waters north of Libya and dispatched five landing craft to its aid.
Among the hundreds saved were 50 small children.
Over 300 migrants were crammed onto a small wooden boat
The Royal Navy ship saved 369 people in total and will now be used to help transport more than 800 stranded migrants to points of safety.
Defence Secretary Michael Fallon praised the efforts of the crew, but stressed there was work left to be done.
Among the hundreds saved were 50 small children
He said: "HMS Bulwark and her crew have once again saved hundreds of lives in the Mediterranean migrant crisis, offering medical assistance, food, water and dry clothes to those in need.
"A wider political solution is required to this crisis, but that does not detract from today's rescue at sea."
Migrants transfer from a landing craft
Prime Minister David Cameron sent Bulwark to alleviate the growing crisis of treacherous migrant crossings earlier this month, after more than 800 people died on a boat travelling from Libya.
It is a flagship of the Royal Navy and was involved in one of five rescue operations that took place today - which included Italian, German and Irish naval units.
HMS Bulwark's Commanding Officer Captain Nick Cooke-Priest, said: "My sailors and marines have once again demonstrated great skill, sense and adaptability, and have carried out the task with complete success.
"I have no doubt that we have again, today, saved hundreds of lives; some horrifyingly young."
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:41:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Pentagon release footage of coalition air strikes in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bce2e1/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cislamic0Estate0C116373630CThe0EPentagon0Erelease0Efootage0Eof0Ecoalition0Eair0Estrikes0Ein0ESyria0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Footage purporting to show air strikes on Islamic State targets in Syria has been released by The Pentagon</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State
The Pentagon release footage of coalition air strikes in Syria
Footage purporting to show air strikes on Islamic State targets in Syria has    been released by The Pentagon
By Telegraph video, and Reuters, video source ITN
9:41PM BST 28 May 2015
Footage has been released by The Pentagon which they say shows air strikes on Islamic State targets in Syria.
The footage shows one strike against an Islamic State armoured vehicle and another on an Isil flighting position near al Hasaka on May 18.
Since early Wednesday, the U.S.-led coalition has staged 26 air strikes targeting Islamic State militants in Syria and Iraq, according to the Combined Joint Task Force leading the air operations.
In Iraq, 20 air strikes struck near 10 cities, including five near Mosul, three by Falluja and one near Ramadi, the task force said in a statement released on Thursday.
Six air strikes in Syria targeted areas near al Hasaka and Dayr az Zawr, it said.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:51:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State gives tour of captured jail where Assad's men tortured prisoners</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bc3a53/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cislamic0Estate0C116368280CIslamic0EState0Egives0Etour0Eof0Ecaptured0Ejail0Ewhere0EAssads0Emen0Etortured0Eprisoners0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Shocking footage of horrific conditions inside Palmyra prison where inmates were often held for years in the dark</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State
Islamic State gives tour of captured jail where Assad's men tortured prisoners
Shocking footage of horrific conditions inside Palmyra prison where inmates    were often held for years in the dark
By Louisa Loveluck, Middle East Correspondent
8:51PM BST 28 May 2015
The Islamic State (Isil) has released a video revealing the gruelling conditions inside the Syrian regimes notorious prison at Palmyra.
The facility fell under the extremists control last week, after they seized the central Syrian city and its world famous Roman ruins.
As viewers are taken on a cruise through the abandoned prison yard, only birdsong breaks the stillness. But inside the facility, echoes of its chilling past are on full view. Its tiny cells are pitch black and filthy, with a small hole in the corner in place of a toilet.
 Islamic State secures third powerbase of Ramadi with visit from group's No.2
.
Faraj Bayrakdar, a Syrian poet who spent four years inside the prisons walls, once described it as a kingdom of death and madness. The institution gained notoriety after news of a prison massacre seeped out in 1980, following an assassination attempt on then-president, Hafez al-Assad, the father of Syrias embattled leader Bashar.
The day after the attempted attack, the president's brother ordered his paramilitaries to enter the jail and butcher its prisoners. More than a thousand people are believed to have been killed in the cells, dormitories and corridors
The Isil video, released on Thursday, showed Mr Assads name still printed on the wall of one cell, apparently used for holding prisoners en masse.
That prison and what is represents is indelibly etched on the mind of every Syrian who lived during those terrible days of the 80s and 90s, said Amr al-Azm, a former Syrian antiquities official and now a professor at Shawnee State University in Ohio. We talk so much about the majestic ruins, but this prison is also a part of Palmyras history.
On Wednesday, Isil shot dead around 20 men in the citys Roman amphitheatre, accusing them of being government supporters, according to a monitoring group.
But in its propaganda, Isil portrays itself as a liberator, releasing photographs of prisoners it reportedly sprang from the Palmyra prison. The Islamic State has taken Tadmor (Palmyra) Prison, a liberation for the Arab world, tweeted one of the groups sympathisers on Friday.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:45:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Barcelona mayor-in-waiting threatens Formula 1 funding</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bc3a5a/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cspain0C116370A770CBarcelona0Emayor0Ein0Ewaiting0Ethreatens0EFormula0E10Efunding0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Ada Colau, whose anti-austerity coalition won the most seats in Sunday's regional election, said she may end the 4 million euro subsidy the city gives to the Montmeló racing circuit, home to the Spanish Grand Prix</Description>
        <MainBody>Spain
Barcelona mayor-in-waiting threatens Formula 1 funding
Ada Colau, whose anti-austerity coalition won the most seats in Sunday's    regional election, said she may end the 4 million euro subsidy the city    gives to the Montmel racing circuit, home to the Spanish Grand Prix
Nico Rosbergof  Mercedes GP crosses the finish line to win the 2015 Spanish F1 Grand Prix at Circuit de Catalunya Photo: Getty Images
James Badcock in Madrid
8:45PM BST 28 May 2015
The winner of last Sunday's local election in Barcelona has threatened to end a 4 million (2.9m) subsidy the council pays to the city's Montmel racing circuit, home to the Spanish Grand Prix.
Ada Colau, who is expected to be selected as mayor in June after her Left-wing Barcelona en Com coalition won the most council seats , said (on Wednesday) that "in the current context of social emergency, subsidising Formula One is not a priority".
The city council signed a deal in 2012 under which the company which runs Montmel receives the subsidy for incorporating the name Barcelona into its brand. Colau, who became known for her activities as an anti-poverty activist in crisis-hit Spain , said the cost of reversing cuts made to school meal subsidies for Barcelona's poorest families over the last year could be covered by pulling out of the Montmel deal.
Ada Colau speaks during a political meeting in Barcelona
"Is the priority guaranteeing school meal grants with 4.5 million or spending four million on Formula One?" Colau said.
Barcelona en Com, which is backed by Spain's anti-austerity party Podemos , confirmed on Thursday that it would consider terminating the Montmel Barcelona circuit sponsorship deal.
But according to Felip Puig, the Catalan regional government counselor for business and employment, Colau could be about to make a mistake which would harm the viability of the circuit and cost Barcelona jobs. "Before she takes a decision, she should look at the repercussion this investment in the circuit has," Puig said, claiming that the services and jobs the Formula One circuit brings to the city is worth an annual 200 million.
"I ask her to sit down and talk about the impact of such a move before she takes aim at the racing circuit. If you remove this money, you are going to put a lot of people out in the street."
Nico Rosberg leads at the 2015 Spanish Formula One Grand Prix at Circuit de Catalunya
On top of the city council subsidy, the Catalan regional government gives the largely state-owned circuit 6 million each year, with a further 2 million coming from Barcelona's provincial authority. Montmel has a deal to host the Spanish Grand prix until 2019.
Colau has also questioned Barcelona's continued hosting of the Mobile World Congress, whose 10th edition in March was attended by Mark Zuckerberg among a host of technology gurus. She has said the event should have a year-round impact on the city and create better-quality employment.
The Barcelona en Com leader also has plans for the city's property sector. According to the coalition's manifesto, all major developments underway in the city will be reappraised in terms of their social utility, while large housing projects will have to include 20 per cent portions of social housing. Colau is also targeting 10,000 empty homes to offer shelter to the poor and promises a moratorium on evictions for families who cannot meet their mortgage demands.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:35:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman meets man with dead brother's face</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bc2b83/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C116372750CWoman0Emeets0Eman0Ewith0Edead0Ebrothers0Eface0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The sister of Joshua Aversano recognised his face after it was transplanted on to disfigured Richard Norris</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman meets man with dead brother's face
The sister of Joshua Aversano recognised his face after it was transplanted on    to disfigured Richard Norris
By Nick Allen, Los Angeles
8:35PM BST 28 May 2015
A woman has met with the man who received her late brother's face in a rare transplant operation .
Three years ago Joshua Aversano, 21, was knocked down and killed while crossing the road.
His face was donated to Richard Norris, who had suffered severe facial disfigurement after accidentally shooting himself in 1997 when he was 22.
A meeting between Rebekah Aversano, Mr Aversano's sister, and Mr Norris in the United States was filmed by 60 Minutes Australia.
The meeting between Rebekah Aversano and the man who received her late brother's face was emotional Picture: 9News Australia
Miss Aversano touched Mr Norris's features and said: "Wow, this is the face I grew up with."
The 36-hour face transplant operation took place in March 2012 took at University of Maryland Medical Centre.
Mr Aversano's family say they were happy Joshua was able to help face transplant recipient Richard Norris Picture: 9News Australia
There was only a 50 per cent chance of survival.
Mr Norris, now 39, from Virginia, was later featured with his new face on the cover of GQ magazine.
The full story on the emotional reunion is due to air on 60 Minutes in Australia this weekend Picture: 9News Australia
Mr Aversano's mother Gwen Aversano, from Maryland, told CTV News: "We can definitely see our son in him. We can see the similarities very much so.
"We are just so pleased we have been able to help him. Even though we had such a tragic loss, we were able to give someone else the benefit of our son."
The full meeting between Mr Norris and Miss Aversano will be shown on 60 Minutes Australia on Sunday.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:24:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Society photographer guilty of swindling hundreds of millions of euros from L'Oreal cosmetics heiress</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bc2b85/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C116371170CSociety0Ephotographer0Eguilty0Eof0Eswindling0Ehundreds0Eof0Emillions0Eof0Eeuros0Efrom0ELOreal0Ecosmetics0Eheiress0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>François-Marie Banier said by judge who sentenced him to three years to have had a "real psychological and moral hold" over 92-year-old Liliane Bettencourt, France's richest woman</Description>
        <MainBody>France
Society photographer guilty of swindling hundreds of millions of euros from L'Oreal cosmetics heiress
Franois-Marie Banier said by judge who sentenced him to three years to    have had a real psychological and moral hold over 92-year-old Liliane    Bettencourt, France's richest woman
From top, L to R) former French Labour minister Eric Woerth, L'Oreal heiress French Liliane Bettencourt, French lawyer Pascal Wilhelm, former financial advisor of Liliane Bettencourt, Patrice de Maistre, French tax lawyer Carlos Vejarano, French businessman Stephane Courbit, French photographer and writer Francois-Marie Banier and Banier's partner photographer Martin d'Orgeval. Photo: AFP/Getty
By Henry Samuel, Paris
8:24PM BST 28 May 2015
A society photographer was on Thursday sentenced to three years in prison for bamboozling Liliane Bettencourt, heir to the LOral cosmetics empire and Frances wealthiest woman , out of hundreds of millions of pounds.
A string of her former advisers were also convicted but the Bordeaux court cleared Eric Woerth, Nicolas Sarkozys former presidential campaign treasurer and budget minister , of taking donations of cash from Mrs Bettencourt before Mr Sarkozys 2007 election. Mr Woerth was also cleared of charges of influence-peddling.
Photographer Franois-Marie Banier, 67, former confidant of the ailing Mrs Bettencourt  who once said he was the only man who made her laugh  was found guilty of abusing the weakness of the doyenne, now 92 and suffering from Alzheimers disease.
Banier was sentenced to three years in prison, with six months suspended, a 250,000 fine and 100 million in damages.
Lillian Bettencourt
Mr Woerth had also been accused of misusing his position of influence to secure favours from Mrs Bettencourts wealth manager, by urging him to employ his wife in exchange for receiving the Legion of Honour, Frances highest decoration. He was cleared of all charges.
The Bettencourt affair erupted more than seven years ago in the form of a family feud between mother and daughter, but it morphed into a political scandal amid allegations of tax evasion and illegal party funding .
These came to the fore after Mrs Bettencourts butler secretly recorded her conversations with her entourage. In one, the deaf and confused heiress was asked by Patrice de Maistre, her wealth manager, to hand over a million euros for the yacht of my dreams.
In 2007, Mrs Bettencourts daughter, Francoise Bettencourt-Meyers, launched legal action against Banier, a Paris socialite, saying he had taken advantage of her mothers confused state to get her to hand over 1 billion in art  including works by Picasso, Matisse and Mondrian  insurance policies and cash.
The case went on to smear Mr Sarkozy, who was placed under formal investigation for illegal campaign financing and taking advantage of Mrs Bettencourt . The charges were later dropped in October 2013 due to lack of evidence.
Banier first met Mrs Bettencourt, 25 years his senior, when he photographed her for a magazine. In court, he claimed he enjoyed her company and had no need of the money.
When her daughter first claimed he was manipulating her, Mrs Bettencourt insisted she could spend her time and money on who she saw fit, briefly making Banier sole heir to her fortune, estimated to be 33 billion (24 billion), by Forbes magazine.
In court, Baniers lawyer conceded he was drowning in gold and the photographer admitted the sums gave even him vertigo but it gave her immense pleasure to shower him with gifts and she got angry when he refused.
The presiding judge, Denis Roucou, said Banier had a real psychological and moral hold over Mrs Bettencourt, whose critical faculties doctors warned were failing as early as 2006.
She found herself at the mercy of men in whom she placed her trust, said the judge.
He had stern words for Mr Woerth despite his acquittal, saying there remained a strong suspicion that money was handed over but that it could not be demonstrated.
Mr de Mestre was sentenced to 18 months in prison for exploiting Mrs Bettencourts frailty and for money laundering, as was her former lawyer.
Martin dOrgeval, Baniers partner, was found guilty on the same charges and received a suspended sentence.
After the verdict, Mrs Bettencourt-Meyers said : My first thought naturally goes to my mother, for her honour and dignity, and then to all her family  ours.
Banier and de Mestre will appeal against the verdicts.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:23:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Yemen TV v Yemen TV: Saudi Arabia steps up propaganda war with copycat media</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bc2b87/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Cyemen0C116372710CYemen0ETV0Ev0EYemen0ETV0ESaudi0EArabia0Esteps0Eup0Epropaganda0Ewar0Ewith0Ecopycat0Emedia0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>With the Houthi rebels having taken over Yemen's state media, the Saudi backers of the exiled government have set up doppelgangers - differing only in their version of events</Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen
Yemen TV v Yemen TV: Saudi Arabia steps up propaganda war with copycat media
With the Houthi rebels having taken over Yemen's state media, the Saudi    backers of the exiled government have set up doppelgangers - differing only    in their version of events
A militiaman loyal to Yemen's fugitive President Abderabbo points at smoke during clashes with Huthi rebels in the city of Aden's Dar SaadPhoto: AFP
By Louisa Loveluck, Cairo
8:23PM BST 28 May 2015
As Saudi Arabia leads airstrikes over Yemen, it has also stepped its propaganda war against the Houthi rebels - with a carbon copy of Yemeni state television.
The Gulf superpower has helped equip and launch two satellite television channels that support Yemens exiled president Abd-Rabbuh Mansur Hadi, as well as an alternative version of the countrys official news agency. One of the channels is identical in appearance to the state broadcaster, having copied its logo and even its name, Yemen TV.
Mr Hadi fled the Yemeni capital, Sanaa, back in March, after Houthi rebels seized full control of government institutions. He now runs his government from Riyadh as its Saudi backers continue a two month-long military campaign against the Houthis.
Two opposing state TV channels are running in Yemen using the same logo
The war has claimed almost two thousand lives since March 19. Thousands more have been injured and the countrys crumbling infrastructure has all but collapsed.
State-owned Yemen TV is in the hands of the Houthis, leaving the government-in-exile - at first - little in the way of supportive coverage. But that changed rapidly after the funding boost from the Gulf. Al-Shar'iyah, which translates as Legitimacy, began test transmission on April 11, launching full operations four days later.
Then came the emergence of the imposter Yemen TV. News broadcasts carry the same logo and introductory sequence as the state channel. But thats where the similarities end - while the original channel now publicises the Houthi version of events, its copycat focuses on Mr Hadi.
The Saba state news agency also has a doppelganger, distinguishable from the original only by its web address.
In Sanaa, residents say the Saudi-backed media is unlikely to be aimed at a domestic audience. They can fund all the channels on [satellite] but fact is no one will watch. Theres no electricity! said Hisham Al-Omeisy, an activist.
As Saudi Arabia has maintained an air and naval blockade on Yemeni territory, gas supplies have run perilously low. Even a five day humanitarian pause was not enough to bring in the necessary aid. Fuel prices have spiked as the casualty count mounts, and some hospitals have been forced to close altogether because they are unable to keep medical supplies refrigerated or perform operations since they cant run backup generators.
The electricity comes on for a maximum of two hours a day, said Mr Omeisy. And when it does, the last thing people think of is television.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:48:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Top Republican presidential contender calls for mandatory ultrasounds before abortion</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bc2b88/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cus0Epolitics0C116371840CTop0ERepublican0Epresidential0Econtender0Ecalls0Efor0Emandatory0Eultrasounds0Ebefore0Eabortion0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Scott Walker thinks the move would decrease the number of mothers opting for abortions</Description>
        <MainBody>Top Republican presidential contender calls for mandatory ultrasounds before abortion
Scott Walker thinks the move would decrease the number of mothers opting for    abortions
Wisconsin Gov. Scott WalkerPhoto: AP
By David Lawler, Washington
Comments
A top contender for the Republican presidential nomination has called for mandatory ultrasounds for women seeking abortions.
Scott Walker, the Wisconsin governor who currently sits second in most polls behind Jeb Bush, said in an interview on Wednesday that ultrasounds were "just a cool thing out there".
Mr Walker said that while some dismissed requiring ultrasounds as "a crazy idea", he was proud to have implemented the policy in Wisconsin.
"We just knew if we signed that law, if we provided the information, that more people if they saw that unborn child would make a decision to protect and keep the life of that unborn child," he said on the conservative radio program The Dana Show.
While reducing the frequency of abortions seems to be Mr Walker's primary objective, he also defended the policy on the grounds that ultrasounds themselves were "cool".
"Most people I talk to, whether they're pro-life or not, I find people all the time who'll get out their iPhone and show me a picture of their grandkids' ultrasound and how excited they are, so that's a lovely thing," he said.
Women's rights groups have condemned mandatory ultrasounds on the grounds that they can be expensive and are intended to "shame" women. Despite opposition, many states have passed laws similar to the one Mr Walker signed into law in Wisconsin.
Mr Walker's comments will likely rankle some Republican strategists, who have argued that the party must steer clear of divisive issues like abortion and gay marriage if they hope to be successful in the general election.
Mr Bush himself has said that a fixation with social issues during the 2012 Republican debates hampered Mitt Romney once he became the Republican standard-bearer.
Barack Obama's 12-point advantage among female voters was a decisive factor in his re-election, and was due in part to a perception - aggressively promoted by the Democrats - that the Republican Party was out of touch with women on issues like abortion and access to contraception.
For his part, Mr Walker said that Republicans should not "be afraid to talk about" abortion.
"When you think about Hillary Clinton, and you think about some others on the Left, I think it's reasonable, whether you're pro-life or not to say that taxpayers' dollars shouldn't be spent to support abortion," he said. "Most Americans believe in that."
Cecile Richards, president of Planned Parenthood, responded to the comments in a statement in which she called Mr Walker's position "appalling".
"Women are very clear that forced government ultrasounds are not 'cool,'" she wrote.
Mr Walker has not yet declared his candidacy for the White House, but looks likely to be a formidable opponent for fellow front-runners Jeb Bush and Marco Rubio. A recent poll from Public Policy put him in the lead, five points clear of Mr Rubio.
He has been polling first consistently in the all important state of Iowa, which will host the first primary election contest.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:18:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tory councillor fighting Islamic State tells of battle for Syria</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bc2b89/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Csyria0C116367830CTory0Ecouncillor0Efighting0EIslamic0EState0Etells0Eof0Ebattle0Efor0ESyria0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Macer Gifford, a 28-year-old former currency trader from Oxfordshire, talks about the vicious fighting he took part in with the Kurdish YPG this month as it battled to take Mount Abdulaziz</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria
Tory councillor fighting Islamic State tells of battle for Syria
Macer Gifford, a 28-year-old former currency trader from Oxfordshire, talks    about the vicious fighting he took part in with the Kurdish YPG this month    as it battled to take Mount Abdulaziz
Macer Giffords with the Kurdish militia YPG in north east Syria Photo: Facebook
Follow
A British man fighting with the Kurds in northern Syria has told how his unit managed to push Islamic State back from an important strategic stronghold in a fortnight of vicious fighting  and has called on Britain to do more to help.
Macer Gifford, a 28-year-old former currency trader, left Britain five months ago after growing increasingly horrified at the atrocities committed by Islamic State in Iraq and the Levant (Isil) . With no military experience, speaking no Middle Eastern language, and being neither a Kurd nor a Muslim, he travelled to Syria and after a brief training session took up arms against the jihadists.
On Thursday he spoke with pride of his part in a battle to reclaim Mount Abdulaziz  seen by some as the most significant Kurdish victory since the retaking of Kobane earlier this year, after a four-month siege .
Macer Giffords a car captured from enemy forces
The mountain was one of Isils key strongholds in north-east Syria, from which they could attack the nearby Kurdish city of al-Hasakah and threaten a Kurdish enclave with a population of one million. Isil had three training camps on the mountain, protected by over 6,000 mines, IEDs and booby-traps. Taking part in the battle, Mr Gifford admitted, was very scary  but he was overjoyed at the result.
Hopefully its in good contrast to Isils recent success in Iraq and southern Syria, he said.
The two-week fight to reclaim the mountain began on May 6, and involved several thousand fighters from the YPG  Mr Giffords Kurdish army. He was fighting in a unit that included other Westerners  from Canada, the US and the UK  and was on the front lines alongside the women of the YPJ, the Kurdish womens forces.
We launched a night attack on an Isil camp, he told The Telegraph, having descended from the mountain to seek an internet caf and contact his family back in Oxfordshire.
The Americans had bombed it the night before, but we had no idea what wed encounter when we arrived at 3am. It was very scary being in the back of the APC, heading up the mountain, with the strong smell of diesel and waiting for an RPG to slam into the back of you.
When we got there, there were dead bodies everywhere. You never get used to that. But its part of war.
He was so exhausted, he said, he fell asleep inside an abandoned house  after he had taken an Isil flag as a souvenir.
In the final week of the operation he found himself in the midst of an intense firefight with the jihadists. The Kurds advance was supported by American bombing raids  directed by Western special forces commanders on the ground.
They didnt wear any insignia and I was banned from speaking to them, so Im not sure of the nationality, he said. They were helping to call in the air strikes and were advising the Kurdish commanders.
Macer Giffords on the front line in north east Syria
There was stiff resistance initially, but as the strikes took their toll, Isil began to flee and it turned into a race for the mountains.
During a five-hour gun battle, Mr Gifford smashed his knee against a truck and a Kurdish girl next to him was shot in the stomach.
The horrible thing was that I had to pick up her ammo bag, which was covered in clotted blood, he said. It was a really sobering moment.
The girl was taken to hospital and apparently survived. And throughout the fortnight of fighting, around 50 Kurdish fighters were killed  including one Iranian . The YPG said that over 550 Isil soldiers died. The vast majority ran away.
We cleared the village and there were some tense moments as we walked through the streets, said Mr Gifford. Isil must have abandoned the place shortly after we climbed out of the APCs because they were nowhere to be seen.
When the mountain was finally captured by the YPG, on May 21, there were wild scenes of celebration. Over 200 villages had been freed from Isil control, the YPG said  and the villagers, emerging from their houses, pointed out Isil fighters that had abandoned their uniforms and were trying to blend in with the local population.
In the week since Isil fled, Mr Gifford has been helping the YPG consolidate their positions  digging trenches and establishing lookout points. Initially there was no food and little water, but now the supply convoy has caught up with them.
Macer Giffords helped YPG consolidate their positions
Its wonderful to be on the mountain and see how far the YPG has come since I first joined five months ago, he said.
When I first arrived the canton was overrun with Isil fighters. To think that the whole region has now been liberated fills me with joy and makes the hardships of the past few months well worth it.
He is now planning to return to Oxfordshire, where he will rest, recuperate, and enjoy being able to live life as I choose  rather than being told when to get up, when to sleep, when to go on guard duty and so on.
Isnt he just a war tourist?
I get asked that a lot, he said. But the fact is: when I arrived, the Kurds had more enemies than friends. I had thought to myself, what can I do to help? Im under no illusion that I have swung the military victory  they dont need people, as they have plenty.
But I can draw attention to what they are doing.
A former Conservative councillor, Mr Gifford said David Cameron should do more to support the YPG  giving them arms and training, even if the UK wont send in its own troops.
But most analysts see that as being an unrealistic request.
Its a bit of a hornets nest, said Professor Gareth Stansfield, director of Middle East studies at RUSI, the defence and security think tank. Britain keeps quiet about the YPG because Turkey would object  they see the YPG as being associated with the PKK, which it is against.
Its a diplomatic nightmare, especially when the Western countries dont seem to have much of a Syria policy anyway.
And Professor Stansfield cautioned that the YPGs capacity should not be overestimated, because they were only interested in operating in their own region.
Macer aka Baran Macer shows off his weaponary
It would be ridiculous to expect them to take on Isil in Raqqa or Palmyra , he said.
David Butter, associate fellow at Chatham House and Middle East analyst, agreed.
I dont think British moral support would make any difference, and they certainly wont arm the YPG, he said. They do a good job, and have given an impressive military performance. They talk in language appealing to the West  about womens rights, and education, and liberty. But its certainly not the easy solution.
Mr Gifford remains convinced, however. His work is done, he said, and within a fortnight he will be at home. All the other foreigners from his unit have gone home too.
Now the international community is really getting behind the Kurds  the American air strikes in particular played an essential role  I do think my own country, Britain, could be doing a lot more, he said.
Even political support is needed in the fight against the Islamic State.
The recent successes have been historic but if were going to completely destroy the Islamic State then we need to be offering British help now.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:18:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Briton fighting Islamic State tells of battle for Syria</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bbbd8b/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Csyria0C116367830CBriton0Efighting0EIslamic0EState0Etells0Eof0Ebattle0Efor0ESyria0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Macer Gifford, a 28-year-old former currency trader from Oxfordshire, talks about the vicious fighting he took part in with the Kurdish YPG this month as it battled to take Mount Abdulaziz</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria
Tory councillor fighting Islamic State tells of battle for Syria
Macer Gifford, a 28-year-old former currency trader from Oxfordshire, talks    about the vicious fighting he took part in with the Kurdish YPG this month    as it battled to take Mount Abdulaziz
Macer Giffords with the Kurdish militia YPG in north east Syria Photo: Facebook
Follow
A British man fighting with the Kurds in northern Syria has told how his unit managed to push Islamic State back from an important strategic stronghold in a fortnight of vicious fighting  and has called on Britain to do more to help.
Macer Gifford, a 28-year-old former currency trader, left Britain five months ago after growing increasingly horrified at the atrocities committed by Islamic State in Iraq and the Levant (Isil) . With no military experience, speaking no Middle Eastern language, and being neither a Kurd nor a Muslim, he travelled to Syria and after a brief training session took up arms against the jihadists.
On Thursday he spoke with pride of his part in a battle to reclaim Mount Abdulaziz  seen by some as the most significant Kurdish victory since the retaking of Kobane earlier this year, after a four-month siege .
Macer Giffords a car captured from enemy forces
The mountain was one of Isils key strongholds in north-east Syria, from which they could attack the nearby Kurdish city of al-Hasakah and threaten a Kurdish enclave with a population of one million. Isil had three training camps on the mountain, protected by over 6,000 mines, IEDs and booby-traps. Taking part in the battle, Mr Gifford admitted, was very scary  but he was overjoyed at the result.
Hopefully its in good contrast to Isils recent success in Iraq and southern Syria, he said.
The two-week fight to reclaim the mountain began on May 6, and involved several thousand fighters from the YPG  Mr Giffords Kurdish army. He was fighting in a unit that included other Westerners  from Canada, the US and the UK  and was on the front lines alongside the women of the YPJ, the Kurdish womens forces.
We launched a night attack on an Isil camp, he told The Telegraph, having descended from the mountain to seek an internet caf and contact his family back in Oxfordshire.
The Americans had bombed it the night before, but we had no idea what wed encounter when we arrived at 3am. It was very scary being in the back of the APC, heading up the mountain, with the strong smell of diesel and waiting for an RPG to slam into the back of you.
When we got there, there were dead bodies everywhere. You never get used to that. But its part of war.
He was so exhausted, he said, he fell asleep inside an abandoned house  after he had taken an Isil flag as a souvenir.
In the final week of the operation he found himself in the midst of an intense firefight with the jihadists. The Kurds advance was supported by American bombing raids  directed by Western special forces commanders on the ground.
They didnt wear any insignia and I was banned from speaking to them, so Im not sure of the nationality, he said. They were helping to call in the air strikes and were advising the Kurdish commanders.
Macer Giffords on the front line in north east Syria
There was stiff resistance initially, but as the strikes took their toll, Isil began to flee and it turned into a race for the mountains.
During a five-hour gun battle, Mr Gifford smashed his knee against a truck and a Kurdish girl next to him was shot in the stomach.
The horrible thing was that I had to pick up her ammo bag, which was covered in clotted blood, he said. It was a really sobering moment.
The girl was taken to hospital and apparently survived. And throughout the fortnight of fighting, around 50 Kurdish fighters were killed  including one Iranian . The YPG said that over 550 Isil soldiers died. The vast majority ran away.
We cleared the village and there were some tense moments as we walked through the streets, said Mr Gifford. Isil must have abandoned the place shortly after we climbed out of the APCs because they were nowhere to be seen.
When the mountain was finally captured by the YPG, on May 21, there were wild scenes of celebration. Over 200 villages had been freed from Isil control, the YPG said  and the villagers, emerging from their houses, pointed out Isil fighters that had abandoned their uniforms and were trying to blend in with the local population.
In the week since Isil fled, Mr Gifford has been helping the YPG consolidate their positions  digging trenches and establishing lookout points. Initially there was no food and little water, but now the supply convoy has caught up with them.
Macer Giffords helped YPG consolidate their positions
Its wonderful to be on the mountain and see how far the YPG has come since I first joined five months ago, he said.
When I first arrived the canton was overrun with Isil fighters. To think that the whole region has now been liberated fills me with joy and makes the hardships of the past few months well worth it.
He is now planning to return to Oxfordshire, where he will rest, recuperate, and enjoy being able to live life as I choose  rather than being told when to get up, when to sleep, when to go on guard duty and so on.
Isnt he just a war tourist?
I get asked that a lot, he said. But the fact is: when I arrived, the Kurds had more enemies than friends. I had thought to myself, what can I do to help? Im under no illusion that I have swung the military victory  they dont need people, as they have plenty.
But I can draw attention to what they are doing.
A former Conservative councillor, Mr Gifford said David Cameron should do more to support the YPG  giving them arms and training, even if the UK wont send in its own troops.
But most analysts see that as being an unrealistic request.
Its a bit of a hornets nest, said Professor Gareth Stansfield, director of Middle East studies at RUSI, the defence and security think tank. Britain keeps quiet about the YPG because Turkey would object  they see the YPG as being associated with the PKK, which it is against.
Its a diplomatic nightmare, especially when the Western countries dont seem to have much of a Syria policy anyway.
And Professor Stansfield cautioned that the YPGs capacity should not be overestimated, because they were only interested in operating in their own region.
Macer aka Baran Macer shows off his weaponary
It would be ridiculous to expect them to take on Isil in Raqqa or Palmyra , he said.
David Butter, associate fellow at Chatham House and Middle East analyst, agreed.
I dont think British moral support would make any difference, and they certainly wont arm the YPG, he said. They do a good job, and have given an impressive military performance. They talk in language appealing to the West  about womens rights, and education, and liberty. But its certainly not the easy solution.
Mr Gifford remains convinced, however. His work is done, he said, and within a fortnight he will be at home. All the other foreigners from his unit have gone home too.
Now the international community is really getting behind the Kurds  the American air strikes in particular played an essential role  I do think my own country, Britain, could be doing a lot more, he said.
Even political support is needed in the fight against the Islamic State.
The recent successes have been historic but if were going to completely destroy the Islamic State then we need to be offering British help now.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:53:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State secures third powerbase of Ramadi with visit from group's No.2</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bbbd8e/sc/15/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Ciraq0C116369630CLeader0Eof0Eal0EQaeda0Ein0ESyria0Esays0Eaiming0Eto0Etake0EDamascus0Ein0Einterview0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Top Isil official known as the 'blind judge' makes appearance in Iraqi city of Ramadi, a high-profile gesture to indicate extremists are sealing control of a third powerbase</Description>
        <MainBody>Iraq
Islamic State secures third powerbase of Ramadi with visit from group's No.2
Top Isil official known as the blind judge makes appearance in Iraqi city of    Ramadi, a high-profile gesture to indicate  extremists are sealing control    of a third powerbase
Among the taken cities is Ramadi, a potential gateway to Baghdad (Reuters)
By Louisa Loveluck, Middle East Correspondent
6:53PM BST 28 May 2015
Comments
The Islamic State (Isil) appeared to be sealing control of a third powerbase across Iraq and Syria on Thursday, sending one of its most senior religious leaders to address residents in the recently captured city of Ramadi.
The Iraqi city, which fell to a fierce assault by Isil on May 17, is the third provincial capital to be captured by the extremists since their lightning sweep through the two states last year.
Ramadi residents said a man with one hand and a shrouded head delivered a victory speech from Ramadis Grand Mosque after evening prayers on Wednesday. The speech reportedly included a promise to the citys Sunni residents that they would not be harmed.
Hisham al-Hashimi, an Iraqi government advisor who monitors Isil, identified the man as Ali Attiya al-Jubouri, also known as Abu Asim, or the blind judge of the Islamic State.
Isil parades its troops in Ramadi as it celebrates victory over Iraqs 'Golden Brigade'
He described Mr Jubouri as the second-highest religious authority after Isils leader, Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi, and the fifth most senior official in the group. Mr Baghdadi himself is believed to have been incapacitated with spinal injuries since his convoy was hit by a US-led coalition airstrike on 18 March.
The capture of Ramadi was Isils most significant military victory in a year, dealing a heavy blow to the beleaguered Baghdad government. The appearance of such a senior official in a newly captured provincial capital suggested that Isil wanted to send a high-profile message of control, even as a thousands of mostly Iran-backed Shia paramilitaries lead an offensive to retake the city.
Iraqi government forces have also been deployed, following their collapse in the face of the extremists assault on Ramadi. Troops fled the city after Isils deadly rout, which began with as many as ten car bombs.
Refugees from Ramadi on the outskirts of Baghdad. Around 40,000 people have fled the advance of Isil into the city (Reuters)
But the militants have mounted a deadly defence, unleashing a wave of suicide attacks targeting pro-government troops in western Anbar. As many as 17 soldiers were killed in the explosions that took place outside the Isil-held town of Fallujah on Wednesday.
On Thursday, US defence secretary Ash Carter told reporters that the Pentagon is examining ways of better equipping and training Iraqs security forces. Mr Carter had previously criticised Baghdads troops of lacking the will to fight.
The push for Ramadi follows the Iraqi militarys prolonged and bloody recapture the city of Tikrit. The offensive, which eventually succeeded with the backing of the US-led coalitions air power, has allowed Iraqi authorities to begin exhuming the bodies of soldiers killed in what has become known as the Speicher massacre, an event now seared on the countrys Shia population.
In June 2014, Isil gunned down as many as 1700 young army recruits, most of them Shia. Some were pushed into the Tigris river, others hastily buried in the mass graves that continue to be uncovered by government workers.
Iraqs health minister said on Thursday that they had exhumed 470 bodies to date. Adila Hammoud told a press conference that the corpses had been lain several layers thick. The work to exhume Speicher victims continues, said Mr Hammoud.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:33:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Missing Tajikistan police chief defects to the Islamic State</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bb7b02/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Ctajikistan0C116365290CMissing0ETajikistan0Epolice0Echief0Edefects0Eto0Ethe0EIslamic0EState0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Colonel Gulmurod Khalimov told his wife he was going on a business trip when he disappeared in April. Now he has resurfaced in a propaganda video for the jihadist group</Description>
        <MainBody>Tajikistan
Missing Tajikistan police chief defects to the Islamic State
Colonel Gulmurod Khalimov told his wife he was going on a business trip when    he disappeared in April. Now he has resurfaced in a propaganda video for the    jihadist group
James Kilner
6:33PM BST 28 May 2015
The missing chief of Tajikistan's paramilitary police force has surfaced in an Islamic State video as a defector to the extremist group, a month after telling his wife he was going on a business trip.
In a propaganda victory for the jihadists, Colonel Gulmurod Khalimov appears in the video sitting cross-legged next to three other fighters and explains that he fled the impoverished former Soviet state because of restrictions it has imposed on Muslims.
He also says that he wants to kill Westerners and spread Sharia law.
"Listen, Americans you pigs. I've been three times to America, and I saw how you train fighters to kill Muslims," he says. "God willing, I will come with this weapon to your cities, your homes, and kill you."
 Video shows militia fighters' attack on key Islamic State-held oil refinery
Dressed in black and wearing a new beard, Colonel Khalimov, who disappeared on April 23, cradles a sniper rifle. The 40-year-old is considered an expert shot in Tajikistan and at the end of the 12-minute video he shows off his skills by shooting a tomato.
For both the West and Tajikistan, Colonel Khalimov's defection is something of a headache.
Tajik President Imomali Rakhmon hand-picked him to head his OMON paramilitary police force used to quash domestic unrest. He has been involved in operations against Islamic extremists and had also been a member of the presidential guard.
And Colonel Khamilov had a personal message for his former boss.
"Listen, you dogs, the president and ministers, if only you knew how many of our boys, our brothers are here, waiting, eager to return to Tajikistan to re-establish sharia law," he said.
Tajikistan, which borders Afghanistan, has hosted NATO and Russian forces over the past few years and Islamic State may be able to pick Colonel Khalimov's knowledge for important intelligence.rip.
Isil has been targeting Central Asia as a fertile recruitment ground. Governments in the region, which is major oil and gas producer, have said they are struggling to counter these recruitment drives. Earlier this year the group released a video of a young Kazakh boy shooting dead alleged Russian spies.
Estimates on just how many men  normally poor and uneducated  have joined Isil from Tajikistan vary from a few hundred up to 2,000, and it is a similar story in neighbouring Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan and Uzbekistan. The influential Brussels-based Think Tank International Crisis Group has estimated that 4,000 men from Central Asia have travelled out to fight with the jihadists.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:21:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vatican official denies fraud charges in Italian castle sale</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bb7b04/sc/24/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Citaly0C11636310A0CVatican0Eofficial0Edenies0Efraud0Echarges0Ein0EItalian0Ecastle0Esale0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Senior Vatican official denies charges that he concocted a property scam in which a historic castle in Umbria was bought for a third of its market value</Description>
        <MainBody>Italy
Vatican official denies fraud charges in Italian castle sale
Senior Vatican official denies charges that he concocted a property scam in which a historic castle in Umbria was bought for a third of its market value
Archbishop Vincenzo Paglia isaccussed of fraud releating to the purchasing of an Italian castlePhoto: Getty Images
Follow
A senior Vatican official is under investigation for alleged fraud and embezzlement in relation to the sale of a 14th century castle in Umbria, in the latest scandal to hit the Roman Catholic Church.
Archbishop Vincenzo Paglia, who is the head of a Vatican department, is accused of buying the castle in central Italy at an artificially low price with the intention of later selling it at its market value, in an alleged scam that would have netted a profit of nearly 4 million (2.9 million).
San Girolamo castle, in the town of Narni, was owned by the local council before being sold to the Church.
San Girolamo castle
Council officials are alleged to have colluded with the archbishop, selling the castle four years ago for a knock-down price of 1.76 million  about a third of its true value.
Prosecutors in the nearby city of Terni suspect that the alleged conspirators planned to manage it for a few years, either as an upmarket guesthouse or for religious purposes, and then sell it for 5.6 million.
 Pope Francis has not watched television since 1990
Archbishop Paglia, 70, who is head of the Vatican's Pontifical Council for the Family, is alleged to have illegally used diocese funds to purchase the property.
Nine other people are under investigation, including the former mayor of Narni and two employees of the diocese of Terni, where Archbishop Paglia formerly served as bishop.
Pope Francis (L) greets archbishop Vincenzo Paglia earlier this year
The castle was sold to a property company, Imi Immobiliare, that was headed by one of the arrested diocesan employees.
The purchase of the castle  albeit at a drastically reduced price  knocked a hole in the coffers of the diocese of Terni, which was already one of the most indebted in Europe, with a deficit of around 25 million.
Archbishop Paglia and the other people under investigation now have 20 days in which to present their defence.
The archbishop denied any wrongdoing. "I remain at the disposition of the investigating authorities and I have full confidence in the justice system," he said in a statement.
Father Federico Lombardi, the Vatican's chief spokesman, said: "We at the Vatican have nothing in particular to say about this affair. We trust that the magistracy will do its work well."
Once a Roman settlement, Narni claims to sit at the geographical centre of Italy. The hilltop town is known for its Roman cisterns, a warren of medieval streets and alleys in its historic centre and commanding views of the Umbrian countryside.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:02:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin rules deaths of Russian troops in 'special operations' a state secret</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bb7b09/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Crussia0C11636160A0CPutin0Erules0Edeaths0Eof0ERussian0Etroops0Ein0Especial0Eoperations0Ea0Estate0Esecret0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Critics accuse Russian leader of imposing an effective blackout on news of death of soldiers as Moscow continues to deny involvement in Ukraine</Description>
        <MainBody>Russia
Putin rules deaths of Russian troops in 'special operations' a state secret
Critics accuse Russian leader of imposing an effective blackout on news of    death of soldiers as Moscow continues to deny involvement in Ukraine
By Marc Bennetts, Moscow
6:02PM BST 28 May 2015
President Vladimir Putin has declared all deaths of Russian soldiers during "special operations" to be classified as a state secret, in a move that comes as Moscow stands accused of sending soldiers to fight in eastern Ukraine.
An order signed by President Putin on Thursday makes it a criminal offence to divulge information about the peacetime loss of its soldiers. The order comes amid mounting evidence of the involvement of Russian troops in the over year-long conflict in Ukraine.
Last week, Moscow-based opposition activists published a report on the deaths of members of an elite Russian army reconnaissance unit, whom they claim were killed while on duty in eastern Ukraine.
Vadim Korovin and Ruslan Leviev say their report, which involved exhaustive investigations and photos of the soldiers graves, proves that the men were serving members of the Russian military at the time of their deaths on May 5, and not volunteers.
 How Vladimir Putin's military firepower compares to the West
This order is clearly linked to events in Ukraine, Mr Leviev told The Telegraph. Nevertheless, we will continue our activities.
While the Kremlin denies frequent allegations that Russian soldiers are in action in Ukraine, Mr Putin has admitted that what he calls Russian volunteers are among those fighting forces loyal to the Ukrainian government.
Mr Putin only publicly admitted Russian soldiers had been deployed in Crimea nearly a month after signing legislation formally completing the peninsula's annexation.
Troops on exercise near the Russian-Ukriane border (REUTERS)
Opposition leader Boris Nemtsov had begun work on a separate report into the involvement of Russian troops in the conflict before he was gunned down opposite the Kremlin walls in February. His report was completed by fellow opposition activists and published earlier this month. It alleged that Russia has lost at least 220 soldiers in Ukraine since the start of fighting there in April 2014. It also alleged that the Kremlin finances the volunteers fighting for separatist forces .
The order was signed amid amid reports of a mass build-up of Russian troops and military hardware at a makeshift base near the border with Ukraine. A reporter for Reuters witnessed this week troops and hundreds of pieces of weaponry including mobile rocket launchers, tanks and artillery some 30 miles from the Ukrainian border. The report said many of the vehicles had been stripped of their identifying marks, while the servicemen had removed insignia from their fatigues.
When asked on Wednesday if the build-up signified an imminent invasion of Ukraine by Russia, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov responded that the question was inappropriate. Russias Defence Ministry has not commented.
Earlier this month, NATO military commander General Philip Breedlove said that pro-Russia rebels were planning a new offensive in eastern Ukraine. He gave no other details, however.
A shaky ceasefire, agreed on during French-German brokered talks in Minsk, Belarus, in February, has resulted in an overall reduction in fighting in Ukraine. However, heavy clashes between Kremlin-backed pro-Russia separatists and Ukrainian government forces are continuing in Shyrokyne, near the strategic port city of Mariupol. Six people, including four pro-Russian rebels, were also killed this week during fighting at a coke and chemical plant, near the separatist-held city of Donetsk, Ukrainian military spokesman Andriy Lysenko told reporters.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:30:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beijing cracks down on China's tobacco industry</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46baf79e/sc/24/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cchina0C116362120CBeijing0Ecracks0Edown0Eon0EChinas0Etobacco0Eindustry0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>After years of unenforced smoking restrictions, China's government is cracking down on cigarette companies</Description>
        <MainBody>Beijing cracks down on Chinas tobacco industry
After years of unenforced smoking restrictions, Chinas government is cracking    down on cigarette companies
A smoker walks along a street in central Beijing, ChinaPhoto: Alamy
By Charlotte Middlehurst
5:30PM BST 28 May 2015
Beijing is toughening up its antismoking efforts with new regulations targeting domestic tobacco companies, vendors and smokers in the Chinese capital from next month.
The new rules prohibit companies from advertising tobacco products through media channels including websites and public billboards. Meanwhile, vendors in the capital have been banned from selling cigarettes within 100 metres of Kindergartens, primary and middle schools.
The new legislation is limited to Beijing but other provinces are expected to follow suit. Authorities in Shanghai have already banned smoking in certain designated public spaces, restaurants and hotels.
 China introduces smoking ban  but with no penalties
"This regulation proves to the world that China is a responsible country. We will publish the national smoking-control regulations, which is a message to society from the government, said Zhi Xiuyi, the deputy chairman of Public Health and Smoking Control Commission, according to state media.
Beijing is toughening up on smokers in certain area's of the city
China is the largest producer and consumer of tobacco in the world, with more than 300 million smokers.
Last year, Chinas tobacco industry generated 1.05 trillion yuan (105 billion) in profit and taxation, up 10 per cent year on year, according to data from the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration.
New enforcement staff have been allocated to patrol restaurants and tourist sites for illegal smokers. Transgressors will be fined 50 yuan (5) fine for a first offence, which can go up to 200 yuan (20).
China first introduced new smoking restrictions in 2010, but in many areas enforcement has been a failure .
Beijing is home to roughly four million smokers, a quarter of the citys population, with each smoker consuming an average of 61 cigarettes per day, according to a survey released by the Beijing Municipal Commission of Health and Family Planning earlier this month.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:30:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How big is Greece's debt? In 60 seconds</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bb7b0e/sc/24/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cfinance0Ceconomics0C1160A830A90CHow0Ebig0Eis0EGreeces0Edebt0EIn0E60A0Eseconds0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>How big is Greece's debt? The Telegraph Video Desk put it into understandable terms in this 60 second explainer</Description>
        <MainBody>Economics
How big is Greece's debt? In 60 seconds
How big is Greece's debt? The Telegraph Video Desk put it into understandable    terms in this 60 second explainer
By Leon Siciliano and Mehreen Khan
5:30PM BST 28 May 2015
Comments
It is common knowldge that Greece is crippled by debt, but how much debt is it actually in?
The Greek governments monthly salary and pensions bill is between 1.4- 1.7bn  this is the equivalent of buying 548 Bugatti Veyrons every month.
Bugatti Veyron in Nevada USA. Credit Ingobarenschee
Greeces debt mountain is due to reach 180% of GDP in 2015  the highest in the 19-member eurozone .
Demonstrators gather outside the Greek parliament. Credit Getty
The country owes the International Monetary Fund 9.2bn in loan repayments in 2015, this amount could buy 266 Challenger 2 tanks and maintain them for a lifetime.
British Challenger 2 tank in Basra. Credit Reuters
By the end of 2015 Greece will have privatised 50bn worth of government assets, which is the equivalent of the UK government selling 485 Admiralty Arches in London.
Admiralty Arch In London. Credit:Getty
The total value of Greeces debt is 330bn, that's 15 times more than the original cost of the Apollo moon landing .
Buzz Aldrin on the moon. Credit: Reuters
Watch the video to see all the mind-boggling stats.
The Telegraph Investor
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:24:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New World Trade Centre observatory opens, banishing memories of the Twin Towers</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bb7b10/sc/38/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C1163620A0A0CNew0EWorld0ETrade0ECentre0Eobservatory0Eopens0Ebanishing0Ememories0Eof0Ethe0ETwin0ETowers0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Visitors to New York will once again be able to revel in one of the greatest views in the world, with few reminders of the horrors of 9/11 that wiped it away</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
New World Trade Centre observatory opens, banishing memories of the Twin Towers
Visitors to New York will once again be able to revel in one of the greatest    views in the world, with few reminders of the horrors of 9/11 that wiped it    away
Illuminated One World Trade Center towers over the lower Manhattan skyline in New YorkPhoto: AP
By Philip Sherwell, New York
5:24PM BST 28 May 2015
Eric Robinson was a young drama student, newly arrived in Manhattan, when suicide bombers flew two planes into the Twin Towers on Sept 11, 2001, in the most notorious terror attack on US soil .
For those trapped above the floors where the hijacked jets smashed into the structures  including some 160 staff and customers in the Windows on the World restaurant, with its legendary views of the New York skyline  there was no escape.
Mr Robinson now rides the worlds fastest elevators to the 102nd floor of the new World Trade Centre for work each day, a journey that visitors will also be able to take starting on Friday morning with the opening of the One World Observatory.
Smoke pours from the twin towers of the World Trade Center after they were hit by two hijacked airliners in a terrorist attack September 11, 2001
That terrible history is impossible to forget, he noted. I think that every single person who steps into this elevator will think about what happened that day and maybe quietly ask themselves OK, Im doing this?
But once youre up here, those thoughts are immediately dispelled. This experience is not about 9/11, its about the future of this great city and reclaiming these unparalleled views.
But visitors to the observatory encounter only the most fleeting reminder of 9/11 in an image that will pass in barely a blink of the eye, as they ride in lifts that take just 47 seconds to complete the 1,250 ft ascent at speeds comparable Usain Bolts world-record sprints .
People look out from the newly built observation deck at One World Trade Center
Instead of a head-spinning and possibly stomach-churning view of the city from the elevators, visitors  paying $32 (21) for the experience  are treated to a multimedia visual display of 500 years of Manhattan history, from its days as a forested island to todays urban jungle of skyscrapers and canyons.
The display features a few short seconds of one of the original towers. But that is the only reference to what happened here, as David Checketts, chief executive of Legends, the observatorys operator, explained.
People do come to Ground Zero expecting to learn about the old World Trade Centre and they will get that from the memorial or just walking around the pools, he said.
Employees rehearse a multimedia presentation in One World Observatory at One World Trade Center in New York
But here, we felt it was time to raise a flag to the future. Those who were lost that day will never be forgotten, but this observatory is a fist-bump to the courage and resilience of this city and a tribute to those who put this building back up.
Asked about what would happen if the building was attacked again, he said: I do not want to talk about that. But I can tell you that this is a very secure structure, designed to withstand all sorts of things.
The lifts (or sky pods) themselves are so smooth that the ascent is barely noticeable, bar the popping of ears for some. Visitors then emerge into the darkened See Forever room where a video montage of city life plays on a wall before the screen rises to reveal the first stunning glimpse of New York .
On a clear sunny day this week, the awe-inspiring panoramic view stretched from the harbour to the south, taking in the Statue of Liberty and the Staten Island ferries churning the waters; west across the new skyscrapers of Jersey City, built by companies that fled the city after 9/11; north towards the thick concrete sprawl of Manhattan, with the landmark pinnacles of the Empire State and Chrysler buildings; and east to the burgeoning new neighbourhoods of Brooklyn.
It took nearly 14 years and a lot of wrenching debate about how to rebuild at Ground Zero to reach this point .
The result is the tallest building in the Western Hemisphere, its soaring antenna lifting the height to the historically symbolic 1,776 ft, to mark the year of the signing of the Declaration of Independence.
I cant tell you how exciting it is to work with this view each day, said Mr Robinson, a trainer with the technology company that has equipped the observatory. It does feel that New York is truly back and whole again.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
