<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Telegraph">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:48:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear talks enter 'difficult phase' as deadline extended again</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7d5c2/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Ciran0C117234920CIran0Enuclear0Etalks0Eenter0Edifficult0Ephase0Eas0Edeadline0Eextended0Eagain0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Negotiations will continue for the next couple of days but we are not extending our deadline, claims Ms Mogherini</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran
Iran nuclear talks enter 'difficult phase' as deadline extended again
Negotiations will continue for the next couple of days but we are not    extending our deadline, claims Ms Mogherini
European Union foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini arrives for a press briefing outside Palais Coburg, the venue for nuclear talks in Vienna, Austria Photo: AFP/Getty
By Agencies
1:48PM BST 07 Jul 2015
Iran and major powers will continue negotiations on a historic nuclear deal past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term agreement, European Union foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days. This does not mean we are extending our deadline," Ms Mogherini told reporters.
The deal under discussion between Iran, Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days," Ms Mogherini told reporters (Reuters)
"We might see some ministers leaving in the next hours and then ready to come back," Ms Mogherini said.
"We are interpreting in a flexible way our deadline, which means that we are taking the time, the days we still need, to finalise the agreement," she said, adding that there remained several difficult issues to resolve .
Iran said that it has no target date for completing a nuclear deal with world powers.
Sergei Lavrov, Russian foreign minister, said on Tuesday that around eight issues remained to be "finalised" before a nuclear deal between Iran and six powers is reached, Interfax news agency reported.
Iran and the major powers will continue negotiations on an historic nuclear deal past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term agreement.
"We have no deadline," a spokesman for the Iranian delegation in talks with major powers in Vienna told AFP.
The negotiators missed a June 30 deadline for a final agreement and then gave themselves until Tuesday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:47:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pictures of the day: 7 July 2015</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e5b593/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Cpicturesoftheday0C117220A720CPictures0Eof0Ethe0Eday0E70EJuly0E20A150Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A Stonehenge sunrise, running with bulls and protesting 'nuns'</Description>
        <MainBody>The sun rises over Salisbury Plain as it's light illuminates the mist shrouding Stonehenge in WiltshirePicture: Robin Morrison / SWNS.com

Comments are closed on this picture gallery.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:40:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pamplona running of the bulls: San Fermin Festival begins in Spain, in pictures</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e4df10/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctravel0Cfestivalsandevents0C117224770CPamplona0Erunning0Eof0Ethe0Ebulls0ESan0EFermin0EFestival0Ebegins0Ein0ESpain0Ein0Epictures0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In pics: The annual San Fermin bull-running festival in northern Spain</Description>
        <MainBody>Three    men were gored and 10 others taken to hospital on the first day of    Pamplona's week-long San    Fermin festival in the northern Spanish city where bulls chase runners    in red scarves through the streets
Picture: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez/Getty Images

Comments are closed on this picture gallery.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:36:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Spanish pharmacy wins right to refuse to sell morning after pills</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7d5c5/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cspain0C117235110CSpanish0Epharmacy0Ewins0Eright0Eto0Erefuse0Eto0Esell0Emorning0Eafter0Epills0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Seville pharmacy had been fined €3,000 in 2008 for refusing to sell emergency contraceptive, but Spanish constitutional court overturns decision on appeal</Description>
        <MainBody>Spain
Spanish pharmacy wins right to refuse to sell morning after pills
Seville pharmacy had been fined 3,000 in 2008 for refusing to sell emergency    contraceptive, but Spanish constitutional court overturns decision on appeal
Spanish pharmacies are required by law to provide morning-after pills and condomsPhoto: Alamy
By Guy Hedgecoe, Madrid
1:36PM BST 07 Jul 2015
A Spanish pharmacy that was fined for refusing to sell women morning-after pills has been told that its right to ideological freedom was violated by the sanction.
The regional health authorities of Andalusia, in southern Spain, fined the pharmacy in Seville 3,000 (2,130) in 2008, because it sold neither the emergency contraceptive morning-after pill nor condoms.
Spanish pharmacies are required by law to provide both, with no prescription required.
However, the constitutional court has overturned the decision on appeal.
It took into account the fact that the owners of the pharmacy in question were officially registered as conscientious objectors on issues where they see a professional conflict between the law and their own beliefs.
Apparently drawing a parallel between the morning-after pill and abortion, the court ruled in its sentence that in this case, legally obligating the vendor to sell the product clashed with the concept advocated by [the pharmacist] regarding the right to life.
However, the court upheld the sanction related to the pharmacys refusal to sell condoms, stating that it saw there no conflict of conscience with constitutional relevance.
It was a tight decision by the court, with several magistrates disagreeing with the final ruling.
The judge overseeing the vote, Andres Ollero, admitted that it was a grey area and that he and his colleagues could not be spiritual directors of citizens, instructing them on which areas of their conscience are protected by fundamental rights and which should be forgotten because they are twisted scruples.
Judge Adela Asua voted against the ruling, arguing that rather than protecting beliefs, the courts sentence itself was tainted by ideology. She also warned that it set a dangerous precedent, which could bring ill-fated consequences for our state and our coexistence.
Spain has seen an intense debate over the issue of abortion in recent year. In 2010, the previous, Socialist government introduced a law allowing abortion until the 14th week of pregnancy.
However, last year the current conservative administration proposed only allowing terminations following rape or if the mothers health was in danger, before withdrawing its reform bill in the face of political and social opposition.
Many Spanish doctors avoid performing abortions by declaring themselves ideologically opposed to the operation.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:32:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dozens of witnesses found dead in India multi-million dollar bribery case</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7d5c8/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cindia0C117234180CDozens0Eof0Ewitnesses0Efound0Edead0Ein0EIndia0Emulti0Emillion0Edollar0Ebribery0Ecase0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 36 people connected to fraud case involving alleged exam cheating for government jobs and medical degrees found dead</Description>
        <MainBody>India
Dozens of witnesses found dead in India multi-million dollar bribery case
At least 36 people connected to fraud case involving alleged exam cheating for    government jobs and medical degrees found dead
Indian Youth Congress workers scuffle with police as they protest against Madhya Pradesh Chief Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan against the series of deaths in Madhya Pradesh Professional Examination Board or VYAPAM scam in Bhopal, IndiaPhoto: EPA
By Reuters
1:32PM BST 07 Jul 2015
Dozens of witnesses in a massive fraud case in India surrounding cheating at college and government jobs have been found dead, including four in the past two days.
Investigators say thousands of people got jobs or medical degrees from systematic exam cheating that generated millions of dollars in bribes in the state of Madhya Pradesh.
At least 36 people connected to the case in the state, run by the ruling Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), have died since the scam was first brought to light in 2013. More than 2,000 have been arrested in relation to the scam.
Four more people connected to the case have died since the weekend, just days before a Supreme Court hearing and amid opposition accusations that a regional unit of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's party was protecting the accused.
"They are not arresting the real culprits," said Vivek Tankha, a lawyer representing three whistleblowers who exposed the scam.
The case has become the latest source of discomfort for India's ruling party, already on the defensive over influence trafficking allegations.
Shivraj Singh Chouhan, Chief Minister of Madhya Pradesh state (Reuters)
State chief minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan, a popular BJP leader, denies wrongdoing.
But on Tuesday he buckled to pressure and said the inquiry should be handed to the Central Bureau of Investigation to avoid suspicion of political meddling.
The latest deaths included a national television journalist who began foaming at the mouth soon after interviewing the parents of Namrata Damor, a student who had obtained a college seat as part of the scam and was herself later found dead on train tracks in January 2012. The journalist died in hospital.
In the past few days, a policeman was found hanging from a ceiling fan, a trainee policewoman was found dead in a pond, and the dean of a college involved in the scam was found dead, with a half empty liquor bottle in a hotel room.
Activists from India's opposition Congress party protest, demanding resignation of Shivraj Singh Chouhan (Reuters)
Mr Chouhan denies accusations made by the opposition Congress party that he and other officials benefited from the fraud.
"There are very powerful big people involved in this," said the Congress party's Digvijaya Singh, a former Madhya Pradesh chief minister who wants the case be investigated by federal agents monitored by the Supreme Court.
On Tuesday, the Supreme Court said it would consider his petition along with several other relating to the case, at a hearing on July 9.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:20:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Poland should join euro only after referendum, says president-elect's adviser</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7d5ca/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cpoland0C117233650CPoland0Eshould0Ejoin0Eeuro0Eonly0Eafter0Ereferendum0Esays0Epresident0Eelects0Eadviser0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Poland will fight EU green policies and the decision to stop using a nation's own currency should be decided by the nation, says Krzysztof Szczerski, foreign affairs adviser to president-elect Andrzej Duda</Description>
        <MainBody>Poland
Poland should join euro only after referendum, says president-elect's adviser
Poland will fight EU green policies and the decision to stop using a nation's    own currency should be decided by the nation, says Krzysztof Szczerski,    foreign affairs adviser to president-elect Andrzej Duda
Andrzej Duda was the surprise winner of a presidential election in MayPhoto: Reuters
By Reuters
Comments
Poland should hold a referendum before joining the euro, a senior adviser to its incoming president said, heralding a more cautious approach to European integration from the European Union 's biggest eastern economy.
Krzysztof Szczerski, foreign affairs adviser to president-elect Andrzej Duda , also signalled Poland would resist giving up more sovereignty to Brussels, and said it would fight EU green policies that harm the Polish economy by forcing it to burn less coal.
Poland has been a major beneficiary of EU funds and a supporter of integration, but that is shifting with the rise to prominence of the Law and Justice party, which is allied to the Conservative party of David Cameron.
Law and Justice candidate Mr Duda was the surprise winner of a presidential election in May , and opinion polls show the right-wing party, now in opposition, will form the next government after a parliamentary election in October.
"The decision on ceasing to mint one's own currency must be ... the nation's decision," Mr Szczerski told Reuters in an interview, saying that this required a "direct vote."
"This realistically means that a discussion about introducing the euro in Poland during President Duda's current term is pointless."
Poland has committed itself to joining the eurozone one day, but there is no legal requirement for it to hold a referendum on the issue. Opinion polls show if there was a vote on accession, it would be firmly rejected.
Echoing views expressed by Mr Cameron's government , and Hungary's ruling Fidesz party, Mr Szczerski said the EU should return more powers to national capitals instead of constantly moving towards ever-greater integration.
"The metaphor of European integration being like a bike is well-known: you can only go forward, there is no reverse gear. Which means we're in a conceptual trap," Mr Szczerski said. "In my view, now is the time for common sense to return to Europe."
Carbon emissions are a sticking point between Brussels, which wants to limit greenhouse gases, and Poland, which depends on coal to generate most of its electricity.
Mr Szczerski said Mr Duda's administration will be "more decisive" than its predecessors in blocking moves on emissions which are unfavourable for the Polish economy.
Countering Russian threat
Mr Szczerski signalled the new administration would take an assertive stance on Russia, despite fears among some of Warsaw's Nato allies about antagonising Moscow.
Mr Szczerski said Poland would continue the existing policy of seeking Nato combat bases on its territory, and would aim to build a coalition of central European countries backing that in time for the alliance's 2016 summit in Warsaw.
Russia said deployment of significant Nato forces close to its borders would violate the 1997 Nato-Russia Founding Act.
Mr Szczerski said this agreement needed to be reviewed, as circumstances have made the limits on Nato's military presence in the region "no longer valid".
Poland will also seek stronger bilateral security ties with the United States, ultimately looking to set up permanent, joint US-Polish military bases on Polish territory, he said.
On Ukraine, Szczerski said the new administration would aim to establish visa-free travel for Ukrainians to Poland and will defend Kiev's right to eventually join Nato and the EU, a prospect that Moscow fiercely opposes.
"The (Nato) membership offer is in itself already a very important political instrument," Mr Szczerski said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:01:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Drone drops burgers for the homeless</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7d5cb/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cnewstopics0Chowaboutthat0C117234750CDrone0Edrops0Eburgers0Efor0Ethe0Ehomeless0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Watch this ingenious video of a man who sets up a drone to deliver free hamburgers to the homeless in San Francisco</Description>
        <MainBody>How about that?
Drone drops burgers for the homeless
Watch this ingenious video of a man who sets up a drone to deliver free    hamburgers to the homeless in San Francisco
By Telegraph Video, video source Jukin
1:01PM BST 07 Jul 2015
A man has helped out the homeless by attaching hamburgers to his drone and dropping them on various people around San Francisco.
In the video, the hobbyist flies his drone around the city, looking for people who might be hungry.
The man fixes the detachable burgers to the drone (Jukin)
The burgers fall off the drone with a detachable device.
People below reach out when they see the drone approaching (Jukin)
Watch the video as the drone burgers bring delight for the hungry people below
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:00:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gaza one year on: The two sisters caught in the crossfire of Israel's war with Hamas</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3f5/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Cgaza0C117179640CGaza0Eone0Eyear0Eon0EThe0Etwo0Esisters0Ecaught0Ein0Ethe0Ecrossfire0Eof0EIsraels0Ewar0Ewith0EHamas0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Twelve months after the bloody 50-day Gaza war, the deaths of Hakema and Nadjah Abu Adwan after being identified as 'terrorists' highlights the hazy rules of engagement in the conflict</Description>
        <MainBody>Gaza
Gaza one year on: The two sisters caught in the crossfire of Israel's war with Hamas
Twelve months after the bloody 50-day Gaza war, the deaths of Hakema and    Nadjah Abu Adwan after being identified as 'terrorists' highlights the hazy    rules of engagement in the conflict
Nada Abu Adwan with her nephew EzzatPhoto: Robert Tait/The Telegraph
By Robert Tait , Morabah, Gaza Strip
1:00PM BST 07 Jul 2015
The three women already sensed danger but there was no warning shot or loud explosion to signal the fatal moment was at hand.
Instead a roaring, howling wind followed by billowing white smoke was all that told the Abu Adwan sisters that their lives were in imminent peril.
The Palestinian Bedouin women were walking away from their ramshackle farm along a lonely dirt track beside an orchard in broad daylight when their bucolic surroundings were transformed into a killing zone during last summer's Gaza conflict .
Moments later, two of them were dead after being identified by Israeli commanders as "terrorists" in an episode that highlights question marks over the army's targeting rules in a 50-day conflict that saw more than 2,200 Palestinians killed, along with 73 on Israel's side.
"There was a hot wind, like a storm or a whirlwind," recalled Nada Abu Adwan, 35. "I thought something had happened. I looked back at my two sisters, Hakema and Nadjah, who were about 30 yards behind me, and they seemed OK.
Nada Abu Adwan, sister of Hakema and Nadjah (Robert Tait/The Telegraph)
"I told them that if the Israelis hit once, they will for sure hit again, so I said, let's get on the ground and move. We moved crawling along the ground and stopped next to a big white rose bush. A few moments later, I heard something and saw my leg was bleeding.
"Then I looked back again at my sisters and told them to follow me. But they said no, just go and get us an ambulance. Nadjah was hurt. But both were still alive."
Not for long - although exactly what happened next is unclear.
Whatever the details, Hakema and Nadjah - aged 45 and 30 according to Nada, although their death certificates indicate they may have been older - were found dead hours later, just yards from where their sister left them, crawling under a wire mesh fence, in a vain effort to find help.
By the time other family members and the Red Crescent were able to reach the scene - sealed off for two hours by Israeli tanks - it was too late.
Hakema's body had been blown to pieces while Nadjah's had several wounds, according to their nephew Ezzat, 21, who discovered them close to a locked gate. The gate and a nearby wall show at least 30 small holes apparently caused by bullets or shrapnel. The bodies of two brothers, Khairy and Khaleel Abu Snaima, 18 and 22, were found nearby - killed after they tried to help Hakema and Nadjah, the family believe.
Ezzat stands at the gate where he found the bodies of his aunts Hakema and Nadjah (Robert Tait)
The two women, who were unmarried, eked out a living breeding chickens, sheep and pigeons and growing olives, grapes and figs at an impoverished family farm where they lived a traditional Bedouin pastoral lifestyle along with Nada, another sister, Masua, 39, and their mother Mansura, 79.
They were implicated as "terrorists" after Israeli forces - stationed in the remote area south-east of Rafah in a search for Hamas tunnels - suspected they were military scouts after expressing astonishment at the presence of human beings in an area that had been designated a combat zone and cleared of its inhabitants days earlier.
In fact, the women had returned to the farm close to the Israeli border from a temporary shelter west of Salaheddin Street, Gaza's main north-south road, to feed livestock and collect belongings after mistakenly believing a ceasefire was under way. They were leaving after realising that Israeli forces were still in the area when the missile strike occurred.
As the first anniversary of last summer's bloody 50-day conflict approaches, the July 22 incident - four days after Israel launched a ground invasion - shines a light on military rules of engagement that have already been questioned in a United Nations report and by several Israeli human rights groups.
Last month's UN human rights commission report - which accused both Israel and the Palestinian factions of multiple breaches of international law - specifically urges Israel to provide more details of its "targeting decisions", noting the often lethal targeting of residential homes and the heavy shelling of civilian areas.
The Abu Adwan case is different because it happened in remote countryside, far from population centres.
The women were initially spotted by Israeli look-out teams stationed in three different locations, one of them on the roof of a requisitioned house more than half a mile away.
Commanders ordered an air force strike after first sending a drone to carry out surveillance. The drone operatives "implicated" the sisters after reporting that the footage showed them "with phones, talking, walking", according to testimony revealed in a recent report published by Breaking the Silence , an Israeli veterans soldiers' organisation that scrutinises Israel's military practices.
An army report listed the women as "terrorists", even though soldiers sent to check on the bodies afterwards found that they were unarmed and not carrying mobile phones or other possible scouting equipment such as binoculars.
One soldier quoted in Breaking the Silence's testimony described the implicating of the women as "bulls***", adding pointedly: "They were fired at, so of course they must have been terrorists."
Even troops who justify last summer's military offensive, codenamed Operation Protective Edge, are critical of the procedure followed leading up to the killing.
While none would agree to be interviewed by the Telegraph, at least one soldier involved is understood to believe there was insufficient evidence justifying the strike.
"They could just see a figure running," said one source. "It could have been a goat or a donkey.
"The area of operation was supposed to have been evacuated and was totally empty, so when you see people come into a war zone after three days, it makes you suspicious.
"The soldiers call it the two indications rule. If you have two indications, you have the green light to strike. The first indication is that they were in a war zone where they weren't supposed to be. Second, there was a figure running and the drone saw what it saw. That's the thinking behind it. I didn't think there was enough evidence but under the rules, nobody thought there was something wrong [with what we did]."
Soldiers deployed in the mission to find and destroy Hamas' tunnel network say it was unlike any previous Gaza operation - involving setting up camp in requisitioned houses for several days at a time. One described the fear of encountering Palestinian militants and recalled being inspired by claims from Shin Bet, Israel's domestic intelligence agency, that it had uncovered a Hamas plot to infiltrate by tunnel from Gaza and kill 1,000 Israelis on Rosh Hashanah, the Jewish new year.
None of this is any consolation to the remaining Abu Adwan women, who are marking this week's anniversary of the conflict by preparing to leave a farm that has always been home - fearing they will otherwise be caught up once more in a future conflict.
"We have spent all our lives here but now we have decided to sell everything and leave," said Nada. "We are going to the west of Salaheddin Street. It is too dangerous here." Her sole surviving sister, Masua, weeps as Nadjah describes the family's plight. A year on, Mansura, the women's mother - having suffered a stroke after the deaths of her daughters - still believes they are alive and regularly calls out for them.
Standing at the spot where he found their bodies, Ezzat Abu Adwan smiled wryly at the thought that either of his aunts were "terrorists".
"You've seen the rest of the family, do you think either of these ladies could have been a fighter," he asked a reporter. "They brought me up and everything I remember about them was good. Everywhere I go I still see them in my imagination."
The Telegraph has contacted the Israel Defence Force who said that they are "looking into these cases".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:59:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Images of 7/7 bombings used to promote Tunisia tourism</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7bacc/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctravel0Cdestinations0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C117233960CImages0Eof0E770Ebombings0Eused0Eto0Epromote0ETunisia0Etourism0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A provocative advertising campaign is using images of the 7/7 bombings in London and the 9/11 attacks in New York to encourage tourists to return to Tunisia</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia
Images of 7/7 bombings used to promote Tunisia tourism
A provocative advertising campaign is using images of the 7/7 bombings in    London and the 9/11 attacks in New York to encourage tourists to return to    Tunisia following last month's beach resort massacre
The posters, created by a Tunisian communications firm, aim to rally support behind the north African country Photo:  Selim Ben Hadj Yahia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:32:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US military tests laser cannon to destroy unexploded bombs</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7bace/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cuknews0Cdefence0C117230A890CUS0Emilitary0Etests0Elaser0Ecannon0Eto0Edestroy0Eunexploded0Ebombs0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The high-powered laser will be able to detonate munitions and makeshift bombs at 300 yards</Description>
        <MainBody>US military tests laser cannon to destroy unexploded bombs
The high-powered laser will be able to detonate munitions and makeshift bombs    at 300 yards
By Ben Farmer , Defence Correspondent
12:32PM BST 07 Jul 2015
Follow
The American military is testing a laser cannon mounted on an armoured truck, to clear air fields of unexploded bombs and booby-traps.
The high-powered laser will be able to detonate unexploded ordnance and makeshift bombs at 300 yards. A robotic arm fitted to the vehicle can also dig around bombs and haul up 50lb of earth and debris at a time.
Developers believe the new vehicle will be quicker and safer for clearing areas than more traditional methods such as shooting at unexploded bombs with a heavy machine gun, or sending in bomb disposal experts and their robots.
Col Jeffry Gates, of the US Air Force, told Army Times that using the new Recovery of Airbase Denied by Ordnance (RADBO) vehicle was a lot more reliable than having a bullet bounce off it.
A weapons operator aims and fires the 3KW laser with a games console-style controller.
"Once you have an idea where these targets are ... you can sit in one location and pretty much cook off dozens of these without even having to move the vehicle, without having to get out of the vehicle," Col Gates said. "I think that'll be a huge savings in time."
Up to 15 vehicles could be ready for use as early as 2017. The RADBO is made from modified Cougar armoured trucks that were rushed into service to protect troops in Afghanistan and Iraq from roadside bombs.
Hundreds of millions of pounds is being poured into developing laser weapons across the US military.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:59:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vain fugitive requests new mugshot from police via Facebook in Australia</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3ea/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Caustraliaandthepacific0Caustralia0C11722630A0CVain0Efugitive0Erequests0Enew0Emugshot0Efrom0Epolice0Evia0EFacebook0Ein0EAustralia0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Daniel Damon, wanted for failing to answer bail, criticised the mugshot used by police appealing for information on his whereabouts</Description>
        <MainBody>Australia
Vain fugitive requests new mugshot from police via Facebook in Australia
Daniel Damon, wanted for failing to answer bail, criticised the mugshot used    by police appealing for information on his whereabouts
Wanted notice for Daniel DamonPhoto: Victoria Police
Follow
A wanted Australian man has contacted police to request they use a "better" mugshot in their appeal for information about his whereabouts.
Daniel Damon, wanted for not answering bail for traffic and drug matters, contacted Victoria Police via Facebook to ask if they could use a "better photo".
His strange request comes after the force put out an appeal on Monday via the social networking website to locate Mr Damon.
You better come down to the station house
Mr Damon, 25, replied soon after asking: "Can you use a better photo tho. This is a horrible mugshot."
"Hi Daniel, please visit your nearest police station and we'll arrange for a new photo to be taken!" the force replied.
Not letting his request be the last word, the wanted man told the police he would attend the police station once he had found a lawyer and "organised" himself.
"Yea I plan on it once I get a few things in order... just gotta organise myself a lawyer and get everything organised."
It is believed that Daniel may be living in St Kilda.
The police appeared to have users on their side after more than 1,200 likes on the comment compared with nearly 800 for Mr Damon's cheeky reply on Tuesday morning.
Although many users appeared amused by the situation, many also criticised Mr Damon.
"Smart***! Hope they catch you...," said Laura Moore.
Earlier on Tuesday, Melissa Seach told the BBC Mr Damon had yet to show up at a police station.
She explained how social media had sometimes yielded positive results for the police as part of their investigations.
"This may encourage someone that may know him to call us and provide information anonymously to crime stoppers," she said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:48:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Celebrity Sightings: Kendall Jenner, Pippa Middleton and Emily Blunt</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3ed/sc/19/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Ccelebritynews0C1172320A30CCelebrity0ESightings0EKendall0EJenner0EPippa0EMiddleton0Eand0EEmily0EBlunt0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Starring: Kendall Jenner, Pippa Middleton and Emily Blunt</Description>
        <MainBody>Kendall Jenner and Karl Lagerfeld at the Autumn Winter 2015 Chanel show at Haute Couture Paris Fashion Week... Others included in the show were...Picture: Rex

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:20:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>2,120-passenger cruise ship to be based in Cuba</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3ef/sc/31/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Ctravel0Ccruises0Ccruise0Enews0C117230A790C2120A0Epassenger0Ecruise0Eship0Eto0Ebe0Ebased0Ein0ECuba0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MSC Opera will become the largest ship based in Cuba when it moves there this winter</Description>
        <MainBody>Comments
MSC Cruises has announced plans to base a 2,120-passenger ship in Havana, Cuba .
The company will become the largest cruise line to offer sailings from the Caribbean island, offering one-week voyages from the capital on board MSC Opera, starting on December 22 and concluding on April 12, 2016. They will include two nights in Havana, with shore excursions offered by Cubanacan, a local travel firm. Their itineraries will also feature Montego Bay, Jamaica; Cozumel, Mexico; and Georgetown in the Cayman Islands.
Fly-cruise packages will be available to passengers in Spain, France, Italy, Germany, Canada, Brazil and Argentina, the company said. MSC Operas original winter schedule, featuring the Canary Islands, Madeira and Morocco, has been cancelled  all of those affected will be offered a refund or a new holiday.
The largest cruise ship currently based in Cuba is the 1,200-capacity Celestyal Cristal, which is operated by the Canadian company Cuba Cruise from the island each winter.
Several cruise lines, such as Thomson, Saga, Fred Olsen, Swan Hellenic and Noble Caledonia, include stops in Cuba in their Caribbean itineraries.
The move further highlights the growing popularity of the country following the easing of trade and travel restrictions with the United States earlier this year.
A vintage car in Havana Photo: AP/FOTOLIA
Barack Obama recently announced that the US Embassy in Havana would soon reopen, more than 50 years after the US and Cuba broke off diplomatic relations.
Many have predicted that Cuba could be transformed by the changes , with greater investment leading to improved infrastructure, new buildings and hotels, more American tourists and fewer vintage cars, and many have reportedly been rushing to visit the island before it loses its traditional character.
Fred Mawer, Telegraph Travels Caribbean expert, describes Cuba as a heady mix of faded Spanish colonial cities, sputtering Fifties Cadillacs, wonderful live music, world-class cigars and an arcane communist system.
Cuba is renowned for its cigars Photo: AP/FOTOLIA
On the downside, he adds. Often things dont work as they should or go to plan, and the service in hotels and the food, though improving, are not on a par with other Caribbean destinations.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:03:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greeks remain surprisingly optimistic over prospects of new deal</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3f1/sc/25/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cgreece0C117228390CGreeks0Eremain0Esurprisingly0Eoptimistic0Eover0Eprospects0Eof0Enew0EEU0Edeal0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>With their PM headed to Brussels for emergency talks, a large proportion of the Greek population is confident that an accord will be hammered out</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece
Greeks remain surprisingly optimistic over prospects of new deal
With their PM headed to Brussels for emergency talks, a large proportion of    the Greek population is confident that an accord will be hammered out
Greeks celebrate the 'No' votePhoto: Christopher Furlong/Gety Images
Follow
As Alexis Tsipras heads to Brussels to try to restart talks with Greece s exasperated creditors, many Greeks remain surprisingly optimistic about the chances of a new deal being forged , despite grave warnings from Berlin and Brussels that patience has been exhausted and no further concessions will be offered.
 Greece crisis: Latest updates live
In spite of clear indications that the Germans, in particular, have had enough of Mr Tsipras brinkmanship, a large proportion of the Greek population is confident that an accord will be hammered out and Greece will not be abandoned.
They say that Sundays referendum, in which nearly 62 per cent of voters opted to reject more austerity measures for a fresh bail-out, strengthened their prime ministers hand and reinforced his mandate.
We are now in a stronger position to fight with Europe for a deal, said Marios, 29, a newspaper kiosk owner in central Athens who declined to give his surname.
I accept that we must pay our debts, but we must have our human rights as well. We cant pay tomorrow. The economy has to start growing again  if we dont make money, we cant pay the debt.
But there are others who fear that European leaders will finally call Mr Tsipras bluff and tell Greece that it would be better off outside the euro zone.
The divergence of opinions is splitting families, couples and business partners.
In a traditional barbers shop in Athens historic district of Plaka, a jumble of streets beneath the Acropolis, hairdresser George Panaiotaras, 80, believes Mr Tsipras will come back from Brussels with a deal.
George Kollaros, left, and his colleague George Panaiotaras, in their barbers' shop in Plaka, near the Acropolis (NICK SQUIRES)
Hes very strong and I think he will fight on behalf of us Greeks, he said, cutting a customers hair amid jars of Brylcreem and pomade.
But his boss, George Kollaros, also 80, thinks Mr Tsipras has played entirely the wrong game since being elected in January, unnecessarily antagonising Greeces lenders and setting the stage for a disastrous confrontation that could see the country reverting to the drachma.
Vagelis Charatsis, 52, a stockbroker, believes the radical Leftist Syriza government will struggle to find sympathy from the rest of Europe.
The trust between the negotiating partners has been badly damaged and I dont know whether it can be repaired, he said.
Tspiras will demand some renegotiation of our debt. But Im afraid that if the hardliners in Europe win, they will tell him to take the existing deal or face an exit from the euro. I think the possibility of a Grexit has increased substantially.
Senior citizens talk to bank staff as they queue up to collect their pensions outside a National Bank of Greece branch in Kotzia Square in Athens (GETTY)
Analysts agree with him. Fitch, the credit ratings agency Fitch, said the victory for the No camp in Sundays referendum "dramatically increases" the risk of the country leaving the euro zone. The agency said a deal was still possible, but that time was running out.
Jeroen Dijsselbloem, the euro zones top official, said he wanted Greece to remain in the euro zone, but warned: There are no easy solutions."
Germany, meanwhile, reiterated that it will not contemplate debt restructuring until the Greeks present a package of credible reforms and budgetary cuts.
"Our position is well-known ... a debt cut is not an issue for us," said Martin Jaeger, a spokesman for the German finance ministry.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:01:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russell Brand confronted by friend of Tunisia victims</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e7b3f2/sc/6/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ctunisia0C117230A220CRussell0EBrand0Econfronted0Eby0Efriend0Eof0ETunisia0Evictims0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Russell Brand asked to explain his stance on the minute's silence for those killed in Tunisia by a man who lost two friends in the attack</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia
Russell Brand confronted by friend of Tunisia victims
Russell Brand asked to explain his stance on the minute's silence for those    killed in Tunisia by a man who lost two friends in the attack
Russell Brand was forced to defend his position on the one minute's silence for the victims of the Tunisia beach massacre by a man who lost two friends in the attack.
The comedian previously described last week's silence as "absolute bull****".
Confronted by van-driver Rob, Brand repeated his argument that the government is hypocritical to honour the Sousse victims at the same time as engaging in the arms trade.
Rob questions Russell Brand on his controversial Tunisia comments (YouTube / Russell Brand)
In an encounter broadcast on the comic's YouTube channel , Rob, who knew Adrian and Patrick Evans , says: "I just wanted to ask you a question, what you meant behind your comments regarding the minute's silence."
Brand then responds with a lengthy diatribe about government policy, saying: "Our government's got loads of countries, it has a human rights abusers list, where it says these countries are dangerous countries, you shouldn't go there, they're dodgy, there's dangerous terrorists there.
"And then our actual government helps arms companies to sell weaponry to those countries."
Russell Brand pontificates on government policy (YouTube / Russell Brand)
By the end of the video, Rob seems to have come round to Brand's point of view.
Asked by Brand what he thinks of his argument, Rob says: "I agree, with the government funding the terrorists with the arms and all that, but they sweep all that under the carpet don't they?"
Watch the exchange in the video above.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:00:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bill Cosby admitted buying drugs to give women for sex</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e34fcb/sc/17/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Ccelebritynews0C117223880CBill0ECosby0Eadmitted0Ebuying0Edrugs0Eto0Egive0Ewomen0Efor0Esex0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Court documents show actor and comedian obtained sedatives to give to women he wanted to have sex with</Description>
        <MainBody>Celebrity news
Bill Cosby admitted buying drugs to give women for sex
Court documents show actor and comedian obtained sedatives to give to women he    wanted to have sex with
By AP, video source ITN
11:00AM BST 07 Jul 2015
American actor and comedian Bill Cosby admitted in 2005 that he obtained drugs with the intent of giving them to young women he wanted to have sex with, and that he gave quaaludes, a sedative, to at least one woman and "other people".
That woman and a second woman testified in the same case that they knowingly took quaaludes from him, according to the unsealed documents.
The Associated Press had gone to court to compel the release of the documents from the deposition in a sexual abuse lawsuit filed by former Temple University employee Andrea Constand  the first of a series of sexual abuse lawsuits against him . Cosby's lawyers had objected on the grounds that it would embarrass their client.
Cosby, who is best known for playing Dr. Cliff Huxtable on the hit TV series "The Cosby Show" in the 1980s and '90s, settled that lawsuit under confidential terms in 2006. His lawyers in the Philadelphia case did not immediately return phone calls on Monday. Ms Constand consented to be identified but did not want to comment, her lawyer said on Monday.
Cosby's lawyers did not want the documents made public
Cosby, 77, has been accused by more than two dozen women of sexual misconduct , including allegations by many that he drugged and raped them in incidents dating back decades. Cosby has never been criminally charged, and most of the accusations are barred by statutes of limitations, but his career has suffered in the past year with TV projects and live shows being cancelled. He also stepped down last year from the board of trustees at Temple University, his alma mater.
A representative for Cosby did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Monday.
The new documents show that Cosby, giving sworn testimony in the lawsuit accusing him of sexually assaulting Ms Constand at his home in Pennsylvania in 2005, said he got seven quaalude prescriptions in the 1970s. The lawyer for Ms Constand asked if he had kept the sedatives through the 1990s  after they were banned  but was frustrated by objections from Cosby's lawyer.
"When you got the quaaludes, was it in your mind that you were going to use these quaaludes for young women that you wanted to have sex with?" lawyer Dolores M. Troiani asked.
"Yes," Cosby answered on Sept 29, 2005.
"Did you ever give any of these young women the quaaludes without their knowledge?"
Cosby's lawyer again objected, leading Ms Troiani to petition the federal judge to force Cosby to cooperate.
Cosby later said he gave Constand three half-pills of Benadryl, although Ms Troiani in the documents voices doubt that was the drug involved. The two other women who testified on Ms Constand's behalf said they had knowingly been given quaaludes.
Cosby had fought efforts to unseal the testimony, with his lawyer arguing the deposition could reveal details of Cosby's marriage, sex life and prescription drug use.
"It would be terribly embarrassing for this material to come out," lawyer George M. Gowen III argued in June. He said the public should not have access to what Cosby was forced to say as he answered questions under oath from the accuser's lawyer nearly a decade ago.
"Frankly ... it would embarrass him, (and) it would also prejudice him in eyes of the jury pool in Massachusetts," Mr Gowen said.
US District Judge Eduardo Robreno asked last month why Cosby was fighting the release of his sworn testimony, given that the accusations in the Temple woman's lawsuit were already in the public eye.
"Why would he be embarrassed by his own version of the facts?" Judge Robreno said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:22:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nick Kyrgios accuses Olympic great Dawn Fraser of being a 'blatant racist'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e6d0a6/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Caustraliaandthepacific0Caustralia0C1172250A50CNick0EKyrgios0Eaccuses0EOlympic0Egreat0EDawn0EFraser0Eof0Ebeing0Ea0Eblatant0Eracist0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Fraser said tennis players should set a better example to young Australians or go back to where their parents came from</Description>
        <MainBody>Australia
Nick Kyrgios accuses Olympic great Dawn Fraser of being a 'blatant racist'
Fraser said tennis players should set a better example to young Australians or    go back to where their parents came from
By Flynn Murphy, Sydney, video source APTN
10:22AM BST 07 Jul 2015
Australian tennis player Nick Kyrgios has accused Olympic great Dawn Fraser of being a "blatant racist" after the former champion swimmer said tennis players should "go back to where their parents came from" if they did not set a better example to Australian youth.
Four-time Olympic gold medallist Dawn Fraser criticised Kyrgios behaviour during his fourth-round defeat by Frenchman Richard Gasquet in a local breakfast television interview.
Fraser, who has been one of Australia's best known sporting figures since she won the 100 metres freestyle at three successive Olympic Games from 1956 to 1964, accused Kyrgios of tanking in his final Wimbledon match, saying: Its absolutely disgusting. I am so shocked to think that he went out there to play and he tanked  thats terrible."
Fraser then said 20-year-old Kyrgios and fellow Aussie top seed Bernard Tomic - who at the weekend used a post-match press conference to attack Australia's tennis body - should be "setting a better example for the younger generation of this great country of ours" .
She added: "If they dont like it go back to where their fathers or their parents come from.
Kyrgios returned fire, accusing the 77-year-old of being a blatant racist.
"Throwing a racket, brat. Debating the rules, disrespectful. Frustrated when competing, spoilt. Showing emotion, arrogant. Blatant racist, Australian legend, Kyrgios posted on Facebook on Tuesday.
Throwing a racket, brat. Debating the rules, disrespectful. Frustrated when competing, spoilt. Showing emotion,...
Posted by Nick Kyrgios on Monday, 6 July 2015
The 26th seed was jeered by the crowd when he appeared to make no effort to return serves in the third game of the second set of Monday's match.
He has previously been penalised for swearing and for throwing a racket with such force that it bounced into the air and narrowly missed a spectator.
Kyrgios' mother Nill accused Fraser of a "nasty racist attack", tweeting that she was "out of line".
I have no comments on Dawn Frasers nasty racist attack...but she is out of line. #unaustralianbehaviour
 nill kyrgios (@nillkyrgios) July 7, 2015
But Fraser later stood by the tirade claiming she was not a racist person.
"I said, 'If they don't want to be Australians then maybe they should go back to the country where their parents come from'. That's not being racist," she told Fairfax Media.
"I can see it being interpreted that way ... but it wasn't intended that way."
Kyrgios, who was born and raised in Canberra, has a Greek-born father and a Malaysia-born mother.
Late on Tuesday afternoon Fraser issued a statement apologising for the controversial comments, and saying she had been taken out of context.
"I want to unreservedly apologise for any comments that I made this morning which may have caused [offence] to my fellow Australians including Nick and his family," Fraser said in a statement.
"My intended message, which was not delivered as articulately as it could have been, was on a purely sporting level rather than meant as an attack on Nick's ethnicity."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:56:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Briton among three gored by bulls in Pamplona</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e5b58f/sc/28/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cspain0C117225910CMan0Egored0Eby0Ebull0Eamong0Eseven0Erushed0Eto0Ehospital0Ein0EPamplona0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Start of annual Running of the Bulls festival in Spain on Tuesday sees 13 people taken to hosptial</Description>
        <MainBody>Spain
Briton among three gored by bulls in Pamplona
Start of annual Running of the Bulls festival in Spain on Tuesday sees 13    people taken to hosptial
A Jandilla bull charges at a participant during the first "encierro" (bull-run) Photo: ANDER GILLENEA/AFP/Getty Images
By Our Foreign Staff
9:56AM BST 07 Jul 2015
Three men including one Briton were gored on Tuesday at the start of the annual Running of the Bulls festival in Spain .
The British man, 30, was gored "between the anus and genitals", a local government official said. His injuries were not thought to be life-threatening.
Another man was gored in the chest near the famous Mercaderes corner on the half-mile course, and was in a stable condition, a doctor at the event said.
Ten others were taken to hospital with injuries, including at least six who fell as they were chased down by bulls in the streets of Pamplona.
A Jandilla bull leaves a participant after charging at him (AFP/Getty)
Red Cross workers were pictured taking several bloodied runners away on stretchers.
The run lasted 2 minutes and 23 seconds.
Tuesday's run included six bulls from the Jandilla ranch in the rural western region of Extremadura, known for the ferocity of its bulls.
It was the first of the eight morning runs that form the highlight of the annual festival - known as San Fermin in Spanish.
The bulls took two minutes and 23 seconds to complete the course through the cobbled streets of Pamplona's old town.
A steer jumps over a fallen runner (Reuters)
Fifteen people have been killed at the annual festival, made famous by 1926 Ernest Hemingway novel 'The Sun Also Rises', since records began in 1911.
The most recent death was in 2009 when 27-year-old Daniel Jimeno, from Madrid, was gored in the neck by a bull called Capuchino.
Several foreigners, from Australians to Americans through to Brits and Irish, are normally among the injured .
Virtually all the revellers wear red and white during the festival.
A spokesman for the hospital to which Tuesday morning's injured were taken said: "We have one person who has been gored in the chest, who is stable and will be operated on.
"The others have suffered facial traumas or injuries to arms and legs."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:48:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al-Shabaab gunmen kill Kenyan workers in their sleep</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e5b591/sc/40/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cafricaandindianocean0Ckenya0C117226890CAl0EShabaab0Egunmen0Ekill0EKenyan0Eworkers0Ein0Etheir0Esleep0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 14 quarry workers killed as they slept in northeast Kenya in attack claimed by Somalia-based Islamic militant group</Description>
        <MainBody>Kenya
Al-Shabaab gunmen kill Kenyan workers in their sleep
At least 14 quarry workers killed as they slept in northeast Kenya in attack    claimed by Somalia-based Islamic militant group
Kenya Red Cross officials help a mourner at Nairobi City mortuary after Al-Shabaab gunmen slaughtered 36 people in a quarry near Mandera in 2014. The terror group have struck the area again, killing at least 14 quarry workers in their sleep.Photo: AFP/Getty
By Reuters
9:48AM BST 07 Jul 2015
Al-Shabaab gunmen killed at least 14 quarry workers as they slept in an overnight attack in northeast Kenya.
The Somalia-based Islamic militant group claimed responsibility for the assault on a residential complex in Mandera town, saying in a statement it had killed "more than 10 Christians".
"We are behind the Mandera attack. We killed over 10 Kenyan Christians," Sheikh Abdiasis Abu Musab, the group's military operations spokesman, told Reuters. "This is part of our ongoing operations against Kenya."
Al-Shabaab has in the past carried out similar attacks, including one in December in the same county in which 36 quarry workers were killed.
"The area they attacked is a plot where quarry workers live. They attacked at around 1 am. Most of those killed are workers from upcountry. In total 14 people are dead," Alex Nkoyo, commissioner for Mandera county, told Reuters by telephone.
Abbas Gullet, secretary general of Kenya Red Cross, said the workers were attacked as they slept.
Mr Nkoyo said that among the dead was a woman who had tried to plead with the gunmen before being shot.
Al-Shabaab, which aims to topple Somalia's government and impose its own strict version of Islamic law, has carried out frequent attacks in Kenya in recent years to try to force Nairobi to pull its troops out of Somalia, where they are part of an African Union peacekeeping mission.
In the most deadly, the group killed 148 people at a university in eastern Kenya's Garissa County in April.
At least 11 people were also wounded in Tuesday's assault, Gullet told Citizen Television.
Edited for Telegraph.co.uk by Andrew Marszal
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:25:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant dies in Channel Tunnel trying to reach Britain, say French authorities</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/47e5b596/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C117227130CMigrant0Edies0Ein0EChannel0ETunnel0Eto0EBritain0Esay0EFrench0Eauthorities0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The news agency AFP reports a migrant has died trying to reach Britain through the Channel Tunnel</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrant dies in Channel Tunnel trying to reach Britain, say French authorities
The news agency AFP reports a migrant has died trying to reach Britain through    the Channel Tunnel
A migrant has died on a freight shuttle trying to reach BritainPhoto: AFP
By Henry Samuel , Paris and agencies
9:25AM BST 07 Jul 2015
Follow
A migrant died on Tuesday trying to reach Britain through the Channel Tunnel, French authorities in the Pas-de-Calais region have confirmed.
One of the six sections of the tunnel was closed for investigation, but train traffic had not stopped. It was as yet unclear how the migrant died.
Following the detection of migrants on a freight shuttle early this morning, the shuttle was immediately stopped, said the Pas-de-Calais prefecture, the local state authority.
During a security inspection by border police, a deceased migrant was found in the tunnel, it said in a statement.
Gilles Debove, of the police union Unit SGP-Police FO, said: "Around 400 migrants arrived and besieged the tunnel, as they do almost every night. One managed to board a freight shuttle and unfortunately fell off, losing his life."
Eurostar announced that "trains are subject to delays" in another tweet without further detail, while Eurotunnel said the shuttle on which the incident took place had now left the tunnel on the French side.
Update: Trains are subject to delays this morning due to the closure of a section of the Eurotunnel.
 Eurostar UK (@EurostarUK) July 7, 2015
Last month, a 26-year old Eritrean migrant was killed on the French side of the Channel Tunnel after trying to board a moving freight train. He was thrown off and collided with a concrete pylon.
Days later, a female migrant was found dead on the A16 motorway after being crushed by a vehicle.
Confirmation that due to migrants found on freight shuttle, we expect delays to Passenger service of 3hrs from UK &amp; 60mins from France. ^LE
 Eurotunnel LeShuttle (@LeShuttle) July 7, 2015
Local police have warned that migrants are now breaking into restricted areas on the French side of the Eurotunnel terminal almost nightly.
A Eurotunnel spokesman said: "Services are partly suspended, and the disruption is principally affecting freight services. Passenger services are running with slight delays.
"We are working very hard to restore full services as soon as possible."
The incident comes days after around 150 migrants caused delays and cancellations when they tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.
There have been increased calls for a resolution to the migrant crisis in Calais.
Kent Police said delays were building around junction 11a of the M20, where lorries are queued as part of Operation Stack when cross-Channel services hit disruption.
The migrant crisis in Calais has escalated in recent months , with around 3,000 people displaced from countries including Eritrea, Syria and Afghanistan setting up camp near the port.
Last week more than 3,000 truckers had to queue for several days in high temperatures on the M20 following a wildcat strike by ferry workers in France.
Industrial action by ferry workers this summer has come on top of the problems faced by hauliers with migrants desperately trying to clamber on board their HGVs to the UK .
French authorities have faced claims they are not doing enough to safeguard lorry drivers from intimidation, violence and attempts by migrants to climb on.
The Road Haulage Association (RHA) has suggested deployment of the French military to boost security in Calais amid fears that a fatality could occur.
The Fresh Produce Consortium estimates that 10 million of fresh fruit and vegetables have been thrown away since the start of the year as a result of the problems in Calais.
And Port of Dover officials said last week's ferry strike cost the UK economy 1 billion.
They have joined calls for "robust contingency plans" to be introduced to ensure the port - a 100 billion trade route - can work unimpeded by others.
Home Secretary Theresa May and her French counterpart Bernard Cazeneuve last week agreed to increase the joint intervention fund to improve security around the port and the Channel Tunnel.
French aid workers have reported a "catastrophic" situation, with predictions that 2,000 more migrants could arrive over the summer at the camp, dubbed Jungle II.
Volunteers from L'Auberge Des Migrants say up to 50 new migrants are arriving every day at the camp, and there are not enough tents, blankets or food.
Dover Conservative MP Charlie Elphicke has said the problems underlined the need to consider expanding the port at Dunkirk, 45 miles from Calais.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
