<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="thestar">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Greek debt sustainable, with new bailout - creditor analysis</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Greek-debt-sustainable-in-most-scenarios-even-worst-does-not-require-a-haircut</Link>
        <Description>BERLIN (Reuters) - Greek debt will miss debt targets set out by creditors in 2012 but an analysis prepared for euro zone finance ministers shows its debt burden is still sustainable without writing off principal -- if Greece gets another three-year bailout.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
BERLIN (Reuters) - Greek debt will miss debt targets set out by creditors in 2012 but an analysis prepared for euro zone finance ministers shows its debt burden is still sustainable without writing off principal -- if Greece gets another three-year bailout.
The analysis, commissioned by the EU creditor governments to help their financing-for-reforms negotiations with Athens, concludes that even in the worst scenario for the Greek economy, the lenders would not have to write off any loans.
Debt relief has been a repeated request from the leftist government in Athens which wants to ease back on austerity.
Under a 2012 bailout agreement, Greece was to reach a debt-to-GDP ratio of 124 percent in 2020 and in 2022 a debt-to-GDP ratio substantially lower than 110 percent, down from 175 percent now.
"It is clear that the policy slippages and uncertainties of the last months have made the achievement of the 2012 targets impossible under any scenario," the analysis, seen by Reuters, said.
"The main factors behind the deterioration of the
Debt Sustainability Analysis are the worsening of economic growth, the revised primary balance path, the lower
privatisation revenues and possible additional financial needs for the banking sector."
Under the revised forecast and the most optimistic scenario that Athens implements all reforms, Greek is debt to fall to 124 percent only in 2022 from 172.8 pct in 2015.
If it implements the reforms only partially, Greek debt will fall only to 135 percent in 2022 from 174.3 pct in 2015.
In the worst case, which the International Monetary Fund sees as its "baseline", which means most likely, Greek debt would fall only to 142.2 percent in 2022 from 176.7 percent in 2015.
"All scenarios assume a new 3-year programme with concessional financing," the analysis said.
The analysis stresses however, that focussing on the debt-to-GDP ratio does not give an accurate picture of debt sustainability and that this is better reflected by gross financing needs of a country.
Measured like this, Greece has no sustainability problem in any scenario, but would require help to improve the sustainability, via for example an extension of maturities, under the third, least favourable option.
"This gross financing need metric points to no sustainability issues under the first two scenarios," the document said.
"The gross financing needs remain well below 15 percent threshold, a threshold mentioned in IMF guidance for
this criterion. Under this scenario, significant reprofiling of the stock of debt and concessional lending terms would improve sustainability," it said.
"Reprofiling of payment flows does not imply nominal
haircut or budgetary costs for creditors. This would also entail further NPV gains for Greece, and strengthen the sustainability of the Greek public debt in the long-run."
=======
        <title>U.S. air strikes target militants near border in east Afghanistan</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/28/US-air-strikes-target-militants-near-border-in-east-Afghanistan</Link>
        <Description>KABUL (Reuters) - U.S. military air strikes have targeted militants who were threatening international coalition forces near the border in eastern Afghanistan, a U.S. forces spokesman said on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 10:00:11 PM
Updated:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 10:00:12 PM
U.S. air strikes target militants near border in east Afghanistan
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
KABUL (Reuters) - U.S. military air strikes have targeted militants who were threatening international coalition forces near the border in eastern Afghanistan, a U.S. forces spokesman said on Sunday.
Most foreign forces withdrew from Afghanistan when NATO combat operations ended last year. Around 13,200 international troops are part of a new training mission, while a small contingent of U.S. troops is separately fighting the Taliban and other militants.
The first air strike took place on Friday in Nuristan, an eastern province next to Pakistan that is partially controlled by the Taliban.
Another strike followed in Paktika on Saturday, a stronghold of the Haqqani network and other groups allied with the Taliban.
A spokesman for U.S. forces in Afghanistan declined to say which troops were involved and the nature of the threat.
"I'll generally say coalition forces for both," Colonel Brian Tribus said.
Six militants were killed in the first air strike, according to an interior ministry report, which also indicated an al Qaeda operative had been killed in the second.
Most U.S. forces withdrew from Afghanistan last year, leaving a small contingent of 9,800 troops to help train Afghan forces and conduct operations against the Taliban and other militants.
This includes around 3,000 U.S. troops that operate outside the new, two-year NATO training mission. The activities of U.S. special forces engaged in counter-terrorism operations have not been made public and little is known of their activities.
In the first fighting season since the official end of the NATO combat mission last year, the Taliban have made gains across the country and succeeded in overrunning 15 district headquarters, according to a senior Afghan security official.
Additionally, support for Islamic State, or Daesh as the group is known locally, has spread and the group is exapnding its contingent of foreign fighters and disenchanted Taliban militants.
(Reporting by Jessica Donati and Hamid Shalizi; editing by Ralph Boulton)
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Some say back to the drachma for a Greek reboot</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Some-say-back-to-the-drachma-for-a-Greek-reboot</Link>
        <Description>LONDON (Reuters) - Mainstream economic thinking may hold that Greece should stay in the euro zone, but there are those who argue that abandoning the single currency will give the cash-strapped and debt-laden country just the boost it needs.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:35:03 PM
Updated:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:35:03 PM
Some say back to the drachma for a Greek reboot
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
LONDON (Reuters) - Mainstream economic thinking may hold that Greece should stay in the euro zone, but there are those who argue that abandoning the single currency will give the cash-strapped and debt-laden country just the boost it needs.
Greece's economy is so depressed, they argue, that unless it regains the competitive edge a massive one-off currency devaluation could offer, it will remain lifeless.
Until then, the idea of a euro zone exit - either by accident or design - will keep on returning.
Roger Bootle, the founder of London-based markets and economic analysis group Capital Economics, won an economics prize of 250,000 pounds ($395,000) three years ago for drawing up a guide on how an ailing nation would exit the euro.
"If Greece were to leave the euro, it is presented with an opportunity. That doesn't mean to say it will take it," he says, arguing that the current negotiations about Greece's debt miss the point.
"How does a debt deal bring about an increase in aggregate demand in Greece? No one seems to be grappling with the economic issue."
Greece and its creditors are locked in talks to secure a deal that will see Greece undertake further economic reforms in return for more aid, thereby averting default on debt repayments to the International Monetary Fund on June 30.
The new proposals currently on the table include further long-term cuts to pensions as well as additional taxation that, while encouraging change in the economy overall, will have the effect of further weakening demand.
There are major caveats to Greece departing from the euro, not least the fact that no legal mechanism exists for a country to leave the currency union.
It would probably create a huge political and financial mess, including a default on all private and public external debts, soaring prices of imported goods and an end to a river of EU money which has pumped billions into infrastructure since Greece joined the bloc in 1981.
So what, says the head of investment for Dutch pension and investment fund manager Nationale Nederlanden, Hans Stoter, if you can have strong growth within a year or so of leaving the euro, when between times the economy has shrunk 30 percent.
"If you have a sore thumb and the infection keeps getting bigger and bigger, you can medicate it, you can deal with it," he says. "Or you can cut off your arm."
BOOST
The most immediate and tangible consequences of leaving would be a sizeable, one-off devaluation in the currency which Athens adopts, possibly the drachma.
Bootle suggests a one-off devaluation of 30 percent could be worth anything up to a 20 percent boost to Greece's economic output, although that would hinge on many other fiscal, regulatory and tax policies being adopted too.
Devaluation is no panacea and wouldn't address the fundamental problems of the Greek economy like the lack of reforms, corruption, and a bloated public sector, Bootle said. But it would give a huge boost to the Greek tourism industry and other service sectors.
He attaches an 80-90 percent likelihood that Greece will ultimately leave the euro zone, and points to Argentina, Russia, Iceland and South Korea as examples over the past 20 years of economies that did "extremely well" out of major currency devaluations.
Neil Record, founder and chairman of Record Currency Management, another of the finalists for the Wolfson award in 2012, assumed the wholesale collapse of the euro and provided for both a 40 percent devaluation of the drachma, as well as a 30 percent revaluation of a new Deutschmark.
Under that scenario, drawing parallels with Argentina, Record said Greece could easily register real growth after inflation of 5 percent annually from 2016.
"It's reasonable to suppose they would have a really awful, torrid 2015," he said. "But in the sort of magical way of these things they could easily then be the best performing country in Europe in 2016 and 2017."
DYSFUNCTION
Paul Krugman, Nobel laureate and professor of economics and international affairs at Princeton University, has been a highly vocal critic of the euro project, saying its inflexible monetary structure has strangled growth in weaker countries like Greece.
He had never advocated "Grexit" and argues that leaving the euro isn't the same as never entering.
But he wrote in The New York Times on June 19: "Grexit would produce a rapid improvement in competitiveness, at the cost of possible financial chaos."
A year ago, the IMF predicted that the Greek economy would contract by 0.6 percent in 2014 before growing almost 3 percent this year and more than 3 percent every year through to 2019, when the country's huge output gap would finally be closed.
But 2014 growth has come at -0.1 percent, making the forecasts for the rest of the decade look decidedly optimistic.
(Reporting by Jamie McGeever and Patrick Graham Editing by Jeremy Gaunt)
=======
        <title>Danish Liberals leader appointed PM, names his cabinet</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/28/Danish-Liberals-leader-appointed-PM-names-his-cabinet</Link>
        <Description>COPENHAGEN (Reuters) - Liberal party leader Lars Lokke Rasmussen was appointed Danish prime minister on Sunday and named ministers in a government that has a small minority in parliament and will have to rely heavily on outside support on a vote by vote basis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 10:00:03 PM
Updated:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 10:00:08 PM
Danish Liberals leader appointed PM, names his cabinet
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
COPENHAGEN (Reuters) - Liberal party leader Lars Lokke Rasmussen was appointed Danish prime minister on Sunday and named ministers in a government that has a small minority in parliament and will have to rely heavily on outside support on a vote by vote basis.
The Liberals were part of a group of centre-right parties that won a general election over a week ago but the party itself had its worst results in a quarter of a century and was unable to form a broad coalition within the bloc.
The Danish People's Party (DF), eurosceptic and rightwing in most aspects of its policies, refused to join the government despite winning its best election result yet and becoming the largest party on the right in parliament.
It had held out on a number of demands including a referendum on whether Denmark should remain in the European Union, spending increases and curbs on immigration.
Rasmussen will now have to depend on other parties' support, including the DF, on a vote by vote basis. He said on Friday he would form a minority government over the weekend after talks with DF and other parties collapsed.
He named veteran party member Claus Frederiksen as finance minister, a position he has held in 2009 to 2011. Frederiksen is known to have a good working relationship with DF.
Kristian Jensen was named foreign minister. He has little experience in this sphere but has a senior rank in the party and was at one point last year widely expected to take over leadership from Rasmussen, who was hit by an expenses scandal.
With 34 seats of 179 in parliament, this is the second smallest government formed in Denmark's history and some pundits doubt it will manage a full term. Only one government, in 1973, had fewer members in parliament, with 22 seats. That cabinet lasted 14 months.
(Reporting by Sabina Zawadzki; editing by Ralph Boulton)
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>At least 19 killed in gun attack on Tunisian tourism hotel - official</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Tourist-hotel-in-Tunisias-Sousse-attacked--security-source</Link>
        <Description>TUNIS (Reuters) - At least 19 people have been killed after at least one gunman attacked a Tunisian tourist hotel in the popular resort of Sousse, an interior ministry official said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
TUNIS (Reuters) - At least 19 people have been killed after at least one gunman attacked a Tunisian tourist hotel in the popular resort of Sousse, an interior ministry official said on Friday.
(Reporting by Tarek Amara; writing by Patrick Markey; editing by John Stonestreet)
=======
        <title>Gunmen kill senior Iraqi oil official in Iraq&amp;#39;s Kirkuk</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/28/Gunmen-kill-senior-Iraqi-oil-official-in-Iraqs-Kirkuk</Link>
        <Description>BAGHDAD (Reuters) - Gunmen shot dead a senior oil official working for Iraq&amp;#39;s state-run North Oil Company (NOC) on Sunday, police and company officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 9:50:03 PM
Updated:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 9:50:04 PM
Gunmen kill senior Iraqi oil official in Iraq's Kirkuk
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
BAGHDAD (Reuters) - Gunmen shot dead a senior oil official working for Iraq's state-run North Oil Company (NOC) on Sunday, police and company officials said.
NOC's chief of operations, Saad al-Karbalaie, was killed in the northern oil city of Kirkuk after gunmen forced him to stop his vehicle as he was leaving his office and then shot him, police sources said.
There was no immediate claim of responsibility for the attack on Karbalaie, who was supervising production and export facilities in Kirkuk.
Major oil producer and OPEC member Iraq faces security challenges from the ultra-hardline Sunni Islamic State which controls a third of the country, and a sectarian conflict exacerbated by the group's presence.
Baiji refinery, north of Baghdad, is a focal point for government efforts to slow the advance of Islamic State. The complex has changed hands several times in months of fighting.
(Reporting by Baghdad bureau; writing by Michael Georgy; editing by Jason Neely)
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Germany&amp;#39;s Schaeuble says sees 50:50 chance of Greek deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Germanys-Schaeuble-says-sees-5050-chance-of-reaching-Greek-deal</Link>
        <Description>FRANKFURT (Reuters) - There is a 50-50 chance of the euro zone reaching an agreement with Greece about the reforms it needs to make in return for further aid, Germany&amp;#39;s finance minister said on Friday, adding that failure could compromise the currency bloc.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
FRANKFURT (Reuters) - There is a 50-50 chance of the euro zone reaching an agreement with Greece about the reforms it needs to make in return for further aid, Germany's finance minister said on Friday, adding that failure could compromise the currency bloc.
Wolfgang Schaeuble's comments underlined the significant risk of failure of last-ditch negotiations this weekend to unlock loans to Greece and avert a default.
"I do not say what will be the outcome, it's 50-50," Schaeuble told a conference, referring to the negotiations.
He criticised proposals from Greece's finance minister which he said were focussed purely on hiking taxes without spending cuts.
Warning that much was at stake in the event of failure to clinch an agreement, Schaeuble said he was nonetheless prepared to take tough decisions.
"If we lose the confidence of the markets then ... we destroy the monetary union, the stability of the euro, and we are risking a lot more, and therefore the decision is not very easy to take but we will take it," he said.
Greece failed again on Thursday to reach a deal with its international creditors and talks with its international backers will resume on Saturday.
Schaeuble said Greece's principled stance in negotiations, where it is pushing for lenient reforms and a debt restructuring, was at odds with other euro zone countries.
"If you are on the autobahn and you are saying this is the right direction and all the others are driving in the other direction ... you are making a mistake."
(Reporting By John O'Donnell, Thomas Atkins and Marc Jones; Editing by Gareth Jones)
=======
        <title>Taiwan probes water park fire as tally of injured put at 498</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/28/Nearly-200-injured-amid-fire-explosion-in-Taiwan--media</Link>
        <Description>TAIPEI (Reuters) - The number of party revellers injured in a fire at a Taiwan water park was put at 498 on Sunday as authorities began investigating the cause, suspected to be a sudden explosion of a coloured powder thrown on those attending the party.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 9:50:02 PM
Updated:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 9:50:02 PM
Taiwan probes water park fire as tally of injured put at 498
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
TAIPEI (Reuters) - The number of party revellers injured in a fire at a Taiwan water park was put at 498 on Sunday as authorities began investigating the cause, suspected to be a sudden explosion of a coloured powder thrown on those attending the party.
Six foreigners and seven visitors from Hong Kong, mainland China and Macau were among those injured after about 1,000 people dancing at Saturday's event were sprayed with the powder, as a special feature of a festival also held in previous years.
The figure released late Sunday by local authorities was lower than an earlier estimate of 519 injured due to patients being transferred between hospitals and being double-counted, a government official said.
The blaze, which broke out at around 8.30 p.m. at the Formosa Fun Coast water park on the outskirts of the capital, Taipei, is suspected to have been caused by an explosion of the coloured powder, local government official Lin Chieh-yu told Reuters.
"It remains under investigation as to what made the powder explode," he said.
Authorities have banned the use of the powder until the investigation is completed and its safety can be assured.
"The next few days will be a critical time for the injured," Taiwan Premier Mao Chi-kuo told reporters. All of the 498 injured were still being treated in 43 hospitals across the island, according to the latest figures provided by the New Taipei City government.
In the immediate aftermath of the explosion, rescuers treated hundreds of people, most of them aged between 20 and 30, who wore wet swimsuits and lay on inflatable plastic doughnuts.
A video posted online by Apple Daily showed dancers in front of the stage engulfed in clouds of coloured powder a moment before a fireball erupted, followed by pockets of flame, triggering panic and screams.
"There was blood and people were on fire," one injured man  said.
No death has yet been reported, but victims suffered burns on limbs and torsos, with some passing out from the pain while others had burned clothes stuck to their skin, media reports and pictures showed.
"Her whole life is ruined," sobbed the father of Chu Li, an 18-year-old girl with burns on 80 percent of her body, during a visit by President Ma Ying-jeou to victims in a Taipei hospital.
Soldiers, army vehicles and medical services joined the rescue effort, while hospitals in four municipal precincts, along with Taipei, are treating sufferers.
The amusement park has been closed temporarily, it said on its website on Sunday.
Taipei has sweltered in temperatures exceeding 30 degrees Celsius (86 degrees Fahrenheit) in recent weeks.
(Additional reporting by Faith Hung; Editing by Clarence Fernandez and Digby Lidstone)
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Merkel, Hollande dangle financing before Greece&amp;#39;s Tsipras</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Greek-minister-says-two-or-three-issues-remaining-in-debt-talks</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS (Reuters) - The leaders of Germany and France offered to release billions in frozen aid on Friday in a last-minute push to talk Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras into contentious pension reforms in exchange for filling Athens&amp;#39; empty coffers until November.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:10:07 PM
Updated:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:10:07 PM
Merkel, Hollande dangle financing before Greece's Tsipras
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
BRUSSELS (Reuters) - The leaders of Germany and France offered to release billions in frozen aid on Friday in a last-minute push to talk Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras into contentious pension reforms in exchange for filling Athens' empty coffers until November.
The leftist premier's response, according to a Greek official, was that he could not understand why his country's creditors were seeking to impose such harsh conditions in return for money to avert imminent default and damage to the euro zone.
Chancellor Angela Merkel and President Francois Hollande, whose countries are Athens' two biggest lenders, held a 45-minute private meeting with Tsipras before the final session of a European Union summit at which they went through details of immediate funding for Greece if it would sign the deal.
The creditors laid out terms in a document that went to Greece on Thursday and was seen by Reuters on Friday. It said Greece could have 15.5 billion euros in EU and IMF funding in four instalments to see it through to the end of November, including 1.8 billion euros by Tuesday as soon as the Athens parliament approved the plan.
The total is slightly more than Greece needs to service its debts over the next six months but contains no new money.
A French source said Merkel and Hollande discussed outstanding differences on reforms Greece needs to accept - centred on pension reform, labour law and increasing value added tax - as well as an extension to Athens' bailout programme and financing.
Merkel and Hollande both said that Saturday's emergency meeting of euro zone finance ministers would be decisive to seal a deal before Greece has to make a key IMF repayment for which the government has said it lacks the money.
"Saturday's meeting is crucial because we are on the eve of a date, June 30, when the Greek authorities have to meet a payment obligation," Hollande told a news conference. "It's also crucial because there are parliaments that have to meet if there's a deal."
The Eurogroup ministers will meet at 5 p.m. (1500 GMT) on Saturday and Greece will be asked whether it accepts a revised offer from the European Commission, the European Central Bank and the International Monetary Fund, a euro zone official said.
"PLAN B"
If Greece refuses, the ministers will move on to discussing a "Plan B" on preparing to limit the damage from a Greek default to Greek banks and other euro zone countries and markets, the official said.
However, Merkel and Hollande have refused to talk publicly about a "Plan B", saying their efforts are focused on getting an agreement to keep Greece in the euro zone.
In public, Berlin kept up the pressure on Athens to yield, saying it was up to the Greek government to move.
Officials said that talks to reconcile the creditors' and Greek positions were continuing behind the scenes, even though Greece continues to denounce the lenders' proposals.
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis had another blast at the creditors' approach in an interview with Irish radio on Friday, saying their demands for tax increases and pension cuts as conditions for disbursing aid were putting Greece in an impossible position.
"I am against increasing the corporate tax, but then again I am against raising the tax on hotels and against cutting the pensions of people who live below the poverty line," Varoufakis said on Irish national radio RTE.
"These issues are putting me and my government in an impossible position, having to make a bad choice among really hard, difficult bad choices."
But he did not rule out accepting the terms.
Dramatising the choice facing Athens, Germany's member of the European Commission, Guenter Oettinger, said Greece had five days left to avoid an exit from the euro zone.
DIVIDED
Euro zone finance ministers are divided over whether a default would necessarily lead to Athens leaving the 19-nation single currency area, which would undermine the principle that membership is irrevocable.
Failure to pay the 1.6 billion IMF euro instalment on Tuesday could trigger a bank run, capital controls to curb deposit flight and possibly the issuance of IOUs or a parallel currency.
China, a growing economic partner of the EU, offered a vote of confidence in the euro zone on Friday ahead of Premier Li Keqiang's visit to Europe next week, saying it was sure Greece's talks with creditors would go positively.
Confidential documents drawn up by Greece's creditors and seen by Reuters showed that the country's debt would remain sustainable, even under a worst-case scenario envisaged by the IMF, if the maturities on euro zone loans were extended and interest rates were cut, without the need for a write-down.
The calculations are regarded as crucial to persuade German lawmakers to agree to the aid disbursement.
They showed that in the most severe case, Greek debt would require substantial "reprofiling" and improved lending terms but no "haircut" nor budgetary costs for the lenders.
Tsipras and Varoufakis have insisted so far that a commitment to debt relief is essential for Greece to accept any deal, while Germany and its allies had refused up to now to discuss the issue until Athens enacts and implements the reform programme to complete its current bailout.
The fact that Hollande and Merkel discussed financing issues with Tsipras on Friday may indicate a new willingness to address the issue as part of a deal.
(Additional reporting by Matthias Sobolewski in Berlin, Jan Strupczewski and Andreas Rinke in Brussels; Writing by Paul Taylor; Editing by Sophie Walker)
=======
        <title>Iran nuclear talks set to go beyond deadline as differences remain</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/28/EUs-Mogherini-says-not-impossible-to-get-Iran-nuclear-deal</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - The six world powers seeking to negotiate an historic agreement with Iran to curb its nuclear programme plan to carry on negotiating beyond a Tuesday deadline, a senior U.S. official</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 9:15:06 PM
Updated:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 9:15:06 PM
Iran nuclear talks set to go beyond deadline as differences remain
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
VIENNA (Reuters) - The six world powers seeking to negotiate an historic agreement with Iran to curb its nuclear programme plan to carry on negotiating beyond a Tuesday deadline, a senior U.S. official
said on Sunday.
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif was to leave Vienna and return to Tehran for consultations with the country's leadership on the state of negotiations, Iran said.
Officials from both sides said big differences still remained.
European Union foreign policy chief Frederica Mogherini said earlier on Sunday it was not impossible to get an accord by the self-imposed deadline but that a few extra days may be needed.
Foreign ministers from the negotiating countries were gathering in Vienna on Sunday to assess where the talks stood.
They expected them to spill over into July.
"Zarif will return to Tehran tonight and will come back to Vienna tomorrow," Iran's Tasnim news agency said, citing an unnamed Iranian official.
An Iranian official told Reuters that Zarif would "consult with the leadership" over the talks in Vienna.
The U.S. official, who spoke to reporters on condition of
anonymity, said Washington was not troubled by Zarif's decision to return to Tehran overnight, saying it was always expected that ministers would come and go from Vienna as the talks heated up.
The negotiations aim to limit Tehran's nuclear programme in exchange for a lifting of U.S., European Union and United Nations sanctions on Tehran.
The United States, Israel and some Western nations fear that Iran has been trying to develop a nuclear weapons capability, but Tehran says its programme is for peaceful purposes only.
The main differences are on the pace and timing of sanctions relief for Iran and on the nature of monitoring mechanisms to ensure Tehran does not cheat on any agreement.
U.S. and European negotiators also want to ensure there is a mechanism for restoring sanctions if Tehran fails to meet its commitments under any future accord.
In November, the seven nations involved in the talks set a late March deadline for a framework agreement, which they ultimately reached on April 2, and a June 30 deadline for a comprehensive deal.
Highlighting how much work remains, British Foreign Minister Philip Hammond said on arrival in Vienna that major challenges remained, including on the parameters already agreed in April.
"There are a number of different areas where we still have major differences of interpretation in detailing what was agreed in Lausanne)," Hammond told reporters.
"There is going to have to be some give or take if we are to get this done in the next few days," he said. "No deal is better than a bad deal."
In addition to Britain, Iran and the United States, the talks include China, France, Germany and Russia.
Speaking after a cabinet meeting in Jerusalem, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said too many concessions were being made to Tehran.
"We see before our very eyes a stark retreat from the red lines that the world powers set themselves only recently, and publicly," said Netanyahu, whose country is generally believed to have the Middle East's only nuclear arsenal.
"There is no reason to hasten into signing this bad deal, which is getting worse by the day."
(Additional reporting by Louis Charbonneau, Arshad Mohammed and Shadia Nasralla and Dan Williams in Jerusalem; Editing by Angus MacSwan)
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>U.S. President Obama briefed on attack in France</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/US-President-Obama-briefed-on-attack-in-France</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. President Barack Obama has been briefed on the attack at a U.S. gas company in France, a senior administration official said on Friday, providing no further details.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:05:02 PM
Updated:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:05:03 PM
U.S. President Obama briefed on attack in France
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. President Barack Obama has been briefed on the attack at a U.S. gas company in France, a senior administration official said on Friday, providing no further details.
A severed head covered in Arabic writing was found at the company in southeastern France, police sources and French media said. The site belonged to Air Products
, a U.S. industrial gases and chemicals company, according to another French company in the same sector.
(Reporting by Roberta Rampton; Writing by Bill Trott; Editing by Susan Heavey)
=======
        <title>Air strikes in northwest Pakistan kill 20 militants - officials</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/28/Air-strikes-in-northwest-Pakistan-kill-10-militants--officials</Link>
        <Description>BANNU, Pakistan (Reuters) - Air strikes killed at least 20 suspected militants in Pakistan&amp;#39;s northwestern Shawal Valley on Sunday, intelligence officials said, more than a month after security forces moved in on Pakistani Taliban strongholds in the region.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
BANNU, Pakistan (Reuters) - Air strikes killed at least 20 suspected militants in Pakistan's northwestern Shawal Valley on Sunday, intelligence officials said, more than a month after security forces moved in on Pakistani Taliban strongholds in the region.
The deeply forested ravines are a smuggling route between Pakistan and neighbouring Afghanistan, and are dotted with militant bases used as launch pads for attacks on Pakistani forces.
Two intelligence officials, who declined to be identified as they are not authorised to speak on the record, said the latest air strikes occurred in the Zoinari area of North Waziristan.
"We got information that local and foreign fighters were hiding in this area," said one of the officials. "Three hideouts were also completely destroyed."
Initially, 10 militants were reported killed but the intelligence officials later raised the toll to 20.
The hard-line Islamist Taliban's Pakistani wing used to control all of North Waziristan, a mountainous region that includes the Shawal Valley and runs along the Afghan border. But the Pakistani military has recaptured most of it in an operation launched last June.
NATO forces had long urged Pakistan for such an offensive, saying Taliban safe havens in Pakistan were being used to attack NATO and Afghan forces in Afghanistan.
Since last month, the military has stepped up operations in Shawal Valley, where the Taliban still operates freely.
The area is a stronghold of Khan "Sajna" Said, the leader of a Taliban faction whose name was added to a sanctions list of "specially designated global terrorists" by U.S. authorities last year.
Most phone lines to the area have been cut and military roadblocks curtail civilian movement.
The Pakistani Taliban mainly fight against the government in Islamabad and are separate from, but allied with, the Afghan Taliban that ruled Afghanistan in the late 1990s before being expelled in a U.S.-led intervention.
Both groups send fighters against Afghanistan's Western-backed government. Afghan officials have said the Pakistani army offensive has driven large numbers of fighters over the border, complicating the war in Afghanistan's east and north.
(Writing by Mehreen Zahra-Malik; Editing by Clarence Fernandez and Digby Lidstone)
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Casualties in attack on Tunisian beach hotel, at least one gunman killed - source</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Casualties-in-attack-on-Tunisian-beach-hotel-at-least-one-gunman-killed--source</Link>
        <Description>TUNIS (Reuters) - Casualties have been reported in an attack on a beach hotel in the Tunisian city of Sousse, and at least one gunman has been killed in clashes there, a security source said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
TUNIS (Reuters) - Casualties have been reported in an attack on a beach hotel in the Tunisian city of Sousse, and at least one gunman has been killed in clashes there, a security source said on Friday.
Sousse is one of the North African country's most popular beach resorts, drawing tourists from Europe and neighbouring countries. Tunisia has been high alert since Islamist gunmen attacked the Bardo museum in Tunis in March, killing a group of foreign visitors.
(Reporting by Tarek Amara; writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Dominic Evans)
=======
        <title>Iran, big powers plan to keep negotiating beyond June 30</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/28/Iran-big-powers-plan-to-keep-negotiating-beyond-June-30</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - The six nations seeking to negotiate a long-term agreement with Iran to curb the most sensitive parts of its nuclear programme plan to continue negotiating beyond Tuesday&amp;#39;s deadline, a senior U.S. official said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 9:05:03 PM
Updated:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 9:05:04 PM
Iran, big powers plan to keep negotiating beyond June 30
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
VIENNA (Reuters) - The six nations seeking to negotiate a long-term agreement with Iran to curb the most sensitive parts of its nuclear programme plan to continue negotiating beyond Tuesday's deadline, a senior U.S. official said.
The official, who spoke to reporters on condition of anonymity on Sunday, said Washington was not troubled by Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif's decision to return to Tehran overnight, saying it was always expected that ministers would come and go from Vienna as the nuclear talks heated up.
Iran's Tasnim news agency reported that Zarif would return to Austria on Monday.
(Reporting By Arshad Mohammed and Louis Charbonneau)
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Kuwait mosque bomb kills 4, governor says, 8 badly hurt</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Kuwait-mosque-bomb-kills-4-governor-says-8-badly-hurt</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - Four people were killed in a suicide attack on Friday on a Shi&amp;#39;ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait City, the governor of Kuwait City Thabet al-Muhanna said. </Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:00:04 PM
Updated: Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:00:04 PM
Kuwait mosque bomb kills 4, governor says, 8 badly hurt
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
DUBAI (Reuters) - Four people were killed in a suicide attack on Friday on a Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait City, the governor of Kuwait City Thabet al-Muhanna said.
Speaking by telephone from Kuwait, Muhanna told Reuters that eight people were in critical condition. A witness said the bombing happened when the mosque was packed with some 2,000 worshippers during Friday prayers.
(Reporting by Hadeel al Sayegh, Writing by William Maclean; editing by John Stonestreet)
=======
        <title>Factbox - A guide to nuclear talks between Iran and six major powers</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/28/Factbox--A-guide-to-nuclear-talks-between-Iran-and-six-major-powers</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - Iran and six world powers - the United States, Britain, France, Germany, Russia and China - are in what may be the final phase of negotiations aimed at securing a deal on sanctions relief in exchange for limits on Iranian nuclear activities.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
VIENNA (Reuters) - Iran and six world powers - the United States, Britain, France, Germany, Russia and China - are in what may be the final phase of negotiations aimed at securing a deal on sanctions relief in exchange for limits on Iranian nuclear activities.
The six powers have a June 30 deadline but diplomats close to the talks expect that to slip.
BACKGROUND
The nuclear standoff between Iran and the West goes back to at least 2002, when a group of exiles revealed undeclared nuclear facilities in Iran. The International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) later confirmed that they were a uranium enrichment plant at Natanz and a heavy-water production plant at Arak. Iran says its nuclear programme is peaceful but Western intelligence agencies are convinced Iran had a nuclear arms programme that went dormant, possibly as far back as 2003.
In 2003, Britain, France and Germany began an inconclusive effort to persuade Iran to suspend uranium enrichment, a process that can produce fissile material, the key component for an atomic bomb.
In 2006, the United States dropped its opposition to engagement with Iran and joined the three European powers, along with Russia and China, a group known both as the "P5+1" and the "E3+3".
That year, the United Nations Security Council imposed sanctions on Iran for refusing to suspend enrichment and other sensitive nuclear work. This was followed by more draconian restrictions imposed by the United Nations, the United States and the European Union.
Negotiations stalled until Iranian President Hassan Rouhani's 2013 election. In November 2013, Iran and the six powers reached an interim deal that gave Tehran limited sanctions relief in exchange for some curbs on its most sensitive nuclear work. It was meant to buy time to negotiate a final, long-term pact. The interim deal has been extended twice, in July and November last year.
On April 2, Iran and the six agreed on the parameters for a final, long-term deal in Lausanne, Switzerland. The deadline for an agreement is June 30, though negotiations are expected to run into July.
REGIONAL CONTEXT
Israel and Saudi Arabia, Iran's main regional foes, are sceptical of the negotiations and oppose a deal. Iran has become more assertive in the Middle East, supporting proxies in Yemen, Syria and Lebanon.
Analysts believe that if Iran secures sanctions relief it will boost its confidence as a regional power and improve its flagging economy. Sunni-ruled Arab states fear it will give Shi'ite Iran more resources to fan regional conflicts.
BREAKOUT TIME
The point of an agreement is to reduce Iran's nuclear "breakout" time - the time needed to produce enough highly enriched uranium or bomb-grade plutonium for a single weapon - to at least one year from the current estimate of 2-3 months.
U.S. CONGRESSIONAL REVIEW
Under a law pushed by Republicans sceptical of negotiations with Iran and ultimately backed by the White House, President Barack Obama's administration will have to submit any agreement to Congress for a 30-day review period during which Obama will refrain from suspending sanctions. If Congress receives the text of a deal after July 9, that review period will be doubled to 60 days, which officials close to the talks worry is too long.
STICKING POINTS
SANCTIONS RELIEF - Sanctions will be suspended and later terminated based on verification of Iran's compliance with the agreement. There are disputes about the timing. Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei wants sanctions lifted as soon as there is a deal, though Western powers say they will be suspended gradually, in return for steps by Iran to constrain its nuclear programme.
U.N. nuclear-related sanctions will be removed on the basis of a Security Council resolution. Those sanctions will be restored under a "snapback" plan if Iran violates the deal
CENTRIFUGES - Machines that purify uranium for use in nuclear power plants or weapons. In Lausanne, Iran agreed to reduce its roughly 19,000 centrifuges installed at two enrichment facilities - Natanz and Fordow - to 6,104.
All 6,104 centrifuges are to be first-generation IR-1s. Iran also agreed to not enrich uranium beyond 3.67 percent for at least 15 years - well below the 90 percent needed for weapons.
There would be 5,060 centrifuges at Natanz and 1,044 at Fordow. Iran would be prevented from installing further centrifuges for 15 years.
RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT - Iran wants to continue research and development (R&amp;D) into uranium enrichment.
According to a French fact sheet, Tehran would be allowed a "gradual and precisely defined increase in (enrichment) capacity between the tenth and thirteenth years with the introduction of advanced IR-2 and IR-4 centrifuges."
According to the United States, the two sides agreed in Lausanne that Iran would be allowed to conduct limited R&amp;D using advanced centrifuges, pending the approval of the other powers.
Critics of a possible deal are opposed to Iran acquiring further nuclear expertise.
MONITORING AND VERIFICATION - Iran and the six have yet to agree on a detailed plan for monitoring and verifying the implementation of the deal. The biggest sticking point is access for International Atomic Energy Agency inspectors to Iranian military sites and nuclear scientists. Khamenei has said both would be off-limits, though Western officials say Iranian negotiators have indicated access would be possible.
DURATION - If there is a deal, Iran's uranium enrichment programme will be subject to limitations for a period of 15 years. After 10 years, some of those would be eased. Khamenei has said Iran would not limit its nuclear activity for as long as 10 years, even though Tehran agreed to that in Lausanne.
URANIUM STOCKPILE - Iran is to reduce its current stockpile of about 8,700 kg of low-enriched uranium (LEU) to 300 kg of 3.67 percent LEU for 15 years. Iran had previously said it was unwilling to ship LEU out of the country and, instead, wants to convert much of the LEU to a less proliferation-risky form. Officials close to the talks say this issue remains unresolved. Olli Heinonen, a nuclear expert and former IAEA deputy chief, says the one-year breakout target cannot be achieved without shipping much of the material out of the country.
ARAK HEAVY-WATER REACTOR - Iran agreed to rebuild the Arak heavy-water research reactor based on a design agreed by the six. The idea is that it will focus on peaceful research and the production of medical isotopes. Officials say the redesign has yet to be agreed.
POSSIBLE MILITARY DIMENSIONS (PMD) - Under the Lausanne agreement, Iran must answer queries the IAEA has about past activities that may have been related to atomic weapons research. Iran has been stonewalling the IAEA probe. Western officials have said that some sanctions relief under a possible nuclear deal would depend on resolving those queries.
U.S. and other Western officials said U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry called Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif and told him that PMD questions must be resolved.
(Compiled by Louis Charbonneau; Editing by Digby Lidstone)
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Islamic State claims responsibility for Kuwait mosque attack - statement</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Islamic-State-claims-responsibility-for-Kuwait-mosque-attack--statement</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - Militant group Islamic State claimed responsibility for a suicide attack on a Shi&amp;#39;ite mosque in Kuwait that killed or wounded several people, according a statement posted on social media.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
DUBAI (Reuters) - Militant group Islamic State claimed responsibility for a suicide attack on a Shi'ite mosque in Kuwait that killed or wounded several people, according a statement posted on social media.
The statement identified the bomber as Abu Suleiman al-Muwahed and said the target was a "temple of the rejectionists" - a term used by the Islamist militant group to refer to Shi'ite Muslims - and said dozens were killed or wounded.
(Reporting by Omar Fahmy, writing by Sami Aboudi; editing by John Stonestreet)
=======
        <title>Lufthansa readies compensation for Germanwings crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/28/Lufthansa-readies-compensation-for-Germanwings-crash</Link>
        <Description>FRANKFURT (Reuters) - Deutsche Lufthansa plans to make offers of compensation in the coming days to the families of those killed in the crash of a Germanwings jet in the French Alps in late March, a spokesman for the airline said on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 9:00:04 PM
Updated:                 Sunday June 28, 2015 MYT 9:00:07 PM
Lufthansa readies compensation for Germanwings crash
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
FRANKFURT (Reuters) - Deutsche Lufthansa plans to make offers of compensation in the coming days to the families of those killed in the crash of a Germanwings jet in the French Alps in late March, a spokesman for the airline said on Sunday.
Germany's biggest airline has already paid immediate financial assistance of up to 50,000 euros per victim in the crash, in which 150 people were killed.
(Reporting by Peter Maushagen,; Writing by Jonathan Gould, editing by William Hardy)
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Israeli forces shoot and kill Palestinian gunman in West Bank - army</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Israeli-forces-shoot-and-kill-Palestinian-gunman-in-West-Bank--army</Link>
        <Description>JERUSALEM (Reuters) - Israeli soldiers shot and killed a Palestinian gunman in the occupied West Bank on Friday after he opened fire on them at a checkpoint, the Israeli military said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
JERUSALEM (Reuters) - Israeli soldiers shot and killed a Palestinian gunman in the occupied West Bank on Friday after he opened fire on them at a checkpoint, the Israeli military said.
It was the third such violent incident in eight days.
On Sunday a Palestinian stabbed and wounded an Israeli paramilitary policeman outside the walled Old City of Jerusalem. The policeman shot back and wounded him. Last Friday a suspected Palestinian gunman shot at two Israeli hikers near a Jewish settlement in the West Bank and killed one. The assailant escaped.
There were no Israeli casualties in the latest incident.
Palestinians seek a state in East Jerusalem, the West Bank and the Gaza Strip, territories Israel captured in the 1967 Middle East war. The last round of peace talks between the sides broke down in April 2014.
Palestinian militants this month fired rockets into Israel from Gaza, drawing Israeli return fire. That frontier has been largely quiet since the Gaza war last year in which more than 2,100 Palestinians and 73 on the Israeli side were killed.
(Writing by Maayan Lubell; Editing by Mark Trevelyan)
=======
        <title>French attack suspect: lone wolf Islamist or &amp;#34;guy who flipped&amp;#34;? </title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/28/French-attack-suspect-lone-wolf-Islamist-or-guy-who-flipped</Link>
        <Description>PARIS (Reuters) - Even as French investigators piece together a clearer picture of events that led on Friday to the beheading of a transport firm manager and attempted destruction of a chemicals plant, the real motivation of the chief suspect remains elusive.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
PARIS (Reuters) - Even as French investigators piece together a clearer picture of events that led on Friday to the beheading of a transport firm manager and attempted destruction of a chemicals plant, the real motivation of the chief suspect remains elusive.
Yassin Salhi, the 35-year-old delivery man suspected of killing his boss, was a father of three with a permanent job and an apartment in a modest but peaceful suburb of the southeastern city of Lyon, and a clean criminal record.
But Salhi had in the past frequented Islamic radicals and was one of thousands of hardliners who caught French authorities' attention among an overwhelmingly moderate Muslim population of five million.
Sources close to the investigation said on Sunday that Salhi, after at first refusing to respond to interrogators, had confessed to killing his manager. Yet many grey areas remain in understanding Friday's attack on a secured industrial site at the heart of one of Europe's top transport hubs.
Searches on his home turned up no weapons cache, propaganda material or evidence of accomplices. Possibly the most troubling detail thrown up by the probe so far is that he sent by "Whatsapp" a macabre selfie posing with the severed head to a Canadian telephone number.
This is a far cry from the detailed body of facts amassed around the three gunmen behind January's Islamist attacks in Paris, where investigators found a weapons haul at the home of one killer and evidence that another had arms training in Yemen. A third was known to have been radicalised in prison.
A testimony by a friend of the victim reported by Le Figaro daily suggested Salhi and his boss had several heated arguments. Other local media cited his former martial arts instructor as saying the otherwise calm Salhi was subject to such outbursts of rage that other pupils would refuse to spar with him.
That the suspect gave the killing the appearance of an Islamist strike is so far not sufficient to convince investigators that he was motivated by a jihadist ideology.
"We don't know whether we're dealing with a fundamentalist who flipped or a real terrorist," one source close to the investigation said.
"Investigators are wondering whether this isn't just a simple criminal act."
STRANGULATION MARKS
Interviewed on French radio minutes after Friday's events became known, the distraught-sounding wife of Salhi said he had set off from home around 7.00 am for the 6-km (4-mile) car ride to the small transport firm that employed him.
There he met up with Herve Cornara, his 54-year-old manager. Cornara's wife, who helped him run the business, saw them together around 7.30 am before she herself went off to make a delivery, according to sources cited by Le JDD weekly newspaper.
What happened between then and 9.28 am, the moment at which prosecutors say video surveillance cameras saw Salhi's Peugeot Boxer pull up at the gate of U.S.-based gas and chemicals group Air Products in nearby Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, is a mystery.
While the autopsy on the victim has revealed strangulation marks, investigators say it is not clear whether he died by decapitation. For now, Salhi has said only that the killing took place in an as yet unidentified car park.
As someone who had made deliveries to the site in the past, Salhi passed without problem through the gates of the Air Products premises and then out of sight of the video cameras for roughly seven minutes.
That, investigators suggest, may have been when he pinned the head of his boss to the wire fence alongside flags bearing references to the Muslim profession of faith.
Cameras once again briefly picked up the van around 9.36 am as it accelerated in the direction of a warehouse within the premises containing gas canisters. A loud explosion was heard.
When emergency services arrived a few minutes later, they found the headless body of the victim by the van, a knife nearby and a fake pistol. They overpowered the suspect as he was opening bottles of acetone, a flammable liquid chemical.
French anti-terrorist laws give authorities 96 hours to hold a suspect before deciding whether to press charges. Salhi is currently detained in Lyon but could be transferred to a facility just outside Paris as early as Sunday.
"He has started to speak about what happened, to explain the circumstances," said one source. While his wife and sister remain under detention, a fourth person has been released.
For now, investigators insist it is too early to speculate on the significance of the "selfie" message to a Canadian mobile number, dismissing media speculation the recipient is in Syria.
Likewise, Salhi's contacts in 2003 and 2004 with a known Islamic radical when he was living in eastern France are being handled cautiously. The radical in question has since left for Indonesia but is not suspected of any crime.
For French authorities, the case shows yet again that there are no easy answers against a threat on its soil that is ever- present but largely hidden under the surface.
Prime Minister Manuel Valls estimated on Sunday there were between 10,000-15,000 followers in France of hard-line Salafism, a radical brand of Islam often associated with support for offensive jihad against those defined as its enemies. He said it was a possible "antechamber of terrorism".
But it emerged after the January killings that a proper surveillance operation on just one suspect could involve up to 30 operatives, making it largely impossible to keep tabs on everyone considered a potential risk.
"We live in a world where this threat will be non-stop," Valls noted. "There is no zero risk."
(Additional reporting by Laurence Frost; Writing by Mark; Editing by Raissa Kasolowsky)
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
