<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="thestar">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Brazil&amp;#39;s Rousseff tells paper she is uncowed by opposition calls to quit</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/07/Brazils-Rousseff-tells-paper-she-is-uncowed-by-opposition-calls-to-quit</Link>
        <Description>SAO PAULO (Reuters) - Brazilian President Dilma Rousseff told newspaper Folha de S. Paulo in an interview published Tuesday that she plans to finish her term and continue with efforts to narrow the budget deficit in spite of growing calls among opponents for her resignation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 9:20:10 PM
Updated:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 9:20:14 PM
Brazil's Rousseff tells paper she is uncowed by opposition calls to quit
to win cash or gadget!
SAO PAULO (Reuters) - Brazilian President Dilma Rousseff told newspaper Folha de S. Paulo in an interview published Tuesday that she plans to finish her term and continue with efforts to narrow the budget deficit in spite of growing calls among opponents for her resignation.
When asked repeatedly by Folha reporters about heightening pressure for her to step down amid revelations that members of her ruling coalition received bribes from state contractors in recent years, Rousseff said she would not back down and was uncowed by calls for her resignation.
"I am not going to fall. I won't, I won't. That's too wimpy, this is a political fight," she told Folha. "There's no basis for me to fall."
"Try me, try me," she added.
In the interview, Rousseff said part of the opposition are trying to instigate an impeachment process.
"To oust a president you have to explain why. They are mixing their wishes with reality. Is there any real basis to do that? I don't believe there is any at all," she added.
According to Folha, she lauded efforts by the PMDB party, the largest in her coalition after her Workers' Party, to support her programme. She also refrained from criticizing her predecessor and political mentor, Luiz Incio Lula da Silva, who in recent weeks said she was "running on fumes."
Rousseff, who began her second, four-year term in January, said the government is working on new measures to adjust public finances, although declined to specify any of them, according to the newspaper. She also reaffirmed her commitment to narrowing the country's budget deficit in the Folha interview.
The government "is preparing structural measures that can contribute to the adjustment in the mid-and-long terms," she told the newspaper.
Efforts by the central bank to meet the 4.5 percent inflation target next year will help consumer price inflation in Brazil converge to international standards, Rousseff said, although she urged the bank to remain attentive to any potential deflation signals. Rousseff said that the intensity of Brazil's downturn caught her by surprise and that she would do "whatever it takes" to attenuate it.
A spokeswoman for the presidential palace confirmed the accuracy of the content of Folha's interview.
(Reporting by Alexandre Caverni and Guillermo Parra-Bernal; Additional reporting by Asher Levine in So Paulo Editing by W Simon)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Turkish army says detains almost 800 trying to cross illegally from Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/07/Turkish-army-says-detains-almost-800-trying-to-cross-illegally-from-Syria</Link>
        <Description>ISTANBUL (Reuters) - Turkey&amp;#39;s army said on Tuesday it had detained almost 800 people trying to cross illegally from Syria, including three suspected Islamic State militants, after bolstering security in border areas near where the radical Islamists hold ground.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 9:20:08 PM
Updated:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 9:20:08 PM
Turkish army says detains almost 800 trying to cross illegally from Syria
to win cash or gadget!
ISTANBUL (Reuters) - Turkey's army said on Tuesday it had detained almost 800 people trying to cross illegally from Syria, including three suspected Islamic State militants, after bolstering security in border areas near where the radical Islamists hold ground.
The military said 768 people had been detained on Monday alone while trying to cross the border. The three suspected Islamic State members were sent to jail in the southern city of Sanliurfa after being detained separately on July 2, it said.
Wary of advances by both Syrian Kurdish forces and Islamic State in northern Syria, Turkey has sent extra troops and equipment to strengthen parts of its 900 km (560-mile) border as the risk of spillover rises.
Turkey has maintained an open border policy throughout Syria's conflict, absorbing close to two million refugees, but requires legitimate refugees to pass through checkpoints and be documented. The military did not say why the 768 people had been detained.
Turkey has faced criticism from some Western nations for failing to do more to stop foreign fighters crossing and joining Islamic State. It argues that domestic intelligence agencies in the West need to stop their nationals being radicalised and travelling to Turkey in the first place.
Ankara has mooted the creation of a 'secure zone' on Syrian soil to prevent a new wave of refugees crossing the border, a strategy which would be likely to require a military incursion, but has made clear it will not act alone and has been lobbying for support from the U.S.-led coalition against Islamic State.
Retired General John Allen, appointed by U.S. President Barack Obama to build that coalition, held talks on Tuesday in Ankara with Turkish officials.
While concerned about the threat from Islamic State, Turkey also fears the creation of an autonomous Kurdish region in Syria which could further embolden its own 14 million ethnic Kurds.
Prime Minister Ahmet Davutoglu said on Friday there were no immediate plans for any incursion into Syria, but said Turkey would respond if its security were threatened.
(Reporting by Humeyra Pamuk, and Gulsen Solaker in Ankara; Editing by Nick Tattersall and Gareth Jones)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Iran says issues remain in nuclear talks as deadline passes - ISNA</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/07/Iran-says-issues-remain-in-nuclear-talks-as-deadline-passes--ISNA</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - An Iranian diplomat said that there were still differences to overcome in nuclear talks with six world powers as the deadline passed on reaching an agreement on Iran&amp;#39;s nuclear work, the Students News Agency ISNA reported on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>to win cash or gadget!
VIENNA (Reuters) - An Iranian diplomat said that there were still differences to overcome in nuclear talks with six world powers as the deadline passed on reaching an agreement on Iran's nuclear work, the Students News Agency ISNA reported on Tuesday.
"Still there are three issues to be resolved, which are sanctions, U.N. resolutions and nuclear work," the unnamed diplomat told ISNA.
(Writing by Parisa Hafezi; Editing by Louise Ireland)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Six powers and Iran to continue nuclear talks past deadline - EU</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/07/Six-powers-Iran-to-continue-nuclear-talks-past-deadline--EU</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - Iran and six major powers will keep negotiating past Tuesday&amp;#39;s deadline for a long-term nuclear agreement as they tackle the most contentious issues, including the continuation of a U.N. arms embargo on Iran, the big powers said.</Description>
        <MainBody>to win cash or gadget!
VIENNA (Reuters) - Iran and six major powers will keep negotiating past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term nuclear agreement as they tackle the most contentious issues, including the continuation of a U.N. arms embargo on Iran, the big powers said.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days. This does not mean we are extending our deadline," EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said outside the hotel where the talks between Iran, Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States are taking place.
The spokeswoman for the U.S. delegation, Marie Harf, said the terms of an interim deal between Iran and the six would be extended through Friday to give negotiators a few more days to finish their work.
"We're frankly more concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock, though we also know that difficult decisions won't get any easier with time," Harf said. "That is why we are continuing to negotiate."
Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said there was "every reason" to believe a deal would be done within "a few days", and that there was an "understanding" that most of the current sanctions against Iran would be lifted.
"There is only one big problem in terms of sanctions - it is the problem of a weapons embargo," he told journalists, according to the news agency Interfax.
He said it was important to reach agreement on this as soon as possible, telling journalists that "ending the bans on supplies to Iran of the weapons required to fight terrorism is a very, very relevant objective".
It is the fourth time the parties have extended the terms of the interim deal, which was struck in November 2013 and provided Iran with limited sanctions relief in exchange for a halt to the production of uranium enriched to a purity level of 20 percent.
EXTENSION EXTENDED
The comprehensive deal under discussion is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from economic sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy.
The negotiators missed a June 30 deadline for a final agreement and then gave themselves until Tuesday.
"We are interpreting in a flexible way our deadline, which means that we are taking the time, the days we still need, to finalise the agreement," Mogherini said, adding that there remained several difficult issues to resolve.
Among these, officials said, are Iranian demands for a U.N. arms embargo and ballistic missiles sanctions to be lifted, the timing of U.S. and EU sanctions relief, and disagreements over future Iranian nuclear research and development.
"We have entered the most difficult, but also the most real, part of the negotiations," Mogherini added.
"We knew it would be difficult, challenging and sometimes hard and some things get tense and others we make progress."
She said foreign ministers now in Vienna might come and go.
"Dont get too excited if you see ministers leaving. They might come back. They will come back. And it doesnt mean that we are stopping the work we are doing inside. On the contrary, on the contrary."
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius confirmed that he would leave, and return to Vienna on Wednesday night.
The United States and its allies fear Iran is using its civilian nuclear programme as a cover to develop a nuclear weapons capability. Iran says its programme is peaceful.
An agreement would be the most important milestone in decades towards easing hostility between the United States and Iran, enemies since Iranian revolutionaries captured 52 hostages in the U.S. embassy in Tehran in 1979.
A deal would also reduce the chances of a U.S. military strike against Iran's nuclear facilities, something Washington refuses to rule out, and of a wider regional war.
(Reporting by John Irish, Louis Charbonneau, Arshad Mohammed and Parisa Hafezi; Writing by Arshad Mohammed)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>EU&amp;#39;s Tusk spoke with Greece&amp;#39;s Tsipras to prepare for euro zone summit</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/07/EUs-Tusk-spoke-with-Greeces-Tsipras-to-prepare-for-euro-zone-summit</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS (Reuters) - European Council President Donald Tusk spoke with Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras on Tuesday to prepare for an emergency euro zone summit later in the day.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 9:20:02 PM
Updated:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 9:20:03 PM
EU's Tusk spoke with Greece's Tsipras to prepare for euro zone summit
to win cash or gadget!
BRUSSELS (Reuters) - European Council President Donald Tusk spoke with Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras on Tuesday to prepare for an emergency euro zone summit later in the day.
"Earlier today I was in touch with Greek PM Tsipras to prepare tonight's EuroSummit on Greece," Tusk said on Twitter.
(Reporting by Julia Fioretti; editing by Robert-Jan Bartunek)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>New Chinese security law opens door to tighter restrictions - U.N.</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/07/New-Chinese-security-law-opens-door-to-tighter-restrictions--UN</Link>
        <Description>GENEVA (Reuters) - China&amp;#39;s new national security law is too vague and could lead to tighter restrictions on civil liberties, U.N. High Commissioner for Human Rights Zeid Ra&amp;#39;ad al Hussein said in a statement on Tuesday. </Description>
        <MainBody>to win cash or gadget!
GENEVA (Reuters) - China's new national security law is too vague and could lead to tighter restrictions on civil liberties, U.N. High Commissioner for Human Rights Zeid Ra'ad al Hussein said in a statement on Tuesday.
This law raises many concerns due to its extraordinarily broad scope coupled with the vagueness of its terminology and definitions, Zeid said.
As a result, it leaves the door wide open to further restrictions of the rights and freedoms of Chinese citizens, and to even tighter control of civil society by the Chinese authorities than there is already.
(Reporting by Tom Miles; Editing by Andrew Heavens)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Srebrenica resolution would widen divisions in Bosnia, Serbs tell U.N.</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/07/Srebrenica-resolution-would-widen-divisions-in-Bosnia-Serbs-tell-UN</Link>
        <Description>BELGRADE/SARAJEVO (Reuters) - Serbia warned that a resolution commemorating the 1995 Srebrenica massacre, which the United Nations Security Council is due to discuss on Tuesday, would only widen ethnic divides in neighbouring Bosnia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 8:45:04 PM
Updated:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 8:45:05 PM
Srebrenica resolution would widen divisions in Bosnia, Serbs tell U.N.
to win cash or gadget!
BELGRADE/SARAJEVO (Reuters) - Serbia warned that a resolution commemorating the 1995 Srebrenica massacre, which the United Nations Security Council is due to discuss on Tuesday, would only widen ethnic divides in neighbouring Bosnia.
The British-drafted resolution condemns what it describes as the genocide at Srebrenica and any denial of the genocide. That has angered Serbia and Bosnian Serbs, who have branded it as "anti-Serb" and sent a letter of protest to the United Nations.
On July 11, 1995, towards the end of Bosnia's 1992-95 war, Bosnian Serb forces overran the eastern enclave of Srebrenica, a U.N.-designated "safe area". Some 8,000 Muslim men and boys were killed in the days that followed. The U.N. war crimes tribunal in The Hague has called the killings genocide.
The Serbs acknowledge that a "grave crime" took place at Srebrenica but reject the genocide label.
The row over the resolution has created an atmosphere of distrust in Bosnia and overshadowed the Srebrenica commemoration scheduled for Saturday, when 136 newly identified victims will be laid to rest next to the 6,241 already buried at a joint cemetery.
Twenty years after a U.S.-brokered 'Dayton peace accord' ended the war, Bosnia remains fragile, with a weak economy, an unwieldy power-sharing system and tensions between its two regions, the Bosniak-Croat Federation and the Serb Republic.
The president of the Bosnian Serb Republic, Milorad Dodik,  who has long called for its secession from Bosnia, has warned that the adoption of the resolution would mean a "disintegration of Bosnia".
Britain says the resolution should encourage reconciliation among Bosnia's Serbs, Croats and Muslim Bosniaks. It has changed the draft several times after Russia, historically an ally of Serbia, submitted its own text it considered more balanced.
But Serbian and Bosnian Serb officials still consider the resolution unacceptable and have urged the Security Council members to abandon it.
Serbian President Tomislav Nikolic has also sent a letter to Britain's Queen Elizabeth, asking her to persuade the British government to drop its initiative.
His Foreign Minister, Ivica Dacic, added:
"I expect the countries who took part in making the Dayton  agreement ... to take no decisions that could destabilise the situation (in Bosnia)," he told regional N1 TV on Tuesday.
Serbian Prime Minister Aleksandar Vucic has said earlier he is willing to visit Srebrenica and "pay respects to the Muslim and Bosniak victims", but later said this would depend on whether the resolution is adopted.
(Editing by Zoran Radosavljevic and Larry King)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Interim Iran nuclear deal extended to Friday to allow more talks - U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/07/Interim-Iran-nuclear-deal-extended-to-Friday-to-allow-more-talks--US</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - An interim nuclear agreement between Iran and six major powers will be extended through Friday to provide more time for talks on a final agreement, the United States said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>to win cash or gadget!
VIENNA (Reuters) - An interim nuclear agreement between Iran and six major powers will be extended through Friday to provide more time for talks on a final agreement, the United States said on Tuesday.
"We've made substantial progress in every area, but this work is highly technical and high stakes for all of the countries involved," Marie Harf, the spokeswoman for the U.S. delegation, said in a statement.
"We're frankly more concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock, though we also know that difficult decisions won't get any easier with time - that is why we are continuing to negotiate," she added.
(Reporting By Arshad Mohammed)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Turkish opposition accuses Erdogan of stalling on government mandate</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/07/Turkish-opposition-accuses-Erdogan-of-stalling-on-government-mandate</Link>
        <Description>ANKARA (Reuters) - Turkish opposition MPs accused President Tayyip Erdogan on Tuesday of stalling efforts to form a coalition government as he seeks to maintain his grip on power, a month after the AK Party he founded lost its parliamentary majority.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 8:25:12 PM
Updated:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 8:25:12 PM
Turkish opposition accuses Erdogan of stalling on government mandate
to win cash or gadget!
ANKARA (Reuters) - Turkish opposition MPs accused President Tayyip Erdogan on Tuesday of stalling efforts to form a coalition government as he seeks to maintain his grip on power, a month after the AK Party he founded lost its parliamentary majority.
The June 7 vote left the AKP unable to rule alone for the first time in over a decade, plunging Turkey into political uncertainty not seen since the 1990s and thwarting for now Erdogan's ambition to amass greater power.
Formal coalition talks cannot begin until Erdogan gives Prime Minister Ahmet Davutoglu the mandate to form a new government, at which point he has 45 days to do so or face the prospect of another election.
Some opposition MPs have suggested Erdogan is stalling to sow opposition disarray and to ensure the AKP is still firmly in power for a High Military Council (YAS) meeting in August, where key army commanders are appointed.
"He wants the changes to be made at the YAS to be done by him alone without debate, with the old cabinet and the old political climate," Ozgur Ozel, an MP with the main opposition Republican People's Party (CHP), told Reuters.
"He thinks the slow process will trigger disputes in the opposition, rather than in his own party," he said, adding the aim was to boost AKP support in case of another election.
Reining in a military which forced four governments from power in the second half of the 20th Century was one of Erdogan's priorities during his 12 years as prime minister.
YAS meetings - at which retirements, transfers and disciplinary actions are decided - were a key element of that process. The current head of the armed forces, General Necdet Ozel, is set to retire at the August meeting.
Deputy Prime Minister Numan Kurtulmus poured cold water on claims of a deliberate delay, telling broadcaster Haberturk on Tuesday that Erdogan would "most probably" give the mandate to Davutoglu this week.
Davutoglu meanwhile last week rejected suggestions that the AKP would wait until after the YAS to form a new government, while Erdogan himself has said he will only give the mandate once parliament's new administration is in place.
A speaker was elected last week but an administrative board is yet to be agreed.
As president, Erdogan is constitutionally bound to remain above party politics but effectively turned the June election into a referendum on his ambitions for an executive presidency, campaigning around the country.
He chaired a cabinet meeting in his controversial new palace on Monday, something which opposition parties have said must end if they are to enter any coalition.
"The president has given the message since the beginning that 'this process will advance under my control'," Meral Danis Bestas, deputy chairwoman of the pro-Kurdish Peoples' Democratic Party (HDP), told Reuters.
(Writing by Daren Butler; Editing by Nick Tattersall and Clelia Oziel)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Judge quits Cambodia&amp;#39;s troubled Khmer Rouge trials</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/07/07/Judge-quits-Cambodias-troubled-Khmer-Rouge-trials</Link>
        <Description>PHNOM PENH (Reuters) - An international judge announced his resignation from the U.N.-backed war crimes trials in Cambodia on Tuesday, the fourth to quit so far and another blow for the troubled tribunal probing the atrocities of the 1970s Khmer Rouge regime. </Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 8:25:10 PM
Updated:                 Tuesday July 7, 2015 MYT 8:25:11 PM
Judge quits Cambodia's troubled Khmer Rouge trials
to win cash or gadget!
PHNOM PENH (Reuters) - An international judge announced his resignation from the U.N.-backed war crimes trials in Cambodia on Tuesday, the fourth to quit so far and another blow for the troubled tribunal probing the atrocities of the 1970s Khmer Rouge regime.
Mark Harmon, from the United States, said in a statement his reasons for stepping down after three years in Phnom Penh were "strictly personal" and "with considerable regret". He did not elaborate.
Several of Harmon's predecessors at the hybrid United Nations-Cambodian court have alleged political interference and a lack of cooperation by Cambodia's government, which contains remnants of the Khmer Rouge regime.
Prime Minister Hun Sen, a former Khmer Rouge soldier, has warned more trials could cause anarchy and a return to civil war. He has promised to thwart new indictments and once said he would be happy if the U.N. packed up and left.
The decade-old tribunal has so far delivered verdicts involving three high-profile leaders from the 1975-1979 "killing fields" era. Attempts to pursue more cases have been met by strong government resistance.
Cambodian police have refused to act on an arrest warrant Harmon has issued for Meas Muth, a former navy chief alleged to have sent detainees to a torture centre where some 14,000 people died.
Court spokesman Lars Olsen said Harmon's resignation was unrelated to any development in cases he was working on. Harmon would continue his role until his replacement was sworn in.
(Reporting by Prak Chan Thul; Editing by Martin Petty)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
