<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="thestar">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>U.S. defence aid to Israel to rise over Iran deal fears - sources</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/US-defence-aid-to-Israel-to-rise-over-Iran-deal-fears--sources</Link>
        <Description>TEL AVIV (Reuters) - U.S. defence aid to Israel is likely to increase after 2017, sources on both sides said on Thursday, seeing a possible link to Washington&amp;#39;s efforts to assuage its ally&amp;#39;s fears over nuclear diplomacy with Iran.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 9:20:02 AM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 9:20:03 AM
U.S. defence aid to Israel to rise over Iran deal fears - sources
by dan williams
TEL AVIV (Reuters) - U.S. defence aid to Israel is likely to increase after 2017, sources on both sides said on Thursday, seeing a possible link to Washington's efforts to assuage its ally's fears over nuclear diplomacy with Iran.
A current package worth $3 billion (1.9 billion) a year expires in 2017. A U.S. official, speaking to Reuters on condition of anonymity, said negotiators were close to a new deal that would bring annual payouts to $3.6 billion to $3.7 billion on average.
An Israeli official, who also declined to be named, put the expected aid at between $3.5 billion and $4 billion.
"They (the United States) are trying to douse the fires after our flare-up about the Iran deal," the official added, referring to curbs being negotiated on Tehran's disputed nuclear programme, which Israel has condemned as insufficient.
Responding to the Reuters report that an increased defence aid package was in the works, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu confirmed there were such discussions with the Americans but said he would keep campaigning against Iran.
"There is no trade-off requiring I agree to this (nuclear) deal with Iran. The deal is bad and we will continue to oppose it," Netanyahu said in remarks quoted by Israeli broadcasters.
In Washington, White House National Security Council spokesman Alistair Baskey said: "These reports are wholly inaccurate."
"While we anticipate discussions in the coming period between the U.S. and Israeli governments about how long-term security cooperation between the two countries can be further strengthened, no such detailed discussions at a senior level have occurred recently," Baskey said in a statement.
The Pentagon had no immediate comment.
The previous U.S. administration signed a 10-year deal with Israel in 2007 giving it $30 billion, most of which must be spent on American military products. Washington has earmarked hundreds of millions more dollars for Israeli missile defences.
A year ago, with talks about the new aid package under way, a U.S. official said Israel was seeking a significant increase but that the Obama administration, beset by domestic cost-cutting, was unlikely to agree beyond adjusting for inflation.
Since then, the United States and five other world powers have pressed ahead with the Iran negotiations, setting a June 30 deadline for a final accord.
Tehran denies seeking nuclear weapons. The talks have been dogged by disputes about the degree to which projects with bomb-making potential should be capped.
Israel's worries about the diplomacy have been echoed by Gulf Arab leaders, whom U.S. President Barack Obama hosted on May 14 and sought to reassure with offers of boosted defence.
Such aid to Gulf Arabs has often ushered in increases in aid to Israel, whose military "qualitative edge" in the region successive U.S. administrations have pledged to preserve.
Asked if the expected hike in defence grants to Israel was linked to Washington's recent dealings with Iran and the Gulf Arab states, the U.S. official said: "Could be."
(Additional reporting by Matt Spetalnick in Washington, Editing by Jeffrey Heller, Andrew Roche and Ken Wills)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Libya&amp;#39;s rival government conducts air strikes on Islamic State in Sirte - official</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Libyas-rival-government-conducts-air-strikes-on-Islamic-State-in-Sirte--official</Link>
        <Description>TRIPOLI (Reuters) - Military aircraft belonging to a rival Libyan government on Thursday attacked Islamic State positions in and around the central city of Sirte, where the radical group claimed to have seized an air base, a government official said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:26 AM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:27 AM
Libya's rival government conducts air strikes on Islamic State in Sirte - official
TRIPOLI (Reuters) - Military aircraft belonging to a rival Libyan government on Thursday attacked Islamic State positions in and around the central city of Sirte, where the radical group claimed to have seized an air base, a government official said.
Islamic State has exploited the general turmoil and security vacuum in Libya to build up a presence in several cities, where two governments are vying for power four years after the ousting of Muammar Gaddafi.
The militants earlier this year seized Gaddafi's home town of Sirte, pushing to its suburbs a force loyal to a rival government in Tripoli which had expelled the official Premier Abdullah al-Thinni to the east in August.
War planes attacked Islamic State positions in Sirte, a government spokesman in Tripoli said, adding he was not aware of reports that the militants had seized the al-Qardhabia air base, located near Sirte's civilian airport, south of the city.
Islamic State militants said in a statement on Twitter that they were in control of the base, adding that both sides were clashing at key points in Sirte.
A nearby resident said the base appeared to be under control of Islamic State, but Reuters was unable to confirm this independently.
Militant fighters in Libya loyal to Islamic State have claimed since the start of the year the killing of dozens of Egyptian and Ethiopian Christians as well attacks on Tripoli's luxury Corinthia hotel, embassies and oilfields.
Libya's internationally recognised government has been working out of the east of the country since losing control of Tripoli and western Libya in August.
(Reporting by Ahmed Elumami and Ahmed Tolba, writing by Ulf Laessing, Tripoli newsrooom; editing by G Crosse)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>U.N. council has first-ever briefing on rights in Myanmar</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/UN-council-has-firstever-briefing-on-rights-in-Myanmar</Link>
        <Description>UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - The United Nations Security Council on Thursday held its first closed-door briefing on the human rights situation in Myanmar, focussing on the dire situation of the country&amp;#39;s Rohingya Muslim minority, the United States and council diplomats said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:25 AM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:25 AM
U.N. council has first-ever briefing on rights in Myanmar
by louis charbonneau
UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - The United Nations Security Council on Thursday held its first closed-door briefing on the human rights situation in Myanmar, focussing on the dire situation of the country's Rohingya Muslim minority, the United States and council diplomats said.
U.N. human rights chief Zeid Ra'ad Al Hussein briefed the council via video link in a meeting that U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Samantha Power welcomed on her Twitter feed as a "historic first" for the 15-nation body, in which Zeid painted a "grim picture of discrimination against Rohingya."
"Zeid gave a powerful briefing on the dire situation and 'institutional discrimination' faced by the Rohingya in Myanmar," a council diplomat present at the meeting told Reuters on condition of anonymity.
"They are often violently abused by smugglers, hundreds recently dying at sea," the diplomat said, summarizing Zeid's remarks about the country formerly called Burma. "This demands a comprehensive response. Must look at root causes."
Power described the conditions for Rohingyas as "troubling and inhumane."
During the meeting Power "underscored that while much progress has been made in Myanmar, some are using newfound freedoms to organise hatred, foment violence, and facilitate the persecution of vulnerable Rohingya," another diplomat said.
She also called for the "immediate lifting of restrictions on the freedom of movement of the more than 140,000 Rohingya trapped in IDP (internally displaced persons) camps, with little access to humanitarian support," the second diplomat added.
Council members welcomed a crisis meeting in Bangkok aimed at addressing Southeast Asia's migrant crisis.
A delegate from Russia complained that the Security Council was not the appropriate forum for human rights, a diplomat said.
China, Myanmar's traditional ally, said it was an internal matter for the country's authorities but expressed concern about the situation.
More than 3,000 migrants from Myanmar and Bangladesh have landed in Indonesia and Malaysia in recent weeks since Thailand launched a crackdown on human trafficking gangs earlier this month. About 2,600 are believed to be still adrift on abandoned boats, relief agencies have said.
Many of those who have landed ashore belong to Myanmar's 1.1 million-member Rohingya Muslim minority who live in apartheid-like conditions in Rakhine state.
Recently Zeid said the Rohingyas' situation was "one of the principal motivators of these desperate maritime movements."
The Myanmar government regards most Rohingyas as illegal immigrants from Bangladesh. They enjoy few rights and have suffered violence from members of the Buddhist majority over the past few years.
(Reporting by Louis Charbonneau; Editing by Jonathan Oatis and Richard Chang)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>U.N. eyes keeping Israel off armed violations list - sources</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/UN-eyes-keeping-Israel-off-armed-violations-list--sources</Link>
        <Description>UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-Moon is leaning toward not including Israel on an annual list of states responsible for violating children&amp;#39;s rights in armed conflicts, despite proposals to include it, U.N. diplomatic sources said. </Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:19 AM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:24 AM
U.N. eyes keeping Israel off armed violations list - sources
by louis charbonneau
UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-Moon is leaning toward not including Israel on an annual list of states responsible for violating children's rights in armed conflicts, despite proposals to include it, U.N. diplomatic sources said.
Israel's foreign ministry has denied pressuring Ban, but several diplomatic sources familiar with the matter said on condition of anonymity that the Israelis were lobbying his office hard to ensure they were not on the list.
U.N. spokesman Stephane Dujarric said Ban had not made a decision on whether to include Israel in the United Nations report, which is due in the coming weeks. The report lists countries where serious violations against children's rights have occurred.
A draft of the report by Ban's special envoy for children and armed conflict, Leila Zerrougui of Algeria, included the Israel Defense Forces (IDF) for incidents including attacks on schools and hospitals in the Gaza Strip war last year. It also cited reports of violations by the Palestinian group Hamas during the conflict.
A U.N. inquiry published in April said Israeli soldiers had  fired on seven U.N. schools during the Gaza war, killing 44 Palestinians who were sheltered at some of the sites, while Palestinian fighters hid weapons and launched attacks from several empty U.N. schools.
More than 2,100 Palestinians, mostly civilians, were killed in the conflict, while 67 Israeli soldiers and six civilians in Israel were killed.
The question of Israeli pressure over the list was first raised in a March 17 article in The Guardian newspaper. After that, the United Nations was leaning toward including Israel but recently reversed course, the diplomatic sources said.
Israel's Foreign Ministry spokesman Emmanuel Nahshon said,  "There is absolutely no Israeli pressure on the U.N. secretary-general. The pressure comes from those countries who want to include Israel in the worst possible list."
"Those countries are motivated by hatred and totally blind to their own failings," he said. "This is a heinous and hypocritical attempt to besmirch the image of Israel and it is doomed to fail."
Human rights organizations have given the United Nations arguments for listing the IDF and Palestinian groups like Hamas.
Some sources said U.N. officials had indicated to rights groups that the IDF and Hamas would most likely be on the list.
"Now, under pressure from Israel, the SG (secretary-general) is leaning towards not heeding the recommendation of Ms. Zerrougui and probably won't include Israel," one source said.
Other U.N. diplomatic sources echoed this and spoke of heated discussions among senior U.N. officials, with one  argument being the IDF should not be categorized with groups like the Taliban in Afghanistan.
On April 27, following release of the U.N. inquiry, Human Rights Watch recommended to Ban that Israel and Hamas be listed. The group's Philippe Bolopion wrote that in their case the U.N.'s "standard of a pattern of violations involving a multiple commission of acts has been met." He said countries had been listed for less serious violations.
Amnesty International said in a report this week that Hamas had committed war crimes against Palestinian civilians in the Gaza Strip during last year's war with Israel. In a March report, the organization criticized Israel and accused it of war crimes during the conflict.
(Reporting by Louis Charbonneau; Additional reporting by Luke Baker and Allyn Fisher-Ilan; Editing by David Storey, Toni Reinhold)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>Lithuania minister urges pressure on Russia to stop arms at Ukraine border</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Lithuania-minister-urges-pressure-on-Russia-to-stop-arms-at-Ukraine-border</Link>
        <Description>UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - Lithuania&amp;#39;s foreign minister confirmed on Thursday reports that Russia has been massing troops and weaponry near the border of Ukraine and urged pressure on Moscow until it stops supporting Ukrainian rebels. </Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:12 AM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:17 AM
Lithuania minister urges pressure on Russia to stop arms at Ukraine border
by louis charbonneau
UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - Lithuania's foreign minister confirmed on Thursday reports that Russia has been massing troops and weaponry near the border of Ukraine and urged pressure on Moscow until it stops supporting Ukrainian rebels.
Reuters reported this week that Russia's army was massing troops and hundreds of pieces of weaponry including mobile rocket launchers, tanks and artillery at a makeshift base near the border with Ukraine.
Asked about that report, Lithuanian Foreign Minister Linas Linkevicius said it was true that Moscow was moving troops and hardware in the vicinity of Donetsk, Mariupol and elsewhere.
"We are concerned about these concentrations of troops, and these are big numbers," he said in an interview. "These groups, the separatists, are equipped better than some European armies."
Lithuania, a former Soviet republic, is a member of NATO and the European Union. It is on the United Nations Security Council through the end of this year.
Earlier in May, NATO military commander General Philip Breedlove said he believed the separatists were taking advantage of a ceasefire that went into effect in February to re-arm and prepare for a new offensive, but he gave no details.
Linkevicius echoed Breedlove's remarks and said the Russian-backed separatists in Ukraine had used the lull in fighting to regroup and reposition, not for de-escalation.
Russia has denied that its military is involved in the conflict in Ukraine's east, where separatists have been fighting forces loyal to the pro-Western government in Kiev.
Russia's defence ministry said it had no immediate comment when asked about the build-up of troops and weapons.
Linkevicius said it was vital to keep pressure on Russia in the form of sanctions and diplomatic isolation.
"If we will not continue our pressure ... that would be a signal (for Russia) to act," he said. "If they will not stop supporting, stop delivering weapons, including heavy weapons, tanks ... we cannot talk about any progress, any change in policy."
(Reporting by Louis Charbonneau; Editing by Toni Reinhold)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Bombs outside two five-star Baghdad hotels kill at least 10</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Bombs-at-two-Baghdad-hotels-kill-at-least-10--police-medical-sources</Link>
        <Description>BAGHDAD (Reuters) - Car bombs exploded in the parking lots of two heavily fortified five-star hotels in central Baghdad late on Thursday, killing at least 10 people, police and medical sources said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:11 AM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:11 AM
Bombs outside two five-star Baghdad hotels kill at least 10
BAGHDAD (Reuters) - Car bombs exploded in the parking lots of two heavily fortified five-star hotels in central Baghdad late on Thursday, killing at least 10 people, police and medical sources said.
A further 30 people were wounded in the blasts, which were around seven minutes apart.
The first bomb targeted the Babylon hotel, where government officials often hold meetings and news conferences, and the second hit the Meridian.
Iraqi authorities lifted a decade-old night-time curfew on Baghdad early this year, seeking to restore a sense of normality to the capital as security forces battle Islamic State militants who have overrun large parts of the country.
But the rate of bombings in Baghdad has increased since then.
Insurgents seized the city of Ramadi, west of Baghdad, on May 17 in the most significant military setback to the government since a U.S.-led coalition launched a campaign of airstrikes against Islamic State last August.
(Reporting by Baghdad Bureau; Writing by Isabel Coles; Editing by Chris Reese)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Rebels capture last Syrian town in Idlib province</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Insurgents-claim-capture-of-last-Syrian-town-in-Idlib-province</Link>
        <Description>AMMAN (Reuters) - The Syrian army has pulled back from the northwestern city of Ariha after a coalition of insurgent groups seized the last city in Idlib province in northwestern Syria near the Turkish border that was still held by the government.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:06 AM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 8:30:06 AM
Rebels capture last Syrian town in Idlib province
by suleiman al-khalidi
AMMAN (Reuters) - The Syrian army has pulled back from the northwestern city of Ariha after a coalition of insurgent groups seized the last city in Idlib province in northwestern Syria near the Turkish border that was still held by the government.
A coalition of rebel groups called Jaish al Fateh, or Conquest Army, said it had taken over the city. Syria's al Qaeda offshoot Nusra Front is a major part of the coalition.
The coalition said it had overrun several checkpoints that defended the city. The Syrian army said intense fighting was going on with Nusra forces that had infiltrated Ariha.
"There are heavy clashes between the army and the terrorists of Jabahat al Nusra who infiltrated inside the city," said an army statement released on state television.
Later the army admitted its forces had pulled back from the city, the latest string of defeats by the Syrian army and a big blow to the morale of President Assad's government forces who have vowed to defeat Sunni militants financed by Saudi Arabia, Qatar and Turkey who seek to overthrow his rule.
"Units of our armed forces evacuated their positions in Ariha and withdrew to defensive positions in the vicinity of the city after battles it fought facing large number of Nusra terrorists," the army source was quoted as saying.
A rebel source from Ahrar al Sham confirmed that street fighting was going on inside the city between army fighters and the insurgents. "There are many bodies that litter the streets," he said, adding that the rebels were searching for Assad's government forces inside the city.
Many civilians have hidden inside shelters.
Syria accuses Turkey of financing and aiding rebels seeking to topple the government. Damascus says foreign jihadi fighters  allowed into Syrian territory by Turkey have played a pivotal role in recent rebel gains.
Rebel sources say they have secured more U.S.-made TOW missiles in recent months that have helped them to gain a military edge over the Syrian army.
The Nusra Front has made gains in northwestern Syria alongside other insurgent groups in recent weeks, seizing the city of Idlib, the town of Jisr al-Shughour and bringing them closer to government-held coastal areas north of the capital.
The loss of Ariha would leave the insurgents in control of  most of Idlib a region that borders Turkey and neighbours President Assad's heartland in Latakia province on the Mediterranean coast.
The city, once home to more than 80,000 people, is strategically located on the main army supply lines between Idlib and Latakia.
Rebel sources said that convoys carrying army forces had fled to Oroum al Jouz, an area west of Ariha and in areas closer to President Assad's ancestral homeland. The army did not comment.
Nusra Front is also a major force against government forces and allied militia around the northern city of Aleppo. It is fighting in southern Syria as well, and its combatants have frequently clashed with Islamic State.
Syria's four-year-old civil war has killed a quarter of a million people and driven nearly 8 million from their homes.
(Reporting by Suleiman Al-Khalidi; Editing by Larry King)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Mexican president misrepresented personal land deal, records show</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Mexican-president-misrepresented-personal-land-deal-records-show</Link>
        <Description>VALLE DE BRAVO, Mexico (Reuters) - Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto misrepresented to authorities the circumstances under which he acquired one of his properties, public documents reviewed by Reuters show, a discrepancy that could add to the controversy surrounding his personal finances.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 5:25:05 AM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 5:25:09 AM
Mexican president misrepresented personal land deal, records show
by simon gardner
VALLE DE BRAVO, Mexico (Reuters) - Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto misrepresented to authorities the circumstances under which he acquired one of his properties, public documents reviewed by Reuters show, a discrepancy that could add to the controversy surrounding his personal finances.
According to an official asset declaration first made in 2013, Pena Nieto stated that he acquired the property through a "donation" or gift from his father. Pena Nieto, who made his asset declaration public in 2013 as part of a transparency and accountability push, has since updated and ratified this declaration twice.
Under a public information request, Reuters reviewed documents showing that Pena Nieto actually purchased the property in question - a 1,000 square metre piece of land in the town of Valle de Bravo - in 1988 from a third party. He paid 11.2 million pesos, equivalent to around $5,000 (3,264) at the time, the registry shows. His wealth declaration lists the property as being valued at just 11,200 "old" pesos, the equivalent to around $5 at the time.
Reuters was unable to determine why Pena Nieto's declaration mischaracterized the purchase as a gift and understated the price. The declaration lists eight other real estate properties, five of which are also listed as donations. Reuters couldn't determine if those five properties, which include houses and land, are accurately characterized.
Mexican public officials face no requirement to explain the source of any funds that were used to obtain properties they receive as gifts, but they are required to accurately declare how they acquire their properties.
The president's office, asked to explain the discrepancies in the documents, declined repeated requests to comment.
Pena Nieto has been under pressure in recent months over aseries of conflict-of-interest scandals centred on properties he, his wife Angelica Rivera and Finance Minister Luis Videgaray acquired from government contractors.
Mexican journalist Carmen Aristegui and her colleagues reported last year that Rivera was acquiring a multi-million dollar home from a unit of a government contractor which was part of a Chinese-led consortium that had won a $3.75 billion high speed rail contract. The Wall Street Journal later reported that Pena Nieto purchased a home from a developer which, the newspaper said, went on to win millions of dollars in state public works contracts.
The president has denied any wrongdoing. But the scandals have overshadowed a major economic reform drive that Pena Nieto was hoping would boost the world's 15th biggest economy.
UPDATE COMING
Pena Nieto will publish his annual asset declaration update later this week with more details, an official at the presidential palace said. He will not reveal his wife's assets, because she is neither a public servant nor financially dependent on him, the official added.
Ten lawyers and law professors at top Mexican law firms and law schools consulted by Reuters said the incorrect asset declaration could spell legal trouble for the president. The discrepancy between the registry documents and his official declaration constitute a false statement to authorities, they said.
Several lawyers pointed to the Federal Law of Public Servants' Responsibilities. Article 80 of the law lists which officials, including "even the president of the republic," must declare their wealth to authorities under oath. "The public servant whose wealth declaration lacks truth ... will be suspended, and when its importance merits it, removed from office and disqualified for three months to three years," the law states.
Several lawyers said they thought the president's wealth declaration should be audited given the discrepancy.
"The property is declared as a donation from the father, when it is in reality the result of a purchase," said Victor Blanco, a Mexican lawyer and academic. "It is incurring falsehood."
Officials who are unable to justify the source of their wealth can face an audit for suspected illicit enrichment. If proven, that would be a crime under Article 224 of Mexico's Federal Penal Code.
One lawyer, speaking on condition of anonymity, said he believed the president could argue that the money used to buy the property was donated to him, and that the discrepancy would not be a major worry.
Lawyers added that there are few precedents for prosecuting senior officials under these laws.
Reuters was unable to check Pena Nieto's other real estate holdings because his wealth declaration doesn't list the addresses of the properties. Mexico's opaque and decentralized property registry makes it difficult to verify the ownership and purchase details of land and buildings. There are more than 220 public registry offices across the country, many of which lack searchable electronic databases. Even modernized registries can be of limited use.
At some public registry offices, members of the public can search an intranet of property records. However, to request a copy of a particular property registration, the user must know the number of the "folio," a compendium of paper records in which properties are originally listed. Searching on an individual's name sometimes turns up no information.
In the case of the president's property identified by Reuters, a computer search in the public registry in Valle de Bravo, a leafy upmarket retreat a two hour drive southwest of Mexico City, initially came up empty for Pena Nieto. A reporter then reviewed old paper files at the registry office, and found the president's name along with a folio number. That enabled the reporter to find the records for the Valle de Bravo property.
FURTHER DISCREPANCIES
There are other discrepancies in Pena Nieto's declaration of assets.
He reported the value of the Valle de Bravo property as 11,200 so-called "old pesos," when the property registry shows he originally paid 11.2 million old pesos. Mexico was gripped by a deep economic crisis in the 1980s, and in the early 1990s the peso was revalued by lopping three zeros off the hyper-inflated currency.
Pena Nieto's declaration includes two other properties registered in old pesos, which lawyers said appeared to underplay their real worth.
One of those properties is a 560 square metre piece of land containing a 492 square metre house. The president's declaration says he acquired the property in cash in 1982, when he was a 16-year-old schoolboy. The other property is a 24,000 square metre piece of farmland.
Converting the declared amounts using today's exchange rate, those two properties are valued in his declaration at a total of just $102.
Not counting these three properties, Pena Nieto declared assets totalling around $3 million in May 2014.
Pena Nieto made his first declaration of assets as president in early 2013. At that time, he listed nine properties, six of which were described as donations. He didn't report their locations or values or name any of the donors.
In May 2013, he amended his declaration to specify that the donated properties came from his mother or father, and assigned them values. Pena Nieto ratified his declaration again last year, but still withheld the location of the properties.
Shortly after filing his first asset declaration with the government, Pena Nieto followed his two immediate predecessors and made the report public. He vowed his government would be open.
"I am doing this, not just because of a legal mandate, but also as an ethical obligation ... to do with accountability," he said at the time. "Above all I reaffirm my democratic conviction to conduct myself with absolute transparency."
(Edited by Michael Williams)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Syrian army pulls out of Ariha city in north western Syria - state TV</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Syrian-army-pulls-out-of-Ariha-city-in-north-western-Syria--state-TV</Link>
        <Description>AMMAN (Reuters) - The Syrian army withdrew from the strategic city of Ariha, its last remaining stronghold in the north western province of Idlib, after heavy battles waged with al Qaeda&amp;#39;s Syrian offshoot Nusra Front, an army source said on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 5:25:02 AM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 5:25:04 AM
Syrian army pulls out of Ariha city in north western Syria - state TV
AMMAN (Reuters) - The Syrian army withdrew from the strategic city of Ariha, its last remaining stronghold in the north western province of Idlib, after heavy battles waged with al Qaeda's Syrian offshoot Nusra Front, an army source said on Thursday.
The source quoted on state television was the first admission that the city of Ariha, the last bastion of government forces in the province that borders Turkey, had fallen to insurgent groups whom it says are financed and equipped by Turkey.
(Reporting by Suleiman Al-Khalidi; Editing by Chris Reese)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>North Korean nuclear, missile experts visit Iran - dissidents</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Iran-North-Korea-forging-ballistic-nuclear-ties--dissidents</Link>
        <Description>PARIS (Reuters) - An exiled Iranian opposition group said on Thursday that a delegation of North Korean nuclear and missile experts visited a military site near Tehran in April amid talks between world powers and Iran over its nuclear programme.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 5:17:17 AM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 5:17:17 AM
North Korean nuclear, missile experts visit Iran - dissidents
by john irish
PARIS (Reuters) - An exiled Iranian opposition group said on Thursday that a delegation of North Korean nuclear and missile experts visited a military site near Tehran in April amid talks between world powers and Iran over its nuclear programme.
The dissident National Council of Resistance of Iran (NCRI) exposed Iran's uranium enrichment plant at Natanz and a heavy water facility at Arak in 2002. Analysts say it has a mixed record and a clear political agenda.
Iran says allegations that is trying to develop a nuclear weapons capability are baseless and circulated by its enemies.
Iran and six world powers are trying to meet a self-imposed June 30 deadline to reach a comprehensive deal restricting its nuclear work. Issues remaining include monitoring measures to ensure it cannot pursue a clandestine nuclear weapons programme.
Citing information from sources inside Iran, including within Iran's Revolutionary Guards Corps, the Paris-based NCRI said a seven-person North Korean Defence Ministry team was in Iran during the last week of April. This was the third time in 2015 that North Koreans had been to Iran and a nine-person delegation was due to return in June, it said.
"The delegates included nuclear experts, nuclear warhead experts and experts in various elements of ballistic missiles including guidance systems," the NCRI said.
The Iranian embassy in France dismissed the report.
"Such fabricated reports are being published as we get closer to final stages of the talks and also because there is a high chance of reaching a final deal," Iran's state website IRIB quoted an unnamed Paris-based Iranian diplomat as saying.
In Washington, the State Department said it was examining the claims but had been unable to confirm them.
"These allegations, we're taking them seriously," State  Department spokesman Jeff Rathke told reporters. "We have not been able to verify them thus far."
There have previously been unconfirmed reports of cooperation between the two countries on ballistic missiles, but nothing specific in the nuclear field.
The U.N. Panel of Experts which monitors compliance with sanctions on North Korea has reported in the past that Pyongyang and Tehran have regularly exchanged ballistic missile technology in violation of U.N. sanctions.
SECRECY
The NCRI said the North Korean delegation was taken secretly to the Imam Khomenei complex, a site east of Tehran controlled by the Defence Ministry. It gave detailed accounts of locations and who the officials met.
It said the delegation dealt with the Centre for Research and Design of New Aerospace Technology, a unit of nuclear weaponisation research, and a planning centre called the Organisation of Defensive Innovation and Research, which is under U.S. sanctions.
Reuters could not independently verify the allegations.
"Tehran has shown no interest in giving up its drive to nuclear weapons. The weaponisation programme is continuing and they have not slowed down the process," NCRI spokesman Shahin Gobadi said.
U.N. watchdog the IAEA, which for years has investigated alleged nuclear arms research by Tehran, declined to comment. North Korean officials were not available for comment.
Several Western officials said they were not aware of a North Korean delegation travelling to Iran recently.
A Western diplomat said there had been proven military cooperation between Iran and North Korea in the past.
North Korean and Iranian officials meet in the course of general diplomacy. On April 23, Kim Yong Nam, North Koreas ceremonial head of state and Iran's president held a rare  meeting on the sidelines of the Asian-African summit in Jakarta.
(Additional reporting by Louis Charbonneau at the United Nations, Parisa Hafezi in Ankara; James Pearson in Seoul and Arshad Mohammed in Washington; editing by Andrew Roche and Christian Plumb)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
