<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="thestar">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Greek debt sustainable, with new bailout - creditor analysis</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Greek-debt-sustainable-in-most-scenarios-even-worst-does-not-require-a-haircut</Link>
        <Description>BERLIN (Reuters) - Greek debt will miss debt targets set out by creditors in 2012 but an analysis prepared for euro zone finance ministers shows its debt burden is still sustainable without writing off principal -- if Greece gets another three-year bailout.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
BERLIN (Reuters) - Greek debt will miss debt targets set out by creditors in 2012 but an analysis prepared for euro zone finance ministers shows its debt burden is still sustainable without writing off principal -- if Greece gets another three-year bailout.
The analysis, commissioned by the EU creditor governments to help their financing-for-reforms negotiations with Athens, concludes that even in the worst scenario for the Greek economy, the lenders would not have to write off any loans.
Debt relief has been a repeated request from the leftist government in Athens which wants to ease back on austerity.
Under a 2012 bailout agreement, Greece was to reach a debt-to-GDP ratio of 124 percent in 2020 and in 2022 a debt-to-GDP ratio substantially lower than 110 percent, down from 175 percent now.
"It is clear that the policy slippages and uncertainties of the last months have made the achievement of the 2012 targets impossible under any scenario," the analysis, seen by Reuters, said.
"The main factors behind the deterioration of the
Debt Sustainability Analysis are the worsening of economic growth, the revised primary balance path, the lower
privatisation revenues and possible additional financial needs for the banking sector."
Under the revised forecast and the most optimistic scenario that Athens implements all reforms, Greek is debt to fall to 124 percent only in 2022 from 172.8 pct in 2015.
If it implements the reforms only partially, Greek debt will fall only to 135 percent in 2022 from 174.3 pct in 2015.
In the worst case, which the International Monetary Fund sees as its "baseline", which means most likely, Greek debt would fall only to 142.2 percent in 2022 from 176.7 percent in 2015.
"All scenarios assume a new 3-year programme with concessional financing," the analysis said.
The analysis stresses however, that focussing on the debt-to-GDP ratio does not give an accurate picture of debt sustainability and that this is better reflected by gross financing needs of a country.
Measured like this, Greece has no sustainability problem in any scenario, but would require help to improve the sustainability, via for example an extension of maturities, under the third, least favourable option.
"This gross financing need metric points to no sustainability issues under the first two scenarios," the document said.
"The gross financing needs remain well below 15 percent threshold, a threshold mentioned in IMF guidance for
this criterion. Under this scenario, significant reprofiling of the stock of debt and concessional lending terms would improve sustainability," it said.
"Reprofiling of payment flows does not imply nominal
haircut or budgetary costs for creditors. This would also entail further NPV gains for Greece, and strengthen the sustainability of the Greek public debt in the long-run."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Some say back to the drachma for a Greek reboot</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Some-say-back-to-the-drachma-for-a-Greek-reboot</Link>
        <Description>LONDON (Reuters) - Mainstream economic thinking may hold that Greece should stay in the euro zone, but there are those who argue that abandoning the single currency will give the cash-strapped and debt-laden country just the boost it needs.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:35:03 PM
Updated:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:35:03 PM
Some say back to the drachma for a Greek reboot
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
LONDON (Reuters) - Mainstream economic thinking may hold that Greece should stay in the euro zone, but there are those who argue that abandoning the single currency will give the cash-strapped and debt-laden country just the boost it needs.
Greece's economy is so depressed, they argue, that unless it regains the competitive edge a massive one-off currency devaluation could offer, it will remain lifeless.
Until then, the idea of a euro zone exit - either by accident or design - will keep on returning.
Roger Bootle, the founder of London-based markets and economic analysis group Capital Economics, won an economics prize of 250,000 pounds ($395,000) three years ago for drawing up a guide on how an ailing nation would exit the euro.
"If Greece were to leave the euro, it is presented with an opportunity. That doesn't mean to say it will take it," he says, arguing that the current negotiations about Greece's debt miss the point.
"How does a debt deal bring about an increase in aggregate demand in Greece? No one seems to be grappling with the economic issue."
Greece and its creditors are locked in talks to secure a deal that will see Greece undertake further economic reforms in return for more aid, thereby averting default on debt repayments to the International Monetary Fund on June 30.
The new proposals currently on the table include further long-term cuts to pensions as well as additional taxation that, while encouraging change in the economy overall, will have the effect of further weakening demand.
There are major caveats to Greece departing from the euro, not least the fact that no legal mechanism exists for a country to leave the currency union.
It would probably create a huge political and financial mess, including a default on all private and public external debts, soaring prices of imported goods and an end to a river of EU money which has pumped billions into infrastructure since Greece joined the bloc in 1981.
So what, says the head of investment for Dutch pension and investment fund manager Nationale Nederlanden, Hans Stoter, if you can have strong growth within a year or so of leaving the euro, when between times the economy has shrunk 30 percent.
"If you have a sore thumb and the infection keeps getting bigger and bigger, you can medicate it, you can deal with it," he says. "Or you can cut off your arm."
BOOST
The most immediate and tangible consequences of leaving would be a sizeable, one-off devaluation in the currency which Athens adopts, possibly the drachma.
Bootle suggests a one-off devaluation of 30 percent could be worth anything up to a 20 percent boost to Greece's economic output, although that would hinge on many other fiscal, regulatory and tax policies being adopted too.
Devaluation is no panacea and wouldn't address the fundamental problems of the Greek economy like the lack of reforms, corruption, and a bloated public sector, Bootle said. But it would give a huge boost to the Greek tourism industry and other service sectors.
He attaches an 80-90 percent likelihood that Greece will ultimately leave the euro zone, and points to Argentina, Russia, Iceland and South Korea as examples over the past 20 years of economies that did "extremely well" out of major currency devaluations.
Neil Record, founder and chairman of Record Currency Management, another of the finalists for the Wolfson award in 2012, assumed the wholesale collapse of the euro and provided for both a 40 percent devaluation of the drachma, as well as a 30 percent revaluation of a new Deutschmark.
Under that scenario, drawing parallels with Argentina, Record said Greece could easily register real growth after inflation of 5 percent annually from 2016.
"It's reasonable to suppose they would have a really awful, torrid 2015," he said. "But in the sort of magical way of these things they could easily then be the best performing country in Europe in 2016 and 2017."
DYSFUNCTION
Paul Krugman, Nobel laureate and professor of economics and international affairs at Princeton University, has been a highly vocal critic of the euro project, saying its inflexible monetary structure has strangled growth in weaker countries like Greece.
He had never advocated "Grexit" and argues that leaving the euro isn't the same as never entering.
But he wrote in The New York Times on June 19: "Grexit would produce a rapid improvement in competitiveness, at the cost of possible financial chaos."
A year ago, the IMF predicted that the Greek economy would contract by 0.6 percent in 2014 before growing almost 3 percent this year and more than 3 percent every year through to 2019, when the country's huge output gap would finally be closed.
But 2014 growth has come at -0.1 percent, making the forecasts for the rest of the decade look decidedly optimistic.
(Reporting by Jamie McGeever and Patrick Graham Editing by Jeremy Gaunt)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>At least 19 killed in gun attack on Tunisian tourism hotel - official</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Tourist-hotel-in-Tunisias-Sousse-attacked--security-source</Link>
        <Description>TUNIS (Reuters) - At least 19 people have been killed after at least one gunman attacked a Tunisian tourist hotel in the popular resort of Sousse, an interior ministry official said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
TUNIS (Reuters) - At least 19 people have been killed after at least one gunman attacked a Tunisian tourist hotel in the popular resort of Sousse, an interior ministry official said on Friday.
(Reporting by Tarek Amara; writing by Patrick Markey; editing by John Stonestreet)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Germany&amp;#39;s Schaeuble says sees 50:50 chance of Greek deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Germanys-Schaeuble-says-sees-5050-chance-of-reaching-Greek-deal</Link>
        <Description>FRANKFURT (Reuters) - There is a 50-50 chance of the euro zone reaching an agreement with Greece about the reforms it needs to make in return for further aid, Germany&amp;#39;s finance minister said on Friday, adding that failure could compromise the currency bloc.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
FRANKFURT (Reuters) - There is a 50-50 chance of the euro zone reaching an agreement with Greece about the reforms it needs to make in return for further aid, Germany's finance minister said on Friday, adding that failure could compromise the currency bloc.
Wolfgang Schaeuble's comments underlined the significant risk of failure of last-ditch negotiations this weekend to unlock loans to Greece and avert a default.
"I do not say what will be the outcome, it's 50-50," Schaeuble told a conference, referring to the negotiations.
He criticised proposals from Greece's finance minister which he said were focussed purely on hiking taxes without spending cuts.
Warning that much was at stake in the event of failure to clinch an agreement, Schaeuble said he was nonetheless prepared to take tough decisions.
"If we lose the confidence of the markets then ... we destroy the monetary union, the stability of the euro, and we are risking a lot more, and therefore the decision is not very easy to take but we will take it," he said.
Greece failed again on Thursday to reach a deal with its international creditors and talks with its international backers will resume on Saturday.
Schaeuble said Greece's principled stance in negotiations, where it is pushing for lenient reforms and a debt restructuring, was at odds with other euro zone countries.
"If you are on the autobahn and you are saying this is the right direction and all the others are driving in the other direction ... you are making a mistake."
(Reporting By John O'Donnell, Thomas Atkins and Marc Jones; Editing by Gareth Jones)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>Merkel, Hollande dangle financing before Greece&amp;#39;s Tsipras</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Greek-minister-says-two-or-three-issues-remaining-in-debt-talks</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS (Reuters) - The leaders of Germany and France offered to release billions in frozen aid on Friday in a last-minute push to talk Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras into contentious pension reforms in exchange for filling Athens&amp;#39; empty coffers until November.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:10:07 PM
Updated:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:10:07 PM
Merkel, Hollande dangle financing before Greece's Tsipras
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
BRUSSELS (Reuters) - The leaders of Germany and France offered to release billions in frozen aid on Friday in a last-minute push to talk Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras into contentious pension reforms in exchange for filling Athens' empty coffers until November.
The leftist premier's response, according to a Greek official, was that he could not understand why his country's creditors were seeking to impose such harsh conditions in return for money to avert imminent default and damage to the euro zone.
Chancellor Angela Merkel and President Francois Hollande, whose countries are Athens' two biggest lenders, held a 45-minute private meeting with Tsipras before the final session of a European Union summit at which they went through details of immediate funding for Greece if it would sign the deal.
The creditors laid out terms in a document that went to Greece on Thursday and was seen by Reuters on Friday. It said Greece could have 15.5 billion euros in EU and IMF funding in four instalments to see it through to the end of November, including 1.8 billion euros by Tuesday as soon as the Athens parliament approved the plan.
The total is slightly more than Greece needs to service its debts over the next six months but contains no new money.
A French source said Merkel and Hollande discussed outstanding differences on reforms Greece needs to accept - centred on pension reform, labour law and increasing value added tax - as well as an extension to Athens' bailout programme and financing.
Merkel and Hollande both said that Saturday's emergency meeting of euro zone finance ministers would be decisive to seal a deal before Greece has to make a key IMF repayment for which the government has said it lacks the money.
"Saturday's meeting is crucial because we are on the eve of a date, June 30, when the Greek authorities have to meet a payment obligation," Hollande told a news conference. "It's also crucial because there are parliaments that have to meet if there's a deal."
The Eurogroup ministers will meet at 5 p.m. (1500 GMT) on Saturday and Greece will be asked whether it accepts a revised offer from the European Commission, the European Central Bank and the International Monetary Fund, a euro zone official said.
"PLAN B"
If Greece refuses, the ministers will move on to discussing a "Plan B" on preparing to limit the damage from a Greek default to Greek banks and other euro zone countries and markets, the official said.
However, Merkel and Hollande have refused to talk publicly about a "Plan B", saying their efforts are focused on getting an agreement to keep Greece in the euro zone.
In public, Berlin kept up the pressure on Athens to yield, saying it was up to the Greek government to move.
Officials said that talks to reconcile the creditors' and Greek positions were continuing behind the scenes, even though Greece continues to denounce the lenders' proposals.
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis had another blast at the creditors' approach in an interview with Irish radio on Friday, saying their demands for tax increases and pension cuts as conditions for disbursing aid were putting Greece in an impossible position.
"I am against increasing the corporate tax, but then again I am against raising the tax on hotels and against cutting the pensions of people who live below the poverty line," Varoufakis said on Irish national radio RTE.
"These issues are putting me and my government in an impossible position, having to make a bad choice among really hard, difficult bad choices."
But he did not rule out accepting the terms.
Dramatising the choice facing Athens, Germany's member of the European Commission, Guenter Oettinger, said Greece had five days left to avoid an exit from the euro zone.
DIVIDED
Euro zone finance ministers are divided over whether a default would necessarily lead to Athens leaving the 19-nation single currency area, which would undermine the principle that membership is irrevocable.
Failure to pay the 1.6 billion IMF euro instalment on Tuesday could trigger a bank run, capital controls to curb deposit flight and possibly the issuance of IOUs or a parallel currency.
China, a growing economic partner of the EU, offered a vote of confidence in the euro zone on Friday ahead of Premier Li Keqiang's visit to Europe next week, saying it was sure Greece's talks with creditors would go positively.
Confidential documents drawn up by Greece's creditors and seen by Reuters showed that the country's debt would remain sustainable, even under a worst-case scenario envisaged by the IMF, if the maturities on euro zone loans were extended and interest rates were cut, without the need for a write-down.
The calculations are regarded as crucial to persuade German lawmakers to agree to the aid disbursement.
They showed that in the most severe case, Greek debt would require substantial "reprofiling" and improved lending terms but no "haircut" nor budgetary costs for the lenders.
Tsipras and Varoufakis have insisted so far that a commitment to debt relief is essential for Greece to accept any deal, while Germany and its allies had refused up to now to discuss the issue until Athens enacts and implements the reform programme to complete its current bailout.
The fact that Hollande and Merkel discussed financing issues with Tsipras on Friday may indicate a new willingness to address the issue as part of a deal.
(Additional reporting by Matthias Sobolewski in Berlin, Jan Strupczewski and Andreas Rinke in Brussels; Writing by Paul Taylor; Editing by Sophie Walker)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>U.S. President Obama briefed on attack in France</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/US-President-Obama-briefed-on-attack-in-France</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. President Barack Obama has been briefed on the attack at a U.S. gas company in France, a senior administration official said on Friday, providing no further details.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:05:02 PM
Updated:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:05:03 PM
U.S. President Obama briefed on attack in France
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. President Barack Obama has been briefed on the attack at a U.S. gas company in France, a senior administration official said on Friday, providing no further details.
A severed head covered in Arabic writing was found at the company in southeastern France, police sources and French media said. The site belonged to Air Products
, a U.S. industrial gases and chemicals company, according to another French company in the same sector.
(Reporting by Roberta Rampton; Writing by Bill Trott; Editing by Susan Heavey)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Casualties in attack on Tunisian beach hotel, at least one gunman killed - source</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Casualties-in-attack-on-Tunisian-beach-hotel-at-least-one-gunman-killed--source</Link>
        <Description>TUNIS (Reuters) - Casualties have been reported in an attack on a beach hotel in the Tunisian city of Sousse, and at least one gunman has been killed in clashes there, a security source said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
TUNIS (Reuters) - Casualties have been reported in an attack on a beach hotel in the Tunisian city of Sousse, and at least one gunman has been killed in clashes there, a security source said on Friday.
Sousse is one of the North African country's most popular beach resorts, drawing tourists from Europe and neighbouring countries. Tunisia has been high alert since Islamist gunmen attacked the Bardo museum in Tunis in March, killing a group of foreign visitors.
(Reporting by Tarek Amara; writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Dominic Evans)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Kuwait mosque bomb kills 4, governor says, 8 badly hurt</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Kuwait-mosque-bomb-kills-4-governor-says-8-badly-hurt</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - Four people were killed in a suicide attack on Friday on a Shi&amp;#39;ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait City, the governor of Kuwait City Thabet al-Muhanna said. </Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:00:04 PM
Updated: Friday June 26, 2015 MYT 8:00:04 PM
Kuwait mosque bomb kills 4, governor says, 8 badly hurt
Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
DUBAI (Reuters) - Four people were killed in a suicide attack on Friday on a Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait City, the governor of Kuwait City Thabet al-Muhanna said.
Speaking by telephone from Kuwait, Muhanna told Reuters that eight people were in critical condition. A witness said the bombing happened when the mosque was packed with some 2,000 worshippers during Friday prayers.
(Reporting by Hadeel al Sayegh, Writing by William Maclean; editing by John Stonestreet)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Islamic State claims responsibility for Kuwait mosque attack - statement</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Islamic-State-claims-responsibility-for-Kuwait-mosque-attack--statement</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - Militant group Islamic State claimed responsibility for a suicide attack on a Shi&amp;#39;ite mosque in Kuwait that killed or wounded several people, according a statement posted on social media.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
DUBAI (Reuters) - Militant group Islamic State claimed responsibility for a suicide attack on a Shi'ite mosque in Kuwait that killed or wounded several people, according a statement posted on social media.
The statement identified the bomber as Abu Suleiman al-Muwahed and said the target was a "temple of the rejectionists" - a term used by the Islamist militant group to refer to Shi'ite Muslims - and said dozens were killed or wounded.
(Reporting by Omar Fahmy, writing by Sami Aboudi; editing by John Stonestreet)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Israeli forces shoot and kill Palestinian gunman in West Bank - army</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/06/26/Israeli-forces-shoot-and-kill-Palestinian-gunman-in-West-Bank--army</Link>
        <Description>JERUSALEM (Reuters) - Israeli soldiers shot and killed a Palestinian gunman in the occupied West Bank on Friday after he opened fire on them at a checkpoint, the Israeli military said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article on Facebook or Twitter
to win cash or gadget!
JERUSALEM (Reuters) - Israeli soldiers shot and killed a Palestinian gunman in the occupied West Bank on Friday after he opened fire on them at a checkpoint, the Israeli military said.
It was the third such violent incident in eight days.
On Sunday a Palestinian stabbed and wounded an Israeli paramilitary policeman outside the walled Old City of Jerusalem. The policeman shot back and wounded him. Last Friday a suspected Palestinian gunman shot at two Israeli hikers near a Jewish settlement in the West Bank and killed one. The assailant escaped.
There were no Israeli casualties in the latest incident.
Palestinians seek a state in East Jerusalem, the West Bank and the Gaza Strip, territories Israel captured in the 1967 Middle East war. The last round of peace talks between the sides broke down in April 2014.
Palestinian militants this month fired rockets into Israel from Gaza, drawing Israeli return fire. That frontier has been largely quiet since the Gaza war last year in which more than 2,100 Palestinians and 73 on the Israeli side were killed.
(Writing by Maayan Lubell; Editing by Mark Trevelyan)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
