<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="thestar">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Amnesty International - Hamas committed war crimes against Gaza civilians</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/27/Amnesty-International--Hamas-committed-war-crimes-against-Gaza-civilians</Link>
        <Description>GAZA (Reuters) - Amnesty International said in a report on Wednesday that Islamist Hamas committed war crimes against Palestinian civilians in the Gaza Strip during last year&amp;#39;s war with Israel.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 8:30:09 AM
Updated:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 8:30:09 AM
Amnesty International - Hamas committed war crimes against Gaza civilians
GAZA (Reuters) - Amnesty International said in a report on Wednesday that Islamist Hamas committed war crimes against Palestinian civilians in the Gaza Strip during last year's war with Israel.
A ceasefire last August ended 50 days of fighting between Gaza militants and Israel in which health officials said more than 2,100 Palestinians, mostly civilians, were killed. Israel put the number of its dead at 67 soldiers and six civilians.
"Hamas forces carried out a brutal campaign of abductions, torture and unlawful killings against Palestinians accused of 'collaborating' with Israel and others during Israel's military offensive against Gaza," the human rights group's report said.
In a previous report in March, Amnesty also criticised Israel and accused it of war crimes during the conflict. Apart from the many deaths, at least 16,245 homes were destroyed or rendered uninhabitable. Gaza militants fired thousands of rockets and mortars at Israel.
In Wednesday's report, Amnesty listed a number of cases it described as "spine chilling" in which Palestinians accused by Hamas of helping Israel were tortured and killed.
"The de facto Hamas administration granted its security forces free rein to carry out horrific abuses including against people in its custody. These spine-chilling actions, some of which amount to war crimes, were designed to exact revenge and spread fear across the Gaza Strip," Amnesty said.
Representatives of Hamas were not immediately available to comment on the Amnesty report.
Hamas controls the Gaza Strip, a coastal enclave on the Mediterranean which borders Israel and Egypt.
The Palestinians have joined the International Criminal Court since the end of the war, a move opposed by Israel, and the ICC is examining possible war crimes in the conflict. But joining the court also exposes Palestinians to possible prosecution if a case is opened.
(Writing by Ori Lewis; Editing by Grant McCool)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Libyan prime minister says survives assassination attempt</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/27/Libyas-elected-lawmakers-say-session-halted-after-car-burned-outside</Link>
        <Description>BENGHAZI, Libya (Reuters) - Libya&amp;#39;s internationally recognised prime minister, Abdullah al-Thinni, said on Tuesday he had survived an assassination attempt by gunmen who opened fire as he was leaving a session of the anarchic country&amp;#39;s elected parliament.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 8:30:08 AM
Updated:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 8:30:08 AM
Libyan prime minister says survives assassination attempt
by ayman al-warfalli
BENGHAZI, Libya (Reuters) - Libya's internationally recognised prime minister, Abdullah al-Thinni, said on Tuesday he had survived an assassination attempt by gunmen who opened fire as he was leaving a session of the anarchic country's elected parliament.
The incident highlighted the unravelling of state authority in the North African country in which two governments and parliaments allied to armed factions are fighting for control four years after rebels overthrew Muammar Gaddafi.
Thinni has faced increasing criticism for running an ineffective rump state in the east since losing the capital Tripoli in the west to a rival faction that now controls ministries and key state bodies based there.
Thinni told pan-Arab news channel al-Arabiya that after he left parliament in the town of Tobruk and drove off, gunmen in several cars followed his entourage and opened fire.
"We were surprised by a lot of bullets... Thank God, we managed to escape," Thinni said, adding that one bodyguard had been wounded.
He did not elaborate but his cabinet said in a statement  the gunmen had been "paid criminals" who had previously tried storming parliament.
Parliament speaker Aqila Saleh had asked Thinni to leave the assembly for his safety after protesters opposed to his government gathered outside the naval base where the parliament meets, two lawmakers told Reuters.
A burning car could be seen outside the gated venue, lawmakers said. The session resumed after Thinni's departure. Thinni works out of Bayda, near Tobruk to the west.
It was the latest disruption in a tumultuous year for the House of Representatives, which has like Thinni struggled to stamp its authority over an increasingly fragmented country.
Thinni's government had originally planned to set up  parliament in the main eastern city of Benghazi but relocated to Tobruk near the Egyptian border after Benghazi turned into a battleground between the government and Islamist militants.
Parliament initially opened in a Tobruk hotel but moved to the naval base after a suicide bomber detonated a car in front of the hotel in December.
The House of Representatives is being challenged by a Tripoli-based assembly known as General National Congress (GNC) that was set up after a rival faction seized the capital in August.
The GNC had been the country's previous assembly whose mandate had ended with the election of the House of Representatives but was reinstated by the new Tripoli rulers as the country split into two administrations.
Islamic State militants have exploited a security vacuum as the two governments fight each other on several fronts without either side gaining the upper hand.
(Reporting by Ayman al-Warfalli; Additional reporting by Ahmed Tolba in Cairo; Writing by Ulf Laessing; Editing by Mark Heinrich, Toni Reinhold)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Afghan insurgents launch late-night attack on Kabul guesthouse</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/27/Heavy-gunfire-multiple-explosions-heard-late-at-night-in-central-Kabul</Link>
        <Description>KABUL (Reuters) - Heavily armed insurgents stormed a guesthouse in the diplomatic quarter of Kabul late on Tuesday night and were still battling Afghan security forces more than two hours after the assault began.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 8:30:06 AM
Updated:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 8:30:06 AM
Afghan insurgents launch late-night attack on Kabul guesthouse
by mirwais harooni AND jessica donati
KABUL (Reuters) - Heavily armed insurgents stormed a guesthouse in the diplomatic quarter of Kabul late on Tuesday night and were still battling Afghan security forces more than two hours after the assault began.
Police did not identify the guesthouse or its occupants. Afghan and Western security sources said the target could be a compound owned by a prominent political family and used by foreigners, or a building next to it.
"A group of insurgents has entered a guesthouse in the Wazir Akbar Khan area," Kabul police chief spokesman Ebadullah Karimi said. "The fight is ongoing."
There was no immediate word on casualties.
Representatives of the Taliban, which has been waging an Islamist insurgency in Afghanistan since being toppled by a U.S.-led coalition in 2001, could not immediately be reached for comment.
Teams of elite Afghan security forces were deployed to the guesthouse area, an upscale part of the capital where many embassies and government buildings are located.
Hours after the attack began, it was still unclear how many insurgents were involved and police vehicles were seen setting up roadblocks around the diplomatic quarter to prevent the insurgents from escaping the area.
Over a dozen explosions that sounded like rockets were counted during the attack and gunfire continued after midnight.
Several of the more powerful blasts heard could have been caused by suicide bombers detonating their vests, an Afghan security source said.
The Afghan capital has been hit by a series of high-profile attacks on foreigners and government targets over the past two weeks.
The Taliban targeted the Park Palace hotel on May 13, killing over a dozen people. The majority of casualties were Afghan civilians, but an American, a British-Afghan national, four Indians, an Italian and a Kazakh were also among the dead.
NATO's 13-year combat mission officially ended in December and the small contingent that remains in the country is mostly focussed on training Afghan security forces.
Afghan civilians, however, are bearing the brunt of the bloody conflict that has escalated around the country as foreign troops have withdrawn.
Following the deadly hotel attack two weeks ago, an EU vehicle was bombed a few days later, near Kabul's airport in a blast that killed a British security contractor and at least two Afghan civilians.
Last week, at least five Afghans were killed and dozens more wounded by a car bomb that detonated in the parking lot of the Afghan Ministry of Justice.
(Writing by Jessica Donati; editing by Mark Heinrich and G Crosse)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Iran nuclear deal unlikely by June 30, French envoy</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/27/No-Iran-sanctions-relief-before-end-2015-at-best--German-envoy</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - An Iran nuclear deal is not likely by June 30 because technical details will remain to defined and Iran will not get sanctions relief before the end of the year in the best of cases, western ambassadors said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 5:45:02 AM
Updated:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 5:45:03 AM
Iran nuclear deal unlikely by June 30, French envoy
by arshad mohammed
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - An Iran nuclear deal is not likely by June 30 because technical details will remain to defined and Iran will not get sanctions relief before the end of the year in the best of cases, western ambassadors said on Tuesday.
Six major powers are seeking to negotiate an agreement under which Iran would limit its nuclear programme in exchange for the easing of economic sanctions that have crippled its economy.
Envoys to Washington from Britain, France and Germany, three of the P5+1 group that also includes China, Russia and the United States, sketched out their expectations for the end game as a self-imposed June 30 deadline approaches.
"Its very likely that we wont have an agreement before the end of June or even (right) after," French ambassador Gerard Araud said in an appearance at the Atlantic Council think tank.
The Iranians want to force the six powers' ministers to decide the issues, rather than lower-level officials, Araud said, saying he expected some melodrama toward the end with late nights and doors slammed as both sides jockey for a deal.
"Even if we get the best deal ... afterwards, you will have to translate it into the technical annexes, so it may be ...  we could have a sort of fuzzy end to the negotiation," he said.
Speaking after the event, Araud said it could take a few weeks of July to complete the technical annexes envisaged under an agreement, if one can be reached.
Iran and the P5+1 reached a framework agreement on April 2, but several issues remain unresolved, including the pace of sanctions relief and the monitoring and verification measures to ensure Iran does not pursue a clandestine nuclear programme.
Iranian officials say they must receive sanctions relief immediately upon reaching an agreement. Western officials  argue that sanctions will be eased gradually and only after Iran has taken steps to limit its nuclear programme.
"Iran needs some time to start the implementation of this agreement, so in the best case sanctions relief would not happen before the end of this year," German ambassador Peter Wittig said.
Peter Westmacott, Britain's ambassador, said it would be hard to tighten sanctions if no deal is struck, particularly if the major powers are blamed for the failure.
"My sense is that we are probably not far away from the high-water mark of international sanctions against the Iranian economy," he said.
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>U.N. chief confirms delay in Yemen peace talks</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/27/UN-chief-confirms-delay-in-Yemen-peace-talks-says-disappointed</Link>
        <Description>UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon has asked his special envoy to Yemen to postpone Geneva peace talks planned for May 28, though he hopes to convene negotiations aimed at ending the war as soon as possible, the United Nations said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 5:20:03 AM
Updated:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 5:20:03 AM
U.N. chief confirms delay in Yemen peace talks
UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon has asked his special envoy to Yemen to postpone Geneva peace talks planned for May 28, though he hopes to convene negotiations aimed at ending the war as soon as possible, the United Nations said on Tuesday.
"The secretary-general is disappointed that it has not been possible to commence such an important initiative at the soonest possible date and reiterates his call for all parties to engage in United Nations-facilitated consultations in good faith and without preconditions," U.N. spokesman Stephane Dujarric said.
Dujarric said the U.N. decision to postpone the talks was in response to a request from the government of Yemen and other parties to the conflict to have "more time to prepare."
An aide to Yemen's president had previously said the negotiations were postponed indefinitely. A Saudi-led coalition has been bombing Iran-allied Houthi rebels for months and supporting Yemeni fighters opposing the Houthis in battle lines drawn across the country.
Iran denies arming Yemen's Houthis and has criticized the Saudi-led coalition's refusal to let Iranian cargo ships and planes into Yemen to deliver what it says is only humanitarian aid.
Dujarric said Ban has instructed his Yemen envoy, Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed, "to redouble his efforts to consult with the Yemen government, Yemen's political groupings and countries in the region with the aim of producing a comprehensive ceasefire and the resumption of peaceful dialogue."
"(Ban) is acutely aware that a postponement or delay in a return to the political process will exacerbate a steadily deepening humanitarian crisis," Dujarric said.
(Reporting by Louis Charbonneau; Editing by Leslie Adler)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Exclusive - Before Myanmar seized migrant boat, Rohingya whisked away </title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/27/Exclusive--Before-Myanmar-seized-migrant-boat-Rohingya-whisked-away</Link>
        <Description>YANGON/THEK KAY PYIN, Myanmar (Reuters) - When the Myanmar navy seized a boat used by people smugglers last week, it announced that the 200 people found aboard were mostly Bangladeshis seeking better economic prospects in Southeast Asia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 5:16:52 AM
Updated:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 5:17:04 AM
Exclusive - Before Myanmar seized migrant boat, Rohingya whisked away
by timothy mclaughlin AND antoni slodkowski
YANGON/THEK KAY PYIN, Myanmar (Reuters) - When the Myanmar navy seized a boat used by people smugglers last week, it announced that the 200 people found aboard were mostly Bangladeshis seeking better economic prospects in Southeast Asia.
The message was clear - that very few of the people on the boat, and by extension in the wave of Asian "boatpeople" drifting on the Bay of Bengal and the Andaman Sea, were members of Myanmar's Rohingya minority. Myanmar denies discriminating against the Rohingya or that they are fleeing persecution.
But in interviews with Reuters, people who were on the boat  said between 150-200 Rohingya were aboard at one point. Many were quietly whisked away by the traffickers in the week before the navy brought the ship to shore, they said. The number is far larger than what Reuters reported previously.
"All of the Rohingya got off the ship. The Bangladeshis stayed behind," said a 27-year-old Rohingya woman who was on the boat with her five children. All six of them returned to their village of Thek Kay Pyin before the ship was seized last Thursday.
It was not possible to independently confirm the account of the woman, who identified herself as Arafa. Like many Rohingya, she uses only one name. But six other villagers said they were among the scores of Rohingya taken off from the boat.
It was not clear why the traffickers would only take the Rohingya off the boat. Matthew Smith, the executive director of the Southeast Asia-based Fortify Rights group, has said in testimony to the U.S. Congress that Myanmar's security forces are complicit in and profit from the trafficking. The government has dismissed the accusation.
WIDE GOVERNMENT PUBLICITY
Last week, Reuters reported that at least eight people found on the boat were Rohingya. The government, which had initially said all on board were Bangladeshis, said eight were "Bengalis" from Myanmar, the term it uses for the Rohingya.
Zaw Htay, an official in the president's office, said on Tuesday he was not aware that any other people were on the boat, other than the Bangladeshis and the eight "Bengalis".
"Our office did not get any information that some of them left before," he told Reuters.
The Myanmar government invited United Nations officials to meet the Bangladeshi migrants and the event was given wide publicity on state television.
After a crackdown on people smugglers in Thailand blocked trafficking routes earlier this month and forced them to abandon some ships, thousands of migrants have washed ashore in Malaysia and Indonesia. Others are stranded on trafficking boats off the shores of several Southeast Asian countries.
The migrant boats contain a mix of people from Bangladesh seeking to escape poverty at home as well as Rohingya, Indonesian and Malay authorities have said.
DESPERATE CONDITIONS
U.S. Deputy Secretary of State Antony Blinken said last week during a visit to Myanmar that the majority of the more than 3,000 migrants who have landed on Malaysian and Indonesian shores this month were Rohingya Muslims fleeing from "the desperate conditions they face" in Myanmar's Rakhine state.
Rakhine Chief Minister Maung Maung Ohn later told Reuters: "I am disappointed by, and completely disagree and reject such unfounded allegations by the United States."
"This (migration) is human trafficking, not (due to) political or religious discrimination at all."
Other Myanmar officials have said the Bangladeshis claim to be Rohingya to receive U.N. aid.
Most of Myanmar's 1.1 million Rohingya Muslims are stateless and live in apartheid-like conditions in Rakhine state. Almost 140,000 were displaced in deadly clashes with majority Buddhists in Rakhine in 2012. They are denied citizenship and have long complained of state-sanctioned discrimination.
About 100,000 have fled overseas since 2012, according to the Arakan Project, a Rohingya advocacy group.
The boat seized by the Myanmar navy was at anchor for about two months off the coast of Myanmar to load up before it was supposed to set sail for Malaysia, the seven villagers and two community leaders, who did not want to be named, told Reuters.
At the time it was filled with about 200 Bangladeshis and around 150-200 Rohingya, Thailand launched its crackdown on traffickers.
Small fishing boats started coming up to the ship and began offloading the Rohingya for about a week before it was brought ashore by the navy last Thursday, the seven Rohingya migrants who came back from the ship told Reuters.
The jobless woman who gave her name as Arafa said she was trying to join her husband in Malaysia and was allowed off the ship for free. Most others had to pay traffickers between $200 (130) and $300 to return to the same villages they tried to escape weeks earlier.
One of them was Mohamed Anyis, 18, from a village close to Sittwe, the capital of Rakhine state. He befriended some of the Bangladeshi men during his two-month stay on the ship.
"We shared scarce food rations and helped the weakest men together," said Anyis.
The migrants were beaten with metal rods and given only two cups of water and a handful of rice a day, Anyis and Arafa said. Anyis still had numerous white scars on his hands and ankles which he said came from repeated beatings.
"As we waited, six Bangladeshi men died of exhaustion. The crew threw their bodies into the sea," he said.
Anyis, Arafa and other villagers separately recognised and correctly named several of the Bangladeshis in photographs Reuters took at the ceremony where the Bangladeshi men were presented to the U.N. officials, confirming they spent weeks on the same boat.
(Editing by Raju Gopalakrishnan)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Rocket fired from Gaza lands near Israeli port Ashdod - police</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/27/Rockets-fired-from-Gaza-Strip-land-in-southern-Israel--TV-reports</Link>
        <Description>JERUSALEM (Reuters) - A rocket fired from the Gaza Strip landed near the Israeli port city of Ashdod on Tuesday but no casualties or damage were reported, police and the military said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 5:16:38 AM
Updated:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 5:16:38 AM
Rocket fired from Gaza lands near Israeli port Ashdod - police
JERUSALEM (Reuters) - A rocket fired from the Gaza Strip landed near the Israeli port city of Ashdod on Tuesday but no casualties or damage were reported, police and the military said.
Palestinian militants in Gaza launched thousands of rockets and mortar bombs into Israel during a war last July and August in which Israeli shelling and air strikes battered the small, coastal Palestinian enclave. The region has been largely quiet since the August ceasefire.
Tuesday's rocket landed near Ashdod some 20 km (12 miles) north of the Gaza border and security forces were searching for remnants. It was the longest-range strike since the truce that ended the 50-day war last year.
There was no immediate claim of responsibility in Gaza for the rocket launching. Earlier reports by Israeli media said five rockets had been fired.
Israeli media speculated that infighting among Islamic Jihad militants in Gaza Strip may have precipitated the rocket firing without the permission of Gaza's Islamist Hamas rulers.
Rival militant factions in Gaza are angry that months after the end of the war, no progress has been made to improve the isolated enclave's plight and pledges for funding to reconstruct buildings devastated during the war have not been honoured.
Reconciliation efforts between Hamas and the Western-backed Palestinian Authority led by President Mahmoud Abbas have faltered, adding to hardships and hampering foreign aid donations and the import of building materials.
Israel maintains a partial blockade on the territory and Egypt largely keeps the Rafah border crossing closed. Hamas has imposed a "solidarity tax" and salaries for workers not aligned with the Palestinian Authority are not being paid in full.
(Additional reporting by Nidal al-Mughrabi in Gaza; Writing by Ori Lewis; Editing by Mark Heinrich)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>China to extend military reach, build lighthouses in disputed waters</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/27/China-to-extend-military-reach-build-lighthouses-in-disputed-waters</Link>
        <Description>BEIJING (Reuters) - China outlined a strategy to boost its naval reach on Tuesday and announced plans for the construction of two lighthouses in disputed waters, developments likely to escalate tensions in a region already jittery about Beijing&amp;#39;s maritime ambitions.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 5:14:03 AM
Updated:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 5:14:03 AM
China to extend military reach, build lighthouses in disputed waters
by megha rajagopalan
BEIJING (Reuters) - China outlined a strategy to boost its naval reach on Tuesday and announced plans for the construction of two lighthouses in disputed waters, developments likely to escalate tensions in a region already jittery about Beijing's maritime ambitions.
In a policy document issued by the State Council, the Communist-ruled country's cabinet, China vowed to increase its "open seas protection", switching from air defence to both offence and defence, and criticised neighbours who take "provocative actions" on its reefs and islands.
China has been taking an increasingly assertive posture over recent years in the disputed waters of the South China Sea, where it has engaged in extensive land reclamation in the Spratly archipelago.
China claims most of the South China Sea and criticised Washington last week after a U.S. spy plane flew over areas near the reefs. Both sides accused each other of stoking instability.
A U.S. State Department spokesman declined to make a specific comment on the Chinese strategy paper, but said Washington urged Beijing "to use its military capabilities in a manner that is conducive to maintaining peace and stability in the Asia-Pacific region."
Jeff Rathke reiterated the U.S. view that Chinas reclamation work had contributed to rising tensions and said building up of underwater features did not confer a right to a territorial sea or an exclusive economic zone.
White House spokesman Josh Earnest said President Barack Obama considered the South China Sea security situation "critically important" to U.S. national security and the global economy and said Washington was committed to working with other Asia-Pacific states to protect the free flow of commerce there.
While also declining to comment on the content of China's policy paper, Pentagon spokesman Colonel Steve Warren said its publication was "a step in the right direction" in terms of transparency and "exactly the type of thing that weve been calling for" in that respect.
China has overlapping claims with the Philippines, Vietnam, Malaysia, Taiwan and Brunei in the South China Sea, through which $5 trillion (3.25 trillion) in ship-borne trade passes every year.
Chinese Defence Ministry spokesman Yang Yujun said China's reclamation in the Spratlys was comparable with construction of homes and roads on the mainland.
"From the perspective of sovereignty, there is absolutely no difference," he told reporters.
Some countries with "ulterior motives" had unfairly characterized China's military presence and sensationalised the issue, he said. Surveillance in the region was increasingly common and China would continue to take "necessary measures" to respond.
"Some external countries are also busy meddling in South China Sea affairs. A tiny few maintain constant close-in air and sea surveillance and reconnaissance against China," the strategy paper said in a thinly veiled reference to the United States.
OFFENCE AND DEFENCE
It said China's air force would shift its focus from territorial air defence to both offence and defence, and building airspace defences with stronger military capabilities.
China also announced plans for the building of two lighthouses in the South China Sea on Tuesday and broadcast a groundbreaking ceremony on state television, defying calls from the United States and the Philippines for a freeze on such activity.
Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying said the construction was to help maritime search and rescue, disaster relief, environmental protection and navigational security.
Wu Shicun, president of the government-affiliated National Institute for South China Sea Studies, said the lighthouses were among the first of planned civilian-use facilities in the region.
"The reefs are located near an important commercial shipping route, so there will be continued development to maintain the security of those shipping lanes," he told Reuters.
The strategy paper also said the People's Liberation Army's nuclear force, known as the Second Artillery Corps, would strengthen its capabilities for deterrence and nuclear counterattack as well as medium- and long-range precision strikes.
"China faces many complex maritime security threats and challenges and requires a navy that can carry out multifaceted missions and protect its sovereignty," Wang Jin, a senior colonel, told reporters.
The paper also cited "grave threats" to China's cyber infrastructure, adding that China would hasten development of a cyber military force.
Self-ruled Taiwan, which China considers a renegade province, called on all South China Sea claimants to shelve their disagreements to enable talks on sharing resources before a conflict breaks out.
Japan meanwhile will join a major U.S.-Australian military exercise for the first time in a sign of growing security links between the three countries as tensions fester over China's moves.
All three nations have said they are concerned about freedom of movement through the South China Sea and air space.
China's Ministry of Defence said on Tuesday it had carried out military training for party cadres from border and coastal areas on border defence, among other topics.
The trainees, who visited military combat units, developed a better understanding of the "national security situation", said a statement on the ministry's website.
(Additional reporting by Sui-Lee Wee and Michael Martina in Beijing, Matt Siegel in Sydney and David Brunnstrom in Washington; Editing by Nick Macfie and Jonathan Oatis)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Italian mafia boss arrested in Brazil after 30 years on the run</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/27/Italian-mafia-boss-arrested-in-Brazil-after-30-years-on-the-run</Link>
        <Description>RIO DE JANEIRO (Reuters) - Brazilian police said on Tuesday they arrested an Italian mafia boss who had been on the run for 30 years and was convicted of killing over 20 people in the 1980s.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 3:50:03 AM
Updated:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 3:50:05 AM
Italian mafia boss arrested in Brazil after 30 years on the run
RIO DE JANEIRO (Reuters) - Brazilian police said on Tuesday they arrested an Italian mafia boss who had been on the run for 30 years and was convicted of killing over 20 people in the 1980s.
Pasquale Scotti, 56, was arrested in the northeast city of Recife in a joint operation of Brazil's federal police and INTERPOL, according to a police statement.
Scotti was convicted in absentia by an Italian court in 1991 for the illegal possession of firearms, extortion and more than 20 homicides.
He was the boss of the Camorra mafia group in Naples and was arrested in a shootout in 1983 in which he was hit multiple times. But on Christmas Eve of 1984 he escaped from a hospital where he was being treated after signing a plea bargain.
Despite multiple raids and road blocks stopping thousands of cars, Italian police were unable to find Scotti.
"He left no traces. It's as if he vanished," Italian police were quoted as saying in a La Repubblica article from the time.
On Tuesday, police said the man had been using a false identity in Brazil and that INTERPOL identified him by comparing archived digital fingerprints.
The Italian authorities have begun the process of getting him extradited, the police said.
Scotti has two Brazilian children and was arrested as he took them to school, the Globo G1 news website reported.
(Reporting by Stephen Eisenhammer; Editing by Steve Orlofsky)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Libya&amp;#39;s premier Thinni says he survived assassination attempt</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/27/Libyas-premier-Thinni-says-he-survived-assassination-attempt</Link>
        <Description>TRIPOLI (Reuters) - Libya&amp;#39;s official premier Abdullah al-Thinni said he survived an assassination attempt after leaving a parliamentary session on Tuesday in the eastern city of Tobruk.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 3:20:08 AM
Updated:                 Wednesday May 27, 2015 MYT 3:20:10 AM
Libya's premier Thinni says he survived assassination attempt
TRIPOLI (Reuters) - Libya's official premier Abdullah al-Thinni said he survived an assassination attempt after leaving a parliamentary session on Tuesday in the eastern city of Tobruk.
"Thank God, we managed to escape," he told pan-Arab news channel al-Arabiya.
(Reporting by Ahmed Tolba; Writing by Ulf Laessing; Editing by Janet Lawrence)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
