<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="thestar">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Thai junta reforms to fail without better charter - former PM</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/01/Thai-junta-reforms-to-fail-without-better-charter--former-PM</Link>
        <Description>BANGKOK (Reuters) - Any achievements by Thailand&amp;#39;s ruling junta while in power will be lost without significant changes to the country&amp;#39;s draft constitution, Democrat Party leader and former Prime Minister Abhisit Vejjajiva said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:45:03 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:45:05 PM
Thai junta reforms to fail without better charter - former PM
by amy sawitta lefevre AND simon webb
BANGKOK (Reuters) - Any achievements by Thailand's ruling junta while in power will be lost without significant changes to the country's draft constitution, Democrat Party leader and former Prime Minister Abhisit Vejjajiva said on Friday.
The military toppled an elected government last May and is engineering wide ranging reforms to heal the country's deep political divisions.
But both the Democrat Party and its rivals have called the junta's draft charter undemocratic, saying it could herald more turmoil under a weak coalition government.
"If they don't come up with a constitution that is accepted, and cannot come up with one that can be sustained, they will have lost everything," Abhisit, who was prime minister from 2008 to 2011, told Reuters in an interview.
"Whatever they have achieved will just come to nothing."
Drafters have worked on the false assumption that weakening political parties would prevent abuse of power and stem corruption, Abhisit said.
But a weakened party system would play into the hands of politicians such as exiled billionaire and former Prime Minister Thaksin Shinawatra, he added.
"He's got the resources to draw politicians away from political parties into groupings that could actually form a new coalition," he added.
Thailand has been divided for more than a decade between supporters of Thaksin and the Bangkok-based royalist-military establishment, which reviled Thaksin's popularity.
Abhisit said his party had "never had a problem" with Thaksin's Puea Thai Party but that it should take the opportunity to move away from the "Thaksin agenda".
He added, "I've always maintained that the conflict has been between Thaksin and the Thai state. That should give a clue to the people in power, as well that the secret of reconciliation is to get beyond the Thaksin issue."
A year after then army chief Prayuth Chan-ocha launched the coup to restore order following months of protests, Abhisit said the junta still had a long way to go to tackle Thailand's political problems.
"What I would warn the current regime is that I don't think they have been able to get to grips with what was wrong with the country before May 22... They still have time to rectify that."
Wide public debate was needed on the constitution and it would be better to delay elections set for early next year if necessary, to get the charter right, Abhisit said.
"There is no way they can correct what I see as mistakes until they open a forum and open their minds," he added.
(Editing by Clarence Fernandez)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Islamist rebels battle Syrian army near Assad heartland</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/01/Syrian-rebels-fight-Syrian-army-near-Assad-heartland</Link>
        <Description>AMMAN/BEIRUT (Reuters) - Islamist rebels and the Syrian army fought fierce battles in Latakia province overnight close to President Bashar al-Assad&amp;#39;s ancestral home, the army and rebels said, after weeks of insurgent gains in the country&amp;#39;s northwest.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:25:05 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:25:05 PM
Islamist rebels battle Syrian army near Assad heartland
AMMAN/BEIRUT (Reuters) - Islamist rebels and the Syrian army fought fierce battles in Latakia province overnight close to President Bashar al-Assad's ancestral home, the army and rebels said, after weeks of insurgent gains in the country's northwest.
Rebels seeking to topple Assad have in the past sought to bring their four-year-long insurgency close to coastal areas in government-held Latakia, heartland of Assad's minority Alawite community.
An army source told state news agency SANA fighter jets hit insurgent hideouts in the northern Latakia countryside with "tens killed and wounded." Latakia is the main port in Syria and along with the capital Damascus is one of the most important government-held areas in the country.
The violence follows advances in neighbouring Idlib province by the hardline Ahrar al-Sham group and Syria's al Qaeda wing Nusra Front as well as other allied fighters.
Rami Abdulrahman, who runs the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights monitoring group, said the Latakia battles started with an army offensive on Thursday, backed by local militias, aimed at pushing the insurgents out of the province in order to advance on captured areas of neighbouring Idlib.
The Observatory, which collects information from a network of sources on the ground, said at least five insurgents were killed and an unidentified number from the pro-government side.
Two rebel sources said the fighting in Latakia was near the mountains of Jabal al-Akrad, close to some of the highest peaks in Syria including Nabi Younis that overlook Alawite villages and close to Qardaha, hometown of the Assad family.
"The capture of the peaks would make the Alawite villages in our firing range," said an Ahrar al-Sham commander based in Idlib on Skype. In August 2013, Islamist rebels and foreign fighters briefly captured Alawite villages.
The Observatory's Abdulrahman said the army wanted to secure the valley and peaks in order to advance on Jisr al-Shughour, a town in Idlib province captured by insurgents a week ago.
Battles raged around a hospital on the southwestern outskirts of the town on Friday where army forces and allied fighters have been holed up since the insurgent offensive began, the Observatory said, adding that a blast had targeted the army earlier in the day.
On Friday Syrian television said army units targeted "groups of terrorists" in the eastern and southern Idlib countryside and "eliminated a great number of them and destroyed their weapons and munitions."
Diplomats say rebels are trying to pressure the overstretched army on as many fronts as possible to spread its resources ever more thinly.
(Reporting by Suleiman Al-Khalidi in Amman and Sylvia Westall in Beirut; Editing by Dominic Evans/Hugh Lawson)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Protesters ready for May Day march over black man&amp;#39;s death in Baltimore</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/01/Baltimore-police-give-prosecutors-report-on-Freddie-Grays-death</Link>
        <Description>BALTIMORE (Reuters) - Protesters and the family of a 25-year-old black man who died of injuries sustained while in police custody planned a May Day march in Baltimore as they demanded answers and punishment for the officers involved.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:20:14 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:20:14 PM
Protesters ready for May Day march over black man's death in Baltimore
by scott malone AND ian simpson
BALTIMORE (Reuters) - Protesters and the family of a 25-year-old black man who died of injuries sustained while in police custody planned a May Day march in Baltimore as they demanded answers and punishment for the officers involved.
Freddie Gray's death is the latest in a string of incidents exposing the tense relations between U.S. minorities and police. Protesters planned to use annual May 1 marches, marking International Labour Day, to focus attention on the case, which follows the killings of unarmed black men in recent months.
Police in Baltimore turned over their report on the case a day earlier to prosecutors but released few details publicly, though local media reports suggested Gray may have been injured while he was in the back of a police van.
After rioting in Baltimore on Monday, protests have spread to major cities around the United States, resembling scenes of outrage sparked last year by police killings of unarmed black men in Ferguson, Missouri, New York and elsewhere.
Baltimore City State's Attorney Marilyn Mosby, a black woman who is the daughter and granddaughter of police officers, has now taken over the investigation to determine what exactly happened to Gray and whether any of the six officers involved in his arrest should face criminal charges. The six have been suspended from duty.
Mosby said her office has been conducting its own independent probe. The U.S. Justice Department is also investigating the case.
"All I want her to do is one thing: Search for the truth," said U.S. Representative Elijah Cummings, a Democrat who has been a fixture in the largely peaceful protests that followed Monday's rioting. "We must allow the process to go forward."
Gray suffered spinal injuries some time between his April 12 arrest and his arrival at a police station. Police have said Gray was not restrained during the ride, a violation of department policies. He died a week later.
Despite the protests, many questions about Gray's death remain unanswered. But media reports on Thursday provided possible accounts of what may have happened.
Multiple law enforcement sources told local broadcaster WJLA that the medical examiner found Gray's neck appeared to have broken when his head slammed into the back of the van. He also suffered a head wound matching a bolt jutting from the vehicle's back door, the sources told the station.
The Washington Post cited a prisoner, who rode in the police van with Gray but could not see him, as saying he heard sounds that suggested Gray tried to hurt himself while riding in the vehicle, according to a document written by a police investigator.
Many on the streets of Baltimore were sceptical of the idea that Gray's injuries were self-inflicted.
"The police did that," said Eugene Russell, 46. "And the police are going to get away with it."
'KAFKA-ESQUE NIGHTMARE'
Roughly 270 people have been arrested since Monday's violence - which saw stores looted, dozens of buildings and cars burned, and numerous officers injured - and officials have since imposed a citywide 10:00 p.m. curfew.
Police Commissioner Anthony Batts said on Wednesday that more than 100 people had been released without being charged, because officials could not keep up with the paperwork, though he said charges would be brought later.
But public defender Marci Tarrant Johnson described the conditions endured by many of the arrestees before their release in a Facebook posting Wednesday that has since gone viral.
Johnson wrote that many had been illegally detained for more than 24 hours and that women she interviewed had taken to using slices of bread served as part of their meals as pillows.
"Interviewing these women was emotionally exhausting. Quite a few of them began crying - so happy to finally see someone who might know why they were there, or perhaps how they might get out of this Kafka-esque nightmare," she wrote.
"The cells were designed to hold people for a few hours, not a few days," she said.
Baltimore police and the state's Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services could not be immediately reached on Friday morning to comment on the allegations.
The Associated Press reported on Wednesday that one of the officers involved in Gray's arrest had been hospitalized three years ago over mental health concerns. The report could not be independently confirmed.
(Writing by Curtis Skinner; Editing by Bernadette Baum)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>One thousand Europeans missing, 12 dead after Nepal quake</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/01/One-thousand-Europeans-missing-12-dead-after-Nepal-quake</Link>
        <Description>KATHMANDU (Reuters) - One thousand people from the European Union are missing in Nepal and 12 are confirmed dead, nearly a week after a devastating earthquake, the head of the EU delegation here said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:20:02 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:20:02 PM
One thousand Europeans missing, 12 dead after Nepal quake
KATHMANDU (Reuters) - One thousand people from the European Union are missing in Nepal and 12 are confirmed dead, nearly a week after a devastating earthquake, the head of the EU delegation here said on Friday.
"We don't know where they are, or they could be," Ambassador Rensje Teerink told reporters, adding that those unaccounted for were mostly tourists in the Langtang and Lukla areas.
Langtang is a trekking region to the north of Kathmandu that has been hit by a huge avalanche and mudslides, while Lukla is the jumping off point for walkers and climbers making the nine-day trek to Everest base camp.
Nepal, struck by a huge earthquake on Saturday that has killed more than 6,000, is a popular destination for trekkers and climbers.
Rescuers have struggled to get to remote areas of the mountainous country popular with climbers to look for survivors, with fighting between tourists and locals marring efforts to airlift hundreds of trekkers to safety.
Diplomats are finding it hard to trace the missing because many backpackers do not register with their embassies when they arrive in the country.
(Reporting by Frank Jack Daniel; Writing by Douglas Busvine and Tommy Wilkes)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>Obama administration says to provide $20 million for police body cameras</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/01/Obama-administration-says-to-provide-20-million-for-police-body-cameras</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The Obama administration will provide $20 million (13.09 million pounds) in grants to local police departments to help buy body cameras for officers, the U.S. Justice Department said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:10:01 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:10:02 PM
Obama administration says to provide $20 million for police body cameras
by julia edwards
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The Obama administration will provide $20 million (13.09 million pounds) in grants to local police departments to help buy body cameras for officers, the U.S. Justice Department said on Friday.
The grants represent the first portion to be approved by Congress of a $75 million, three-year body camera funding program requested in December by President Barack Obama.
Demand for the cameras, which clip onto officers' uniforms to record interactions with citizens, has risen amid a series of deadly altercations between police and unarmed black men, followed by protests in several American cities.
Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake said last week that she would launch a body-camera pilot program after a black man died from a spinal injury while in police custody.
Some critics have accused Obama of doing too little to respond to the shootings. Democratic presidential front-runner Hillary Clinton said on Wednesday that the United States should make sure every police department has body cameras.
The cameras are expensive for police departments still struggling to regain pre-recession funding levels.
Los Angeles, which plans to deploy 860 cameras this summer, will spend $1.5 million in the first year to cover equipment, maintenance and storage.
The American Civil Liberties Union has warned that body camera use must be governed by standards that protect the privacy of those being recorded.
The federal funding will match local funds and be available only to departments that already have body camera policies in place, the Justice Department said in a fact sheet.
It will match funds dedicated to buying cameras and training police on how to use them, but not for storage of the footage they capture, which can often make up the bulk of the cost.
Departments awarded the money will be part of a pilot program, overseen by the Bureau of Justice Statistics, to evaluate the impacts of body cameras.
(Reporting by Julia Edwards; Editing by Kevin Drawbaugh, Lisa Shumaker and Susan Heavey)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Two Ukrainian serviceman killed in past 24 hours in east - military</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/01/Two-Ukrainian-serviceman-killed-in-past-24-hours-in-east--military</Link>
        <Description>KIEV (Reuters) - Two Ukrainian serviceman have been killed and two  wounded in separatist attacks on government forces in eastern Ukraine despite the Minsk ceasefire agreement, Interfax news agency quoted the Ukrainian military as saying on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:00:02 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 8:00:02 PM
Two Ukrainian serviceman killed in past 24 hours in east - military
KIEV (Reuters) - Two Ukrainian serviceman have been killed and two  wounded in separatist attacks on government forces in eastern Ukraine despite the Minsk ceasefire agreement, Interfax news agency quoted the Ukrainian military as saying on Friday.
"In the past 24 hours the situation in the conflict zone remained not quiet, but under control. Rebels continue to use weapons banned under the Minsk agreement," military spokesman Andriy Lysenko was quoted as saying at a briefing.
(Reporting by Alessandra Prentice; Editing by Louise Ireland)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Turkish police use tear gas on hundreds of May Day protesters - Reuters witness</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/01/Turkish-police-use-tear-gas-on-hundreds-of-May-Day-protesters--Reuters-witness</Link>
        <Description>ISTANBUL (Reuters) - Turkish police used water cannon and tear gas on hundreds of stone-throwing protesters on Friday, a Reuters reporter at the scene said, after the demonstrators attempted to defy a ban and march on Taksim Square in central Istanbul. </Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 7:45:10 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 7:45:10 PM
Turkish police use tear gas on hundreds of May Day protesters - Reuters witness
ISTANBUL (Reuters) - Turkish police used water cannon and tear gas on hundreds of stone-throwing protesters on Friday, a Reuters reporter at the scene said, after the demonstrators attempted to defy a ban and march on Taksim Square in central Istanbul.
Riot police in the Besiktas neighbourhood near the square chased protesters who threw bottles and set off fireworks.
(Reporting by Humeyra Pamuk; Writing by David Dolan; Editing by Louise Ireland)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Topless Femen activists disrupt Le Pen&amp;#39;s May Day speech in Paris</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/01/Topless-Femen-activists-disrupt-Le-Pens-May-Day-speech-in-Paris</Link>
        <Description>PARIS (Reuters) - Three topless women from the Femen activist group, making Nazi salutes, disrupted a May Day speech by French far-right leader Marine Le Pen on Friday attacking her political rivals.  </Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 7:45:03 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 7:45:08 PM
Topless Femen activists disrupt Le Pen's May Day speech in Paris
PARIS (Reuters) - Three topless women from the Femen activist group, making Nazi salutes, disrupted a May Day speech by French far-right leader Marine Le Pen on Friday attacking her political rivals.
After elections in which her anti-EU party gained power in local and regional elections across France, Le Pen has sought to capitalise on discontent over Socialist President Francois Hollande's handling of the economy and rising unemployment.
Her speech took aim at Hollande and former President Nicolas Sarkozy, who is trying to put his conservative UMP party back on track ahead of the 2017 presidential election.
"They have allowed massive immigration to install itself in France. They have unpinned the Islamic fundamentalist grenade," Le Pen said. "We are right on everything."
Before she was able to start her speech to hundreds of National Front (FN) supporters in central Paris, she was twice caught off guard.
Her father Jean-Marie, founder of the party and usually a speaker at the event, unexpectedly took to the podium to cheers despite a party disciplinary procedure against him over his repeated controversial comments about World War Two.
The 86-year-old former paratrooper trundled off stage without uttering a word and did not wait to listen to his daughter's speech.
Minutes later, three Femen activists with the slogans "Heil Le Pen" and "Stop Fascism" written on their bare breasts chanted anti-National Front slogans from the balcony of a building overlooking the stage, to boos from the crowd.
"Lots of surprises on this May 1," a visibly uneasy Le Pen said. "It's quite a paradox when you call yourself a feminist and try to disturb a tribute to Joan of Arc."
FN supporters had earlier laid a wreath at a statue of the 15th-century French heroine, who has been seized on by the far right as a nationalist symbol.
After about 10 minutes, four National Front security men seized the protesting women, who were later arrested.
"They will be forced to get dressed," Le Pen said.
Since succeeding her father as party chief in 2011, Marine has sought to rid the FN of its anti-Semitic image and position it as an anti-immigrant, Eurosceptic force proposing protectionist policies.
(Reporting by John Irish; editing by Andrew Roche)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>U.N. urges action from Maldives over trial of ex-president</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/01/UN-urges-action-from-Maldives-over-trial-of-expresident</Link>
        <Description>MALE/GENEVA (Reuters) - A senior U.N. human rights official said on Friday she had visited jailed former Maldives president Mohamed Nasheed for two hours in detention and urged the government to take action on his flawed trial.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 7:35:03 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 7:35:03 PM
U.N. urges action from Maldives over trial of ex-president
MALE/GENEVA (Reuters) - A senior U.N. human rights official said on Friday she had visited jailed former Maldives president Mohamed Nasheed for two hours in detention and urged the government to take action on his flawed trial.
"We kind of started to get signals that even the government recognises that something went wrong with the process of the trial," Mona Rishmawi, chief of the rule of law, equality and non-discrimination branch of the U.N. Human Rights Office, told a regular U.N. briefing.
"We would like to see this translate into concrete political action and see something happening in this case... What is very clear is that the president still has clemency powers.
She was speaking as supporters of the jailed former president took to the tropical island's streets to call for his release.
Nasheed, the country's first democratically elected leader, was imprisoned in March for his role in ordering the arrest of a senior judge, after a trial that the U.N. high commissioner for human rights said was marked by "flagrant irregularities".
The country is increasingly polarised between Nasheed's supporters and those who back current President Abdulla Yameen, whose half-brother lost power to Nasheed in 2008, ending 30 years of authoritarian rule.
Clashes broke out in February in the run-up to Nasheed's sentencing, although small-scale protests have since remained largely peaceful.
Rishmawi said Nasheed's trial had been politically motivated and the Maldives legal system was "totally incomplete", with makeshift rules and judges wielding "incredible discretionary powers".
"What we saw is that the rules have been really changed to lead to a certain result," she said.
She said people in prison always go through "ups and downs" but when she met Nasheed in a "temporary location" he was thoughtful as well as cracking jokes.
"But I wouldnt say he was relaxed. He knew he was facing 13 years in prison and he knew that his situation is really really difficult and he worried a lot about his safety."
She said she had warned the government to be "extremely careful" to ensure Nasheed's safety in the maximum security prison where he was moved to shortly after Rishmawi met him during her April 20-23 trip.
On Thursday, the European Parliament demanded an "immediate end" to the political use of justice, and called on member states to publish travel warnings about the government's human rights record to pressure the tourist industry, which accounts for about a third of the Maldives economy.
(Reporting by Tom Miles, Daniel Bosley and Tommy Wilkes; Editing by Dominic Evans)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Air strikes kill civilians in Yemeni capital </title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/01/Air-strikes-kill-civilians-in-Yemeni-capital</Link>
        <Description>CAIRO (Reuters) - Warplanes from a Saudi-led coalition struck a residential district of the Yemeni capital Sanaa overnight, killing eight to 10 civilians, residents said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 7:10:02 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 1, 2015 MYT 7:10:08 PM
Air strikes kill civilians in Yemeni capital
CAIRO (Reuters) - Warplanes from a Saudi-led coalition struck a residential district of the Yemeni capital Sanaa overnight, killing eight to 10 civilians, residents said on Friday.
The Saba state news agency, controlled by the Houthi movement in charge of Sanaa, put the death toll in the Sawan district at 20 and said more than 50 people had been wounded. It said casualties included woman and children.
Warplanes also struck a military airbase near the capital.
Saba said medics rushed to Sawan to try to rescue residents trapped under the rubble of homes.
The strikes came days after jets bombed the runway to stop an Iranian aid plane landing. Damage to the airport has stopped aid deliveries, officials said.
Saudi Arabia believes the Houthi group is a proxy its regional rival Iran, and Saudi backing for the resistance in Yemen's mostly Sunni Muslim south has raised fears that Yemen could descend into all-out sectarian war.
The Houthis hail from Yemen's far north and belong to the Zaydi sect of Shi'ite Islam. They swept into the capital Sanaa in September and pushed south and east, saying they were winning a revolution against Sunni militants and corrupt officials.
On Thursday, dozens of Houthi fighters were killed in clashes with Saudi forces on Yemen's northern border, Riyadh said. Air strikes and artillery fire rocked the southern city of Aden in fighting residents said was the worst in over a month of war.
(Reporting by Mohammed Ghobari; Writing by William Maclean; Editing by Andrew Roche)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
