<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Times of India">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:55:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Germany's oldest remaining nuclear plant shuts down</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a43f72/sc/3/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CGermanys0Eoldest0Eremaining0Enuclear0Eplant0Eshuts0Edown0Carticleshow0C478542580Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Germany's oldest remaining nuclear reactor has been shut down, part of a move initiated four years ago to switch off all its nuclear plants by the end of 2022.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Europe
Breaking News:
Germany's oldest remaining nuclear plant shuts down
AP | Jun 28, 2015, 07.25 PM IST
Grafenrheinfeldreactorwent into service in 1981. It is the first reactor to close since Germany switched off the oldest eight of its 17 nuclear reactors in 2011, just after Japan's Fukushima nuclear plant disaster.
RELATED
BERLIN: Germany's oldest remaining nuclear reactor has been shut down, part of a move initiated four years ago to switch off all its nuclear plants by the end of 2022.
The Grafenrheinfeld reactor in the southern state of Bavaria was taken offline as scheduled overnight, authorities and operator E.ON said Sunday.
Grafenrheinfeld went into service in 1981. It is the first reactor to close since Germany switched off the oldest eight of its 17 nuclear reactors in 2011, just after Japan's Fukushima nuclear plant disaster.
The next to close will be one of two reactors at the Gundremmingen plant in Bavaria, which is set to shut by the end of 2017. The rest will be closed by the end of 2022.
Environment Minister Barbara Hendricks said the Grafenrheinfeld shutdown is "a visible signal that the nuclear exit is moving forward."
"Every nuclear power station that goes offline reduces the so-called residual risk that is linked to the use of nuclear power plants and moves us a step forward in the reorganization of our energy supply," she said.
Germany aims to generate 80 percent of its electricity from renewable sources by 2050.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=renewable energy,Nuclear reactor,Germany
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:10:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pakistan heatwave claims 26 more, toll nears 1,300</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a40342/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cpakistan0CPakistan0Eheatwave0Eclaims0E260Emore0Etoll0Enears0E130A0A0Carticleshow0C478537540Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Twenty six people died today of high temperatures in Pakistan's Karachi, taking the death toll to around 1,300 as residents grappled with the week-long heatwave that has crippled life and overwhelmed the healthcare system.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Pakistan
Breaking News:
Pakistan heatwave claims 26 more, toll nears 1,300
PTI | Jun 28, 2015, 06.40 PM IST
Pakistani relatives shift a heatstroke victim to a government hospital in Karachi on June 28, 2015. More than 1,000 people have died as a result of days of scorching temperatures in southern Pakistan. (AFP photo)
RELATED
KARACHI: Twenty six people died today of high temperatures in Pakistan's Karachi, taking the death toll to around 1,300 as residents grappled with the week-long heatwave that has crippled life and overwhelmed the healthcare system.
Weather experts forecast the temperatures, which have been as high as 45 degrees Celsius in the past week, are again likely to soar in the next few days in Karachi, the country's biggest city and the financial capital.
Sindh health minister Jam Mahtab confirmed that out of the nearly 1,300 people killed in the Sindh province due to the heatwave, about 35 per cent were women.
Mahtab said around 25 per cent of those who died were the homeless, some were drug-addicts and lived on the streets.
The power crisis in the Sindh capital and other parts of the province has compounded the problems of residents, who have to face daytime outages lasting several hours.
Mahtab stressed that the number of casualties could have been prevented had it not been for the severe power breakdowns in the city by Karachi Electric. The power supplier's operations are being investigated by the federal government.
Bilawal Bhutto, chairman of the Pakistan Peoples Party which governs Sindh, yesterday pinned down the responsibility on the federal government, saying the deaths could have been prevented had load shedding been avoided.
The deadliest heatwave in decade in Pakistan has coincided with the holy month of Ramazan, when the country's Muslim majority observes a dawn-to-dusk fast.
The healthcare system in the province has been overmatched and is struggling to cater to the medical needs of the huge influx of people seeking treatment for heat-related ailments.
Nearly 2,000 patients with such ailments were still being treated at several hospitals, though the temperature has hovered under 40 degrees Celsius this week and came down to 35 degrees today.
"Since the last three days mass burials of around 200 unclaimed bodies have been carried out and these are mostly homeless people," Mahtab said.
According to Sindh health department statistics, a total of 1,206 people have died in Karachi alone due to the heatwave since June 20.
Raza Kazim, a spokesman for the Edhi Foundation which runs a private ambulance service and Karachi's main morgue, said they were still receiving dead bodies and had yesterday buried around 160 unclaimed bodies.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Ramazan,Pakistan Heatwave,Karachi Electric,karachi,Jam Mahtab
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:32:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Five dead in suicide blast at Nigeria leprosy hospital</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a4695a/sc/40/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CFive0Edead0Ein0Esuicide0Eblast0Eat0ENigeria0Eleprosy0Ehospital0Carticleshow0C478534740Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least five people have been killed and 10 wounded after a suicide bomber blew himself up outside a leprosy hospital on the outskirts of the northeast Nigerian city of Maiduguri, emergency services said.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Rest of World
Breaking News:
Five dead in suicide blast at Nigeria leprosy hospital
AFP | Jun 28, 2015, 06.02 PM IST
At least five people have been killed and 10 wounded after a suicide bomber blew himself up outside a leprosy hospital on the outskirts of the northeast Nigerian city ofMaiduguri. (Representative image)
RELATED
KANO: At least five people have been killed and 10 wounded after a suicide bomber blew himself up outside a leprosy hospital on the outskirts of the northeast Nigerian city of Maiduguri, emergency services said.
The bomber, who tried to gain access to the hospital, detonated his explosives outside the building at around 5:30 pm (1630 GMT) today.
"Five people were killed and 10 others injured near the Molai leprosy hospital when a male bomber blew himself up," said Mohammed Kanar, regional coordinator for the National Emergency Management Agency.
"The bomber had wanted to get entry into the hospital but was contemplating how to pass through security checks at the gate when the bomb went off."
He added: "We took the bodies and the injured to the specialist hospital (in Maiduguri)."
Local resident Ibrahim Bulama said the bomber was one of three men who were dropped off near the hospital by a SUV vehicle.
"They looked around for a while, obviously trying to sneak into the hospital," Bulama said, adding that the facility was being guarded by civilian vigilantes who are assisting the military in the fight against Boko Haram Islamist insurgents.
"Suddenly, the explosives on one of them went off. The other two fled in the confusion. Five people were killed and 10 others injured."
There was no immediate claim of responsibility for the bombing, but Nigeria's Borno state, where the attack took place, has been the hardest hit by the Boko Haram insurgency which has left at least 15,000 people dead.
Boko Haram, which has been fighting to establish a hardline Islamic state in northeast Nigeria since 2009, has intensified its campaign of violence in the last month.
Danlami Ajaokuta, a civilian vigilante fighting Boko Haram, confirmed the hospital explosion and added that there had been a failed suicide attack by two women in Jakarna village, about 40 kilometres from Maiduguri yesterday afternoon.
"Two female suicide bombers died when the explosives on one of them went off prematurely while they were waiting for a bus along the highway in Jakarna," Ajaokuta said.
"Residents from the village heard a huge explosion and when they arrived at the scene they found one of the bombers in parts while the other lay dead face down.
"Her explosives were still intact." Ajaokuta added that bus drivers have been refusing to pick up female passengers on the road outside Maiduguri since March, when three female suicide bombers blew themselves up at a bus stop in the area.
The armies of Nigeria, Chad, Niger and Cameroon have been fighting a joint campaign against Boko Haram for several months, pushing militants out of captured towns and villages.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Suicide blast,Nigeria,National Emergency Management Agency,Leprosy hospital,Kano
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:25:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French attack suspect admits to killing his boss -source</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a3f243/sc/40/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CFrench0Eattack0Esuspect0Eadmits0Eto0Ekilling0Ehis0Eboss0Esource0Carticleshow0C478534260Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The suspected Islamist militant held over an attack against a French chemical plant has admitted killing his boss, a source close to the investigation said on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>A photo taken on June 27, 2015, shows a tram in Saint-Priest, near Lyon southeastern France, where the man suspected of carrying out an attack on the US-owned Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier on June 26, 2015 lived. (AFP photo)
RELATED
PARIS: The suspected Islamist militant held over an attack against a French chemical plant has admitted killing his boss, a source close to the investigation said on Sunday.
Yassin Salih, 35, told detectives he had killed Herve Cornara in a parking area before arriving at the plant in Saint Quentin-Fallavier, 30 km (20 miles) south of Lyon, where he attempted to cause an explosion on Friday.
Police found the 54-year-old victim's decapitated body at the scene of the attack, where there were no other casualties.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Yassin Salih,Islamist militant,Herve Cornara
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:16:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK warns of more terror strikes in Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a432f5/sc/40/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cuk0CUK0Ewarns0Eof0Emore0Eterror0Estrikes0Ein0ETunisia0Carticleshow0C478533260Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Britain on Sunday asked its citizens in Tunisia to be on alert, warning that further terrorist attacks in the country are possible after the beach resort massacre by an IS militant that left 38 people dead, including 15 Britons.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World UK
Breaking News:
UK warns of more terror strikes in Tunisia
PTI | Jun 28, 2015, 05.46 PM IST
Britain's home secretary Theresa May gives a statement to the media after attending a COBRA National Emergencies Committee meeting at the Cabinet Office in London, Britain June 28, 2015. (Reuters photo)
RELATED
LONDON: Britain on Sunday asked its citizens in Tunisia to be on alert, warning that further terrorist attacks in the country are possible after the beach resort massacre by an IS militant that left 38 people dead, including 15 Britons.
In an updated travel advice, the foreign office said, "Further terrorist attacks in Tunisia, including in tourist resorts, are possible, including by individuals who are unknown to the authorities and whose actions are inspired by terrorist groups via social media."
Asking those who remained in Tunisia to be vigilant, it said, "You should be especially vigilant at this time and follow the advice of Tunisian security authorities and your tour operator."
At least 38 people were killed after an Islamic State militant opened fire on a beach in front of hotels in the Tunisian resort of Sousse on Friday. The victims include 15 Britons, though officials have warned that the toll is expected to rise.
Another 39 people were injured, including 25 Britons, in the attack.
Meanwhile, UK home secretary Theresa May, who chaired a meeting of the UK Government's emergency Cobra committee today, said that she has seen no evidence so far that the beach resort was targeted specifically because it is popular with British tourists, the BBC reported.
She, however, warned, that the risk to Britain had become "more diverse" in recent years - including not just the risk of groups plotting over time to strike in the country but also that of spontaneous attacks by a "lone wolf".
She said that some 40 plots had been foiled in the UK in the past decade.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=UK. Terror strikes,Tunisia,Theresa May,Islamic State,IS militant
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:34:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran's Zarif to return to Tehran for consultations on nuclear talks</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a3ec13/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CIrans0EZarif0Eto0Ereturn0Eto0ETehran0Efor0Econsultations0Eon0Enuclear0Etalks0Carticleshow0C478529250Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Iran's foreign minister Mohammad Javad Zarif will return on Sunday to Tehran for one day to consult with the country's leadership over the ongoing nuclear talks with major powers ahead of a June 30 deadline, Iran's Tasnim news agency reported.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Middle East
Breaking News:
Iran's Zarif to return to Tehran for consultations on nuclear talks
Reuters | Jun 28, 2015, 05.04 PM IST
Iran's minister of foreign affairs Mohammad Javad Zarif (R) attends a meeting at the Palais Coburg Hotel, the venue of the nuclear talks in Vienna, Austria on June 27, 2015.(AFP photo)
RELATED
VIENNA: Iran's foreign minister Mohammad Javad Zarif will return on Sunday to Tehran for one day to consult with the country's leadership over the ongoing nuclear talks with major powers ahead of a June 30 deadline, Iran's Tasnim news agency reported.
"Zarif will return to Tehran tonight and will come back to Vienna tomorrow," Tasnim said, citing an unnamed Iranian official.
An Iranian official told Reuters on condition of anonymity that Zarif will "consult with the leadership" over the talks in Vienna, where disagreements over several sticking points remain. Officials close to the talks say they will likely run into July.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Nuclear talks,Mohammad Javad Zarif
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:03:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK warns of possible further attacks in Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a3cf93/sc/6/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cuk0CUK0Ewarns0Eof0Epossible0Efurther0Eattacks0Ein0ETunisia0Carticleshow0C478521180Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Foreign Office minister Tobias Ellwood said Saturday that several British tourists had been seriously injured, while desperate families have said that some relatives are still unaccounted for.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World UK
Breaking News:
UK foreign office warns further attacks possible in Tunisia
AFP | Jun 28, 2015, 03.33 PM IST
Kuwait arrests driver of bomber in IS mosque attack
LONDON: The British government cautioned on Sunday that other attacks "are possible" in Tunisia after the mass shooting two days ago that left 38 people dead including at least 15 Britons.
Interior minister Theresa May said there had been no change in the British toll, the worst in a terror attack since the 2005 London bombings, but told the BBC: "We are expecting that to rise."
Foreign Office minister Tobias Ellwood said Saturday that several British tourists had been seriously injured, while desperate families have said that some relatives are still unaccounted for.
The attack led to the largest British loss of life in a terror attack since 52 people died in suicide bombings on the London transport system on July 7, 2005.
May said: "This is still an ongoing investigation and we're working very closely with the Tunisian authorities in relation to this.
"I've seen no evidence so far that this was targeted because there were British tourists there."
About 20,000 Britons were on package holidays at the time of the attack, and travel companies have laid on flights to repatriate those who want to come home.
In updated travel advice, the Foreign Office urged those who remained in Tunisia to be vigilant and said there was a risk of further incidents.
"Further terrorist attacks in Tunisia, including in tourist resorts, are possible, including by individuals who are unknown to the authorities and whose actions are inspired by terrorist groups via social media," it said.
The TUI travel group, which runs Thomson and First Choice holidays, sent out 11 flights on Saturday and had another 12 planned for Sunday, with the aim of bringing home a total of 2,500 people over the weekend.
Three members of the same family were among the British victims, according to media reports, including 19-year-old student Joel Richards, his uncle and grandfather.
Another 39 people were injured, including 25 Britons, in the attack claimed by the Islamic State group.
The shooting came the same day as a bombing in Kuwait, which was also claimed by the IS group, and a suspected Islamist murder at a factory in France.
The British government held meetings of its emergency response committee on Friday and on Saturday, and May was due to chair a third meeting later on Sunday.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Tunisia Terror Attack,Tobias Ellwood,british tourists
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:03:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK foreign office warns further attacks possible in Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a39cb7/sc/6/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cuk0CUK0Eforeign0Eoffice0Ewarns0Efurther0Eattacks0Epossible0Ein0ETunisia0Carticleshow0C478521180Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Foreign Office minister Tobias Ellwood said Saturday that several British tourists had been seriously injured, while desperate families have said that some relatives are still unaccounted for.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World UK
Breaking News:
UK foreign office warns further attacks possible in Tunisia
AFP | Jun 28, 2015, 03.33 PM IST
Kuwait arrests driver of bomber in IS mosque attack
LONDON: The British government cautioned on Sunday that other attacks "are possible" in Tunisia after the mass shooting two days ago that left 38 people dead including at least 15 Britons.
Interior minister Theresa May said there had been no change in the British toll, the worst in a terror attack since the 2005 London bombings, but told the BBC: "We are expecting that to rise."
Foreign Office minister Tobias Ellwood said Saturday that several British tourists had been seriously injured, while desperate families have said that some relatives are still unaccounted for.
The attack led to the largest British loss of life in a terror attack since 52 people died in suicide bombings on the London transport system on July 7, 2005.
May said: "This is still an ongoing investigation and we're working very closely with the Tunisian authorities in relation to this.
"I've seen no evidence so far that this was targeted because there were British tourists there."
About 20,000 Britons were on package holidays at the time of the attack, and travel companies have laid on flights to repatriate those who want to come home.
In updated travel advice, the Foreign Office urged those who remained in Tunisia to be vigilant and said there was a risk of further incidents.
"Further terrorist attacks in Tunisia, including in tourist resorts, are possible, including by individuals who are unknown to the authorities and whose actions are inspired by terrorist groups via social media," it said.
The TUI travel group, which runs Thomson and First Choice holidays, sent out 11 flights on Saturday and had another 12 planned for Sunday, with the aim of bringing home a total of 2,500 people over the weekend.
Three members of the same family were among the British victims, according to media reports, including 19-year-old student Joel Richards, his uncle and grandfather.
Another 39 people were injured, including 25 Britons, in the attack claimed by the Islamic State group.
The shooting came the same day as a bombing in Kuwait, which was also claimed by the IS group, and a suspected Islamist murder at a factory in France.
The British government held meetings of its emergency response committee on Friday and on Saturday, and May was due to chair a third meeting later on Sunday.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Tunisia Terror Attack,Tobias Ellwood,british tourists
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:46:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nine trapped in unlicensed coal mine in China</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a33a45/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cchina0CNine0Etrapped0Ein0Eunlicensed0Ecoal0Emine0Ein0EChina0Carticleshow0C478514520Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Nine persons have been trapped inside an unlicensed coal mine when they broke into it without permission in China's eastern Fujian Province.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World China
Breaking News:
Nine trapped in unlicensed coal mine in China
PTI | Jun 28, 2015, 02.16 PM IST
The cause of the accident is unclear, state-runXinhuanews agency reported. (Representative image)
RELATED
BEIJING: Nine persons have been trapped inside an unlicensed coal mine when they broke into it without permission in China's eastern Fujian Province.
Twelve workers broke into an abandoned and unlicensed coal mine in Wendong village in Yongding district without permission yesterday.
Three of them came out of the mine and called the police for help after the rest of their fellow workers failed to emerge from the mine.
The cause of the accident is unclear, state-run Xinhua news agency reported.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=coal mine
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:40:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain warns further Islamist attacks in Tunisia possible</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a33a44/sc/40/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cuk0CBritain0Ewarns0Efurther0EIslamist0Eattacks0Ein0ETunisia0Epossible0Carticleshow0C4785140A20Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Britain says Islamist militants may launch further attacks on tourist resorts in Tunisia after a gunman killed 39 people, including at least 15 Britons, in the worst assault of its kind in modern Tunisian history.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World UK
Breaking News:
Britain warns further Islamist attacks in Tunisia possible
Reuters | Jun 28, 2015, 02.10 PM IST
With some British tourists holidaying in Tunisia still unaccounted for, the number of Britons confirmed killed in the attack is expected to rise.
RELATED
LONDON: Britain says Islamist militants may launch further attacks on tourist resorts in Tunisia after a gunman killed 39 people, including at least 15 Britons, in the worst assault of its kind in modern Tunisian history.
Attacks may be carried out by "individuals who are unknown to the authorities and whose actions are inspired by terrorist groups via social media", the Foreign Office said in updated travel advice on its website late on Saturday.
Britain's Defence Secretary Michael Fallon and Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond, writing in separate Sunday newspapers, said the Tunisian murders would inform Britain's defence and security this year and stiffen London's resolve to tackle what they described as the poisonous narrative of Islamist extremism.
With some British tourists holidaying in Tunisia still unaccounted for, the number of Britons confirmed killed in the attack is expected to rise. Many Britons were due to fly home from Tunisia on Sunday, having cut short their holidays.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Tunisia attack,Islamist militants
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:36:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sri Lankan ex-president to contest as PM candidate</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a37d9f/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Csouth0Easia0CSri0ELankan0Eex0Epresident0Eto0Econtest0Eas0EPM0Ecandidate0Carticleshow0C478513730Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Former Sri Lankan President Mahinda Rajapaksa would contest as a prime ministerial candidate in the August 17 parliamentary elections, a source said on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>A file photo of former Sri Lankan PresidentMahindaRajapaksa.
RELATED
COLOMBO: Former Sri Lankan President Mahinda Rajapaksa would contest as a prime ministerial candidate in the August 17 parliamentary elections, a source said on Sunday.
Kumara Welgama, a former minister in Rajapaksa's government, said the former president would look to contest under the betel leaf symbol of the opposition United People's Freedom Alliance (UPFA), Xinhua news agency reported.
Welgama said all attempts would be made to unite the political parties in the UPFA, including the main opposition Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP), and put forward Rajapaksa as the UPFA prime minister candidate.
He hoped President Maithripala Sirisena, as UPFA chairman, would take a stand with regard to the nominations to be given to UPFA candidates, keeping in mind the best interest of the country.
There have been reports indicating that the president would not agree to nominate Rajapaksa as the prime minister candidate of the UPFA.
However, in the August 17 elections, all the political parties in the national unity government have decided to contest separately.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP),Sri Lanka,Maithripala Sirisena,Mahinda Rajapaksa
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:24:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Republican White House hopefuls deride gay marriage ruling</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a37d9d/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0CRepublican0EWhite0EHouse0Ehopefuls0Ederide0Egay0Emarriage0Eruling0Carticleshow0C478512980Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Republican presidential candidate Mike Huckabee told conservatives that the Supreme Court tried to "unwrite the laws of nature and the laws of nature's God" when it legalised gay marriage across the nation.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World US
Breaking News:
Republican White House hopefuls deride gay marriage ruling
PTI | Jun 28, 2015, 01.54 PM IST
The Republicans offered few suggestions on what to do about the gay marriage ruling, highlighting the party's challenges on social issues ahead of the 2016 elections. (Representative image)
RELATED
DENVER: Republican presidential candidate Mike Huckabee told conservatives that the Supreme Court tried to "unwrite the laws of nature and the laws of nature's God" when it legalised gay marriage across the nation.
The former Arkansas governor suggested Saturday that people in the United States flout the ruling, as President Abraham Lincoln did in the wake of the justices' 1857 decision that blacks could not be citizens. Huckabee also pointed out that President Barack Obama opposed gay marriage until 2012.
"He was either lying in 2008, or he's lying now, or God has rewritten the Bible and only Barack Obama has gotten the new edition," Huckabee told the crowd at the Western Conservative Summit.
Huckabee was among the Republican presidential hopefuls at the gathering, which followed a week in which the high court also upheld Obama's signature health care law.
The Republicans offered few suggestions on what to do about the gay marriage ruling, highlighting the party's challenges on social issues ahead of the 2016 elections.
Joining Huckabee at the conference was Republican hopeful Carly Fiorina, who said she supports civil unions.
She said opponents of the ruling should now focus efforts on religious freedom in public accommodations, such as cases of bakers facing penalties for refusing to serve gay couples. Former Texas Gov Rick Perry derided the ruling but didn't suggest a next step.
"These decisions need to be made in the states," said Perry, who noted that his states' rights plank extends even to Colorado legalizing recreational marijuana in defiance of federal drug law.
"I defend the right of Colorado to be wrong on that issue," Perry said. The crowd chuckled.
Wisconsin Gov Scott Walker, who has called for a constitutional amendment to undo the marriage ruling, did not mention the ruling in his remarks yesterday. He did talk broadly about judicial appointments when asked afterward by a moderator.
"The sole role of the judiciary ... is to uphold the Constitution of the United States and those laws duly enacted, no more, no less," Walker said to applause.
On Friday, former Pennsylvania Sen. Rick Santorum said the gay marriage ruling was "based on a lie" that gay-marriage opponents are motivated by discrimination.
"We have a Supreme Court that says the only reason that you could possibly oppose changing marriage laws in America is because you hate people who want to marry people of the same sex. That is not true," Santorum said.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=gay marriage ruling,Gay marriage
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:21:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait says mosque suicide bomber was Saudi</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a35688/sc/11/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CKuwait0Esays0Emosque0Esuicide0Ebomber0Ewas0ESaudi0Carticleshow0C478512720Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Kuwait has identified the suicide bomber who carried out the country's worst attack as a Saudi citizen, Kuwait state media reported on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Middle East
Breaking News:
Kuwait says mosque suicide bomber was Saudi
AFP | Jun 28, 2015, 01.51 PM IST
Terror attacks in France, Tunisia, Kuwait kill 63
RELATED
Kuwait arrests driver of bomber in IS mosque attack
DUBAI: A suicide bomber who carried out a deadly attack claimed by the Islamic State group on a Shiite mosque in Kuwait was a Saudi national, the interior ministry said Sunday.
In a statement carried by the official KUNA news agency, the ministry identified the attacker as Fahd Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Qaba'a.
The ministry said that Qaba'a entered the country through Kuwait Airport at dawn on Friday, the same day of the bombing.
Kuwait arrests driver of bomber in IS mosque attack
IS claimed the attack, which killed 26 and wounded 227 worshippers at the Al-Imam Al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City.
The ministry statement provided no further details about the bomber. Earlier on Sunday, the ministry said that security services arrested the driver of the car that transported the bomber to the site of the attack.
Authorities have also detained the owner of the house where the bomber was staying. He was described by the interior ministry as a Kuwaiti national who subscribes to "extremist and deviant ideology".
The driver, named as Abdulrahman Sabah Eidan Saud, was described as an "illegal resident" born in 1989.
Authorities on Saturday arrested the owner of the car, Jarrah Nimr Mejbil Ghazi, born in 1988, and also listed as a stateless person.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=suicide bomber,Shi'ite Muslim mosque killing,mosque suicide bomber,Fahd Suliman Abdul-Muhsen al-Qabaa
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:22:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deformed Mutt is crowned world's ugliest dog</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a2c640/sc/19/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0CDeformed0EMutt0Eis0Ecrowned0Eworlds0Eugliest0Edog0Carticleshow0C47850A8650Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A 10-year-old mutt named Quasi Modo, whose spinal birth defects left her a bit hunchbacked, is the winner of this year's World's Ugliest Dog contest.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World US
Breaking News:
Deformed Mutt is crowned world's ugliest dog
NYT News Service | Jun 28, 2015, 12.52 PM IST
A 10-year-old mutt named Quasi Modo, whose spinal birth defects left her a bit hunchbacked, is the winner of this year's World's Ugliest Dog contest. (AFP photo)
RELATED
PETALUMA: A 10-year-old mutt named Quasi Modo, whose spinal birth defects left her a bit hunchbacked, is the winner of this year's World's Ugliest Dog contest.
The pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix and her owner took the $1,500 prize Friday night, besting 25 other dogs competing in the contest that applauds imperfection, organizers said.
And though the name might make you think of the Quasimodo character in the Victor Hugo tale "The Hunchback of Notre Dame," this dog is female, not male as some thought.
Karen Spencer, marketing director for the Sonoma-Marin Fair, said she was notified Friday night by Quasi Modo's owner that the world's newly crowned ugliest dog is a she, and not a he.
Quasi Modo was abandoned at an animal shelter before being adopted by a veterinarian in Loxahatchee, Florida, according to her biography posted on the contest's website.
Two Chinese crested and Chihuahua mixes named Sweepee Rambo and Frodo took the second- and third-place prizes, respectively.
An 8-year-old Chihuahua named Precious received the "spirit award," honoring a dog and owner who have overcome obstacles and/or are providing service to the community. Precious, who is blind in one eye, is trained to monitor smells related to low blood sugar levels and alert her owner, a disabled veteran, of the problem, her biography said.
The contest, held at the Sonoma-Marin Fairgrounds in Petaluma, is in its 27th year.
The dogs are scored by a three-judge panel in several categories, including special or unusual attributes, personality and natural ugliness.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=World's Ugliest Dog Contest,World's Ugliest Dog,Quasi Modo,hunchbacked
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:03:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait arrests driver of bomber in IS mosque attack</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a2e77a/sc/3/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CKuwait0Earrests0Edriver0Eof0Ebomber0Ein0EIS0Emosque0Eattack0Carticleshow0C47850A7190Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Kuwaiti police arrested a driver who transported a suicide bomber to a Shiite mosque where he blew himself up, killing 26 and injuring 227 people, the interior ministry said Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Middle East
Breaking News:
Kuwait arrests driver of bomber in IS mosque attack
AFP | Jun 28, 2015, 12.33 PM IST
Crowds gather as victims of a bombing at a mosque on Friday, are buried at Al Jafariya cemetery in Suleibikhat. (Reuters photo)
RELATED
ISIS suicide bombing at Kuwait mosque kills 25
KUWAIT CITY: Kuwaiti police arrested a driver who transported a suicide bomber to a Shiite mosque where he blew himself up, killing 26 and injuring 227 people, the interior ministry said Sunday.
Authorities have also detained the owner of the house used as a hideout by the bomber, a Kuwaiti national who subscribes to "extremist and deviant ideology", the ministry said in a statement.
The suicide attack, the first bombing of a mosque in the oil-rich Gulf state, was claimed by the Islamic State jihadist group.
The IS-affiliated group in Saudi Arabia, calling itself Najd Province, said militant Abu Suleiman al-Muwahhid carried out the bombing.
The driver, named as Abdulrahman Sabah Eidan Saud, was described as an "illegal resident" born in 1989, who took the bomber to the Al-Imam Al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City on Friday.
"Illegal resident" is the official term used in Kuwait to describe stateless people, locally known as bidoons, who number around 110,000 and claim the right to Kuwaiti citizenship.
The driver had been hiding in a house in the Al-Rigga area in the city's southern Al-Ahmadi Governorate.
Authorities on Saturday arrested the owner of the car, Jarrah Nimr Mejbil Ghazi, born 1988, and also listed as a stateless person.
Although IS named the perpetrator, authorities have so far been unable to identify him from remains found at the scene, Al-Anbaa daily reported.
Samples of the body were sent to neighbouring countries for DNA tests as no records of his were found in Kuwait, the daily said.
Authorities will "continue efforts to uncover the conspirators in this criminal act and to reveal all of the information and circumstances behind it", the interior ministry said.
The attack is the first claimed by Islamic State group jihadists in the small Gulf emirate.
Local media said 18 of those killed were Kuwaitis, three Iranians, two Indians, one each from Pakistan and Saudi Arabia and one bidoon.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Shiite mosque,Islamic State jihadist group,IS mosque attack
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 09:45:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Funerals in Charleston for slain members of black church</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a2e779/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0CFunerals0Ein0ECharleston0Efor0Eslain0Emembers0Eof0Eblack0Echurch0Carticleshow0C47850A5560Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Funerals for three more victims of a deadly shooting during a Bible study group in South Carolina were held at the historic black church where they were killed.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World US
Breaking News:
Funerals in Charleston for slain members of black church
PTI | Jun 28, 2015, 12.15 PM IST
Pastor Julius McDowell embraces Reverend Brenda Kneece during a prayer vigil. (File photo)
RELATED
CHARLESTON (US): Funerals for three more victims of a deadly shooting during a Bible study group in South Carolina were held at the historic black church where they were killed.
The services for Cynthia Hurd, Tywanza Sanders and Susie Jackson were at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston, 11 days after a gunman entered the church and opened fire on a Bible study group. Police contend the attack was racially motivated.
Attendees included South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley and civil rights leaders.
The funerals follow one Friday for the Rev Clementa Pinckney, whose eulogy was delivered by President Barack Obama
The nation's first black president called for gun control and efforts to eliminate poverty and job discrimination, and said the Confederate battle flag, long a symbol of Southern pride, must be removed from places of honour.
A woman was arrested early yesterday on the grounds of the South Carolina Capitol in Columbia after scaling a flagpole to rip down a Confederate flag that flew at the Statehouse. Bree Newsome, 30, was arrested immediately afterward and later released.
The 21-year-old Dylann Storm Roof, who is charged with nine murders, embraced Confederate symbols before the attack, posing with the rebel battle flag and burning the US flag in photos.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 06:57:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Korea reports 32nd MERS death</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a26220/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CSouth0EKorea0Ereports0E32nd0EMERS0Edeath0Carticleshow0C478495380Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>South Korea today reported its 32nd death from MERS as the virus's mortality rate continued to rise even as the pace of the outbreak appeared to slow.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Rest of World
Breaking News:
South Korea reports 32nd MERS death
PTI | Jun 28, 2015, 09.27 AM IST
The total number of infections remained unchanged at 182 and fifteen patients were in critical condition, the health ministry said.
RELATED
SEOUL: South Korea today reported its 32nd death from MERS as the virus's mortality rate continued to rise even as the pace of the outbreak appeared to slow.
A 55-year-old man died yesterday of Middle East Respiratory Disease, the health ministry said, putting the latest mortality rate at 17.5 per cent.
That is up from 15 per cent a week ago and 10 per cent two weeks ago, though still lower than World Health Organization figures which put the mortality rate for the disease at around 36 per cent.
The man was diagnosed on June 9 after contracting the virus at Samsung Medical Centre in Seoul -- the epicentre of the outbreak where about 90 patients, visitors and medical staff had been infected.
The total number of infections remained unchanged at 182 and fifteen patients were in critical condition, the health ministry said.
A total of 91 patients have recovered and been released from hospital, including one yesterday, according to the ministry.
As of today, a total of 2,562 people were under quarantine either at state facilities or at home, it added.
The outbreak started on May 20 when a 68-year-old man was diagnosed after returning from a trip to Saudi Arabia.
Since then the potentially deadly virus - for which there is no vaccine - has spread at an unusually rapid pace in the Asia's fourth-largest economy, becoming the largest outbreak outside Saudi Arabia and sparking public alarm at home and elsewhere in Asia.
South Korea's government is facing criticism for failing to stop the outbreak.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Middle East Respiratory Disease,MERS
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 05:13:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French terror suspect took selfie with beheaded victim</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a2180e/sc/11/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CFrench0Eterror0Esuspect0Etook0Eselfie0Ewith0Ebeheaded0Evictim0Carticleshow0C478491560Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The top suspect in the beheading of a businessman that French authorities are calling a terrorist attack took a "selfie" photo with the slain victim and sent the image via WhatsApp to a Canadian mobile phone number, officials said Saturday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Europe
Breaking News:
French terror suspect took selfie with beheaded victim
AP | Jun 28, 2015, 07.43 AM IST
Police officers guard the road leading to a plant in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon, France where an attack took place on Friday.(AP photo)
RELATED
READ ALSO: Terror attack in France, severed head covered in Arabic writing found at factory
French investigators were working to determine the recipient's identity, but weren't able to immediately confirm media reports that it was an unspecified person now in Syria, where the radical Islamic State group has seized territory, the security officials said.
The revelation added a macabre twist to an investigation that has not turned up a solid link to radical or foreign groups, but has revived concerns about terrorism in France less than six months after deadly attacks in the Paris area.
Top suspect Yassine Salhi, a truck driver with a history of radical Islamic ties, as well as his sister and wife remained in police custody in the city of Lyon, a day after he allegedly crashed a truck into a U.S.-owned chemical warehouse and hung his employer's severed head on a factory gate, officials said.
READ ALSO: France's Hollande says factory attack was of 'terrorist' nature
One of the officials said the selfie was forwarded via WhatsApp, the globally popular instant messaging system owned by Facebook, to a phone number in Canada. The officials spoke on condition of anonymity because the investigation was ongoing.
Jean-Christophe de Le Rue, a spokesman for Canada's Public Safety Minister, confirmed that Canadian authorities are involved in the case.
"While I cannot comment on operational matters of national security, we are assisting the French authorities with their investigation,'' he said.
He declined to comment further on details of the investigation.
No group immediately claimed responsibility. The severed head appeared to mimic Islamic State's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see, and came days after the militants urged attacks during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan. French authorities say Salhi had links to radical Salafists in the past.
READ ALSO: Delivery man beheads boss in suspected Islamist attack on French gas site
Paris prosecutor's office spokeswoman Agnes Thibault-Lecuivre said the leading suspect began speaking with investigators after first refusing to do so. She declined to provide details, but said investigators haven't found any foreign connection.
The site of the beheading wasn't yet known to investigators, and the victim had been strangled beforehand, she said.
A fourth person arrested Friday was released without being charged. Under French anti-terrorism laws, Salhi and the women can be held up to four days before either being released or handed preliminary charges and locked up.
President Francois Hollande's office said he will convene a meeting with top parliamentary leaders about the matter on Tuesday.
Separately on Saturday, hundreds of people turned out in the region to honor slain businessman Herve Cornara and denounce the violence. Dozens turned out for a minute of silence in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, the town southeast of Lyon where Friday's attack took place at an Air Products chemicals warehouse.
Several hundred people also gathered outside a housing project in the town of Fontaines-sur-Saone to honor Cornara, 54, the manager of a transportation company that had employed Salhi since March. They recalled a kind, humble man who was active in the community of the Lyon suburb.
"He lived on the fifth floor, me on the fourth. He spoke with all the young people in the neighborhood. He didn't differentiate between (non-Muslim) French and Muslims,'' said Leila Bouri, a 24-year-old cafeteria cashier. ``If you ever had a problem, you would go see him.''
"When I heard this, I was shocked. It's shameful,'' she said. "I am a Muslim, but you can't kill like this. It's not who we are. In Islam, we're not told to slit throats. We only slit the throats of sheep. You don't slit the throats of people.''
The suspected killer, she added, "isn't a Muslim in my opinion."
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=WhatsApp,French terror suspect,French attack,beheaded victim
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 05:05:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Egypt sees sandstorm and earthquake on the same day</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a25b36/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CEgypt0Esees0Esandstorm0Eand0Eearthquake0Eon0Ethe0Esame0Eday0Carticleshow0C478491270Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Egypt faced treacherous weather conditions Saturday as a sandstorm blanketed the north of the country and a magnitude-5.2 earthquake centered in the Sinai peninsula shook buildings more than 200 miles away in the capital, Cairo.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Middle East
Breaking News:
Egypt sees sandstorm and earthquake on the same day
AP | Jun 28, 2015, 07.35 AM IST
ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
The epicenter of the quake was 4 kilometers (2.5 miles) southeast of thebeachsidetown ofNuweibain the Sinai, and about 75 kilometers (46 miles) south of Egypt's border with Israel, according to the US Geological Survey.
RELATED
CAIRO: Egypt faced treacherous weather conditions Saturday as a sandstorm blanketed the north of the country and a magnitude-5.2 earthquake centered in the Sinai peninsula shook buildings more than 200 miles away in the capital, Cairo.
The epicenter of the quake was 4 kilometers (2.5 miles) southeast of the beachside town of Nuweiba in the Sinai, and about 75 kilometers (46 miles) south of Egypt's border with Israel, according to the US Geological Survey.
Airports near Alexandria and Marsa Matrouh, along the Mediterranean coast, closed and diverted flights to Cairo due to poor visibility from the day's sandstorm, Civil Aviation Minister Hossam Kamel said in a statement. Visibility reached as low as 500 meters at the Burg al-Arab airport near Alexandria, he said.
Fierce winds whipped through the capital as many residents took cover from the sand by staying indoors. Others were seen braving the storm wearing surgical masks or covering their faces with clothing, as the wind sent rubbish and dust swirling.
At its peak, the sandstorm covered the capital in a thick orange cloud, dramatically reducing visibility.
In the Red Sea town of Dahab, 68 kilometers (42 miles) south of the epicenter of the quake in the Sinai peninsula, the tremor shook loose clouds of dust that enveloped nearby mountains, according to a witness. The quake appeared to startle local residents and tourists. It also shook the nearby Gaza strip. No serious damage was immediately reported from the earthquake in Egypt or in Gaza.
The Egyptian Ministry of Health said in a statement that there were no reports of deaths or injuries anywhere in Egypt due to the quake.
Israeli media reported that very mild aftershocks of the earthquake were felt in some places in the south of the country, but that no damage or injuries were caused.
The extreme weather conditions provided fodder for social media humor. Some wondered which of the 10 Biblical plagues would come next, while the popular Zamalek football club tweeted that it wasn't actually an earthquake--just preparation for their match tonight.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 05:03:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China to send exam cheats to jail</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47a25b35/sc/28/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cchina0CChina0Eto0Esend0Eexam0Echeats0Eto0Ejail0Carticleshow0C478491190Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>China is working on a new law which stipulates a jail sentence for those who copy in university entrance examination or use proxy examinees to sit in the tests on their behalf.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World China
Breaking News:
China to send exam cheats to jail
Saibal Dasgupta Saibal Dasgupta,TNN | Jun 28, 2015, 07.33 AM IST
ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
Authorities in Central China'sHenanprovince found that 165 candidates had violated exam laws, out of which 127 had employed stand-in test takers to face the exam on behalf of them, last year. It led to a public outcry.
RELATED
BEIJING: China is working on a new law which stipulates a jail sentence for those who copy in university entrance examination or use proxy examinees to sit in the tests on their behalf.
The new draft legislation is being considered by the Standing Committee of the National People's Congress, the Chinese parliament.
Chinese students need to pass a nationwide examination called Gaokao to get admissions in universities across the country.
The recently concluded Gaokao saw widespread exam fraud particularly those related to hiring stand-in examinees. In one case, a candidate in Jiangxi province was proxy for six different students on different examination dates.
Authorities in Central China's Henan province found that 165 candidates had violated exam laws, out of which 127 had employed stand-in test takers to face the exam on behalf of them, last year. It led to a public outcry.
The official media quoted education experts saying that amending laws to make exam cheating a criminal offense would help to promote integrity and protect fair competition.
The new draft law stipulates a minimum 3-year jail term, criminal detention or imposing a fine for organized cheating at a national exam. But the jail term can go up to a maximum seven years based on the severity of the case.
Huang Jingping, a professor at the prestigious Renmin University's faculty of law, said that it is not only the candidates and impostors who are involved in cases of fraud. Parents of candidates and their teachers are collectively responsible for the violations as well.
According to the Ministry of Education, 9.42 million Chinese high school students are taking the national college entrance exam this year.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
