<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Times of India">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:50:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>HSBC sacks half a dozen employees for posting fake Islamic State video online</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e81237/sc/28/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cuk0CHSBC0Esacks0Ehalf0Ea0Edozen0Eemployees0Efor0Eposting0Efake0EIslamic0EState0Evideo0Eonline0Carticleshow0C479748270Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>British bank HSBC has sacked half a dozen of its employees for producing a shocking video and posting it online which showed a fake Islamic State style execution during a team building exercise in Birmingham</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World UK
Breaking News:
HSBC sacks half a dozen employees for posting fake Islamic State video online
Kounteya Sinha Kounteya Sinha,TNN | Jul 7, 2015, 06.20 PM IST
READ MORE Islamic State | HSBC | fake video
RELATED
LONDON: British bank HSBC has sacked half a dozen of its employees for producing a shocking video and posting it online which showed a fake Islamic State style execution during a team building exercise in Birmingham. The eight-second video was just like the one posted by the world's most wanted terrorist organisation IS when they beheaded British nationals and aid workers David Haines and Alan Henning. One staff member also shouts out "Allah Hu Akbar" (God is greater) during the filming of the clip.
British taxi driver Alan Henning had skipped Christmas with his family to raise funds to purchase ambulances and medical equipment and join an aid convoy to Syria when he was beheaded by Islamic State militants. Henning (47) from Eccles, Greater Manchester had been held captive in Syria for nine months by ISIS. The others who were similarly beheaded on video were US journalists James Foley and Steven Sotloff and Scottish aid worker David Haines.
The video produced by the HSBC staff has been described by the bank as shocking and abhorrent. It showed staff members in balaclavas holding a fake knife over a kneeling man in an orange jumpsuit.
"We took the decision to sack the individuals involved. This is an abhorrent video and HSBC would like to apologise for any offence caused," a spokesman for the bank said.
The employees had posted the video on Instagram before deleting it.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Islamic State,HSBC,fake video
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:49:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK marks 10th anniversary of July 7/7 bombings</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e81230/sc/3/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cuk0CUK0Emarks0E10Ath0Eanniversary0Eof0EJuly0E70C70Ebombings0Carticleshow0C479748750Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it was ten years ago, but Britian will never cowed by it, Prime Minister David Cameron said on Tuesday as the country observed a minute's silence in memory of the 52 people killed by suicide bombers in London on July 7, 2005.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World UK
Breaking News:
UK marks 10th anniversary of July 7/7 bombings
PTI | Jul 7, 2015, 06.19 PM IST
British Prime Minister David Cameron (R) and London Mayor Boris Johnson take part in a wreath laying ceremony in London's Hyde Park on July 7, 2015, in memory of the 52 victims of the 7/7 London attacks. (AFP Photo)
RELATED
LONDON: The threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it was ten years ago, but Britian will never cowed by it, Prime Minister David Cameron said on Tuesday as the country observed a minute's silence in memory of the 52 people killed by suicide bombers in London on July 7, 2005.
Survivors of the attacks and relatives of the victims were among those to mark the 10-year anniversary at a ceremony at St Paul's Cathedral in London.
Cameron and London Mayor Boris Johnson were among those who laid wreaths in Hyde Park before the minute's silence at 11.30 am (local time), when London buses also came to a halt.
On the card attached to his wreath, Cameron wrote: "To the victims of terrorism in London 10 years ago today. We grieve your loss and will honour your memory forever."
Johnson wrote: "Ten years may have passed, but London's memory is undimmed. We honour again today the victims of 7/7. You will live forever in the hearts of the people of this city."
The bombings of three Tube trains and a bus - carried out by four bombers linked to Al Qaeda and carrying rucksacks of explosives - has been described as the worst single terrorist atrocity on British soil.
"Today the country comes together to remember the victims of one of the deadliest terrorist atrocities on mainland Britain," Cameron said in a statement.
"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly - the murder of 30 innocent Britons whilst holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact. But we will never be cowed by terrorism.
"We will keep on doing all that we can to keep the British public safe, protecting vulnerable young minds from others' extremist beliefs and promoting the shared values of tolerance, love and respect that make Britain so great," he added.
Petals fell from the dome of St Paul's Cathedral at the end of the silence. The Bishop of London, Richard Chartres, said in his address: "There could have been so easily demonstrations of anger but beyond the numbing shock there was solidarity.
"London had been attacked and our unity was in our grieving."
Candles representing the site of each bombing were carried through St Paul's by those who helped in the immediate aftermath of the attacks.
A second, more informal, service was held by hundreds of family members of those who died and survivors of the attack at Hyde Park in central London later on Tuesday.
They were joined by Prince William who laid flowers as all 52 victims names were read out at the 7 July Memorial, which consists of 52 stainless steel pillars, designed to symbolise the random nature of the loss of life.
Ten years ago to the day, suicide bombers Mohammed Sidique Khan, Shezhad Tanweer, Habib Hussain and Jermaine Lindsay met at Luton station in the morning and travelled to King's Cross.
Within three minutes of 8.50am UK time, Tanweer detonated his bomb at Aldgate, Khan set off his device at Edgware Road and Lindsay blew himself up between King's Cross and Russell Square.
Hussain detonated his device on board the number 30 bus at Tavistock Square at 9.47am. Some of the tube stations across London, including King's Cross and Aldgate, also held a minute's silence at 08:50 earlier today to mark the first bombing.
Survivors comforted each other and shared a moment of quiet reflection on what they had experienced exactly a decade ago.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=suicide bombers,Prime Minister,David Cameron,Boris Johnson,7/7 bombings
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:44:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Viral video: Sikh grandfather leaps into path of speeding train to save baby girl</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e8123d/sc/3/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CViral0Evideo0ESikh0Egrandfather0Eleaps0Einto0Epath0Eof0Espeeding0Etrain0Eto0Esave0Ebaby0Egirl0Carticleshow0C47974820A0Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A grandfather is being hailed a hero after dramatic CCTV footage emerged of him risking his life by jumping into the path of a speeding freight train to save his granddaughter.</Description>
        <MainBody>ApnaCircle
My Saved articles
Speaking with Nine News, acting inspector Paul Reynolds, summed-up the incident in just a few words: Baby  very lucky. Grandfather  just as lucky.
RELATED
A grandfather is being hailed a hero after dramatic CCTV footage emerged of him risking his life by jumping into the path of a speeding freight train to save his granddaughter.
The 62-year-old man arrived at Wentworthville station in Sydney, Australia, to pay for a ticket, Nine News reports.
Not realising the platform had a slight slant, his 18-month-old grandchild's buggy rolled away from him and crashed face-first onto the train tracks.
In a matter of seconds, he is seen rushing and jumping onto the tracks, lifting the child and stroller back up onto the platform to her grandmother and mother - only to realise that a freight train is racing towards him.
Watch the dramatic footage:
Unable to climb back up onto the platform himself, the train blows its horn in warning and the man can be seen racing for his life down the tracks.
He finally makes it to the top of the platform - with seconds to spare - as the train zooms by.
Speaking with Nine News, acting inspector Paul Reynolds, summed-up the incident in just a few words: "Baby - very lucky. Grandfather - just as lucky."
A statement issued by police after the accident said the toddler suffered cuts to her forehead and knees, as well as some swelling, but that she was quickly released from hospital.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:58:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece faces last chance to stay in euro as cash runs out</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e82b5b/sc/25/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CGreece0Efaces0Elast0Echance0Eto0Estay0Ein0Eeuro0Eas0Ecash0Eruns0Eout0Carticleshow0C479741440Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras had a final chance to present credible reform proposals to an emergency euro zone summit on Tuesday to persuade sceptical creditors to reopen aid talks before his country's banks run out of money.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Europe
Breaking News:
Greece faces last chance to stay in euro as cash runs out
Reuters | Jul 7, 2015, 05.28 PM IST
Euclid Tsakalotos: Greece's new finance minister
RELATED
Euclid Tsakalotos: Greece's new finance minister
BRUSSELS: Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras had a final chance to present credible reform proposals to an emergency euro zone summit on Tuesday to persuade sceptical creditors to reopen aid talks before his country's banks run out of money.
With Greek lenders down to their last few days of cash and the European Central Bank tightening the noose on their funding, Tsipras must convince the bloc's other 18 leaders, many of whom are exasperated with five years of crisis, to authorise negotiations fast on a new loan to rescue Greece.
READ ALSO: Eurozone leaders to hold emergency summit on Greece
But Greek officials said the leftist premier's proposals would not go far beyond a plan he sent to the euro zone last week before Greek voters overwhelmingly rejected the austerity terms of a bailout in a referendum on Sunday.
The leaders of Germany and France, the currency area's two main powers, said after conferring on Monday that the door was still open to a deal to save Greece from plunging into economic turmoil and ditching the euro.
Chancellor Angela Merkel, under pressure in Germany to cut Greece loose, made clear it was up to Tsipras to come up with convincing proposals after Athens spurned the tax rises, spending cuts and pension and labour reforms that were on the table before its 240 billion euro bailout expired last week.
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker, under suspicion from both sides for trying to broker a last-minute deal, told the European Parliament: "There are some in the European Union who openly or secretly are working to exclude Greece from the euro zone."
READ ALSO: Here's how Greece reached the brink of collapse
He did not name names but may have been referring to German finance minister Wolfgang Schaeuble, who has made no secret of his scepticism about Greece's fitness to stay in the euro and last week suggested a possible "temporary" exit.
From the Greek side, the key to making any deal politically acceptable will be to win a stronger commitment from Merkel and other lenders to reschedule Greece's giant debt burden, which the International Monetary Fund says is unsustainable.
Without some firmer pledge of debt relief, neither Greece nor the IMF is likely to accept a deal. But that may be more than Germany and its northern allies can swallow.
Schaeuble said on arrivial for a preparatory meeting of finance ministers that anyone who had read the EU treaty knew debt write-offs were forbidden in the euro zone. He did not rule out other forms of restructuring.
Asked about reports that Greece was seeking an immediate bridging loan of several billion euros, Italian finance minister Pier Carlo Padoan the creditors would listen to Greek requests.
"The door is open to negotiations, but there isn't much time left and the situation is urgent both for Greece and for Europe," French President Francois Hollande said in a joint media appearance with Merkel in Paris on Monday.
At stake at the emergency summit beginning at 6pm (1600 GMT) in Brussels is more than just the future of Greece, a nation of 11 million that makes up just 2 percent of the euro zone's economic output and population.
If Greek banks run out of money and the country has to print its own currency, it could mean a state leaving the euro for the first time since it was launched in 1999, creating a precedent and fuelling doubts about the long-term viability of an incomplete European monetary union.
"Even if it did not trigger a short-term domino effect, the integrity of the euro zone would come under fresh threat with each episode of political uncertainty within member countries," said Thibault Mercier, an analyst at BNP Paribas.
Even in France, the euro zone country most sympathetic to Athens, an opinion poll published on Tuesday showed one in two people want Greece to leave the euro zone.
reece says has no plans to issue parallel currency
Concessions unclear
Strengthened by the overwhelming 61.3 per cent 'No' vote in Sunday's referendum, the leftist Tsipras won the unprecedented support of all other Greek party leaders on Monday and replaced his abrasive finance minister Yanis Varoufakis with the soft-spoken negotiator Euclid Tsakalotos.
Tsakalotos entered the euro zone finance ministers' meeting without comment. Eurogroup chairman Jeroen Dijsselbloem said it was up to Greece to show a credible way forward.
"The pressure is especially on the Greeks, the banks are closed and the situation is difficult. I guess the Greek government has an interest in coming up with serious and credible solutions soon," Dijsselbloem told reporters.
In an intensive round of telephone diplomacy, Tsipras spoke to the heads of the ECB, the IMF and the European Commission, as well as Merkel, Russian President Vladimir Putin and US Treasury Secretary Jack Lew.
The United States, China and Japan all called for a solution in which Greece stays in the euro zone.
People stand in a queue to use ATM of a bank in Athens, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. (AP photo)
Tsipras gave little clue of what reform concessions he would make to try to convince deeply sceptical European leaders to lend Athens more money after five months of acrimonious and fruitless negotiations with his leftist administration.
Even with the country on the brink of economic collapse, Greek officials said the government was still seeking exceptions from its reform pledges for special interests.
Athens wants to keep a 30 per cent discount on value added tax on Greek islands and delay defence spending from cuts, which rightist junior coalition partners the Independent Greeks have called "red lines". It is also resisting raising VAT on restaurants to 23 per cent, and wants to wait until 2019 to phase out an income supplement for poorer pensioners, officials said.
Juncker told EU lawmakers he was working night and day to get negotiations reopened and chided the Greeks for their aggressive approach, saying it was unacceptable to accuse the EU of behaving like "terrorists", as Varoufakis did last week.
"Throwing Greece out of the monetary union or indeed the European Union is not something we want or indeed should want," the EU's chief executive said.
European Central Bank policymaker Ewald Nowotny suggested the bank might be able to provide some sort of bridge funding while Greece negotiated a longer-term conditional loan to see it over a crucial July 20 bond redemption to the ECB.
READ ALSO: Europe stands to lose more if we exit from eurozone
Greek newspapers dramatized the make-or-break nature of the Brussels showdown.
Centrist daily Ethnos headlined: "Time has run out for a solution before catastrophe," while the centre-right Eleftheros Typos said: "Tsipras' games finish at today's council: Time of crisis: deal or Grexit."
A clear majority of Greece's 18 partners favour a hard line at the summit, arguing that they too are democracies and that Greeks should not get easier money because they had rejected the austerity terms, casting further doubt on whether they would implement any reforms agreed now.
The ECB left unchanged its emergency liquidity lifeline for Greek banks but raised the discount it charges on collateral they present for funds - a measure banking sources said was largely symbolic since the total they could borrow was capped.
A bank closure in force since the talks collapsed was prolonged until Thursday at least, and cash withdrawals remain limited to 60 euros a day, with 20 euro notes running out.
The Athens stock exchange was also ordered closed for two days in Tuesday and Wednesday to throttle speculation.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Greek crisis,Greece crisis,Eurozone
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:50:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French special forces kill top al-Qaida militant in Mali: Army</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e7e4fb/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CFrench0Especial0Eforces0Ekill0Etop0Eal0EQaida0Emilitant0Ein0EMali0EArmy0Carticleshow0C479740A650Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>French special forces killed a leader of al-Qaida in Mali who was involved in the kidnapping of hostage Serge Lazarevic, but released from prison in exchange for the Frenchman's freedom, the army said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Members of the French GIGN special forces. (AFP photo for representative purpose only)
RELATED
PARIS: French special forces killed a leader of al-Qaida in Mali who was involved in the kidnapping of hostage Serge Lazarevic, but released from prison in exchange for the Frenchman's freedom, the army said on Tuesday.
During an operation on Sunday in the northeastern town of Kidal in Mali, "two terrorists were captured and a third, Ali Ag Wadossene, was killed. He is one of the operational leaders of AQIM (al-Qaida in the Islamic Maghreb) in the zone," said a French army statement.
Two special forces soldiers were injured in the operation in the troubled west African nation where France has had troops since 2013 when it launched an operation to oust Islamists who had seized northern Mali.
While never confirmed by France, Mali admitted in December that four prisoners were released in exchange for the freedom of Serge Lazarevic, who spent three years in the hands of Islamist militants.
Wadossene was also one of the instigators of the 2011 kidnapping of Lazarevic and fellow Frenchman Philippe Verdon who was found shot dead in 2013.
"He who dared kidnap a peaceful French citizen in our country" and killed a prison guard during his brief escape in June 2014 "could never, ever be pardoned of this fact and in his place I would prefer a thousand times over that I be kept in prison," Malian President Ibrahim Keita said at the time.
"It is not a denial of justice. We don't have the right to deprive a man of freedom for three years whose only mistake was to be in Mali."
Lazarevic was the last of more than a dozen French citizens taken captive in recent years, with those held in Africa reaching a high of 15 last year.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Serge Lazarevic,French Special Forces,Al-Qaida in the Islamic Maghreb,al-Qaida
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:21:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Syrian Kurds retake northern villages from Islamic State -monitor</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e78441/sc/11/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CSyrian0EKurds0Eretake0Enorthern0Evillages0Efrom0EIslamic0EState0Emonitor0Carticleshow0C479734860Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Syrian Kurdish fighters have recaptured more than 10 villages seized by Islamic State north of its de facto capital of Raqqa city, aided by US-led coalition air strikes, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights reported on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>A Syrian refugee carries mattresses as he re-enters in Syria from Turkey after Kurdish People's Protection Units took control of the area, in Tal Abyad town, Raqqa governorate, Syria. (AFP photo)
RELATED
BEIRUT: Syrian Kurdish fighters have recaptured more than 10 villages seized by Islamic State north of its de facto capital of Raqqa city, aided by US-led coalition air strikes, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights reported on Tuesday.
Intensified air strikes across northern Syria and clashes on the ground have killed at least 78 Islamic State fighters since Sunday night, the Britain-based Observatory said.
The strikes are some of the most sustained since they began in September, according to US officials who say they are aimed at curbing the militants' ability to operate out of Raqqa and to prevent it from fighting back against Kurdish advances.
But, on Tuesday, the ultra-hardline group was still in control of Ain Issa, the Observatory said. The town, 50 km (30 miles) north of Raqqa city, was seized by Islamic State fighters from the Kurdish YPG militia in an attack on Monday.
That attack on YPG-held areas followed an intensification of air strikes on Raqqa city over the weekend, which US defense secretary Ash Carter said on Monday were aimed at disrupting the militants' ability to respond to YPG advances north of Raqqa.
The YPG, a militia operating mostly in predominantly Kurdish areas of northern Syria towards the Turkish border, has emerged as the only significant partner in Syria for US-led alliance fighting to tackle Islamic State both there and in Iraq.
The Observatory, a British-based organisation reporting on Syria's four-year-old civil war, said the coalition had played an "effective role" in helping YPG forces recover 11 villages northeast of Ain Issa.
The YPG, backed by small Syrian rebel groups, has made significant gains against Islamic State in Raqqa province in recent weeks, seizing Tel Abyad at the Turkish border on June 15 before advancing south to Ain Issa.
The YPG captured Ain Issa on June 23.
While the YPG has shown itself to be a potent force in the fight against Islamic State, its effectiveness is seen to diminish beyond the predominantly Kurdish areas it was set up to defend in northern and northeastern Syria.
The United States aims to train and equip Syrian rebel fighters it deems politically moderate in order to fight Islamic State in Syria. But the Pentagon said on June 18 the effort was moving more slowly than expected.
US president Barack Obama said on Monday the United States would do more to train and equip "the moderate opposition".
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Syrian Observatory for Human Rights,Raqqa,Islamic State,Beirut
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:11:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Drone strikes target Islamic State fighters in eastern Afghanistan</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e7aca6/sc/11/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CDrone0Estrikes0Etarget0EIslamic0EState0Efighters0Ein0Eeastern0EAfghanistan0Carticleshow0C4797340A60Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Two drone strikes targeted militants loyal to Islamic State in Afghanistan on Tuesday, killing between 25 and 49 insurgents, according to differing estimates by Afghan and foreign officials.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Middle East
Breaking News:
Drone strikes target Islamic State fighters in eastern Afghanistan
Reuters | Jul 7, 2015, 04.41 PM IST
An increasing number of militants are pledging allegiance to the Islamic State in Afghanistan, making them a target of deadly strikes there by the US unmanned aircraft.
RELATED
KABUL: Two drone strikes targeted militants loyal to Islamic State in Afghanistan on Tuesday, killing between 25 and 49 insurgents, according to differing estimates by Afghan and foreign officials.
An increasing number of militants are pledging allegiance to the Islamic State in Afghanistan, making them a target of deadly strikes there by the US unmanned aircraft.
A total of 49 militants were killed in the strikes in the eastern province of Nangarhar, which targeted the village of Mamd Dara in Achin district, where the fighters routinely held gatherings, a spokesman for the governor said.
"The first drone strike took place at 12am on Monday... the second one happened at 02:00pm," said Ahmad Zia Abdulzai.
However, the foreign official, who asked not to be named in order to be able to speak freely, said the number of dead was believed to be closer to 25.
One of the most high profile figures to have been targeted in drone strikes so far was former Guantanamo Bay detainee Mullah Abdul Rauf, who had defected to Islamic State and was killed by a strike in southern Helmand province in February.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=US unmanned aircraft,Islamic State,Guantanamo Bay,Drone strike
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:58:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Berlin losing its financial clout</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e64d3f/sc/28/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cuk0CBerlin0Elosing0Eits0Efinancial0Eclout0Carticleshow0C47971780A0Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Berlin – the European city of power, influence and prestige, may be fast losing its financial clout</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World UK
Breaking News:
Berlin losing its financial clout
Kounteya Sinha Kounteya Sinha,TNN | Jul 7, 2015, 02.28 PM IST
Only 24% of Germanys billionaire population built their fortunes through their own entrepreneurship.
RELATED
LONDON: Berlin - the European city of power, influence and prestige, may be fast losing its financial clout.
In an interesting finding revealed on Tuesday, Germany's capital which once decided the fate of the world is now home to only two of Germany's billionaires who are jointly worth only eight billion dollars.
In comparison, Germany is home to 123 billionaires with a combined net worth of 368 billion euros or $413 billion.
Germany has the fourth largest billionaire population in the world - behind the United States (571 individuals), China (190) and the United Kingdom (130).
The findings show that there are no individuals from this top wealth tier located in five of the country's 16 states.
Wealth-X research released on Tuesday shows that no billionaires live in the state of Brandenburg - the eastern part of the country, Mecklenburg-Vorpommern - northern Germany and the landlocked states of Saxony, Saxony-Anhalt and Thuringia in central Germany.
The most interesting finding was that Berlin - the home of the German president and one of Europe's most powerful cities lies way below in the billionaire table.
The region of North Rhine-Westphalia - home to the cities of Bonn, Cologne, Dusseldorf, Monchengladbach, Duisburg, Essen and Dortmund seems to be Germany's billionaire capital. It is home to over 30 billionaires who are jointly worth $108 billion. It is also home to 27% of the country's wealth.
With a population of 18,033,000 inhabitants, North Rhine-Westphalia would be the fifth most populous country in Western Europe, after France, the UK, Italy and Spain.
This is followed by Bavaria which is home to the city of Munich. Bavaria is home to 27 of Germany's billionaires worth $ 88 billion. Baden-Wuerttemberg - home to the city of Stuttgart has 25 billionaires and is the third richest region. The city of Hamburg stands fourth with 16 billionaires jointly worth $50 billion.
The research shows that Germany has a smaller billionaire population than the United Kingdom, but the combined net worth of Germany's 123 wealthiest individuals is $413 billion - more than that of the United Kingdom's billionaire population.
Only 24% of Germany's billionaire population built their fortunes through their own entrepreneurship, while the rest of the country's billionaire population inherited a significant portion of their wealth. Globally, about 60% of the billionaire population is self-made. Manufacturing is the top industry for Germany's billionaires, with 14% creating their wealth in this sector.
The average age of Germany's billionaires is 65. Of the 123 billionaires in Germany, 22 are women. Only 6% of Germany's billionaires are born overseas, unlike in London where 53% are foreign-born. As much as 8% of Germany's billionaires have no formal education. German billionaires have a history of giving with 84% of Germany's billionaires are active philanthropists.
Wealth-X research said "despite having the third smallest general population in Germany, Hamburg ranks fourth in terms of the size of its billionaire population, with 16 individuals. In contrast, Lower Saxony has only five billionaires despite its population of eight million individuals."
Alex Story from Wealth X said "wealth is spread out across Germany with a few concentration points such as Cologne, Hamburg and Munich. Although German brands dominate the world like the Colossus did Rhodes harbour, German wealth is local and broadly German, as opposed to the UK where more than half the ultra-wealthy are foreign. What is also interesting is that the divide between East and West is stark. With the exception of Berlin, there are no billionaires in the East."
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=financial clout,berlin
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:44:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Key witness in Benazir Bhutto's killing turns hostile</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e52d0f/sc/40/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cpakistan0CKey0Ewitness0Ein0EBenazir0EBhuttos0Ekilling0Eturns0Ehostile0Carticleshow0C47970A0A650Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A key witness in Pakistan's former prime minister Benazir Bhutto's murder case has retracted from his earlier statement during cross examination before the Anti-Terrorism Court, media reported on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Pakistan
Breaking News:
Key witness in Benazir Bhutto's killing turns hostile
IANS | Jul 7, 2015, 12.14 PM IST
Pakistan's former prime minister Benazir Bhutto.
RELATED
ISLAMABAD: A key witness in Pakistan's former prime minister Benazir Bhutto's murder case has retracted from his earlier statement during cross examination before the Anti-Terrorism Court, media reported on Tuesday.
Prosecution witness, retired SSP Imtiaz, a key security official of Bhutto, on Monday withdrew his earlier statement before Judge Rai Mohammad Ayub Marth who is hearing the case.
Imtiaz told the ATC that a foolproof security cover was provided to Bhutto outside Liaqat Bagh where she was assassinated in a gun-and-bomb attack on December 27, 2007, Dawn reported.
He added all police officers were present on the scene to provide security to Bhutto.
Earlier, Imtiaz had claimed that Bhutto was killed due to inadequate security arrangements at Liaqat Bagh where the former chairperson of Pakistan People's Party (PPP) had delivered her last speech.
He had then said: "Had Benazir not appeared from sunroof of the vehicle, she might not have been killed."
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Liaqat Bagh,Benazir Bhutto's killing,Benazir Bhutto,anti-terrorism court
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 08:42:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thai military court releases 14 student protesters</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e51ad2/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CThai0Emilitary0Ecourt0Ereleases0E140Estudent0Eprotesters0Carticleshow0C479693170Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Thailand's military overthrew the previous democratic government last year after months of political unrest. The junta has since stifled dissent, barring political gatherings and debate.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Rest of World
Breaking News:
Thai military court releases 14 student protesters
Reuters | Jul 7, 2015, 11.12 AM IST
READ MORE united nations | Thai military court | European Union
RELATED
BANGKOK: A Thai military court on Tuesday released 14 students held for almost two weeks for holding anti-coup protests in defiance of a ban on public gatherings, but the charges against them have not been dropped.
There had been growing calls for their release, including from the United Nations and the European Union, and public shows of support for the 14 have taken place across Thailand and among the Thai diaspora over the past few days.
Thailand's military overthrew the previous democratic government last year after months of political unrest. The junta has since stifled dissent, barring political gatherings and debate.
"Police asked to extend the students' detention but today the court threw out that request," said Kisadang Nutjarat, a lawyer for the students.
"They have released the kids from prison today. There are no conditions and there was no bail," he said, adding that charges against the students had not been dropped.
The students, part of a coalition of university groups from around Thailand, held street demonstrations across Bangkok against the ruling junta, known as the National Council for Peace and Order.
They were arrested last month and charged with sedition.
Scores gathered outside a military court in Bangkok on Tuesday, shouting slogans and holding signs, to show their support for the students as 150 police officers stood guard nearby.
The 2014 coup ousted the government of Prime Minister Yingluck Shinawatra, Thailand's first female prime minister and a scion of the Shinawatra political family.
Thailand has been bitterly divided for a decade between supporters of Yingluck and her brother, former Prime Minister Thaksin Shinawatra, who was himself ousted by the army in 2006, and the traditional establishment in the capital and the south.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=united nations,Thai military court,European Union
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 08:26:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen kill 14 in northern Kenya attack: police</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e4c33c/sc/40/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Crest0Eof0Eworld0CGunmen0Ekill0E140Ein0Enorthern0EKenya0Eattack0Epolice0Carticleshow0C479690A660Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least 14 people were killed and 11 wounded on Tuesday when gunmen attacked a northern Kenyan village, close to the border with war-torn Somalia, police and Red Cross said.</Description>
        <MainBody>The attack occurred at a village near a large livestock market just outside the town in Nairobi, 14 people are dead. (Representative Photo)
RELATED
NAIROBI: At least 14 people were killed and 11 wounded on Tuesday when gunmen attacked a northern Kenyan village, close to the border with war-torn Somalia, police and Red Cross said.
There was no immediate claim of responsibility but Somali-led Shebab militants have carried out a string of attacks in the region, highlighting the insecurity that plagues parts of the country.
"The attack occurred at a village near a large livestock market just outside the town, 14 people are dead," a senior police officer said in the town of Mandera.
Top local official, county commissioner Alex Ole Nkoyo, confirmed the attack to Kenya's Daily Nation newspaper, while Kenya Red Cross said it had taken 11 wounded to hospital.
Kenya Red Cross said the gunmen attacked in the early hours of Tuesday morning, and were sending a medical airplane to evacuate the critically injured to the capital Nairobi. It has not given figures on the numbers killed.
Under pressure in Somalia where it has for years been fighting to overthrow the Western-backed government, the Al-Qaeda-linked Shebab is now increasingly targeting Kenya.
The Islamic militants have stepped up their attacks during Islam's holy fasting month of Ramadan.
In the group's deadliest attack to date four gunmen killed 148 people, mostly students, at a university in the Kenyan town of Garissa in early April.
In 2013, four Shebab gunmen killed at least 67 people in an assault on the Westgate mall in the capital Nairobi.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=red cross,nairobi,Kenyan village,Gunmen
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 07:37:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>HSBC fires 6 staff for mock Islamic State execution video</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e4aa9d/sc/6/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cuk0CHSBC0Efires0E60Estaff0Efor0Emock0EIslamic0EState0Eexecution0Evideo0Carticleshow0C479685140Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>British bank HSBC fired six staff after they filmed a mock Islamic State-style execution video during a team-building day out and posted footage online, a spokesman confirmed on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World UK
Breaking News:
HSBC fires 6 staff for mock Islamic State execution video
AFP | Jul 7, 2015, 10.07 AM IST
The bank described the video, showing staff members inbalaclavasholding a fake knife over a kneeling man in an orange jumpsuit, as "abhorrent".
RELATED
The bank described the video, showing staff members in balaclavas holding a fake knife over a kneeling man in an orange jumpsuit, as "abhorrent".
"We took the decision to sack the individuals involved," a spokesman for the bank said.
READ ALSO: Where will the so-called 'Islamic State' be a year from now?
The employees filmed the video on an HSBC team-building day at a go-karting centre in Birmingham and posted it on Instagram before deleting it, according to newspaper The Sun, which published the video on its website.
In the eight-second clip, a kneeling man in a jumpsuit is held by the shoulders while a colleague wields a coat hanger like a knife above him, as though preparing to cut off his head.
One staff member shouts "Allahu Akbar" (God is greater in Arabic) during the clip.
The staging recalls gruesome beheading videos released by the IS group, which has executed over 3,000 people in Syria in the year since it declared an Islamic "caliphate" in Syria and Iraq, according to the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:38:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World's oldest man dies in Japan, aged 112</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e419ae/sc/3/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Csouth0Easia0CWorlds0Eoldest0Eman0Edies0Ein0EJapan0Eaged0E1120Carticleshow0C479679820Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Sakari Momoi, who was recognised as the world's oldest man and credited healthy eating and getting plenty of sleep for his longevity, has died at the age of 112, Japanese media said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World South Asia
Breaking News:
World's oldest man dies in Japan, aged 112
Reuters | Jul 7, 2015, 09.08 AM IST
Momoi was born in an area of Fukushima hit hard by the tsunami and nuclear meltdowns of four years ago in February 1903.
RELATED
TOKYO: Sakari Momoi, who was recognised as the world's oldest man and credited healthy eating and getting plenty of sleep for his longevity, has died at the age of 112, Japanese media said on Tuesday.
Momoi was born in an area of Fukushima hit hard by the tsunami and nuclear meltdowns of four years ago in February 1903 - the year the teddy bear was introduced and Orville Wright carried out the first powered, heavier-than-air flight.
Named the world's oldest man in August 2014, Momoi, a former teacher who spent his days practising calligraphy and taking part in recreational activities at the hospital where he lived, donned a suit and tie for a ceremony to receive a plaque from Guinness World Records.
"I want to live two more years," he said at the time.
The world's oldest man is now likely to be Japanese Yasutaro Koide, born in March 1903, a little over a month younger than Momoi. US resident Susannah Mushatt Jones, 116, is the world's oldest person.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=world's oldest man,Sakari Momoi,Japan
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:33:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eurozone leaders to hold emergency summit on Greece</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e43bae/sc/25/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CEurozone0Eleaders0Eto0Ehold0Eemergency0Esummit0Eon0EGreece0Carticleshow0C47967940A0Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Eurozone leaders will hold an emergency summit in Brussels Tuesday to discuss the fallout from Greek voters' defiant "No" to further austerity measures, with the country's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras set to unveil new proposals for talks.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Europe
Breaking News:
Eurozone leaders to hold emergency summit on Greece
AFP | Jul 7, 2015, 09.03 AM IST
Germany and France presented a united front, calling on Tsipras to make "precise" proposals in a bid to revive bailout talks.
RELATED
BRUSSELS: Eurozone leaders will hold an emergency summit in Brussels Tuesday to discuss the fallout from Greek voters' defiant "No" to further austerity measures, with the country's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras set to unveil new proposals for talks.
As the country's economy gasps for air, with banks closed until at least Thursday on fears cash machines are running dry, Germany and France presented a united front, calling on Tsipras to make "precise" proposals in a bid to revive bailout talks.
"The door is open to discussions," said French President Francois Hollande Monday after crisis talks in Paris with German Chancellor Angela Merkel, held a day after Greeks rejected creditors' proposed terms for a new bailout in a historic referendum that was a political victory for Tsipras but plunged Europe into crisis.
"It is now up to the government of Alexis Tsipras to make serious, credible proposals so that this willingness to stay in the eurozone can translate into a lasting programme," Hollande said.
For her part, Merkel said the conditions for a new Greek rescue package "have not yet been met."
"And that is why we are now waiting for very precise proposals from the Greek prime minister, a programme that will allow Greece to return to prosperity," said Merkel, adding that eurozone countries had already shown "a lot of solidarity with Greece".
Without any proposals, the European digital commissioner Gunther Oettinger told German media, any new negotiations would be "meaningless".
Greece's new finance minister Euclid Tsakalotos said Greece wants "to continue the discussion".
Tsakalotos, who admitted to having "stage fright" upon assuming the post "not at the easiest moment in Greek history", was thrust into the spotlight Monday after the surprise resignation of his firebrand predecessor Yanis Varoufakis.
Positions among Greece's 18 partners in the eurozone vary ahead of Tuesday's summit.
Germany, Finland, Slovakia and the Baltic states have taken a notably harder line, whereas France, Italy and Spain have adopted a more conciliatory tone.
Despite its tougher approach to debt relief, Germany said Monday eurozone leaders should discuss humanitarian aid for a country fatigued by years of belt-tightening and chronic unemployment.
The White House urged all parties to seek a compromise that would keep Greece in the euro zone and place its economy "on a path toward debt sustainability but also economic growth".
The special summit is set to begin at 1600 GMT, after a meeting of eurozone finance ministers.
European Commission head Jean-Claude Juncker is also scheduled to speak, for the first time since the Greek vote, during a session of the European Parliament in Strasbourg in the morning.
In Sunday's plebiscite, Greeks voted by 61.31 percent to 38.69 percent to reject austerity terms in exchange for releasing more funds under an international bailout package.
The result dealt a body blow to the vision of European integration, but elated parties campaigning against austerity and loss of national sovereignty.
Athenians were set to awake yet again Tuesday to the grim reality of closed banks and more lines at cash machines to make their daily withdrawal limit of 60 euros ($67), as fears grew the ATMs could soon run dry.
"I'm very afraid we will get no cash anymore in the coming days. They really have to fix it, end of this week at the latest, otherwise it (the economy) is collapsing," said pharmacist Lambros Vritios.
The European Central Bank, which has been keeping Greek lenders afloat, meanwhile said it had decided to maintain emergency funding to Greek banks -- so-called Emergency Liquidity Assistance (ELA) -- at the level set on June 26, keeping it at roughly 89 billion euros.
But it noted that the key financial support can only be provided against sufficient collateral.
"In this context, the Governing Council decided today to adjust the haircuts on collateral accepted by the Bank of Greece for ELA," the statement said, a move that will make it more difficult to access ELA funds in the future.
Late on Monday, a Greek government source said Tsipras had spoken to ECB chief Mario Draghi to stress that Greek banks, closed last week to prevent a run on deposits, needed to reopen with assistance from the Frankfurt-based lender.
Tsipras also spoke to IMF chief Christine Lagarde "on the need to find a viable solution dealing with the real problems of the Greek economy," the source said.
Greece last week defaulted on a 1.5 billion euro repayment to the International Monetary Fund but Lagarde said her organisation was "ready to assist Greece if requested to do so".
Market reactions to the referendum were mostly muted, suggesting limited contagion from a possible "Grexit", or Greece's exit from the eurozone.
More than three-quarters of Greeks want to stay in the eurozone, according to surveys, but analysts are now putting the chances of a Grexit at "very high".
Tsipras, 40, insists that instead of Grexit, the creditors will now finally have to talk about restructuring Greece's massive 240 billion euro ($267 billion) debt.
The last EU-IMF bailout for Greece expired last Tuesday, despite Tsipras's appeals for it to be extended.
Greece was officially declared in default on Friday by the European Financial Stability Facility, which holds 144.6 billion euros ($160 billion) of Greek loans.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=greece,Eurozone leaders,Brussels
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:30:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US, France vow to rev up cooperation against IS</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e43bac/sc/25/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0CUS0EFrance0Evow0Eto0Erev0Eup0Ecooperation0Eagainst0EIS0Carticleshow0C479679180Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>US secretary of defence Ash Carter has met with French defence minister Jean-Yves Le Drian at the Pentagon, vowing to strengthen cooperation between the two countries with the aim to fight against the Islamic State (IS).</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World US
Breaking News:
US, France vow to rev up cooperation against IS
IANS | Jul 7, 2015, 09.00 AM IST
US defense secretary Ash Carterand France's LeDrianheld a joint news conference on Monday after their meeting, which focused on discussing efforts in fighting against IS
RELATED
WASHINGTON: US secretary of defence Ash Carter has met with French defence minister Jean-Yves Le Drian at the Pentagon, vowing to strengthen cooperation between the two countries with the aim to fight against the Islamic State (IS).
Carter and Le Drian also held a joint news conference on Monday after their meeting, which focused on discussing efforts in fighting against IS, Xinhua reported.
Carter commended France for its commitment in the fight to deliver a lasting defeat to IS, a campaign that both sides agreed requires a sustained long-term effort.
Earlier this year, France deployed its aircraft carrier Charles de Gaulle to the Persian Gulf to support counter-IS airstrikes, according to Carter.
The French air force continues to play a critical role after being the first to join the US in striking IS targets in Iraq, the US defence chief added.
US forces would continue to support France in efforts with airlift and aerial-refueling capabilities, Carter pledged, stressing the partnership between France and the United States has long been instrumental to building lasting peace and prosperity.
Le Drian said that IS was no longer a terrorist group, but rather has morphed into a "terrorist army". That change means IS has to be fought on multiple fronts, he said. IS now has the capability to act as a classical army, but also to have operations in urban areas and terroristic operations. "They can do all three at the same time".
Le Drian also defended the coalition strategy against IS. "The repetition of strikes in Iraq allowed us to stabilise: not to win, but to stabilize the situation," said the French defence minister, reiterating "It is a long-term job".
According to a Pentagon statement, the two defence officials have also discussed how to further enhance intelligence sharing between two militaries for counterterrorism operations.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=US Secretary of Defence,French defence minister Jean-Yves Le Drian,Ash Carter
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:01:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wait for Hindu marriage law in Pakistan just got longer</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e38f50/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cpakistan0CWait0Efor0EHindu0Emarriage0Elaw0Ein0EPakistan0Ejust0Egot0Elonger0Carticleshow0C479672180Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The minority Hindu community in Pakistan will have to wait more before they can register their marriages as the lawmakers on Monday deferred till July 13 the final approval of the Islamic country's first Hindu marriage law.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Pakistan
Breaking News:
Wait for Hindu marriage law in Pakistan just got longer
PTI | Jul 7, 2015, 06.31 AM IST
The minority Hindu community in Pakistan will have to wait more before they can register their marriages as the lawmakers on Monday deferred till July 13 the final approval of the Islamic country's first Hindu marriage law. (Representative image)
RELATED
ISLAMABAD: The minority Hindu community in Pakistan will have to wait more before they can register their marriages as the lawmakers on Monday deferred till July 13 the final approval of the Islamic country's first Hindu marriage law.
The Hindus, who constitute 1.6% of Pakistan's total population, have been struggling to get a specific marriage law since the country was founded in 1947. Hindu marriages can not be legalized or registered in Pakistan in absence of such a law. The National Assembly Standing Committee on Law, Justice and Human Rights headed by Chaudhry Muhammad Bashir Virk met in Islamabad to discuss and finalize a set of laws to formalize and facilitate registration of Hindu marriages.
The 2014 bill was jointly presented in the parliament last year by Ramesh Lal of opposition Pakistan People's Party (PPP) and Dr Darshan of ruling Pakistan Muslim League-Nawaz (PML-N).
A separate but similar government law known as 'The Hindu Marriage Bill, 2015' had been tabled in the parliament by law minister Pervaiz Rashid in March this year.
The two bills will establish rules and regulation for registration of marriage and di vorce for Pakistani Hindus, as currently in the absence of such a law, Hindus in the country do not even have a legal proof of marriage.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Pakistan Muslim League,Islamabad,Hindu marriage law
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:55:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Germany sizzles at 40.3°C, hottest temperature since 1881</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e38d91/sc/31/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Ceurope0CGermany0Esizzles0Eat0E40A0E3C0Ehottest0Etemperature0Esince0E18810Carticleshow0C4796720A90Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The heat wave blanketing wide parts of Europe has pushed temperatures in Germany to the highest since recordings began in 1881.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Europe
Breaking News:
Germany sizzles at 40.3C, hottest temperature since 1881
Bloomberg | Jul 7, 2015, 06.25 AM IST
People dive into the Mediterranean sea in Nice, southeastern France, where temperature rose to 34 degree Celcius on Sunday. (AP photo)
RELATED
The heat wave blanketing wide parts of Europe has pushed temperatures in Germany to the highest since recordings began in 1881.
The town of Kitzingen in Bavaria recorded a temperature of 40.3 Celsius on Sunday afternoon, beating the previous record of 40.2C last reached in 2003, the country's DWD weather service said on Monday .
"The number of these heat waves has strongly increased in the past 25 years, and it's exactly what we expect to happen because of climate change," Uwe Kirsche, a spokesman for DWD, said by phone. "Society will have to learn how to handle more of these events." The heat boosted power demand, lifting the cost of electricity for nextday delivery on the European Energy Exchange 32% to 49.02 a megawatt-hour, the highest since December 8.
Europe has seen sweltering hot weather in the past week, with a temperature record smashed in the UK and the wheat crop affected in France. Scientists say Europe faces more severe and extended periods of droughts because of man-made climate change. High temperatures in 2003 resulted in over 14,000 deaths in France and 7,500 in Germany, and caused losses in billions for Europe's agriculture and forest industries.
Germany after the 2003 heat wave introduced a warning system that sends out heat alerts to institutions like nursing homes and schools, Kirsche said.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=United Kingdom,Kitzingen,France
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:57:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>No change for now in Cuba migration policy: US</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e2fd77/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0CNo0Echange0Efor0Enow0Ein0ECuba0Emigration0Epolicy0EUS0Carticleshow0C479664570Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Washington has no current plans to modify its Cuban migration rules after the Cold War foes announced the re-establishment of diplomatic ties from July 20, officials said on Monday.</Description>
        <MainBody>(Image courtesy: Google Maps)
RELATED
WASHINGTON: Washington has no current plans to modify its Cuban migration rules after the Cold War foes announced the re-establishment of diplomatic ties from July 20, officials said on Monday.
A 1966 law gives the US attorney general the discretion to offer any citizen of Cuba admission and permanent residence in the US after spending one year in the country, with no yearly quota on immigrants.
"The administration has no plans to alter current migration policy, including the Cuban Adjustment Act," the State Department said in a statement.
According to a fact sheet, the United States "continues to support safe, legal and orderly migration from Cuba," as well as "the full implementation of the existing migration accords" with the Communist-ruled island nation.
Cuban migration to US shores has surged since the historic bilateral thaw announced in mid-December, amid uncertainty over the future of the migration policy.
US figures show the number of Cuban migrants doubled in the first three months of 2015 compared to the same period last year.
As for the economic restrictions, the 1962 "embargo on Cuba is still in place and legislative action is required to lift it," the State Department noted.
The current rules on travel to Cuba by US citizens also remain in effect, it said, noting the US Treasury Department still licenses 12 categories of authorized travel to Cuba.
Washington and Havana last week announced their decision to restore diplomatic ties that had been frozen for more than half a century.
Their respective embassies are due to open on July 20.
"Normalizing relations is a long, complex process that will require continued interaction and dialogue between our two governments," the State Department said.
"We will have areas of cooperation with the Cubans, and we will continue to have differences."
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=united states,Department of State,Cuba
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:53:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hoax letter to Russian media seeks to tie US senator to Ukraine</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e2c472/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cus0CHoax0Eletter0Eto0ERussian0Emedia0Eseeks0Eto0Etie0EUS0Esenator0Eto0EUkraine0Carticleshow0C479664350Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A forger sent a hoax letter to Russian media in an apparent bid to convince journalists that a senior US lawmaker, senator Richard Durbin, was trying to tell Ukrainian Prime Minister Arseny Yatsenyuk how to run his government, Durbin's office said on Monday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World US
Breaking News:
Hoax letter to Russian media seeks to tie US senator to Ukraine
Reuters | Jul 7, 2015, 03.23 AM IST
Ukrainian Prime Minister Arseniy Yatsenyuk.
RELATED
WASHINGTON: A forger sent a hoax letter to Russian media in an apparent bid to convince journalists that a senior US lawmaker, senator Richard Durbin, was trying to tell Ukrainian Prime Minister Arseny Yatsenyuk how to run his government, Durbin's office said on Monday.
The hoaxer wrote to Yatsenyuk on what appeared to be US senate letterhead, claiming to be Durbin, the number two Democrat in the senate, a leading American voice on Ukraine-related issues.
Ben Marter, a spokesman for Durbin, said his office had told the CIA and the FBI about the letter. Marter said he first learned about it when he was contacted by Russian state-owned media asking for comment.
The forged letter was on paper that resembled US senate stationery, but with Durbin's title wrong. The Illinois lawmaker is assistant Democratic leader, but the forged letter called him "Assistant Minority Leader."
It suggested that Yatsenyuk "invest every effort" to keep some cabinet members in place, but said the US senate feels that others do not have the qualities necessary for their jobs.
"Senator Durbin has been outspoken in his criticism of Russia's invasion of Ukraine and supportive of Ukrainian efforts to reform their economy and defend their nation. This letter is a forgery and was obviously written by somebody with a tenuous grasp of the English language," Marter said.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=United States Senate,united states,Senator,Arseny Yatsenyuk
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:49:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IS abducts 111 Iraqi kids to be trained as terrorists</title>
        <Link>http://timesofindia.feedsportal.com/c/33039/f/533917/s/47e2c474/sc/7/l/0Ltimesofindia0Bindiatimes0N0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0CIS0Eabducts0E1110EIraqi0Ekids0Eto0Ebe0Etrained0Eas0Eterrorists0Carticleshow0C479664190Bcms/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Islamic State terrorists have abducted 111 school children from various districts of the northern Iraqi city of Mosul to use them in terrorist moves, a media report said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>You are here: Home  World Middle East
Breaking News:
IS abducts 111 Iraqi kids to be trained as terrorists
IANS | Jul 7, 2015, 03.19 AM IST
The abducted children, mostly aged between 10-15 years, have been transferred to the IS terrorist group's educational and militarycentresfor brainwashing.
RELATED
BAGHDAD: Islamic State terrorists have abducted 111 school children from various districts of the northern Iraqi city of Mosul to use them in terrorist moves, a media report said on Tuesday.
The abducted children, mostly aged between 10-15 years, have been transferred to the IS terrorist group's educational and military centres for brainwashing, Iraq's Arabic news channel Al Sumaria quoted Iraqi Kurdistan's Democrat Party, spokesperson Saeed Mamuzini as saying.
He added that the IS terrorists also arrested 78 men who protested against the abduction of their children.
The Kurdish official noted that the militants have kidnapped 1,420 Iraqi children since the capture of the country's second city over a year ago and forced them to receive military training, so that IS could use them in terrorist and intelligence operations.
Mamuzini previously said that IS terrorists had executed 15 of its own militants after facing a defeat in Bashiqa town northeast of Mosul, adding they were killed by children trained by the terrorist group.
Iraqi local and security officials have said that IS terrorists abducted 500 children in the eastern province of Diyala and western province of al-Anbar.
The IS started its campaign of terror in Iraq in early June 2014. The heavily-armed militants took control of Mosul before sweeping through parts of the country's Sunni Arab heartland.
The terrorists have been carrying out horrific acts of violence against all Iraqi communities such as Shias, Sunnis, Kurds and Christians.
http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/followceleb.cms?alias=Saeed Mamuzini,Iraq,Democrat Party spokesperson
Stay updated on the go with Times of India News App. Click here to download it for your device.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
