<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="tvnz">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As it happened: The Sharks have no answer to Highlanders fire power</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/rugby-news/happened-sharks-have-no-answer-highlanders-fire-power-6305778?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The Highlanders back to their best handing the Sharks a thumping, final score: 48-15.</Description>
        <MainBody>The Highlanders have dominated the Sharks winning 48-15.
FULLTIME
77 min - HIG 48-15 SHA
TRY! Elliot Dixon has crossed over to score - the Highlanders are proving to be unstoppable at this point.
71 min - HIG 43-15 SHA
TRY!Bismarck du Plessis has scored off a rolling maul.
 The Highlanders (@Highlanders) May 1, 2015

66 min - HIG 43-10 SHA
Advertisement
TRY!Brendon Edmonds has scored a brilliant team try. The Highlanders have marched their way from inside their own 22 to score through their reserve front rower Edmonds.
59 min - HIG 36-10 SHA
TRY! Aaron Smith has dotted over to score a wonderful Highlanders try off the great offload of Highlanders second-five Richard Buckman.
55 min - HIG 31-10 SHA
TRY! Mark Reddish has come up with an awesome try as he grounded the ball inside the in goal beating Sharks' halfbackCobus Reinach.
50 min - HIG 24-10 SHA
Ben Smith has been taken off the field for a concussion test. Marty Banks has come on as his replacement.
MASSIVE SCRUM FROM THE HIGHLANDERS! Forcing the penalty against the feed! #HIGvSHA
 The Highlanders (@Highlanders) May 1, 2015

41 min - HIG 24-10 SHA
Highlanders receive the restart.
HALFTIME
38 min - HIG 24-10 SHA
TRY!Patrick Osborne has dived over in the corner to score a fantastic team try. Lima Sopoaga has thrown a crazy pass to put Osborne over in the corner. Again a quick darting run from Aaron Smith started the attack which lead to Osbourne's try.
34 min - HIG 17-10 SHA
TRY!Waisake Naholo has scored a magnificent try from a cross field kick by Lima Sopoaga. It all started from a quick tap off a penalty by none other than All Blacks halfback Aaron Smith. The Highlanders have struck back in impressive style.
30 min - HIG 10-10 SHA
TRY! Sharks prop Tendai Mtawarira has scored from some smart pick and go's.
24 min - HIG 10-3 SHA
The Highlanders have been penalised for being offside. The Sharks five-eighthFred Zeilinga has converted the penalty.
20 min - HIG 10-0 SHA
The Sharks have been penalised for hands in the ruck right out in front of the posts. The Sharks are struggling to contain the illusive attack of the Highlanders. Sopoaga has slotted the penalty.
16 min - HIG 7-0 SHA
Sopoaga has put in another brilliant kick making the Sharks work hard to get out of their 22. The return of the Highlanders All Blacks have really shown some marvelous attacking flair.
13 min - HIG 7-0 SHA
Aaron Smith has thrown a fantastic dummy in the middle of the park to split open the Sharks' defense but was unable to get his pass out to speedster Waisake Naholo.
10 min - HIG 7-0 SHA
Lima Sopoaga plucked a difficult ball from Patrick Osbourne's pass and managed to get boot to ball to put the Highlanders in good position inside the Sharks 22.
4 min - HIG 7-0 SHA
TRY! Gareth Evans has scored - Highlanders scored out wide with some nice crisp passing. Nasi Manu's brilliant tip on to blindside flanker Evans has helped the Highlanders score their first-five pointer of the match. Aaron Smith's return to the side has really lifted the Highlanders attacking play.
1min - HIG 0-0 SHA
Kick-off was at 7:35pm (NZT).
Pre-game
 The Highlanders (@Highlanders) May 1, 2015

 Super Rugby (@SuperRugbyNZ) May 1, 2015

 Super Rugby (@SuperRugbyNZ) May 1, 2015

TEAMS:
Highlanders: 1. Kane Hames, 2. Liam Coltman, 3. Josh Hohneck, 4. Tom Franklin, 5. Mark Reddish, 6. Gareth Evans, 7. Dan Pryor, 8. Nasi Manu (co-Captain), 9. Aaron Smith, 10. Lima Sopoaga, 11. Patrick Osborne, 12. Richard Buckman, 13. Malakai Fekitoa, 14. Waisake Naholo, 15. Ben Smith (co-Captain)
Reserves: 16. Ash Dixon, 17. Brendon Edmonds, 18. Pingi Tala'apitaga, 19. Joe Latta, 20. Elliot Dixon, 21. Fumiaki Tanaka, 22. Marty Banks, 23. Jason Emery
Sharks: 15. Odwa Ndungane, 14. S'bura Sithole, 13. JP Pietersen, 12. Andre Esterhuizen, 11. Lwazi Mvovo, 10. Fred Zeilinga, 9. Cobus Reinach, 8. Willem Alberts, 7. Renaldo Bothma, 6. Marcell Coetzee, 5. Marco Wentzel (Captain), 4. Stephan Lewies, 3. Lourens Adriaanse, 2. Bismarck du Plessis, 1. Tendai Mtawarira
Reserves: 16. Franco Marais, 17. Dale Chadwick, 18. Matt Stevens, 19. Mouritz Botha, 20. Etienne Oosthuizen, 21. Conrad Hoffmann, 22. Lionel Cronje, 23. Waylon Murray
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:49:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Highlanders thrash the Sharks in Dunedin</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/rugby-news/highlanders-thrash-sharks-in-dunedin-6305825?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Highlanders dismantle the Sharks with ease in their Super Rugby clash at Forsyth Barr Stadium</Description>
        <MainBody>Highlanders thrash the Sharks in Dunedin
Published: 9:47PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Highlanders' winger Patrick Osborne - Source: Photosport
Brendon Edmonds celebrates a brilliant team try. - Source: Sky Sport
Related
The return of Ben Smith, Malakai Fekitoa and Aaron Smith to the Highlanders sparked the Otago side to life as they dismantled the Sharks with ease in their Super Rugby clash at Forsyth Barr Stadium tonight winning 48-15.
Highlanders blindside flanker Gareth Evans scored the Highlanders' first try off Nasi Manu's brilliant tip on.
Sharks prop Tendai Mtawarira scored from some smart pick and go's from the South African side in the 30th minute.
Both Fijian wingers Waisake Naholo and Patrick Osborne crossed in the later stages of the first half for the Highlanders from some great build up work from Aaron Smith and Lima Sopoaga.
The Highlanders went into the break leading 24-10.
The Highlanders continued to score through their forwards as Mark Reddish showed great determination to dive on a loose ball in the Sharks' in-goal to score in the 55th minute.
Aaron Smith and Brandon Edmonds crossed the white chalk later in the second half as the Sharks couldn't stop the Highlanders offloads and dangerous attack in open play.
All Blacks halfback Smith seemed somewhat rejuvenated from his week off, cutting through the Sharks' defence at will.
The Sharks had no answer to the brilliant attacking flair of the Highlanders as they continued to leak points and the New Zealand side continued their onslaught.
Bismarck du Plessis scored off a rolling maul in the 71st minute but it was a little too late.
Elliot Dixon put the icing on the cake for the Highlanders as he crossed over in the dying minutes of the match from some excellent forward build up play.
The Highlanders dominated the Sharks, winning 48-15.
Sopoaga was instrumental, providing some brilliant kicks and passes to set up his team mates with scoring opportunities.
Advertisement
The Highlanders will travel to South Africa to take on the Lions at Ellis Park in Johannesburg next week.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:38:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Strong 7.1 earthquake measured in Papua New Guinea</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/strong-7-1-earthquake-measured-in-papua-new-guinea-6305814?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A severe earthquake struck Papua New Guinea this evening, prompting a short-lived tsunami warning.</Description>
        <MainBody>Strong 7.1 earthquake measured in Papua New Guinea
Published: 8:38PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

A map showing the epicentres of two earthquakes which struck in Papua New Guinea - Source: USGS
Related
Added 02:54 Papua New Guinea jolted by 6.7 quake
A severe earthquake struck Papua New Guinea this evening, prompting a short-lived tsunami warning.
The magnitude-7.1 shake struck at 6.06pm local time (8.06pm NZT) at a depth of 54km, 110km SSW of Kokopo on the island of New Britain, according to the U.S. Geological Survey.
The Pacific Tsunami Warning Centre issued an alert that a damaging tsunmai was possible within 300km of the epicentre, but the warning was cancelled a few minutes later.
The 7.1 earthquake followed a magnitude-6.7 shake very closeby around 22 hours beforehand.
Papua New Guinea sits on the 'Ring of Fire', where the Australian and Pacific tectonic plates collide. A high number of earthquakes are recorded in the country.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Leicester manager Nigel Pearson calls reporter 'daft' and 'stupid'</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/football-news/leicester-manager-nigel-pearson-calls-reporter-daft-and-stupid-6305769?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>For a man who once repelled a pack of vicious dogs while hiking in the Carpathian Mountains, handling an innocuous question in a news conference should have been easy for the manager of English soccer club Leicester</Description>
        <MainBody>Leicester manager Nigel Pearson calls reporter 'daft' and 'stupid'
Published: 6:40PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: AP
Leicester City's manager Nigel Pearson - Source: Getty Images
Related
Chelsea players dominate PFA Team of the Year
For a man who once repelled a pack of vicious dogs while hiking in the Carpathian Mountains, handling an innocuous question in a news conference should have been easy for the manager of English soccer club Leicester.
Instead, a lengthy rant at a reporter left Nigel Pearson under more scrutiny in a season in which the normally unflappable coach has lost his cool several times while his team struggles to avoid relegation.
After Leicester lost to Chelsea in the Premier League on Wednesday, Pearson took issue when he was asked to clarify his view that his team had received "criticism and negativity" this season.
In an uncomfortable verbal altercation, Pearson used an expletive, called the reporter "daft" and "stupid," and came out with a line that is generating plenty of buzz on social media.
"I think you are an ostrich," Pearson said, in his typically measured tone as he twirled on his chair. "Your head must be in the sand. Is your head in the sand? Are you flexible enough to get your head in the sand? My suspicion would be no . I can, you can't."
Before walking out of the news conference, Pearson made his feelings known about the reporter.
"You are either being very, very silly or you are being absolutely stupid," Pearson said. "One of the two, because for you to ask that question... I am sorry, son, you are daft."
Pearson also made fun of the reporter as he stumbled while attempting a response to the coach.
"What's 'erm'?" Pearson said.
Advertisement
Pearson apologized to the reporter on Thursday - "I hope it doesn't ruin our relationship," he said at the start of another news conference - and blamed his outburst on losing and then being "wheeled out straight after the game" with emotions still high.
Still, the altercation is the talk of the Premier League, to some extent overshadowing the 3-1 victory for Chelsea that moved the team to within three points of winning the title.
After walking into a room of reporters Thursday ahead of his weekly news conference, West Ham manager Sam Allardyce said jokingly: "Are there any ostriches in?"
"When you are down there dealing with the pressures that come upon in terms of staying in the Premier League, I think it is a huge pressure for everybody to continue to work under that situation and come through it," Allardyce said in defense of Pearson. "People have been talking about bullying and stuff like that - what a load of rubbish. It's an outburst. Simple as that, plain and simple."
Pearson has made plenty of headlines this season, mainly for the wrong reasons.
In December, he was handed a one-match ban for using abusive language in an exchange with a Leicester fan during a match. In February, Pearson placed his hands around the neck of Crystal Palace midfielder James McArthur after the player had slid off the field into the technical area and collided with Pearson during a game.
That incident came at a time when there was fierce speculation about his job, but Pearson remained in his position and four straight wins in April has lifted Leicester out of the Premier League's relegation zone. With four games left, Leicester is a point above the bottom three.
Pearson has a reputation as a calm, plain-speaking man. He is also seen as a tough guy.
In an interview with The Daily Telegraph newspaper last year, he recounted a story from a walking holiday in the Carpathian Mountains in Romania. While walking alone, he was confronted by a pack of dogs, who often attack hikers and protect their owners' sheep.
Pearson says he fended them off with his walking pole before diving into stinging nettles. They then attacked him again but he managed to escape.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Protests off as McDonald's agrees to end zero hour contracts</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/business-news/protests-off-mcdonald-s-agrees-end-zero-hour-contracts-6305484?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Unite union says the agreement will be welcomed by tens of thousands of workers in the fast food industry.</Description>
        <MainBody>Protests off as McDonald's agrees to end zero hour contracts
Published: 6:26AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Agreement on controversial zero-hour contracts at McDonalds (0:25)
Protests against McDonald's that were planned for today have been scrapped after a late-night agreement to end zero hour contracts.
Unite union director Mike Treen says it's a historic agreement and will be welcomed by tens of thousands in the fast food industry.
McDonald's now says that from July staff will have a guaranteed minimum number of hours rostered each week.
"This is the culmination of a decade long campaign for secure hours...it represents a fundamental shift in the employment relationship of the most vulnerable workers in the country," says Mr Treen.
"Now all the of the major fast food chains have committed to ending zero hours."
A spokesperson says McDonald's has been working on details around security of hours since April 13 and from October 1 all employees will be offered 80% security of hours, up to a 32 hour weekly cap, based on the average of the previous fixed quarterly worked hours.
The union is now calling on the Government to turn the decision into law for other workers in the country.
The Government has agreed to walk away from the contracts, but says it's proving more difficult than first thought.
"It's very important to make sure that in creating a policy environment that is fair to everyone, we don't have unintended consequences. There are a number of tricky loop holes," Workplace Relations Minister, Michael Woodhouse said.
Mr Woodhouse says he is hoping to put forward a bill to cabinet in the next few weeks, which could become law by next year.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Auckland's Queen Street's only book store, Whitcoulls, to close</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/auckland-s-queen-street-only-book-store-whitcoulls-close-6305672?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The three-storey heritage building will be refitted and reopened as a Farmers store.</Description>
        <MainBody>Auckland's Queen Street's only book store, Whitcoulls, to close
Published: 12:50PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News

Whitcoulls Christmas statue - Source: Seven Sharp
Bookseller Whitcoulls' flagship store, the only book shop on Queen Street, will close to make way for a Farmers store.
The chief financial officer of the James Pascoe Group, which owns both Whitcoulls and Farmers, confirmed the store will shut at the end of June.
Kevin Turner says the three-storey heritage building will be refitted and reopened as a Farmers department store by Labour Weekend in October. Farmers previously had a store on Queen St but closed it last year at the end of its lease.
Mr Turner told ONE News that with $40 million of improvements to Queen Street's retail area including the opening of a TopShop opposite the Whitcoulls store, it was the right time to move Farmers into the heritage building on the corner of Queen and Victoria Streets.
"We know that with Queen St there are a lot of people knocking on the door, and the problem is there's not really the vacancies for a number of international retailers wanting to come here," says Heart of the City'sTania loveridge.
Those international retailers are rumoured to be Marks and Spencer, Apple, and clothing retailers H&amp;M and Zara.
A Whitcoulls closing-down sale will begin next week. Whitcoulls also has a store in the Downtown Mall in Auckland.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sofia Vergara's ex-fiancé demands she give him her frozen embryos</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/entertainment-news/sofia-vergara-s-ex-fianc-demands-she-give-him-her-frozen-embryos-6305761?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Sofia Vergara's ex-fiancé's has demanded that she give him two frozen embryos they created - referring to them as "our girls".</Description>
        <MainBody>
Sofia Vergara - Source: BANG Showbiz
Sofia Vergara's ex-fianc's demands that she give him two frozen embryos they created - referring to them as "our girls" - highlights the wider legal and ethical issues surrounding frozen embryos created by in-vitro fertilization.
Businessman Nick Loeb wrote on Wednesday on NYTimes.com that he has sued the "Modern Family" star for the embryos because he longs to become a parent and doesn't want the "two lives" they created to "be destroyed or sit in a freezer until the end of time."
He said he "push(ed) for children" after he and Vergara got engaged in 2012, and said the couple agreed the following year to try in vitro fertilization and a surrogate to have children. Loeb wrote that they signed a form stating that any embryos they created could only be brought to term if both of them agreed. He said the form didn't specifically say, as California law requires, what would happen to the embryos if they separated.
He is seeking to have the document voided. He and Vergara split in 2014. She is now dating actor Joe Manganiello.
Loeb said Vergara's lawyer has told reporters that she wants to keep the embryos frozen indefinitely. Attorney Fred Silberberg declined to make additional comments Thursday.
At the Hollywood premiere of her new movie, "Hot Pursuit," on Thursday night, Vergara was asked if she had anything to say about Loeb's article. "No," she replied and then walked off. A publicist for Vergara did not respond to earlier requests for comment.
Courts have wrangled over what to do with frozen fertilized embryos since at least the early 1990s. But with laws that cover contracts between couples varying by state, consensus is still emerging - and judges are reluctant to compel either a man or woman to become a parent against their will, experts say.
Advertisement
"If I am the judge I don't know what I would do. I certainly would put some emphasis on the contract because that was the course they chose to pursue," said Charles Kindregan, Jr., co-author of "Assisted Reproductive Technology: A Lawyer's Guide to Emerging Law &amp; Science," when asked about the Vergara case. "The question would be for me: Can I force this woman to become a mother?"
Many judges have looked to a 1992 Tennessee case between a woman in a divorcing couple who sought custody of frozen embryos, and a husband who wanted them destroyed. The state Supreme Court eventually ruled in his favor, reasoning that the embryos had to be treated differently from property that could be divided equitably, or children, whose custody is awarded based on what is best for them.
But the Tennessee court also left an opening, ruling that if embryos were the only means by which the person seeking them could become a parent, that should carry some legal weight, said Steven H. Snyder, a Maple Grove, Minnesota, attorney specializing in law covering fertility and assisted reproductive technology.
In 2012, the Pennsylvania Supreme Court employed just such a test, awarding frozen pre-embryos to a woman who claimed she was incapable of having children after her treatment for cancer.
In Vergara's case, her former fianc wrote that he has offered "to pay for all expenses to carry our girls to term and raise them."
"If she did not wish to share custody," he wrote, "I would take on full parenting responsibilities and agree to have her declared an egg donor."
That isn't likely sway a judge, wary of depriving a child of support from one parent, should the other change his mind or become unable to provide support, Snyder said.
"That's a wonderful promise," he said, "that can't be kept."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Moments of joy in Nepal as two are rescued five days after quake</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/moments-joy-in-nepal-two-rescued-five-days-after-quake-6305756?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A 15-year-old boy and a 20-something-year-old girl were pulled out of rubble.</Description>
        <MainBody>Moments of joy in Nepal as two are rescued five days after quake
Published: 6:20PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: AP
New video captures tourists' panic as temple crumbles in Nepal quake (0:27)
The 15-year-old boy had been buried alive for five days, listening to bulldozers clearing mountains of debris, fearful the incessant aftershocks might collapse the darkened crevice he was trapped in.
And then, "all of the sudden I saw light," Pempa Tamang said, recounting the moment today he was pulled from a hole at the bottom of what was once a seven-story building in Kathmandu.
Tamang did not know whether he was alive or dead. "I thought I was hallucinating," he said.
The improbable rescue was an uplifting moment in Nepal, which has been overwhelmed by death and destruction since the 7.8-magnitude earthquake hit. Today, the government said the toll from the tremor, the most powerful recorded since 1934, had risen to 6,198 dead.
After night fell, police reported another dramatic rescue: A woman in her 20s, Krishna Devi Khadka, was pulled from a building in the same neighborhood as Tamang near Kathmandu's main bus terminal, according to an officer who spoke on condition of anonymity because he wasn't authorized to talk to the media.
"Life has become a struggle to survive. It gives us hope," Hans Raj Joshi said after watching Tamang's rescue. "We thought they were only bringing out the dead. It's hard to believe people are still alive."
When Tamang was finally extricated, rescue workers inserted an IV in his arm, propped him onto a yellow plastic stretcher - the same kind that has helped convey countless dead - and carried him through the ruins on their shoulders as if he was a newly crowned king.
Lines of police stood on both sides, keeping back mobs of bystanders and journalists. A dazed Tamang, wearing a dark shirt with the New York Yankees logo and the words "New York Authentic," blinked at the bright sky.
When the procession turned a corner and entered the main road outside, there came a sound Kathmandu hadn't heard in days: the jubilant cheers of thousands of ecstatic onlookers.
Nepal, however, is far from normal. More than 70 aftershocks have been recorded in the Himalayan region by Indian scientists in the past five days, according to J.L. Gautam, the director of seismology at the Indian Meteorological Department in New Delhi.
Advertisement
Anxiety over the aftershocks and worries over the fate of relatives have caused many to leave the capital. Thousands have boarded buses provided by the government to their rural hometowns.
Some residents have begun returning to work, including at Dutta's bank, but he said it was impossible to concentrate. "We roam around the office. We only have one topic of conversation: the earthquake."
Tamang recounted his story to a group of reporters inside a tent at an Israeli field hospital. He looked weak and tired. His dark hair was disheveled. But otherwise he seemed fine.
When Saturday's quake began at 11:56 am, Tamang said he was having lunch with a friend in the hotel where he worked. As he ran down toward the way out, the stairs shook. He saw walls cracking, ceilings caving in.
He was in the basement when "suddenly the building fell down. I thought I was about to die," he said. Tamang fainted, and when he regained consciousness, he could see little but darkness.
He was buried face down in a tiny crevice deep in the rubble, and terrified. He could barely move.
Tamang survived on cans of ghee, or clarified butter. He rested his head on chunks of concrete and broken piece of corrugated aluminum roof.
Finally, one Nepalese team began combing the rubble in Tamang's neighborhood, a place they had found another survivor Monday. They cried out and knocked on broken concrete slabs, and then listened closely for any response.
Mostly there was silence. But when an officer named L. Bahadu Basnet, shouted "Is anyone there?" he was shocked to get a reply.
"Who is there? Brother, I am here!" Tamang shouted back weakly.
The team used a car jack to help ensure a slab above the rectangular entrance did not cave in. Basnet took off his helmet, put on a headlamp, and crawled on his arms 10 feet (3 meters) inside, pushed in by his colleagues.
He could see Tamang wedged lying down in a crevice behind a motorcycle, and was shocked how responsive he was. "He thanked me when I first approached him," Basnet said. "He told me his name, his address, and I gave him some water. I assured him we were near."
It took a few hours to delicately clear the way for Tamang to be lifted out. Members of the U.S. Agency for International Development's Disaster Assistance Response Team brought in equipment to help and lowered a pole-mounted rotatable camera into the hole, said one of the team's members, Andrew Olvera.
Police said Tamang asked for one thing while he waited: juice.
Looking at a pair of huge, ripped concrete floors hanging precariously like curtains on the side of the destroyed building, just above the cratered rescue site, Olvera said the operation was dangerous. But, "it's risk versus gain. To save a human life, we'll risk almost anything."
At the Israeli field hospital, doctors X-rayed Tamang and injected him with glucose. Lt. Libby Weiss of the Israeli Defense Forces said he was dehydrated but lucid and "in remarkably good shape," with no other injuries except scratches.
"It's a miracle," Weiss said. "I think it's an amazing thing to see in the midst of all this calamity."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 08:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Steven Joyce's $1248 one-day car hire 'worth taxpayer dollars'</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/steven-joyce-s-1248-one-day-car-hire-worth-taxpayer-dollars-6305742?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Asked if he thought it was a good use of taxpayer dollars, Mr English said he "wouldn't be concerned about it".</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

Finance Minister Bill English has joined in defending a $1248 one-day car hire by Economic Development Minister Steven Joyce, saying Mr Joyce's expenditure "is well worth it".
The car hire, from Mr Joyce's visit to Australia in November, was detailed among ministerial expense records released yesterday by the Department of Internal Affairs.
A spokesperson for Mr Joyce said he was in Sydney for the Australian Jobs Fair, "but had a number of other engagements on the day including three media interviews and a meeting with and tour of the National Innovation Centre in Sydney".
The spokesperson said the hire car was "organised by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Trade on behalf of Minister Joyce's office at an hourly rate of $110 per hour".
"His day was planned as a day trip and no accommodation costs were incurred. His day started in Auckland at 4am and finished in Wellington at 11pm."
Mr Joyce says: "Using this sort of car is cost-effective in terms of achieving the maximum amount in the shortest possible time," Mr Joyce said.
Asked if he thought it was a good use of taxpayer dollars, Mr English said he "wouldn't be concerned about it" as "it's worth spending tax payer dollars to have [Mr Joyce] advocating New Zealand's economic interests".
"All I'm saying is incurring a bit of expenditure ... is well worth it."
Advertisement
Ministers have previously used Commonwealth Cars organised by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs through the Australian Government. However, early last year the Australian Government withdrew the service to New Zealand Ministers.
Mr Joyce's spokesperson said the $1248 cost is similar to the use of a Crown car in New Zealand.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 08:46:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The music of a champion? Pacquiao shares favourite pre-fight tunes</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/othersports-news/music-champion-pacquiao-shares-favourite-pre-fight-tunes-6305743?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>How does a legendary boxer like Manny Pacquiao get into the zone before a fight?</Description>
        <MainBody>Armoured vehicles, vault and 24 hour watch for Mayweather-Pacquiao belt video
How does a legendary boxer like Manny Pacquiao get into the zone before a fight? With music - and his newly-released Spotify playlist lists the hits which get him fighting fit.
Pacquiao released the playlist exclusively on Spotify to share with fans ahead of 'the fight of the century' against Floyd Mayweather Jnr. in Las Vegas on Sunday.
Pacquiao starts his playlist with "Eye of the Tiger," famously known as the theme song on Sylvester Stallone's action boxing film Rocky III.
Boxing fans have been waiting for six years for the blockbusting fight between 'Pacman' Pacquiao and 'Money' Mayweather to go ahead.
Mayweather Jnr will be protecting his impressive record of 47 wins with 26 of them coming from way of knockout and no losses.
Pacquiao compiled the playlist ahead of Sunday's fight at The MGM Grand Garden Arena, where both fighters are set to earn more than $100 million each.
The playlist is listed below and you can also play it online in the embedded player.
&amp;nbsp;
1. Eye of the Tiger (Survivor)
2. I Got It (Ashanti and Rick Ross)
3. Thank You (Sly &amp; The Family Stone)
4. Stole The Show (Kygo Parson James)
5. See You Again (Wiz Khalifa and Charlie Puth)
6. La Tortura (Shakira Alejandro Sanz)
7. Sugar (Maroon 5)
8. Cheerleader Felix Jaehn Remix (Omi)
9. Gold On The Ceiling (The Black Keys)
10. Thinking Out Loud (Ed Sheeran)
11. I Loved You (Blonde Melissa Steel)
12. Lover's Carvings (Bibio)
14. Rumble (Link Wray &amp; His Ray Men)
15. Lights Out, Words Gone (Bombay Bicycle Club)
16. You Make Me Feel Good (Satin Jackets)
17. Rock Wit U (Awww Baby) (Ashanti)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 08:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>McDonald's dragged into Ekim Burger rant controversy</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/mcdonald-s-dragged-into-ekim-burger-rant-controversy-6305637?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>"Well played with the old phone number swap. You got us good."</Description>
        <MainBody>McDonald's dragged into Ekim Burger rant controversy
Published: 11:51AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Wellington burger bar boss blasts customer for food poisoning complaint
McDonald's has been dragged into the middle of public backlash over yesterday's fiery Facebook rant by Ekim Burger boss Mike Duffy.
Mr Duffy posted a barrage of abuse on the business' Facebook page after a customer accused the burger bar of giving her son food poisoning. This morning he again refused to apologise, instead taking to Facebook once again to lash out.
"Is it no longer ok [sic] to drink gin for breakfast and rant meaningless s** on Facebook? I'm a long way from those few examples of customers we deal with regularly," Mr Duffy posted.
Now Ekim Burger's Facebook page lists McDonald's 0800 number as its phone number. So McDonald's is receiving calls from angry people who want to give Ekim Burger a piece of their mind.
"Well played with the old phone number swap. You got us good," McDonald's posted to Ekim Burger's Facebook.
"We're telling people calling to complain that you're giving away free burgers tonight, so let us know if that's not the right message for your callers."
Criticism flows
Mr Duffy has been heavily criticised for his handling of the food poisoning accusation and the decision to share his thoughts on the internet.
"I had a lot of respect for what you do and what you built up, but quite frankly it's all gone out the window ... someone says some bad s*** and you turn into an a**hole and attack every.. single.. one.. of your customers. That's not how to run a business."
However, some people have stood by the burger flipper and encouraged him to "stick to the grill".
"You make wicked burgers but you suck at pr," Gareth Leniston-Lee said.
Mr Duffy replied: "So people keep saying."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 07:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kangaroos' biggest star wants Aussie 'indigenous' haka to rival Kiwis</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/rugby-league-news/kangaroos-biggest-star-wants-aussie-indigenous-haka-rival-kiwis-6305728?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Kangaroos star Johnathan Thurston is calling for the Australian rugby league team to revive a Kiwis style haka which was ditched by the green and golds nearly 50 years ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kangaroos' biggest star wants Aussie 'indigenous' haka to rival Kiwis
Published: 4:18PM Friday May 01, 2015
Australian five-eighth Johnathan Thurston in action. - Source: Photosport
Jonathan Thurston of the Cowboys with a blackeye - Source: Getty Images
Related
Benji Marshall worried Kiwis career might be over after Kearney snub
Kangaroos star Johnathan Thurston is calling for the Australian rugby league team to revive a Kiwis style haka which was ditched by the green and golds nearly 50 years ago.
An Australian indigenous tribal dance was used for 60 years before it was axed after the Kangaroos lost a test series to France in 1967-68, Nine's Wide World of Sports reports.
The North Queensland Cowboys playmaker is a proud indigenous player and told News Limited he would love to see the All Blacks-like war cry return.
The dance would serve as a response to the pre-match hakas from New Zealand and Pacific Island teams.
"Look at the rep round we have this weekend - we are the only nation that doesn't have a traditional dance," Thurston said, as he prepares for the Anzac test in a wet Brisbane tonight.
"You look at Tonga, Samoa, Fiji, PNG, they all have their dances that mean something and the Kiwis have their haka."
Thurston has previously led indigenous chants on the footy field, including during the Indigenous All Stars clash with the NRL All Stars in February.
The original Australian war cry was derived from the warriors of Stradbroke Island and the players chant: "We are a race of fighters, descended from the War Gods the Kangaroo is dangerous when at bay."
Thurston, who is one of six indigenous players playing tonight against, said a return would honour the history between the Kangaroos and Indigenous Australia.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 07:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ali William's Toloun up against fierce opposition in European final</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/rugby-news/ali-william-s-toloun-up-against-fierce-opposition-in-european-final-6305725?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Toloun's bid to become European rugby champion for an unprecedented third year running will meet fierce resistance on Saturday in the shape of a French rival determined to deliver on years of unfulfilled promise.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ali William's Toloun up against fierce opposition in European final
Published: 4:09PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: AP
Toulon's lock Ali Williams - Source: Photosport
Source: ONE News
English flyhalf Cipriani turns down offer from champion French club, Toulon
Toloun's bid to become European rugby champion for an unprecedented third year running will meet fierce resistance on Saturday in the shape of a French rival determined to deliver on years of unfulfilled promise.
Considering its team of "galacticos" and its recent pedigree in Europe's top competition, Toulon should start as favorite against Clermont-Auvergne in the inaugural final of the European Rugby Champions Cup at Twickenham. It is the first year of the competition after the demise of the Heineken Cup.
However, the manner of Clermont's run to the showpiece match suggests this could be the year that the side from central France finally comes of age in Europe.
While Toulon slugged out uninspiring wins over Wasps and Leinster in the knockout stage, Clermont produced arguably the performance of the season in a 37-5 win over Northampton in the quarterfinals before overcoming Saracens in a bone-shuddering semifinal.
"Clermont are a wonderful team," said Matt Giteau, Toulon's Australian center. "For me, they are even the best team this year."
This has been said before about Clermont, only for disappointment to follow.
They have lost six of their nine finals in all competitions since 2004, including a nerve-wracking 2013 European final to Toulon that finished 16-15 in Dublin. Clermont lost in the semifinals in 2012 and '14 when many were tipping them to go all the way, invariably leading to accusations the players are mentally vulnerable and scarred by so many losses in big games.
In Fijian-born wingers Noa Nakaitaci and Napolioni Nalaga and centers Wesley Fofana and Jonathan Davies, Clermont has a back line of flair and potency that is backed up by the organizational skills of Brock James at flyhalf. Clermont's pack rarely gets bullied, either, meaning the team can play different styles depending on the match.
But will the big-game experience of Toulon and its cast of international stars prove the difference?
Jonny Wilkinson may be gone but superstars remain in the form of former New Zealand forwards Carl Hayman, Ali Williams and Chris Masoe, Springboks Bakkies Botha and Juan Smith, European Player of the Year Steffon Armitage and Argentina captain Juan Martin Fernandez Lobbe. And that's just the pack.
In the backs, Giteau, Bryan Habana, Leigh Halfpenny, Mathieu Bastareaud and Frederic Michalak provide the X-factor.
It is a stunning lineup built by owner Mourad Boudjellal, who made his millions from publishing comic books and ploughed much of it back into his home-town club on the French Riviera.
Advertisement
"There exists this spirit in Toulon of winning at all costs, to always want to win, to be the best," Toulon hooker Guilhem Guirado said. "That's what they teach you when you join the club.
"Toulon have been so consistent for a few years now in finals. I don't see why it shouldn't continue."
Toulon will emulate Toulouse's record - from 2003-05 - of appearing in three consecutive European finals. Leicester (2001 and '02) and Leinster (2011 and '12) have both won back-to-back titles but no team has achieved three in a row.
This will be the fifth all-French European Cup final in the past 13 years but it is set to be played in a half-full stadium at the 82,000-seater Twickenham, with only 8,000 French fans expected to travel across the Channel, according to organizers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 07:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Climbers huddle in tents as quake avalanche hits Everest camp (+ video)</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/climbers-huddle-in-tents-quake-avalanche-hits-everest-camp-video-6305719?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Climbers on Mt Everest could do nothing but huddle in tents as a huge avalanche struck their base camp following the Nepal earthquake.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

Climbers on Mt Everest could do nothing but huddle in tents as a huge avalanche struck their base camp following the Nepal earthquake.
The terrifying footage was captured by Paul Devaney following the magnitude-7.8 earthquake in the region, and shows mountaineers rushing to get inside as an immense cloud of snow approaches down the mountain.
The group can only take cover and wait as the avalanche hits.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 06:54:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'The layoff definitely gave me a new hunger to crack the ABs,' says Elliot</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/rugby-news/layoff-definitely-gave-me-new-hunger-crack-abs-says-elliot-6305704?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Former All Black Hika Elliot says layoff has helped him find a new hunger to get an All Black jersey</Description>
        <MainBody>'The layoff definitely gave me a new hunger to crack the ABs,' says Elliot
Published: 3:34PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Tim Nanai-Williams, Peter Saili in Samoa squad
Former All Black Hika Elliot has shown great form for the Chiefs in the Super Rugby competition so far this year and his layoff has helped him find a new hunger to get an All Black jersey.
Chiefs coach Dave Rennie said Elliot's form has been impressive and that he has matured as a player.
"He's (Elliot) been great for us in the past but it's not just the way he has been playing. Obviously his throwing's good, he's been scrummaging well, carrying well and defending well," Rennie said.
"But it's been a lot about his leadership - he's come back with a lot more maturity, he's desperate and he knows that this is a second chance for him. So he has impressed us in a lot of areas.
"Ultimately the All Blacks will make that selection, but he has certainly been playing well enough," Rennie said.
Elliot suffered a neck injury in 2013 which cost him his Chiefs contract last year.
But Elliot has fought hard and worked his way back into the Waikato Super Rugby franchise team.
"The layoff definitely gave me a new hunger and desire to crack the ABs this year," said Elliot.
"But first and foremost I have got to take care of my business here at the Chiefs. That's my lineout, that's my scrum work and all those things that come along with it.
"If I make the All Blacks again that's a bonus and that's going to be on the back of the work that I do for the Chiefs," he said.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 06:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blessie Gotingco's throat was slashed when she was still alive, court hears</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/blessie-gotingco-s-throat-slashed-she-still-alive-court-hears-6305701?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Justice Timothy Brewer warned the jury that they would be shown photos that would be difficult to stomach. </Description>
        <MainBody>Blessie Gotingco's throat was slashed when she was still alive, court hears
Published: 3:18PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Blessie Gotingco murder trial enters third day (1:40)
The jury at the trial of a man accused of raping and murdering Blessie Gotinco has heard evidence of the horrible injuries she sustained.
Defence pathologist Dr Carl Wigren, who performed the autopsy on Blessie Gotingco, today described her injuries to the High Court at Auckland.
Ms Gotingco, 58, disappeared while walking home from a bus stop in Birkdale on May 24 last year and her body was found dumped in a nearby cemetery two days later.
Justice Timothy Brewer warned the jury that they would be shown photos that would be difficult to stomach.
The jury heard Ms Gotingco suffered multiple stab wounds, the most serious being a 14.5cm laceration across her throat, which partially severed her airway.
The bleeding from that wound was so severe that a white t-shirt Mrs Gotingco was wearing had turned red because of the bloodshed.
Blood was also found in Blessie Gotingco's lungs, meaning that she was alive when she suffered that injury.
The court has also heard that it was highly likely Ms Gotingco was strangled.
Evidence from Dr Carl Wigren continues.
Advertisement
The Crown alleges the 28-year-old accused, whose name is supressed, knocked Ms Gotingco down with his car then took her back to his apartment.where he raped her, slit her throat and stabbed her several times.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 06:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mammoth cruise liner turned away after Ports of Auckland compromise</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/mammoth-cruise-liner-turned-away-after-ports-auckland-compromise-6305476?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Only one of the two planned Bledisloe Wharf expansions will go ahead, but it seems nobody is happy. </Description>
        <MainBody>Mammoth cruise liner turned away after Ports of Auckland compromise
Published: 5:21AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
The Ovation of the Seas cruise ship - Source: Royal Caribbean International
Related
Len Browns legacy to Auckland is going to be a one fingered salute  Lobby group on Ports decision (0:18)
A planned visit of what would have been the biggest cruise liner to ever visit New Zealand has been canned, following yesterday's compromise by Ports of Auckland.
After a months-long stoush, Auckland Council yesterday announced an agreement with Ports of Auckland to proceed with only one of two planned wharf expansions at Bledisloe Wharf - the eastern B2 wharf - and to commit to having it removed if the forthcoming Port Future Study found it to be redundant.
The decision means the 'Ovation of the Seas' cruise ship will not be able to visit Auckland as planned next year.
The ship would have been the largest ever to visit New Zealand, at a length of 348m and a maximum capacity of 4900 passengers and 1300 crew.
"Ports of Auckland has advised that due to the change in its development plans, it will not now be able to accommodate the Ovation of the Seas," Cruise New Zealand chairman Kevin O'Sullivan said.
Mr O'Sullivan said yesterday's announcement could slow growth in the cruise ship sector, as cruises are planed "three to five years ahead".
Opponents of PoA's expansion say one expansion is still one too many and they are planning another protest march on Sunday.
Employers and Manufactures Association chief executive Kim Campbell spoke to TV ONE's Breakfast today, saying the agreement is a "temporary solution".
"Obviously they had to come to some short term arrangement. It was impossible having the public up in arms and also the port facing an uncertain future, unable to park large boats," he said.
Advertisement
"What's unfortunate about this is the public should have been paying attention a number of years ago when all these plans were being tabled."
He said what transpired was the "inevitable collision" between land use for recreation and tourism and industry growth, with a "grown up conversation" needed about the port's future.
"This short term solution is absolutely necessary - we need these big ships coming to New Zealand," he added.
But Michael Goldwater from the 'Stop Stealing Our Harbour' group, which opposes the expansions, was unhappy with the compromise, saying one expansion was still one too many, and a protest march planned for the weekend is set to go ahead.
"I think it's very disappointing - it seems like Len Brown's legacy to Auckland is going to be a one-finger salute in the shape of a whole lot of concrete out into the Waitemata Harbour."
More than 200 people had signed up to attend the protest march, which would make its way from Tinley St to the Viaduct Events Centre from 11am on Sunday.
The Port Future Study will be a wide-ranging report showing trends in North Island freight distribution and where infrastructure needs to adapt - the draft scope and terms of reference are to be reported to the Auckland Development committee on May 14.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:43:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pair arrested in Levin after aggravated robbery</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/pair-arrested-in-levin-after-aggravated-robbery-6305696?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A teenage girl and a 26-year-old man were arrested after allegedly robbing a family of Singaporean tourists. </Description>
        <MainBody>Pair arrested in Levin after aggravated robbery
Published: 2:43PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News

New Zealand Police - Source: ONE News
A teenage girl and a 26-year-old man were arrested in Levin today after allegedly robbing a family of Singaporean tourists.
Police say the man, carrying a broken bottle, confronted and threatened the family about 3pm yesterday after they had parked their campervan in the Levin Countdown car park.
"He demanded money and the couple who had two young children with them at the time, feared for their safety and handed over some of their belongings," Detective Sergeant Peter Vine said.
The pair will appear at Blenheim District Court this afternoon charged with aggravated robbery.
Police say they have recovered the vehicle they allege was used during the robbery and a scene examination is taking place.
Mr Vine said while some of the victim's property has been recovered, police would still like to hear from anyone who witnessed the robbery.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Auckland's average house now costs more than $800,000</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/auckland-s-average-house-now-costs-more-than-800-000-6305689?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Auckland's housing market increased at nearly double the nationwide average over the past year.</Description>
        <MainBody>Auckland's average house now costs more than $800,000
Published: 2:02PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Reserve Bank makes extraordinary call for housing tax rethink (3:27)
Auckland's housing market increased at nearly double the nationwide average over the past year, with the city's average home now costing more than $800,000, according to the latest QV figures.
Prices are showing no sign of slowing either, with nationwide, inflation-adjusted house prices up 8.2 per cent compared to this time last year. Auckland's market increased at nearly double that rate - 14.5 per cent compared to this time last year.
QV spokesperson Andrea Rush said the nationwide increase is "indicative of the sharp rise in Auckland values".
Hamilton, Christchurch and Dunedin all had increases of less than four per cent compared to this time last year.
"Auckland has continued its rapid rise, with many areas seeing double digit increases in values since November," said Ms Rush.
"Dunedin is the only main centre where values decreased slightly since February."
A double income household saving 10 per cent of their income every year, assuming both adults earn the average wage ($51,532), would take 78 years to save up enough money to buy Auckland's average home ($809,200).
"With net migration at a record 54,000 and still rising, and 50 per cent of migrants moving to Auckland, home values in the Super City are likely to remain high and keep rising during 2015 as supply continues to outstrip demand," said Ms Rush.
The nationwide house price average is $507,040.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 01 04:52:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman found dead on SH1 may have been hit by 'more than one vehicle'</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/woman-found-dead-sh1-may-have-been-hit-more-than-one-vehicle-6305687?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Police are investigating the death of a woman hit by more than one car near Mercer.</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman found dead on SH1 may have been hit by 'more than one vehicle'
Published: 1:52PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

A white vehicle being sought by police in relation to the death of a woman near Mercer - Source: Counties Manukau Police
Police are investigating the death of a woman who appeared to have been hit by more than one car on a road near Mercer.
Sarah Bromley, 37, was found dead on State Highway One near Mercer, just south of the Bombay hills, about 2:30am on April 25 near a petrol station and the Counties Manukau Serious Crash Unit is investigating.
Police were interested in speaking with anyone who was driving in the area around that time, and in particular were seeking the driver of a white vehicle recorded on a CCTV camera, which dropped a person off near the Podges Place pub in Mercer about 2am.
"We are in the process of piecing together Ms Bromley's movements leading up to her death and any information we can gain from the public will assist the investigation," Detective Sergeant Sam Rice of Counties Manukau Police said.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri May 01 04:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Government warning over Nepal fundraising</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/government-warning-over-nepal-fundraising-6305679?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Jo Goodhew is encouraging people to donate to well-established registered charities. </Description>
        <MainBody>Government warning over Nepal fundraising
Published: 1:18PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Man heroically pulled from rubble 82 hours after Nepal earthquake video
The Government's minister responsible for the charity sector is warning people wanting to give money to help Nepal after its massive earthquake disaster to be careful.
Community and Voluntary Sector Minister Jo Goodhew says: "New Zealanders swift response to the appeals set up to provide assistance to victims of the Nepalese earthquakes has been incredible. It is a real tribute to New Zealand's generosity and sympathy for those facing a terrible disaster.
"However experience shows that although the vast majority of fundraising is genuine, the public should be mindful of people fundraising fraudulently."
Ms Goodhew is encouraging people to donate to well-established registered charities "that have the experience and infrastructure needed to provide disaster-relief assistance".
She has offered a series of checks, which she says only take a few minutes:
 Check whether collectors are wearing an ID badge
 Ask a collector for the charity's registration number, and check that against the charity's entry on the online Charities Register at www.charities.govt.nz
 Ask the collector for more information - a fundraiser should be able to explain the work of the charity and how your donation will be used.
 Fundraising materials should display the charity's name, registration number and a landline contact number - be wary of those that list only a mobile    number or email address.
 If in any doubt, contact your preferred charity directly to make a donation.
It's estimated New Zealanders have given nearly $500,000 in donations for relief efforts in Nepal since the first deadly earthquake struck last Saturday.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bill English admits defeat in surplus pledge</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/bill-english-admits-defeat-in-surplus-pledge-6305675?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Finance Minister blames another deficit on lower tax revenue, low inflation and low interest rates.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bill English admits defeat in surplus pledge
By ONE News Political Reporter Katie Bradford
Published: 12:51PM Friday May 01, 2015
Solid Energy's boss quit after clash with Bill English video
Three weeks out from Budget day the Finance Minister has confirmed he won't be meeting his much-vaunted surplus.
Addressing the Wellington Chamber of Commerce at lunchtime, Bill English admitted the outlook for the economy has got worse since Treasury's Half-Year fiscal update.
The Government has repeatedly promised it would reach surplus by this year but instead Mr English says there'll be a slightly bigger deficit in this year's budget with hopes of a small surplus next year.
He's blaming it on lower tax revenue, low inflation and low interest rates.
"Although we're seeing more bank deposits which would ordinarily lead us to collect more tax, these are being more than offset by lower interest rates," he says. "Consequently the Government is collecting less tax."
Treasury expects the Government will collect $4.5 billion less tax revenue over the next four years than it expected this time last year.
"The surplus target is important. It has imposed a discipline on us and on government agencies to work hard on achieving value for money and providing new spending only where we can get better results," Mr English says.
But there's one more promise - there'll be no cuts in spending in the Budget.
Mr English says there'll still be a $1 billion operating allowance, as there has been in previous years.
"We will not be pursuing cuts in services or income support in a knee-jerk response to lower tax revenue," he says.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police establish 0800 number for Gloriavale complaints</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/police-establish-0800-number-gloriavale-complaints-6305662?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>There have been allegations of brainwashing, physical punishment and sexual abuse at the Christian Commune.</Description>
        <MainBody>Police establish 0800 number for Gloriavale complaints
Published: 12:37PM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Gloriavale responds to abuse allegations: 'It doesn't mean they're all true' video
Police have set up an 0800 number for Gloriavale residents and escapees to discuss their experiences at the West Coast commune.
A "growing response" to a police call for people to open up about the secretive sect has led police to establish the toll free number.
Former members have recently made claims, including on TV ONE's Sunday, of brainwashing, physical punishment and sexual abuse against girls as young as 12 at the West Coast Christian Commune.
Tasman Police District Commander Superintendent Karyn Malthus said it will help people around New Zealand contact police directly involved in the investigation.
She said calls would be answered by Tasman District Police who are trained to deal with sensitive issues.
"We will collate any information within our District from where we will determine what, if any, further steps may be required," she said.
To protect the privacy and welfare of those raising concerns, operational matters in relation to the investigation and specific matters raised with police would not be made available to the media, she said.
"Our priority is gathering information and doing a thorough investigation and to do that we do wish to hear from ex-residents, residents or anyone that thinks they may information that will assist," she said.
The number is 0800 400 800.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'We've written a couple of songs' - Joel Little hints at new Lorde album</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/entertainment-news/we-ve-written-couple-songs-joel-little-hints-new-lorde-album-6305657?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Joel Little dishes a little dirt on Lorde's follow-up album to her 2013 smash hit Pure Heroine.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

Joel Little says he has begun working with Lorde on the follow-up to her 2013 debut album Pure Heroine.
Little co-wrote, produced and played the instruments on the album, which was released worldwide on September 30, 2013.
"We've written a couple of songs," Little told Billboard.
"We haven't done a whole lot of production on it yet, we just want to make sure the songs are really good."
No release date has been set and Little said the pair are "just trying new things".
Pure Heroine was released by Universal Music and the lead single Royals was a huge success, topping the charts in New Zealand, the United Kingdom and the United States, where Lorde, 18, became the first solo New Zealand act to top the Billboard Hot 100 chart.
The Kiwi songstress clinched Song of the Year and Best Pop Solo Performance at the 56th Grammy Awards in Los Angeles in January last year.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:57:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Who are the Kiwis still missing after Nepal quake?</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/kiwis-still-missing-after-nepal-quake-6305604?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Several Kiwis remain missing a week after the 7.8 quake, as new video captures the moment a World Heritage temple crumbles to the ground.</Description>
        <MainBody>Who are the Kiwis still missing after Nepal quake?
Published: 11:20AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Man heroically pulled from rubble 82 hours after Nepal earthquake video
Several Kiwis are still missing following the devastating earthquake that decimated Kathmandu and much of Nepal.
Peter Joseph Curreen, 63, is still missing and has not been heard from since the 7.8-magnitude earthquake which killed more than 6000 people and injured more than 13,500, his cousin, Ellen Curreen, told ONE News.
Others missing since last week's quake include 31-year-old Doug Sealy, who was volunteering in India but had travelled to Nepal to renew his visa at the time of the earthquake, and New Zealand born William Seymour-Jones, 25.
However, three other New Zealanders who were missing have seemingly since been found.
Peter Donald McLeod, 62, and 34-year-old Joshua Dane are no longer on the Red Cross's missing list but it is yet to be confirmed that they have been found.
Taupo-born Brad Robson, who had been living in Brisbane, has also been found according to a Facebook message from his parents.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pacquiao has grand design for Mayweather victory</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/othersports-news/pacquiao-has-grand-design-mayweather-victory-6305606?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Boxing trainer Freddie Roach has devised an elaborate strategy he says will deliver a decisive victory for Filipino icon Manny Pacquiao in his 'Fight of the Century' against Floyd Mayweather.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pacquiao has grand design for Mayweather victory
Published: 11:22AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: AP
Which Hollywood stars will be ringside at the Fight of the Century? (0:43)
Boxing trainer Freddie Roach has devised an elaborate strategy he says will deliver a decisive victory for Filipino icon Manny Pacquiao in his 'Fight of the Century' against Floyd Mayweather.
The revered trainer expects a bulked up Mayweather to seek an early rounds knockout but warned Pacquiao would be ready to go the distance if necessary
"I have the winning formula for Manny," Roach said at the MGM Grand Hotel, ahead of Sunday's (NZT) bout.
"He (Mayweather) put on a lot of muscle for this fight. I think he will come out in early rounds and try to knock us out.
"He could also run all night. I have fallen asleep at a couple of his fights before. So I am ready for whatever he brings to the ring."
Pacquiao set up his training camp for the richest fight in boxing history in a private facility built underneath Roach's Wild Card Gym in Los Angeles.
They gutted the old laundromat that was there and replaced it with a de facto war room where Roach and Pacquiao have been crafting the plan they believe will end Mayweather's unbeaten record.
Roach said the new gym allowed Pacquiao to escape the clamour and chaos of the Wild Card that comes with having the Filipino superstar training there.
"I blocked the gym off and we kept it private. This camp I didn't have Manny trying to perform for an audience, he was performing for himself," Roach said.
Advertisement
Roach said earlier he thought Mayweather's unusually quiet demeanour in the build up to the fight was a sign he lacked motivation.
Pacquiao meanwhile went for a "light" run Thursday morning followed by another low-key workout in the afternoon.
"We are not focused on one strategy but two or three strategies," Pacquiao said earlier in the week.
"Any way he wants to fight me is good. If he wants to run we will cut the ring off."
Roach is using Mayweather's fights against Zab Judah and Oscar De La Hoya as blueprints for what they want to achieve in the ring.
Mayweather beat Judah by a unanimous decision in 2006 and De La Hoya by a split decision a year later.
Roach said if De La Hoya had continued to use his jab effectively in the later rounds he could have beaten Mayweather.
"Oscar beat him in the first six rounds and lost to him in the last six. Oscar started following him around. We will improve on that. Zab just started tiring."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:22:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Doomsday at Mercury: NASA craft falls from orbit into planet</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/doomsday-mercury-nasa-craft-falls-orbit-into-planet-6305603?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The only spacecraft ever to orbit Mercury ended its four-year tour with a crash landing.</Description>
        <MainBody>An artist's rendering showing Messenger around the planet Mercury - Source: AP
The only spacecraft ever to orbit Mercury ended its four-year tour with a crash landing.
NASA's Messenger plunged from orbit as planned and slammed into the sun's closest planet at about 14,081 km/hr, creating a crater an estimated 16 metres across.
Messenger became the first spacecraft to orbit hot, little Mercury, in 2011. It circled the solar system's innermost planet 4,105 times and collected more than 277,000 images.
"Today we bid a fond farewell to one of the most resilient and accomplished spacecraft ever to have explored our neighboring planets," said lead scientist Sean Solomon, director of Columbia University's Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory.
Messenger set a record for planetary flybys - once past Earth, twice past Venus and three times past Mercury before entering Mercury's orbit - and survived "both punishing heat and extreme doses of radiation" to surpass expectations.
Flight controllers managed to keep the spacecraft going a few extra weeks by using helium gas not originally intended as fuel. But the gas tank finally emptied and gravity's relentless tug did Messenger in.
Mercury is the last of the rocky inner planets in our solar system - also counting Mars and Venus - to be littered by mankind.
The crash occurred on the side of Mercury facing away from Earth and telescopes. Several minutes passed before NASA received confirmation. Controllers received no signal from Messenger when it was supposed to be back in the coverage zone - a sign that the spacecraft, measuring 10 feet solar wingtip to wingtip, had, indeed, succumbed to gravity.
"Well I guess it is time to say goodbye," the Messenger Twitter feed stated as the end drew near.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:10:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boychoir: Movie Review</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/entertainment-news/boychoir-movie-review-6305507?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Feel-good movie Boychoir goes under the microscope.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cast: Dustin Hoffman, Kathy Bates, Josh Lucas, Debra Winger, Kevin McHale, Garett Wareing, Joe West
Director: Francois Girard
Heavenly voices, predictable story and made for TV movie moments.
That pretty much sums up Boychoir, from the French director Girard (The Red Violin). It's the story of Stet, a troubled kid (played sympathetically by Wareing) whose life is chaos at school and turbulent at home with an alcoholic mother.
When the unthinkable happens, Stet finds his life at a cross-roads and despite failing an audition to enter a prestigious musical academy, Stet's estranged father (Josh Lucas) ends up making the school a financial offer it can't afford to ignore to secure him a place, rather than face the indignity of telling his current wife and family that Stet exists.
Thrust into the Harry Potter style school, complete with blonde-haired nemesis and prodigy Devon (West), Stet becomes the underdog in his campaign to get a place on the touring American Boychoir. But under the tutelage of the brisk Carvelle (a genial Hoffman) and a puffy English teacher (Eddie Izzard), will Stet find his voice?
Advertisement
Boychoir hits the right notes in many places, doing exactly what you'd expect of a crowd-pleasing feel good movie that's probably more at home on the small screen than the big.
While there are certainly goosebumps to be had with the singing scenes, the relative one-note characters and drama outside of the Harry Potter and the Chamber Choir antics (Izzard is Snape, Hoffman is Dumbledore, Devon is Draco etc etc) is under-cooked and poorly serviced in terms of development.
Girard steers clear of too much sentimentality though, with several scenes which could have wallowed in the moment brusquely dealt with to help the film's flow. Though, along with Stet's father's dilemma being largely confined to looking troubled through a window, more could have been made of that situation and the crux of the Boychoir dilemma - namely, that their heavenly voices have only a short window to shine through before nature cruelly drops them down a level. Missed opportunities scatter this aria throughout and conspire to drag the film down.
It's a restrained Hoffman who generates some empathy and warmth from Carvelle, whose relationship with Stet could have easily fallen into some kind of musical Full Metal Jacket scenario, but wisely shows the power a proficient and caring teacher can make to a child's life. Wareing manages well too in his first lead, with the wide-eyed and naturalistic turn helping the more predictable and by-the-numbers elements of the plot along.
Ultimately, Boychoir offers a feeling of deja-vu; in the likes of Mr Holland's Opus, we've seen it all before, but, thanks to a lack of over-egging the pudding, the one note nature of the story just about manages to leave you with a warm glow.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:06:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Gunman: Movie Review</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/entertainment-news/gunman-movie-review-6305508?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Sean Penn launches his action man bid</Description>
        <MainBody>Cast: Sean Penn, Jasmine Trinca, Javier Bardem, Ray Winstone
Director: Pierre Morel
The geri-action franchise gets a new entrant in the form of Sean Penn who's teamed up with the director of Taken. Well, with the news that Liam Neeson's stepping down from the action game, a new contender had to emerge.
Penn stars as Jim Terrier, an international operative working undercover in the Democratic Republic of Congo in 2006, whose assassination mission sees him forced to leave the country, his friend Felix (Bardem) and lover Annie (Trinca).
Resurfacing 8 years later, Terrier's back in the DRC now with for a humanitarian organisation but finds himself in the gun when an attack where he's working takes place. Suddenly finding he's part of a conspiracy that relates back to his actions in 2006, Terrier begins to revisit his old life to find out exactly what's going on.
In its initial scenes, The Gunman appears to be an intelligent piece about potential sins of the past coming back to haunt before betraying its set up and settling for a generic geriatric action thriller that has some impressive stunt work and set ups but ultimately blunts your senses.
Advertisement
Penn's wiry and intent outlook gets you through the exposition heavy sequences to start off before the bullets start to fly, the explosions begin to shake the screen and the globe-hopping kicks in to dizzy you out of any intelligent thought you had about the issues being explored. If anything Penn makes a good case for his entrant into the pantheon of oldie action heroes, looking better than most, puzzled when the conspiracy kicks in and suffers through the many indignities of the script with utter commitment.
And it is the script that causes issues - a life threatening illness for our hero only kicks in when the circumstances necessitate (and therefore irritates), a bull fight is leaned upon too heavily as an allegory for the final showdown and Trinca's character serves only to become the damsel in distress after a strong start.
Coupled with a near unwatchable Bardem and a bloated Winstone wearing a bizarre wig, The Gunman betrays any pretence towards grandeur and settles for a cliched unoriginal action thriller and pulpy trashy conspiracy novel.
Quite simply, this Gunman is shooting blanks
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Women open fire on would-be rescuers in Nigeria</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/women-open-fire-would-rescuers-in-nigeria-6305589?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Some women being 'rescued' from Islamic extremists in a remote forest fought their saviours fiercely, Nigeria's military said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Civilians walk past a check point manned by Nigerian soldiers in Gwoza, Nigeria - Source: AP
Related
Nigeria kidnap: Bring Back Our Girls becomes Never to be Forgotten
Some women among a group of women and children rescued from Islamic extremists in the remote Sambisa Forest fought their rescuers fiercely, Nigeria's military said.
A senior army officer at the scene described the women opening fire on shocked troops in the village of Nbita a week ago, with Boko Haram Islamic insurgents using the women to shield their main fighting force.
He said he was told that 12 women fighters and seven soldiers died in a fierce firefight.
The Nigerian military first reported rescuing almost 300 women and children in the Sambisa Forest on Tuesday after deploying ground troops into the forest more than a week ago. Colonel Sani Usman said more than 100 additional girls and over 50 more women have also been rescued.
He said in a statement that several lives were lost, including that of a soldier and a woman, during shootouts in nine separate extremist camps in the forest. Eight women sustained gunshot wounds and four soldiers were seriously injured. It was not clear who shot the women.
All the women and children were being evacuated to a safety zone for further processing, Usman said.
It remains unclear if some of the women had willingly joined Boko Haram, or are family members of fighters.
Also killed were several Boko Haram field commanders and foot soldiers. Combat tanks and munitions of high caliber used by Boko Haram were also recovered while others were destroyed, the army spokesman said.
It is still unclear if any of the schoolgirls kidnapped from the northeastern town of Chibok a year ago were among those rescued. The plight of the schoolgirls, who have become known as "the Chibok girls," aroused international outrage and a campaign for their release under the hashtag #BringBackOurGirls. Their kidnapping brought Boko Haram, whose nickname means "Western education is forbidden" in the local Hausa language, to the world's attention.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Oklahoma City Thunder appoint star college coach</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/basketball-news/oklahoma-city-thunder-appoint-star-college-coach-6305564?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Billy Donovan has agreed to become the head coach of the Oklahoma City Thunder, where he will work with the reigning NBA MVP Kevin Durant</Description>
        <MainBody>Oklahoma City Thunder appoint star college coach
Published: 10:15AM Friday May 01, 2015

Kevin Durant of the Thunder - Source: Getty Images
Billy Donovan has agreed to become the head coach of the Oklahoma City Thunder, where he will work with the reigning NBA MVP Kevin Durant.
Donovan agreed to the move today after 19 successful seasons at the University of Florida.
Donovan will sign a multi-year deal to succeed Scott Brooks, who was fired last week after the Thunder failed to reach the playoffs.
The Thuder's roster includes Kiwi Steven Adams and All-Stars Keven Durant and Russell Westbrook.
"I knew it would take a unique opportunity to leave the University of Florida and that is clearly how I look at the situation," Donovan said.
"The Thunder represents so many of the values that I embrace as a head coach; the commitment to the team above oneself, the dedicated pursuit of excellence, the commitment to organisational culture, the identity they have established and the fact that the Thunder and the community are so intricately woven into the fabric of one another."
Thunder general manager Sam Presti says the 49-year-old Donovan is the perfect fit to guide the club.
Advertisement
Donovan has compiled a sparkling resume, accumulating a 467-186 record at Florida that includes back-to-back national titles in 2006-07.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:14:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>League star shocked at 'last letter' from pen pal Andrew Chan - after his execution</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/league-star-shocked-last-letter-pen-pal-andrew-chan-after-his-execution-6305563?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Origin captain Paul Gallen was exchanging letters with the Bali Nine leader - but never expected one after Chan's execution.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tragic photo reveals smiling Andrew Chan marrying on eve of his execution
New South Wales State of Origin captain Paul Gallen has revealed he received a bittersweet letter from Andrew Chan the day after the Bali Nine ringleader was executed.
The rugby league star began sharing letters with Chan during the past few months, he told 2Day FM.
"I was pretty apprehensive about it at first - to be honest with you, I left it for a couple of weeks," The Cronulla Sharks player said.
"I didn't know what to do and I ended up getting in contact with him and talking to him ... one of the things that stuck out in my mind was just how hard a childhood he had and just his upbringing was pretty full on."
Gallen spoke of their shared love for rugby league and Chan's troubled youth.
"He said, 'I've been stabbed, I've been shot at, I've been bashed, but I've never cried in my whole life'," Gallen said, recalling one of Chan's letters.
But Chan cried when the Blues won State of Origin last year, ending an eight year Queensland reign, Gallen added.
Gallen, who said Chan's death was a "waste of life", then told the radio station he received what would be "the final letter" the day after Chan was executed by an Indonesian firing squad.
"One line he wrote to me was: 'For myself, each day is like a diamond. I can either appreciate what I have and see the value of it - or I can just lay around and do nothing':"
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tom Marshall confirms he remains UK-bound</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/rugby-news/tom-marshall-confirms-he-remains-uk-bound-6305552?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Tom Marshall has confirmed he remains Gloucester-bound but his arrival in the UK could be delayed following interest from the All Blacks. </Description>
        <MainBody>
Chiefs' Tom Marshall gets the offload away against the Bulls. - Source: Getty Images
Tom Marshall has confirmed he remains Gloucester-bound but his arrival in the UK could be delayed following interest from the All Blacks.
Reports emerged that the utility back has signed a deal to remain with the Tasman Makos in the ITM Cup - throwing his commitment to Gloucester into doubt.
The Makos posted on Facebook: "WELCOME BACK TOM .. Chiefs fullback Tom Marshall, who was to leave for Gloucester, will rejoin Tasman for the 2015 season.
"This after being advised by NZ Rugby he is on the All Blacks selectors' radar for the Rugby World Cup ?#?FinsUp."
But Marshall was always contracted to the New Zealand Rugby Union until November and his scheduled June arrival at Kingsholm was on the proviso that he was not in international contention.
"As far as my contract goes nothing had changed, I was already signed with the Makos for 2015 but was hoping to exercise an early release clause from the NZRU," Marshall told the Gloucester Citzen.
"However at this stage it looks as though I will be unable to do so. I'm not too sure about how much I can read into that but I guess it is a good thing.
Advertisement
The 24-year-old has been starring in Super Rugby for the Chiefs this season but making the All Blacks appears a tall order given the strength in depth they boast.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Special catwalk for George Clooney to check out Amal's clothes</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/entertainment-news/special-catwalk-george-clooney-check-amal-s-clothes-6305547?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>George Clooney has installed a runway in his closet so his wife Amal can show him her outfits.</Description>
        <MainBody>Special catwalk for George Clooney to check out Amal's clothes
Published: 9:43AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: BANG Showbiz
George Clooney put on diet by new wife
George Clooney has installed a runway in his closet so his wife Amal can show him her outfits.
The 'Monuments Men' star has reportedly had a catwalk put in his Studio City home because he is "very involved in selecting her looks".
A source said: "George will watch her try on clothes and will say, 'I like that. You should get it,' or 'No, not that.'
"He installed a runway, floor-to-ceiling mirrors, and a crazy light system in their closet. Amal can see every single angle and tell if her outfit is see-through!"
And the 37-year-old human rights lawyer is said to love the 53-year-old actor offering opinions about her outfits.
The insider added to Us Weekly magazine: "Amal loves it! She shops a lot because she needs her lawyer looks and then street clothes."
Meanwhile, George recently hosted an intimate dinner for Amal's birthday.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vocal kauri tree protester defends actions - then pleads guilty</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/vocal-kauri-tree-protester-defends-actions-then-pleads-guilty-6305539?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Outside court, Michael Tavares said "communities shouldn't have to risk their safety ...to simply have their voices heard".</Description>
        <MainBody>Kauri tree protester Michael Tavares has pleaded guilty to trespass over his 81-hour vigil atop a kauri tree in West Auckland last month.
Michael Tavares appeared in Waitakere District Court after being charged with wilful trespass on April 16.
In a statement before his court appearance, Tavares said that by occupying the 500-year-old kauri tree the Titirangi community was finally able to have their voice heard on an issue that they should have been consulted on in the first place.
"Communities shouldn't have to risk their safety or break the law to protect significant ecosystems or just simply have their voices heard," he said.
Tavares spent 81 hours perched in a kauri tree in March to stop developers cutting it down to make way for a house to be built on the site.
He says with reforms to the Resource Management Act and local body decision making processes communities all over New Zealand have been seriously let down.
He is calling for a National Day of Action on Sunday to call for the rules protecting trees to be strengthened.
"We can't climb every tree and we shouldn't have to, what we need is better leadership and legislation."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Top Belgian footballer dies 3 days after heart failure on field</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/othersports-news/top-belgian-footballer-dies-3-days-after-heart-failure-field-6305536?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Lokeren says defender Gregory Mertens died today three days after he suffered heart failure during a training match.</Description>
        <MainBody>Top Belgian footballer dies 3 days after heart failure on field
Published: 9:16AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: AP

Lokeren defender Gregory Mertens - Source: Getty Images
Lokeren says defender Gregory Mertens died today, three days after he suffered heart failure during a training match.
The club in Belgium's top division said, "With sadness, we announce the passing of Gregory Mertens."
The 24-year-old player collapsed early in Monday's game, and was kept in a coma.
Lokeren said doctors tried to operate on the player on Tuesday, but there were more complications.
Lokeren said Mertens was medically screened several times during his career, and that nothing pointed toward a fundamental heart problem.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boy, 15, amazed by own survival after five days buried in Kathmandu rubble</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/boy-15-amazed-own-survival-after-five-days-buried-in-kathmandu-rubble-6305512?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Pempa Tamang heard the bulldozers and was ready for falling rubble to end his life.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boy, 15, amazed by own survival after five days buried in Kathmandu rubble
Published: 8:00AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: AP
Huge aftershock rips through Kathmandu following 7.8 quake video
A 15-year-old boy was buried alive under the rubble Kathmandu for five days, listening to bulldozers clearing mountains of debris, fearful the incessant aftershocks might finally collapse the darkened crevice where he was trapped.
And then, "all of the sudden I saw light," Pempa Tamang said, recounting the moment today he was pulled from a hole at the bottom of what was once a seven-story building in Kathmandu.
Tamang did not know whether he was alive or dead. "I thought I was hallucinating," he said.
The improbable rescue was an uplifting moment in Nepal, which has been overwhelmed by death and destruction since the 7.8-magnitude earthquake.
The Nepalese government said the toll from the tremor, the most powerful recorded in the country since 1934, had risen to 6,130 dead and 13,827 injured.
After night fell, police reported another dramatic rescue: A woman in her 20s, Krishna Devi Khadka, was pulled from a building in the same neighbourhood as Tamang near Kathmandu's main bus terminal.
"Life has become a struggle to survive. It gives us hope," said Hans Raj Joshi, who watched Tamang's rescue. "We thought they were only bringing out the dead. It's hard to believe people are still alive."
More than 70 aftershocks have been recorded in the Himalayan region by Indian scientists in the past five days, according to J.L. Gautam, the director of seismology at the Indian Meteorological Department in New Delhi.
Shortages of food and water and worry over the fate of relatives have triggered an exodus from the capital, prompting thousands to board buses provided by the government to their rural hometowns.
It's thought a quarter of Nepal's 27 million population has been severely affected by the quake.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lydia Ko sends caddy up a tree in mid-round meltdown (+video)</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/golf-news/lydia-ko-sends-caddy-up-tree-in-mid-round-meltdown-video-6305510?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Kiwi world number one has a shocking opening round at the North Texas Open. </Description>
        <MainBody>Lydia Ko in hot form at Swinging Skirts video
Lydia Ko's great run of form has come to an abrupt halt in the first round of the LPGA Tour's North Texas Open.
The world number one, who has never missed the cut since turning professional, has carded a four over par 75.
Her round included a triple bogey on the 14th, a double bogey on the 15th and a bogey on the 16th.
The par-four 14th was especially problematic for Ko. With her second shot, she hit her ball up a tree and after sending her caddy up there, the ball wouldn't come down.
The ball was unplayable and Ko took the dropped shot. The 18-year-old Ko is tied for 130th, eight shots off the pace.
It's bad timing for an off day on the course after the 18-year-old revealed yesterday that all her winnings from the tournament will go to the relief effort in quake-hit Nepal.
Ko would need to make the cut to earn any money from the tournament.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:32:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What A-List stars will be ringside at the Fight of the Century?</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/othersports-news/list-stars-ringside-fight-century-6305523?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The so-called Fight of the Century is expected to have an A-List cast almost bigger than the fight itself.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

The so-called Fight of the Century is expected to have an A-List cast almost bigger than the fight itself.
Academy award-winning actors Leonardo DiCaprio and Denzel Washington are among those expected to be sitting ringside when Manny Pacquiao and Floyd Mayweather Jr. finally get it on at the MGM Grand on Sunday.
The two were among the Hollywood stars Top Rank promoter Bob Arum mentioned when asked about the star power expected to lend further glamor to a fight that will go down as the biggest and richest fight in boxing history.
"You can't believe the VIPs coming," Arum said.
"There'll be as many celebrities in Hollywood at the fight as there are during the Academy Awards."
A celebrity list will be provided for the media tomorrow, although stars who visited Pacquiao while holding training camp at the Wild Card gym in Hollywood such as Mark Wahlberg, Sylvester Stallone, Robert Duvall, Liam Neeson, and Keanu Reeves are likely to be in attendance.
"Every name that you can imagine," said Arum. "What HBO did was it brought about US$3 million worth of tickets from us to bring in celebrities. And Showtime is doing the same thing."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Terminally ill man dies naturally after being granted right to end his life</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/terminally-ill-man-dies-naturally-after-being-granted-right-end-his-life-6305515?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The 65-year-old died of natural causes shortly after being granted the right to end his life in South Africa.</Description>
        <MainBody>Terminally ill man dies naturally after being granted right to end his life
Published: 8:08AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: AP

South Africa right to die display - Source: AP
A terminally ill man died of natural causes shortly after he was granted the right to end his life in South Africa, where euthanasia is illegal.
In a first-of-its-kind ruling for South Africa, Judge Hans Fabricius said that Robin Stransham-Ford could be euthanised with no legal or professional consequences for the doctor who would participate. But Stransham-Ford died before that could happen.
"He died before the legal injection was delivered, so a peaceful, natural death," said Sean Davison, founder of the group DignitySA.
Stransham-Ford, 65, only had weeks to live, said DignitySA, which supported his court bid and picketed outside the courthouse in the capital Pretoria. He had prostate cancer and the medication used to manage his pain left him constantly sedated, the group said in a statement.
Stransham-Ford, who was being cared for by the mother of his 12-year-old daughter, died in his home in Cape Town with his family, which is what he wanted.
"I wish to end my life with dignity, surrounded by my loved ones, while I am able to breathe on my own, speak to my loved ones and see and hear them," Stransham-Ford told Fabricius, according to a local newspaper, the Pretoria News.
The Justice Department said before Stransham-Ford died that it planned to appeal Fabricius' decision.
Advertisement
Willem Landman of DignitySA said the group would welcome an appeal as a chance to test the right to die against the constitution.
The law currently regards assisted suicide in the same way as homicide or murder. In his court order granting the assisted suicide, Fabricius said this limited the constitutional right to dignity.
But the judge said the decision was not an endorsement of proposed assisted suicide legislation that has languished since it was submitted to the country's justice and health departments 17 years ago.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Black Caps rise to third in the world in one-day rankings</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/cricket-news/black-caps-rise-third-in-world-one-day-rankings-6305514?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The Black Caps have risen to third in the one-day cricket rankings after making the World Cup final</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

The Black Caps have risen to third in the one-day cricket rankings after making the World Cup final.
Australia's thumping World Cup victory has solidified their place at the top of the one-day cricket rankings.
Australia has moved to 129 points in the latest rankings, doubling its lead from six to 12 points over the second-placed nation following the World Cup, in which Australia crushed trans-Tasman rivals New Zealand by seven wickets in the final.
Despite the loss, New Zealand has also received a ratings boost, jumping eight points to leapfrog South Africa into third place.
England, who failed to reach the knockout stages of the World Cup, have felt the heaviest blow for their failings, dropping seven rankings points while remaining in sixth place.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Claim Gloriavale treating women like 'mushrooms', calls for end to Govt funding</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/claim-gloriavale-treating-women-like-mushrooms-calls-end-govt-funding-6305513?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Women at Gloriavale are educated to stay and have babies and serve in the kitchen their whole lives, an education lobbyist says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Claim Gloriavale treating women like 'mushrooms', calls for end to Govt funding
Published: 8:02AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
The 'greatest concentration of virgin young people': A rare look inside Gloriavale video
Women at Gloriavale are being treated like mushrooms to have a life of breeding, an education lobbyist says.
Dr Liz Gordon says the school at the isolated Christian sect on the West Coast is registered even though "the education offered there is substandard".
"Women are free to leave but they're educated to stay and have babies and serve in the kitchen their whole lives," says Ms Gordon who is co-convenor of the Quality Public Education Coalition.
Ms Gordon has been researching the school for three years and believes it should be denied government funding.
"I think the Education Act is totally inadequate, all it says is that the education has to meet the needs of the community but that community holds women down.
"The legislation should require that all New Zealand children are taught the New Zealand curriculum that upholds rights of the child."
Ms Gordon says education should be about liberation and making a better life and while Gloriavale is a highly stable community she doesn't believe it is the life for the 21st century.
It is based on the Old Testament, says Ms Gordon, adding that the issue is about the lives and freedoms of 200 children who get no health education, no sex education, no examination of science.
"I think this is a very damaging education that they get."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'I wouldn't eat there' - public weighs in on burger bar boss's rant</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/i-wouldn-t-eat-there-public-weighs-in-burger-bar-boss-s-rant-6305475?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Is it okay for an eatery to post an expletive-laden rant to Facebook after receiving a food poisoning complaint?</Description>
        <MainBody>Wellington burger bar boss blasts customer for food poisoning complaint
Is it ever okay for an eatery to post an expletive-laden rant to Facebook after receiving a food poisoning complaint? ONE News Facebook readers say no.
Mike Duffy, owner of a popular Wellington burger bar Ekim Burger, was yesterday simultaneously praised and chastised for ranting at a woman who said her son "vomited all Friday night" after eating at his burger place.
"Almost 20 years in this f****** industry and never had a person who ate what I cook get sick from it," Mr Duffy wrote.
Several ONE News readers have hit out at Mr Duffy's reaction on the ONE News Facebook page.
Karyn Booker wrote: "I wouldn't eat there after doing this from a private message, wasn't even a complaint. It was just letting him know politely he 'may' have a problem. AND he got all personal and abusive. Plenty of other places to eat." It was the most liked comment.
Ryan Foley said the woman's comments "should be taken seriously".
"May not be food poisoning but the boss is obligated to look into it. It is his responsibility to ensure his staff follow safe work practices," Mr Foley added.
Anthony Wilson chimed in: "She was polite and courteous in her PRIVATE message to him. He outed her on social media and brought the attention to himself. They could have resolved the issue between each other but he has chosen to make it public. That's silly management, but according to his interview with Stuff, he doesn't care. Oh well, there are other burger joints."
Rita Cochrane said his response was over the top and the restaurant was a "place to never bother eating at".
Advertisement
Brian Donaldson commented: "As a business owner myself I think it's unacceptable. Sure you may have the odd challenging customer - but there are amazing customers that make up for it. Think he needs a holiday!"
Mr Duffy stood by his comments and did not apologise when contacted by media for comment.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 22:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds of events planned for NZ Music Month</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/entertainment-news/hundreds-events-planned-nz-music-month-6305493?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>NZ Music Month gets underway today as an annual celebration of homegrown music and the people who make it.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hundreds of events planned for NZ Music Month
Published: 7:03AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

NZ Music Month gets underway today as an annual celebration of homegrown music and the people who make it.
Local music will be showcased in libraries, schools and parks as well as on screens and music systems.
More than 700 events are planned around the country for the 15th celebration of local talent and music.
To kick it all off in Auckland Play It Strange and Orbitsound are hosting three up and coming artists, Under Cover, a mini-festival showcase of Wellington musicians, is being held at capital's Meow and in Christchurch Martin Phillipps from The Chills, Minisnap and the Swan Sisters are at the Peterborough Street Library .
For a full run down of events, updates, links and info about all the fantastic music click here

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 21:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chilean volcano erupts again, forcing renewed evacuations</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/chilean-volcano-erupts-again-forcing-renewed-evacuations-6305483?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Calbuco volcano has sent more bursts of ash and hot rock four kilometres into the air, following two huge blasts last week.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chilean volcano erupts again, forcing renewed evacuations
Published: 6:26AM Friday May 01, 2015 Source: AP
Two thousand flee Chile volcano (0:28)
The Calbuco volcano has erupted again, sending dark bursts of ash and hot rock billowing 4 kilometres into the air and prompting Chilean officials to order a new evacuation of nearby residents.
Thick clouds boiled out of the 2,000-metre cone, bringing the threat of new, heavy ash fall over villagers struggling to clean up from two huge blasts last week.
The area was evacuated after the volcano first erupted last Wednesday afternoon, but many people had begun to return to their ash-drowned homes.
The eruptions at the Calbuco are the first in more than four decades. About 4,500 people have been evacuated since the Calbuco roared back to life on April 22, sending ash about 18 km into the sky.
The ash spread across the southern part of the continent, disrupting flights in Argentina's capital, Buenos Aires.
"This latest eruption is much smaller than the other two," Deputy Interior Minister Mahmud Aleuy said, adding that while the situation is not dangerous so far, some 2,500 people will be evacuated.
"We're talking about a plume that is about four kilometres and that is directed toward the southern part of the volcano, so we shouldn't have major problems except for those who live in the south of the volcano and who will be hit by ash."
The director of the National Mining and Geology service warned that forecast rain could lead to devastating volcanic mud, known as lahars, which are capable of levelling anything in their path once in motion.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
