<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="tvnz">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Multiple people in custody after one beheaded in attack on a French factory </title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/multiple-people-in-custody-after-one-beheaded-attack-french-factory-6347844?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>An attack at a gas factory has left one person decapitated and multiple people wounded.</Description>
        <MainBody>Multiple people in custody after one beheaded in attack on a French factory
Published: 10:55PM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: AP

Police working outside plant of attack in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon, France. - Source: AP
Emergency services at the scene outside a factory where a man was allegedly beheaded, in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, France - Source: AP
An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory Friday in southeastern France, and a severed head was staked on a post at the entrance, officials said. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.
Two people were injured, authorities said.
President Francois Hollande, speaking in Brussels, said the attack began shortly before 10 a.m. when a car crashed through the gate of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon. The car then plowed into gas canisters, touching off an explosion, he said.
"No doubt about the intention - to cause an explosion," Hollande said, calling the attack "of a terrorist nature."
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said a man who had been flagged in 2006 for suspected ties to extremists was seized by an alert firefighter, one of multiple people in custody after the attack.
He said authorities were trying to identify the victim whose severed head was posted at the factory's entrance.
"People who could have participated in this abject crime are in custody," he said.
Cazeneuve said the suspect had been known to intelligence services, who had him under surveillance from 2006-08. The man is from the Lyon region, he said.
A severed head was found staked on a gate at the factory's entrance, in what appeared to be an echo of the Islamic State group's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see.
An official said two flags - one white and one black, both with Arabic inscriptions - were found nearby.
Advertisement
The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to release details to the media, said the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
France's anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, and potential charges including plotting as part of "a terrorist group."
Hollande spoke after watching TV news reports about the attack with German Chancellor Angela Merkel as both leaders attended a European Union summit in Brussels.
The industrial site belongs to Air Products, an American chemical company based in Allentown, Pennsylvania. The company would not confirm whether any employees were injured or killed.
"Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for," the company said in a statement.
"The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
Cazeneuve said the investigation had just begun and cautioned against jumping to conclusions.
France went on high alert after attacks in January against the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, a kosher grocery store and a policewoman that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including three Islamic extremist attackers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:53:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Women gush over brooding gorilla with 'ripped muscles'</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/women-gush-over-brooding-gorilla-ripped-muscles-6347806?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Young girls have gone bananas for perhaps the most handsome ape in captivity.</Description>
        <MainBody>Women gush over brooding gorilla with 'ripped muscles'
Published: 8:53PM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: ONE News

Young girls have gone bananas for perhaps the most handsome ape in captivity.
Shabani, a western lowland gorilla, has been described as a "heart-throb" and responsible for a huge spike in female visitor numbers at the Higashiyama Zoo and Botanical Gardens in Japan, News Corp reports.
Originally from Sydney's Taronga Zoo, Shabani has been admired for his "brooding poses", "ripped muscles" and "flirtatious glances".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kiwi's near miss as sightseeing plane crashes in Alaska</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/kiwi-s-near-miss-sightseeing-plane-crashes-in-alaska-6347700?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A Kiwi on holiday in Alaska very nearly boarded a tourist flight which has crashed today.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kiwi's near miss as sightseeing plane crashes in Alaska
Published: 6:16PM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: ONE News

A map showing the location of a sightseeing plane crash in Alaska - Source: Google Maps
A Kiwi on holiday in Alaska very nearly boarded a tourist flight which has crashed today.
The sightseeing plane crashed near Ella Lake in Alaska, the Holland America cruise line said in a statement today, and the condition of the plane and its passengers was not known.
The United States Coastguard and Alaskan authorities were on their way to the site, more than 250m above a lake on a cliff face.
Kiwi Sam Caughey tweeted that her mother was very nearly on that flight.
"Just got word from my mum...she pulled out of a scenic flight in Alaska...plane just reported as crashed," she wrote.
"What a near miss. So sorry to all those on board."
Eight passengers and a pilot were aboard the floating plane owned by Promech Air.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 06:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Oh, sorry!' - police let white comedienne who tries to sell them drugs walk away</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/oh-sorry-police-let-white-comedienne-tries-sell-them-drugs-walk-away-6347638?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>An American comedienne faced no consequences after trying to sell two police officers antidepressants in a video she made to illustrate white privilege.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

US comedienne Jessie Kahnweiler tries to sell prescription drugs to police with no consequences - Source: Jessie Kahnweiler/YouTube
Watch Video
Comedian offers to sell drugs to pair of cops (0:44)
An American comedienne faced no consequences after trying to sell two police officers antidepressants in a video she made to illustrate white privilege.
Jessie Kahnweiler, 30, posted a video to YouTube which she captioned: "Jessie sets out to see if white privilege really exists and can she get arrested or will her whiteness prevent it?"
The video comes at a time when racial tensions in parts of America with police are high, with several high-profile cases of undue police force against minorities hitting the headlines recently.
"My one black friend told me that because I'm white, I have all of these privileges, and I get treated totally different by the cops than black people get treated," she says in the video.
In the video, she drinks in public, cartwheels naked in front of a restaurant and ultimately tries to sell prescription medicine to police officers - with no apparent consequences.
"Those are prescribed drugs, and you are becoming a drug dealer by selling them," a police offer tells her.
"Oh, sorry!" she says, and walks away.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Promise of 'gay conversion' therapy a fraud - US jury finds</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/promise-gay-conversion-therapy-fraud-us-jury-finds-6347547?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>An organisation's claim that it could turn gay men straight violated New Jersey's Consumer Fraud Act.</Description>
        <MainBody>
Arthur Goldberg - Source: AP
A nonprofit organisation that claimed it could turn gay men straight violated New Jersey's Consumer Fraud Act, a jury concluded in a civil trial that an attorney for the plaintiffs called "a momentous event" for LGBT rights.
The jury said that Jews Offering New Alternatives for Healing, co-founder Arthur Goldberg and counsellor Alan Downing made misrepresentations and engaged in unconscionable business practices.
Three men and two parents were awarded more than $100,000 in damages.
The judge will rule later on their request to revoke the company's license, plaintiffs' attorneys said.
"This is a momentous event in the history of LGBT rights," attorney David Dinielli said. "The same lies that motivate gay conversion therapy motivate homophobia - that gay people are broken and need to be fixed. The strength of our plaintiffs brought that to light."
Attorneys for the plaintiffs argued during the trial that the group, known by the acronym JONAH, claimed a success rate that wasn't backed up by actual statistics and used therapy methods that had no scientific basis, including having one client beat a pillow, meant to represent his mother, with a tennis racket.
In an emailed statement, defence attorney Charles LiMandri called the verdict "a sad day, not just for my clients, but for America."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Irate French taxi drivers smash cars in strike against Uber</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/irate-french-taxi-drivers-smash-cars-in-strike-against-uber-6347512?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The taxi drivers went on the offensive against Uber, smashing cars, setting tires ablaze and blocking traffic.</Description>
        <MainBody>Irate French taxi drivers smash cars in strike against Uber
Published: 11:19AM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

French taxi drivers pulled out the throttle in an all-out confrontation with the ultra-cheap Uber car service, smashing livery cars, setting tires ablaze and blocking traffic during a nationwide strike that caught tourists and celebrities alike in the mayhem.
Travellers going to and from the airport were forced to walk alongside highways with their bags, while others, including singer Courtney Love, had their cars set upon by striking taxi drivers.
Dude @kanyewest we may turn back to the airport and hide out with u.picketers just attacked our car #ParisUberStrike pic.twitter.com/MtanurybOO
 Courtney Love Cobain (@Courtney) June 25, 2015

The French government was aghast, with Prime Minister Manuel Valls lamenting: "These incidents give a deplorable image to visitors of our country."
Taxi drivers justified their rage, saying Uber's lowest-cost service UberPop was ruining their livihoods.
Despite repeated rulings against it and an October law that explicitly outlaws UberPop, its drivers continue to ply French roads and the American ride-hailing company is actively recruiting drivers and passengers alike. Uber claims to have a total of 400,000 customers a month in France.
Advertisement
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve rushed back from a trip to Marseille to meet with taxi unions, declaring afterward that UberPop must be shut down and its vehicles seized if caught by police carrying passengers. He said 70 vehicles had been damaged around France in yesterday's protests and 10 people were arrested.
Taxi drivers in other European countries also complain that car services like Uber unfairly undercut them.
A judge ordered a temporary suspension in Spain, and in the Netherlands a Dutch court has ruled that UberPop must stop service. A world away, in China, the government banned drivers of private cars from offering services through an app.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Doctor says US movie massacre accused was insane at time of shooting </title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/doctor-says-us-movie-massacre-accused-insane-time-shooting-6347438?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Woodcock testified today that Holmes had a strong family history of mental illness and was in the grip of a psychotic compulsion.</Description>
        <MainBody>Doctor says US movie massacre accused was insane at time of shooting
Published: 9:30AM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: AP
James E. Holmes appears in Arapahoe County District Court in Centennial, Colo. - Source: AP
Related
Biggest jury selection in US history begins in Batman movie massacre trial
A psychiatrist who determined that Colorado theater shooter James Holmes was insane at the time of the 2012 shootings says that people suffering from delusions can't always control behavior - even if they know the behavior is wrong.
Dr. Jonathan Woodcock interviewed Holmes four days after the attack and concluded that he wasn't sane. Two other court-appointed psychiatrists later concluded that Holmes was sane at the time of the attack.
Woodcock testified today that Holmes had a strong family history of mental illness and was in the grip of a psychotic compulsion he could not control.
He said Holmes' emotions also were extremely flat. About midway through the two-hour jail interview, Woodcock said Holmes said he was bored. That kind of reaction in the wake of the mass shooting helped Woodcock conclude that Holmes was suffering from significant mental illness.
Two court-appointed psychiatrists concluded that Holmes was sane at the time of the attack. They interviewed Holmes much later - in December 2013 and July 2014.
Jonathan Woodcock is an assistant professor of neurology and psychiatry at the University of Colorado's medical campus, the school where James Holmes was studying before the July 2012 attack. He didn't treat Holmes before the attack; the defense asked him to interview Holmes after.
A total of 12 people were killed and 70 were injured when the 27-year-old opened fire in the packed cinema in Denver in 2012, where The Dark Knight Rises was playing.
Holmes has admitted he carried out the killings but has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mother and baby survive days in the jungle after plane crash</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/mother-and-baby-survive-days-in-jungle-after-plane-crash-6347348?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The pilot died in the crash but the mother and baby were rescued after four days lost in the Colombian jungle.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mother and baby survive days in the jungle after plane crash
Published: 6:29AM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

A woman who survived a plane crash with her months-old baby, drinking water to stay alive, was finally rescued after four days lost in the jungle, Colombia's air force and rescuers said.
Maria Nelly Murillo and her child were aboard a twin-engine Cessna that crashed last weekend in a remote area of western Colombia shortly taking flight from the city of Quibdo, the air force said.
The pilot was killed, but rescuers said a heavy load of fresh fish in the cabin absorbed much of the crash impact, allowing Murillo and her son to survive against the odds.
She forced open the cabin door and climbed a hill to get away from the aircraft, which she feared might explode, the air force reported.
Apparently disoriented, she wandered in the jungle carrying her child, surviving on coconut water and trying unsuccessfully to trap rodents for food, said Acisclo Renteria, the Red Cross volunteer who eventually found her.
Searchers reached the plane two days after the crash but found the two passengers missing.
The air force said it sent out a helicopter with a loudspeaker urging the woman to return to the crash site, and Renteria said a team of about 40 people began to search for her. They were aided, he said, by a trail of clues left by Murillo, including a flip flop sandal, her son's birth certificate, a cellular phone and the remains of coconuts.
Advertisement
But after two more days, as rescuers began to lose hope, Renteria said he spotted a buzzing circle of flies hovering over something on the ground. As he approached, Murillo began to shout for help and attempted to get to her feet in a state of near-starvation and apparent shock.
"I told her 'Mama, Mama, be calm. The Colombian Red Cross is here to rescue you,'" Renteria said.
Colombian woman and her baby survive lost in the jungle after plane crash
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Video: This bear belly-flopping into a pool is the happiest thing you'll see all day</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/video-bear-belly-flopping-into-pool-happiest-thing-you-ll-see-all-day-6347373?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Bruiser was born in 2011 and when fully grown will weigh about 270 kilograms. </Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

While New Zealand hovers around near-record low temperatures, four-year-old Bruiser the bear's busy focussing on where he can cool off.
The clever bear, at Single Vision wildlife park in Florida, can let himself in the free-standing pool after he learned to climb its ladder.
Bruiser was born in 2011 and when fully grown will weigh about 270 kilograms, the Single Vision website says.
His hobbies include swimming and tearing up boxes, and "Bruiser will also stand up on his back legs and walk around when he wants something from you, but sometimes he just wants to latch on and suckle".
Bruiser's friend Honey, a black bear who can be seen in the video, was born in 2014 and when fully grown will weigh about 130 kilograms.
Staff at the not-for-profit wildlife park provide him with a surfboard and other toys to play with in the pool.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Second prison worker accused of aiding escaped New York murderers</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/second-prison-worker-accused-aiding-escaped-new-york-murderers-6347343?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Gene Palmer admitted to providing the two inmates with tools, paint and even access to a catwalk electrical box.</Description>
        <MainBody>Second prison worker accused of aiding escaped New York murderers
Published: 6:07AM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

New York State troopers investigate an area at the intersection of Mt. View Ave. and County Route 27 in Mountain View, N.Y - Source: AP
Related
Woman who helped prisoners escape was a 'serial cheater' - ex-husband (0:26)
A second worker at a maximum-security prison accused of helping two murderers before their brazen escape was being arraigned today after being accused of delivering frozen meat to the men with tools hidden inside.
Prison guard Gene Palmer, 57, admitted to providing the two inmates with tools, paint and even access to a catwalk electrical box, but he says he never knew they planned to escape.
Officials at Clinton County Jail said Palmer was released just after midnight after using a credit card to pay his $25,000 bail.
His lawyer, Andrew Brockway, said his client will plead not guilty to charges of promoting prison contraband, tampering with physical evidence and official misconduct. Clinton County District Attorney Andrew Wylie said investigators have no proof Palmer knew hacksaw blades were embedded in the meat and have no indication he was knowingly involved in the escape.
Palmer's statement to authorities says he allowed one of the convicts access to an interior catwalk behind the men's adjacent cells that was later used in their escape. He says he did it to change the wiring on electrical boxes as "a favor" to make it easier for them to cook in their cells.
The statement also says he provided one of the men with paint and paintbrushes and provided the other on four separate occasions with needle-nose pliers and a screwdriver. In return, one of the inmates provided "information on the illegal acts that inmates were committing within the facility," Palmer's statement says.
After the escape, Palmer burned and buried the elaborate paintings he had received from one of the men, according to court documents. He had known both of the men for at least five years.
David Sweat and Richard Matt remained on the run after slipping out of the Clinton Correctional Facility on June 6. Authorities say they cut through the steel wall at the back of their cells, crawled down a catwalk, cut their way into and out of a steam pipe and emerged from a manhole outside the prison.
Sweat, 35, was serving a life sentence without parole in the killing of a sheriff's deputy. Matt, who turned 49 Thursday, was doing 25 years to life in the kidnapping, torture and hacksaw dismemberment of his former boss.
Advertisement
Prison employee Joyce Mitchell also has been charged with helping them escape. Mitchell, a prison tailor shop instructor, has pleaded not guilty and remains in custody.
Wylie said Mitchell told investigators she smuggled hacksaw blades, a screwdriver and other tools into the prison by placing them in the frozen meat. He said she placed the meat in a refrigerator in the tailor shop and Palmer took the meat to Sweat and Matt.
More than 1,000 searchers this week have focused on a section of a large wilderness area near the Canadian border after a man was seen running away from a hunting cabin Saturday morning and items inside had DNA evidence.
Challenges in the search include thick woods, bogs, biting bugs and the possibility that the two men are armed. The region in the coming days will get a surge of holiday visitors, including young campers.
Police still have no substantiated sightings of Sweat and Matt.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS militants re-enter Syrian town of Kobani</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/isis-militants-re-enter-syrian-town-kobani-6347341?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Islamic State militants have launched major attacks in northern Syria after a string of recent setbacks.</Description>
        <MainBody>Isis militants. - Source: ONE News
Related
ISIS recruiting scientists to build chemical weapons
Islamic State militants have launched major attacks in northern Syria after a string of recent setbacks, storming government-held areas in a mostly Kurdish city and setting off deadly car bombs as they pushed into a border town they were expelled from six months ago.
The two-pronged counter-offensive left dozens of people dead or wounded. On one front, Islamic State fighters advanced early in the morning into the northeastern city of Hassakeh, long split between Syrian Kurds and government forces, capturing parts of it.
The other push was into the Syrian border town of Kobani, which famously resisted a months-long IS assault before the extremists were driven out in January. An activist group said 12 people died in fighting in Kobani - the first time in six months the IS had managed to enter the town along the Turkish border - and that the militants had detonated three car bombs.
In the Kobani attack, the extremists donned Syrian rebel uniforms and carried flags of the mainstream Free Syrian Army to deceive the town's Kurdish defenders, said Redur Khalil, a spokesman for the Kurdish People's Protection Units, or YPG.
In Hassakeh, Khalil said IS militants attacked government-held neighbourhoods on the southern edge of the town, capturing some areas.
Syrian state TV reported intense clashes inside Hassakeh's southern neighbourhood of Nashawi. According to the report, IS fighters killed several people they captured in the city, including the head of a military housing institution. It said the militants sustained many casualties, including the commander of the group, who is a foreign fighter. IS tried to storm the city earlier this month and reached its southern outskirts before facing strong resistance from Syrian government troops who pushed them away.
The Hassakeh and Kobani attacks came just days after YPG fighters and their allies captured the Islamic State stronghold of Tal Abyad on the border with Turkey and the town of Ein Issa to the south. Kurdish fighters have been advancing since January under the cover of airstrikes by the US-led coalition.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Donors pledge $6.3 billion for earthquake-hit Nepal </title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/donors-pledge-6-3-billion-earthquake-hit-nepal-6347340?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The figure covers about two-thirds of what the Himalayan nation says it needs to rebuild.</Description>
        <MainBody>Amazing shots of life after the deadly Nepal earthquake (1:07)
Donor nations and agencies announced $US4.4 billion ($6.3b) in aid for Nepal today, covering about two-thirds of what the Himalayan nation says it needs to rebuild from devastating earthquakes that killed more than 8,800 people and made millions homeless.
Finance Minister Ram Sharan Mahat said the amount was pledged by donors that attended a one-day conference in Kathmandu.
The biggest pledge came from Nepal's large southern neighbor, India, which offered $1 billion in grants and low-interest loans.
"Nepal and India are joined in both their joys and sorrows. Therefore, we need to closely coordinate our disaster response, and help each other in the wake of such calamities," Indian External Affairs Minister Sushma Swaraj said.
Nepal says it needs about $6.7 billion for reconstruction following a magnitude-7.8 earthquake on April 25 and a magnitude-7.3 quake on May 12, which together killed 8,841 people. About 875,000 public and private buildings were damaged, according to the National Emergency Response Center.
Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi said his country would provide $483 million.
Asian Development Bank President Takehiko Nakao pledged $600 million.
"ADB will make the best use of its long-term experience in rehabilitation and reconstruction work after serious disasters," he said.
ADB is a major donor for Nepal and has supported several development projects in the past.
Advertisement
Japan said it would give $260 million and the United States $130 million. The World Bank has already announced $500 million for Nepal.
European Union's Neven Mimica said it would give $112 million to Nepal's government for spending on reconstruction.
Earlier, Mahat said Nepal's trade deficit will widen because of the earthquakes, but foreign reserves will remain adequate with transfers from the rest of the world increasing. The quakes destroyed factories and farmland, reducing exports and pushing up imports.
Revenue collection will face a shortfall of 8 percent during the current fiscal year, he said.
"This is the reason why we are looking to our development partners to fill a growing fiscal gap for the next three to five years," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:31:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heat wave subsides in Pakistan as death toll reaches 860 </title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/heat-wave-subsides-in-pakistan-death-toll-reaches-860-6347337?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The devastating heat wave is slowly subsiding.</Description>
        <MainBody>Heat wave subsides in Pakistan as death toll reaches 860
Published: 5:31AM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

The devastating heat wave that struck southern Pakistan last weekend is slowly subsiding but the toll was still climbing Thursday, to a total of 860 confirmed deaths, a senior health official said.
Jam Mehtab Hussain, the provincial health minister in the southern Sindh province, said people were still being admitted to hospitals with heat-related ailments - though in smaller numbers than in previous days, when dehydrated patients lay in hospital corridors and outside on the streets as overwhelmed medical staff struggled to cope with the disaster.
Ahmad Kamal, a spokesman for the National Disaster Management Authority, said authorities were providing free medical treatment to people in Karachi, the capital of Sindh province. He said the situation was improving due to lower temperatures.
On Thursday, the temperature dropped to 34 degrees Celsius (93.2 degrees Fahrenheit) in Karachi from a high of 45 degrees Celsius (113 degrees Fahrenheit) on Sunday.
TV footage showed ambulances transporting heatstroke patients to various hospitals in Karachi, where people continued holding small rallies against power outages, which had exacerbated the effects of the heat wave.
The heat wave was the worst seen in the city since 1979, officials said, and came as Muslims were fasting from dawn to dusk for the holy month of Ramadan.
The drinking of even a single drop of water invalidates the fast, but Muslims are also encouraged not to fast if they are sick or if doing so would cause serious physical harm.
Mohammad Ayaz said he and other Karachi residents were struggling to stay cool, with hundreds of people sleeping outside because of long power cuts.
Advertisement
Wakil Ahmed, another resident, said the weather had improved from previous days, when it was so hot it became difficult to breathe. He said Thursday brought clouds and a slight breeze.
Karachi is home to some 20 million people and has long suffered from an inefficient power grid and a shortage of potable water.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French woman goes on trial for deaths of 8 of her babies </title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/french-woman-goes-trial-deaths-8-her-babies-6347336?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Her lawyers are expected to argue that she was a victim of rape and incest, and ask for a lesser sentence. </Description>
        <MainBody>French woman goes on trial for deaths of 8 of her babies
Published: 5:24AM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

Dominique Cottrez, 51, appears with her lawyer Franck Berton, left, in the courtroom of Douai, northern France - Source: AP
One day in the summer of 2010, a man was digging in his garden in northern France when he discovered a trash bag containing the remains of an infant. When he summoned the police, they found the body of another newborn. A few days later, they found more bags in the garage - with six additional small corpses.
Police contacted the house's previous owners, and quickly discovered the horrifying explanation: Frenchwoman Dominique Cottrez confessed to secretly bearing and then killing eight of her newborns, saying she feared they were children of a long, incestuous relationship with her father.
Cottrez, a 51-year-old mother of two grown daughters, went on trial Thursday in the city of Douai, accused of multiple counts of first-degree murder of minors.
Cottrez wept as she took her seat. She faces life in prison if found guilty.
Her lawyers are expected to argue that she was a victim of rape and incest, and ask for a lesser sentence.
The worst infanticide case in modern French history stunned the country when the bodies were discovered in and around the Cottrez' former home in 2010.
Cottrez's obesity appeared to hide the pregnancies, which went unnoticed by her husband, children, neighbors, colleagues - and even doctors at a nearby hospital.
Advertisement
Dozens of forensic and psychiatric experts, police investigators and witnesses, including her husband, daughters and siblings, are scheduled to testify to help understand the incomprehensible, and perhaps to help the defendant open up.
A withdrawn, secretive nurse's aide, Cottrez told investigators she was raped by her father, first when she was 8 and repeatedly through her childhood and teenage years, according to judicial documents. She later entered a long, incestuous relationship with him as an adult, including after she married, and said that it became consenting - and even said she was in love with her father more than she was with her husband.
Her father died in 2007.
One of the first witnesses called to the stand Thursday is Leonard Meriaux, who bought the Cottrez family house and discovered the first corpse in 2010. He called police, who found another in the garden.
From one interrogation to another, the police went from surprise to stupor. Cottrez first admitted killing the two infants found in the garden. Then she herself informed the investigators that several other bodies were in the garage of the house, but she didn't know how many exactly, according to court documents.
She told the investigating judge that she had never used contraception or had an abortion because of a phobia of doctors. She also said she didn't keep the babies because she was afraid that they were the results of her incestuous relations with her father. She said the killing had become a "means of contraception," according to the judicial documents.
She said she told her father of the eight pregnancies and the eight murders, and investigators believe he could have helped her hide some of the bodies.
The death she described the most clearly is the first one, in 1989. She said she smothered the baby boy with sheets, placed him in a trash bag that she had prepared in advance, and put the bag in her wardrobe, according to the documents.
The second killing happened when she was hospitalized for an epilepsy seizure. She said she gave birth in the hospital toilet, strangled the child, wrapped it in plastic sheeting and towels, placed it in the closet of her hospital room and then brought it back home, hidden in her garment bag.
Her memories became blurred for the following births and deaths. The last infanticide was in 2000.
Her husband and daughters say they noticed foul odors in various parts of the house, but thought they came from sewage, or their dog, or even their father's feet.
Cottrez was released from jail in 2012 after spending two years in temporary detention. In a January interview with a local newspaper, she said: "I never gave first names to the babies. The first one, I saw he was a baby boy. The others, I didn't look, I didn't want to. But when they were in the garage, when it was cold, I went there and covered them with a blanket. "
The verdict is expected next Thursday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Support continues to flood into earthquake stricken Nepal</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/support-continues-flood-into-earthquake-stricken-nepal-6347331?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>More than $4 Billion in aid has been pledged to Nepal as the country recovers from a devastating earthquake. </Description>
        <MainBody>Support continues to flood into earthquake stricken Nepal
Published: 4:00AM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: AP

Damage following second earthquake in Nepal. - Source: ONE News
Foreign donor nations and agencies have announced $4.4 billion in aid for Nepal, covering about two-third of what the Himalayan nation says it needs to rebuild from devastating earthquakes that killed more than 8,800 people and made millions homeless.
Finance Minister Ram Sharan Mahat said the amount was pledged by donors that attended a one-day conference in Kathmandu.
The biggest pledge came from Nepal's large southern neighbor, India, which offered $1 billion in grants and low-interest loans.
"Nepal and India are joined in both their joys and sorrows. Therefore, we need to closely coordinate our disaster response, and help each other in the wake of such calamities," Indian External Affairs Minister Sushma Swaraj said.
Nepal says it needs about $6.7 billion for reconstruction following a magnitude-7.8 earthquake on April 25 and a magnitude-7.3 quake on May 12, which together killed 8,841 people. About 875,000 public and private buildings were damaged, according to the National Emergency Response Center.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 11:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bomb threat forces passenger plane into emergency landing</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/bomb-threat-forces-passenger-plane-into-emergency-landing-6347233?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>An Irish passenger jet was forced into an emergency landing in Poland after a tip-off about an explosive device.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bomb threat forces passenger plane into emergency landing
Published: 8:18PM Thursday June 25, 2015 Source: ONE News

A Ryanair flight was forced to land after a bomb scare - Source: Twitter
A European passenger jet has made an emergency landing because it is thought there were explosives on board.
The plane, operated by Irish airline Ryanair, was forced into an emergency landing during its flight from Oslo in Norway to Warsaw in Poland due to a bomb threat, Sky News reports .
The jet landed safely at Modlin airport, near the Polish capital, while police were searching the plane using bomb disposal experts, a police spokesman told Sky News.
Ryanair later said in a statement that the Modlin Airport received an anonymous call about an explosive device on the aircraft.
"The airport security authorities ordered an immediate inspection of the aircraft and closed the airport to inbound arrivals as a security precaution."
"Warsaw Modlin believes this is a hoax call and expect the security sweep to confirm this fact. They expect to release the aircraft and reopen the airport shortly," the statement read.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 07:21:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'You're in my house' - Obama shuts down heckler during LGBT speech</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/you-re-in-my-house-obama-shuts-down-heckler-during-lgbt-speech-6347085?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>U.S. President Barack Obama had a transsexual heckler removed during his speech today at the White House.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

United States President Barack Obama has banished a transsexual heckler during a civil rights speech at the White House today.
President Obama was midway through an address about lesbian, gay and transgender rights at the famous Pennsylvania Avenue home when he was rudely interrupted by a guest, The Daily Mail reports.
The person was later identified as transsexual Mexican campaigner Jennicet Gutierrez, and the abuse projected towards Obama was reportedly pre-planned to raise awareness about deportation centres.
After Ms Gutierrez failed to stop her protest, Obama intervened and said: "Okay, you know what? No, no, no, no, no. You're in my house."
"It's not respectful when you get invited ... You're not going to get a good response from me by interrupting me like this," the President said.
The crowd also started booing Ms Gutierrez, who said she was "tired of the abuse" against minorities from immigration officials in the United States.
"Shame on you. You shouldn't be doing this," Obama said, before the heckler was escorted from the White House.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 06:26:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cruel prank sees pro-footballer kidnapped and threatened with execution</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/cruel-prank-sees-pro-footballer-kidnapped-and-threatened-execution-6347047?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>An Algerian footballer was kidnapped by a group of "terrorists" and sent for execution during an elaborate stunt.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

An Algerian footballer was kidnapped by a group of masked, armed men and taken into the middle of the North African desert for execution before it was revealed to be a reality television stunt.
Madhid Bougherra, 32, who has played for English clubs Sheffield Wednesday and Charlton Athletic and Rangers in Scotland, was at a cafe with a friend when the elaborate prank began, Nine News reports.
Video of the practical joke shows hooded men waving weapons as they seize control of the cafe and capture the sports star.
Bougherra, who appears overwhelmed with fear, is then blindfolded and escorted by car into the Algerian desert for what appears to be a mock execution.
It is only after the footballer's blindfold is removed that it is revealed the prank was for Algerian television show Camera Cache, reportedly similar to MTV's show Punk'd.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 03:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boy suffers 'minor' shark bites off North Carolina</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/boy-suffers-minor-shark-bites-off-north-carolina-6346933?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>An 8-year-old boy suffered minor injuries after being bitten by a shark while swimming in Surf City.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boy suffers 'minor' shark bites off North Carolina
Published: 12:40PM Thursday June 25, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

Emergency responders assist a teenage girl at the scene of a shark attack in Oak Island, North Carolina - Source: AP
Related
An 8-year-old boy suffered minor injuries after being bitten by a shark yesterday while swimming in Surf City, North Carolina.
The incident is the fourth shark bite off a North Carolina beach in the past two weeks.
Town Manager Larry Bergman says the town does not plan to warn visitors about the shark bite or tell swimmers to get out of the water, but it has increased police beach patrols.
He said some beachgoers have approached police officers after hearing about the bite on social media.
Bergman said the boy had superficial wounds on his lower leg and ankle, and was treated by emergency personnel at the scene. Afterward, his parents took him to an emergency room to have the wounds cleaned.
"Police and EMS felt like it wasn't a serious bite," Bergman said.
The child had been swimming about five blocks from a fishing pier afternoon. Town policy prohibits people from swimming or surfing within 120 metres of a fishing pier, Bergman said.
On June 11, a 13-year-old girl suffered small cuts on her foot from a shark bite at Ocean Isle Beach. Three days later, two separate shark attacks occurred within 90 minutes at Oak Island, North Carolina. Both victims, ages 12 and 16, had an arm amputated after the attacks. One victim had been swimming about 100 metres from a fishing pier when she was attacked.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 03:32:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope: Separation may be needed to protect a weaker spouse or children</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/pope-separation-may-needed-protect-weaker-spouse-children-6346920?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis says sometimes the separation of a husband and wife may be "inevitable" or "even morally necessary".</Description>
        <MainBody>
Source: AP
Pope Francis says sometimes the separation of a husband and wife may be "inevitable" or "even morally necessary" to protect the "weaker spouse or small children."
Addressing damaging dynamics within families, the Pontiff said some troubled spouses are able to overcome their problems and revive their marriages. However, he said not all separated couples can do so.
"There are cases in which separation is inevitable. Sometimes it can become even morally necessary, precisely when it comes to subtracting the weaker spouse, or small children, from more serious injuries caused by arrogance and violence, by humiliation and exploitation ... and by indifference," the pope said, at his weekly general audience.
Francis has been making a series of statements about family issues ahead of a much-anticipated October synod, or meeting, of bishops to address the topic.
The bishops will take up many issues, including how the church can be more welcoming to divorced Catholics who remarry without going through the church process that declares their first marriage null.
"Let us ask the Lord for a strong faith to see with his eyes the reality of family life, and for a deep love to approach all families with his merciful heart," Francis said.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 02:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dictionary editors say twerking goes back almost 200 years</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/dictionary-editors-say-twerking-goes-back-almost-200-years-6346880?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Twerking has been admitted to the venerable Oxford English Dictionary.</Description>
        <MainBody>Dictionary editors say twerking goes back almost 200 years
Published: 11:45AM Thursday June 25, 2015 Source: AP
Young women jailed for twerking in front of WWII memorial (+video) video
Twerking may be older than you think.
The provocative dance that gained global fame thanks to an attention-grabbing performance by Miley Cyrus has been admitted to the venerable Oxford English Dictionary - and lexicographers say its origins go back almost 200 years.
The dictionary now describes twerking as dancing "in a sexually provocative manner, using thrusting movements of the bottom and hips while in a low, squatting stance."
It had previously listed the word, but then to refer to a twisting or jerking movement or twitch. Researchers found it used as a noun with that meaning in 1820, spelt "twirk." It became a verb by 1848, and the "twerk" spelling was popularly used by 1901.
Senior editor Fiona McPherson called revelations about the word's roots "quite spectacular."
She said the word as a description of a dance has its roots in the 1990s New Orleans music scene.
Other new entries, announced Thursday, include social-media term "twitterati" and smokers' helper "e-cigarette."
The OED charts the historical development of the English language and has stricter admission criteria than other Oxford dictionaries. New entries must have been in use in both news stories and fiction for at least 10 years.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:31:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WARNING: Horrifying GoPro vision of high speed motorcycle head on with truck</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/warning-horrifying-gopro-vision-high-speed-motorcycle-head-truck-6346701?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>If mums of the world needed more proof that motorcycles are dangerous, here it is. </Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

If the mothers of the world needed any more proof that motorcycles are dangerous, this crash is it.
Jesse Lopez, 24, was out for a cruise in the Angeles National Forest in California, so he strapped a GoPro to his head to capture the day.
Except when he entered a blind bend, instead of recording the sights, he captured what could have easily been his death.
Mr Lopez smashed into a truck, which was travelling around 80km/h at the time of impact, NBC Los Angeles reported.
"I don't remember what happened due to memory loss, but I might have panicked when I saw the truck," Mr Lopez told NBC LA.
"So I applied the front brake, which straightened me out and I went straight toward the truck."
Mr Lopez miraculously survived, suffering a broken femur, tibia, fibula, ulna and humerus.
The truck's driver was not injured.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 22:10:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tigers, baboons, camels abandoned by circus in Mexico</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/tigers-baboons-camels-abandoned-circus-in-mexico-6346027?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Six tigers, seven baboons, four camels and three dromedaries have been found abandoned in cages without food, water or adequate care in the southern Mexico state of Yucatan</Description>
        <MainBody>Tigers, baboons, camels abandoned by circus in Mexico
Published: 7:06AM Thursday June 25, 2015 Source: AP

Baboon - Source: iStock
Six tigers, seven baboons, four camels and three dromedaries have been found abandoned in cages without food, water or adequate care in the southern Mexico state of Yucatan.
The passage of laws forbidding animal acts in circuses has raised fears that the exotic species might be abandoned once they could no longer pay for their keep by performing.
The Attorney General's Office for Environmental Protection said a total of 20 animals were found near the city of Merida, many missing claws, teeth or fur.
Many were underweight or had scars or skin infections and the animals were seized.
A circus had been set up nearby.
"Circuses are urged to avoid fines for abandoning exotic animals," the office said. Circus owners say they will no longer be able to feed the animals if they can't show them.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 21:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hungary to build fence on Serbian border to shut out illegal immigrants</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/hungary-build-fence-serbian-border-shut-illegal-immigrants-6346010?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Hungary will build a temporary fence on the border with Serbia to stop the flow of illegal migrants.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hungary to build fence on Serbian border to shut out illegal immigrants
Published: 6:28AM Thursday June 25, 2015 Source: AP

Illegal migrants at the Tisza river, near Szeged, Hungary - Source: AP
Hungary will build a temporary fence on the border with Serbia as fast as possible to stop the flow of illegal migrants, the foreign minister said.
Austria, meanwhile, reacted angrily to Hungary's announcement that, for an indefinite period, it would not take back refugees it registered when they entered Hungary but left for other destinations in Europe before their asylum requests were decided.
Foreign Minister Peter Szijjarto said several laws needed to be amended before construction of the fence could begin so he could not say exactly when the work on the "temporary border seal" could start.
"In the future, we will apply temporary border seals on every border section where there is no other effective way to impede illegal immigration," Szijjarto said, adding that the government had set aside 6.5 billion forints (20.9 million euros) for the project.
Szijjarto said the fence, which is opposed by neighbouring Serbia, "is not a bilateral issue. Relations with Serbia have never been as good as now."
He said 61,000 migrants had entered Hungary this year, nearly all by crossing Hungary's southern border with Serbia. Most of those who request refugee status in Hungary quickly leave for other destinations in western Europe, like Austria, Germany and Sweden.
Austria's Foreign Ministry said that Foreign Minister Sebastian Kurz told Szijjarto that Hungary's suspension of the agreement on refugees was "unacceptable."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 21:40:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boston Bomber tells victims: I pray for your relief, for your healing</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/boston-bomber-tells-victims-i-pray-your-relief-healing-6346013?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev apologised for the deadly attack just before a judge formally sentenced him to death.</Description>
        <MainBody>Will Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev become a martyr? video
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev apologized for the deadly attack for the first time today, just before a judge formally sentenced him to death.
"I am sorry for the lives that I've taken, for the suffering that I've caused you, for the damage that I've done, irreparable damage," the 21-year-old college student said, breaking more than two years of public silence.
To the victims, he said: "I pray for your relief, for your healing."
His five-minute speech included religious references and praise of Allah. He paused several times, looking as if he was trying to remain composed. He stood and faced the judge while speaking, but spoke of the victims.
The apology came after Tsarnaev listened impassively for about three hours as victims and their loved ones lashed out at him for his "cowardly" and "disgusting" acts.
"He can't possibly have had a soul to do such a horrible thing," said Karen Rand McWatters, who lost a leg in the attack and whose best friend, 29-year-old Krystle Campbell, was killed.
Campbell's mother, Patricia Campbell, spoke directly to Tsarnaev.
"What you did to my daughter is disgusting," she said. "I don't know what to say to you. I think the jury did the right thing."
The judge was required under law to impose the jury's death sentence for the April 15, 2013, attack that killed three people and wounded more than 260.
Advertisement
An appeal is automatic in death penalty cases.
The only real suspense today was whether Tsarnaev would say anything when given a chance to speak near the end of the proceedings. He had said almost nothing publicly since his arrest more than two years ago.
U.S. District Judge George O'Toole Jr. said no one will remember that Tsarnaev's teachers or friends were fond of him. What they will remember is that he "murdered and maimed innocent people" and "did it willfully and intentionally."
Tsarnaev looked down and rubbed his hands together as the judge sentenced him.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 21:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anger, no surprise as US accused of spying in France</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/anger-no-surprise-us-accused-spying-in-france-6346005?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>France is demanding answers from the Obama administration while calling for an intelligence "code of conduct" between allies.</Description>
        <MainBody>Anger, no surprise as US accused of spying in France
Published: 5:58AM Thursday June 25, 2015 Source: AP

The sign outside the National Security Agency campus in Fort Meade - Source: AP
Embarrassed by leaked conversations of three successive French presidents and angered by new evidence of uninhibited American spying, France is demanding answers from the Obama administration while calling for an intelligence "code of conduct" between allies.
France's foreign minister summoned the US ambassador to respond to the WikiLeaks revelations, as French eyes fixed on the top floor of the US Embassy after reports that a nest of NSA surveillance equipment was concealed behind elaborately painted windows there, just down the block from the presidential Elysee Palace.
"Commitments were made by our American allies. They must be firmly recalled and strictly respected," Prime Minister Manuel Valls said. "Being loyal doesn't mean falling into line."
President Barack Obama told French President Francois Hollande in a phone conversation that the US wasn't targeting his communications. The White House said Obama told Hollande that the US was abiding by a commitment Obama made in 2013 not to spy on the French leader after Edward Snowden disclosed the extent of NSA surveillance powers.
The White House said Obama also pledged to continue close cooperation with France on matters of intelligence and security.
If not a surprise, the latest revelations put both countries in something of a quandary.
France's counter-espionage capabilities were called into question at the highest level. The United States, meanwhile, was shown not only to be eavesdropping on private conversations of its closest allies but also to be unable to keep its own secrets.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 20:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds dead as Pakistan swelters in heatwave</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/hundreds-dead-pakistan-swelters-in-heatwave-6345995?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>At least 749 people have been killed in a scorching heat wave in Pakistan as temperatures have begun to drop in the country</Description>
        <MainBody>Hundreds dead as Pakistan swelters in heatwave
Published: 5:44AM Thursday June 25, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

At least 749 people have been killed in a scorching heat wave in Pakistan as temperatures have begun to drop in the country.
Officials say the hardest-hit has been the port city of Karachi where temperatures have soared to 45 degrees Celsius.
Meteorologists say the heat wave is the worst in at least a decade.
Hours-long power outages, little running water and the majority of people fasting for the Muslim holy month of Ramadan had worsened the situation.
However slightly cooler temperatures yesterday appeared to be helping.
Hospital officials said admittances had dropped compared to previous days, when dehydrated patients lay in corridors and outside of clinics.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 20:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ebola showing no signs of slowing in parts of Africa</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/ebola-showing-no-signs-slowing-in-parts-africa-6346000?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The virus shows no signs of abating in Guinea and may be flaring up once more in Sierra Leone </Description>
        <MainBody>Ebola showing no signs of slowing in parts of Africa
Published: 5:47AM Thursday June 25, 2015 Source: AP
Ebola ruled out for healthcare worker video
Despite hopes that the deadly Ebola outbreak could soon be contained in West Africa, it shows no signs of abating in Guinea and may be flaring up once more in Sierra Leone as people are flouting rules limiting travel meant to stop it.
The election in Guinea in October adds a new layer of worry for Guineans and health workers, with some residents saying that campaign events, in which people crowd together, shouldn't be held yet.
The deadly virus, which has killed over 11,100 people mostly in West Africa in its worst outbreak ever, has been stamped out in neighboring Liberia, but is hanging on stubbornly in Guinea, where the Ebola outbreak was first reported in March 2014. Impending presidential elections could make it even worse.
"Ebola is on the rise again because of population movements. People move from one place to another," said Dr. Amadou Talibe, an Ebola response team worker in Dubreka, 30 kilometers (19 miles) north of capital, Conakry. "People who have come into contact with Ebola but have not been identified, they go to another village and only then develop the symptoms of Ebola and then contaminate others."
In Dubreka, a burial team put on protective equipment and sprayed themselves before entering a facility to collect the body of a baby, not even 20 hours old. They left with the newborn, wrapped and on a stretcher, for safe burial.
The virus, which is transmitted through direct contact with the bodily fluids of someone showing Ebola symptoms, has killed more than 2,400 people in Guinea, officials estimate. New cases keep cropping up because some communities refuse to follow safe burial practices, among other reasons.
Intense efforts are being made to identify the chain of transmission for the most recent cases, with checkpoints on roads and tracking down those infected. Some people are nervous about election campaigning.
"You have a lot of people gathering here. We are at risk of Ebola, yet we are gathering here. There are no preventative measures for us," said Abubacar Sylla at a campaign event in Conakry last week for President Alpha Conde.
Ebola also returned to Sierra Leone's capital, Freetown, last week after being absent for 18 consecutive days, officials there said. A third case was confirmed in government figures released Tuesday.
The first new case popped up in Freetown after a young man sick with the disease in another part of Sierra Leone ran away from a quarantine area and came to Freetown, said Patrick Fatoma, a spokesman for the National Ebola Response Center.
Advertisement
"Infected people are still running away from quarantine areas with the consequences of infecting other people. Right now we have 12 suspected high risk people on the run from the (Northern) Port Loko District," he said
Fatoma said health workers are mobilizing and engaging the local community so they are more aware of bad practices, providing support to quarantined homes and enforcing curfews in hotspots.
"If people do not change their attitude, there are bound to be more Ebola cases," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 13:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dutch court orders carbon emissions cuts to protect citizens from global warming</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/dutch-court-orders-carbon-emissions-cuts-protect-citizens-global-warming-6345926?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The ruling by The Hague District Court could set a precedent for similar cases aiming to protect people from climate change.</Description>
        <MainBody>Dutch court orders carbon emissions cuts to protect citizens from global warming
Published: 10:11PM Wednesday June 24, 2015 Source: AP

Alaska - Source: Photos.com
In a sweeping victory for Dutch environmental activists that could have global repercussions, a court ordered the government today to cut the country's greenhouse gas emissions by at least 25% by 2020.
The ruling by The Hague District Court could lay the foundations for similar cases around the world, said the director of the organisation that took the government to court on behalf of 900 Dutch citizens.
The plaintiffs argued - and the court agreed - that the government has a legal obligation to protect its people against looming dangers, including the effects of climate change on this low-lying country, much of which is below sea level and vulnerable to rising sea levels caused by global warming.
"This is a great victory - the judge said exactly what we wanted and had the courage and wisdom to say to the government 'you have a duty of care toward your citizens,'" said Marjan Minnesma, director of Urgenda, the group that filed the case.
Climate activists in the packed courtroom clapped and cheered as Presiding Judge Hans Hofhuis read the ruling.
"A courageous judge. This is fantastic," said Sharona Ceha, another Urgenda worker. "This is for my children and grandchildren."
Dutch government lawyers swiftly left the courtroom after the judgment and could not immediately be reached for comment.
Advertisement
The court said, based on current government climate policy, the Netherlands will cut its emissions by only 17% by 2020, compared with benchmark 1990 levels.
"The state must do more to avert the imminent danger caused by climate change, also in view of its duty of care to protect and improve the living environment," read a statement from the court.
The Dutch government can appeal the ruling to a higher court.
It remains unclear exactly how the court can enforce its ruling. It has the power to impose fines for failure to carry out its orders, but never uses such powers against the government and Urgenda did not request such a move, said judge Peter Blok.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
