<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="tvnz">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:57:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece's future in the eurozone looking increasingly shaky</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/greece-s-future-in-eurozone-looking-increasingly-shaky-6348510?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Greece's parliament voted early today to hold a July referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece's future in the eurozone looking increasingly shaky
Published: 8:57PM Sunday June 28, 2015 Source: AP

Greece's parliament voted to hold a referendum on creditor proposals for reforms - Source: AP
Greece's parliament voted early today in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans, with the country's future in the eurozone looking increasingly shaky.
Tsipras' surprise call stunned Greece's international debt negotiators, and the country took a big step closer to falling out of the euro currency union after fellow eurozone member states refused to extend its bailout program past its expiry date on Tuesday, leaving Greece on the brink of financial chaos.
In the streets of Greece, worried people queued outside banks for cash from dawn to dusk after Tsipras' announcement in the early hours of Saturday, after billions of euros had already been emptied in the preceding weeks.
Greece has a 1.6 billion euro ($NZD 2.61 billion) debt due to the International Monetary Fund on Tuesday and its bailout program expires the same day, after which it is unclear how the country might survive financially.
The referendum is set for next Sunday with the question on whether to accept proposed reforms needed to get bailout loans from other eurozone countries and the IMF. The government is advocating a rejection of the proposals.
The radical left-wing leader accused the creditors of using blackmail and ultimatums against his proud but struggling people. European officials and all Greek opposition parties except the extremist far-right Golden Dawn party called his move for a vote a foolish and rash gambit that effectively ended negotiations to keep Greece financially afloat.
The sudden move comes after five months of stalemated negotiations, with Tsipras accusing creditors of trying to strong-arm his country into taking harsh austerity measures he says would hammer an economy already on its knees after months of creditor-demanded spending cuts and tax hikes.
Advertisement
"They didn't ask us to agree, they asked us to surrender our political dignity," Tsipras said during a tumultuous and nearly 13-hour parliamentary session that cumulated in a vote just before 3am. Out of parliament's 300 lawmakers, 178 voted in favor and 120 against, with two people absent.
He insisted the Greek side had "exhausted every limit" of concessions so there could be an agreement, adding that "perhaps some saw that as a weakness."
The referendum move further crumbled already strained relations between Greece and its European partners, but Tsipras dismissed harsh criticism from other European countries on his decision.
"The referendum will take place as scheduled, next Sunday, whether our partners want it or not," he said.
Without a bailout program extension or more loans from creditors, Greece is likely to be in arrears on a debt payment due the same day. Its banks face the risk of collapse.
Now much will depend on whether the European Central Bank will accept to continue to prop up Greek banks even after the country's bailout program expires. It would be under huge pressure to stop using eurozone taxpayer money to keep alive the banks if there is no prospect for a deal.
If Greece's banks collapse, the government would have to support them itself. Penniless, it would have to revert to printing a new currency, effectively drawing the country out of the euro union.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Concerns Pacific neighbour Nauru is moving towards a dictatorship</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/concerns-pacific-neighbour-nauru-moving-towards-dictatorship-6348464?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A Wellington family has been forcibly separated from its Naruan MP father and husband.</Description>
        <MainBody>Concerns Pacific neighbour Nauru is moving towards a dictatorship
Published: 6:59PM Sunday June 28, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

A Wellington family has been forcibly separated from its father and husband as concerns mount over democracy on the island of Nauru.
Growing tension and reports of restrictions on freedom have drawn the attention of the New Zealand Government.
The Wellington-based Kun family have been forcibly separated from their Nauru opposition MP dad, Roland Kun. When he boarded his plane to join them in New Zealand he was hauled off by Nauruan officials and had his passport cancelled.
"I was deemed a risk to the nation. And the other reason was there were criminal investigations with which I was directly linked," Mr Kun told ONE News in a telephone interview.
The criminal investigation relates to protests last week at Parliament. Three opposition MPs have been charged, two of them imprisoned, accused by the Government of trying to destabilise it. Mr Kun is under investigation, having been suspended from Parliament a year ago.
"We are concerned to hear that there have been steps taken that might impinge on the liberties of individuals, and particularly elected representatives," says Murray McCully, New Zealand Foreign Minister.
The arrests are the latest in what critics say are moves towards a dictatorship. The Nauruan Government has suspended five opposition MPs, banned the use of Facebook, deported outspoken foreigners and introduced a law where threatening public order can result in up to seven years in jail.
"It's an attempt to try and stifle democracy in a way that is not good for the future of the country," says Dr Steven Ratuva of Canterbury University.
Advertisement
New Zealand gives $2 million a year towards Nauru's justice system and wants some answers over recent events. Mr McCully will be meeting with Nauru's president early next month, but it's also drawing international attention.
"It's serious enough for the Pacific Islands Forum to seriously look at what it can do," says Dr Ratuva.
The Nauru Government insists it is upholding law and order, looking after the best interests of its people. But those on the receiving end, including the Kun family, are paying a harsh price.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 07:05:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Daredevil surfers flock to ride 'Australia's biggest ever wave'</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/daredevil-surfers-flock-ride-australia-s-biggest-ever-wave-6348404?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>One surfer badly broke his leg while attempting to ride the massive waves off Western Australia. </Description>
        <MainBody>Daredevil surfers flock to ride 'Australia's biggest ever wave'
Published: 4:06PM Sunday June 28, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

Big wave surfers have travelled to Western Australia to catch a "once in a decade swell", which has already left one thrill seeker with a badly broken leg.
Gold Coast surfer Justin Holland told Nine News he flew to Gracetown, south of Perth near Margaret River, to catch the massive waves at open-ocean surf break Cow Bombie.
However, the brave father of two was swamped by a massive wall of whitewater, breaking his leg, after he rode the giant for several seconds.
"His left femur is completely broken ... It was one of the biggest waves ridden in Australia, for sure," Mr Holland's jet ski tow-in partner Jamie Mitchell told Perth Now .
Mr Holland has been taken to a Bunbury hospital for surgery.
Photographer Jamie Scott was filming the event and said the wave was "huge" with an 18-21m face.
The swell has been generated by a low pressure system in the Southern Ocean, and the conditions have been described as a "once in a decade".
The biggest wave ever ridden was reportedly a 33m monster off the coast of Portugal two years ago.
 World Surf League (@wsl) June 27, 2015

One bloke caught the lip of a monster at Cow Bombie. Left leg injured. Towed in by jet ski. @abcnewsPerth pic.twitter.com/gZtDu8WDX8
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 03:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Disney World bans selfie sticks</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/disney-bans-selfie-sticks-6348334?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Growing safety concern for both our guests and cast have seen the selfie stick get the boot from Disney World.</Description>
        <MainBody>Disney World bans selfie sticks
Published: 12:18PM Sunday June 28, 2015 Source: AP
A typical selfie stick scenario - a group photo with friends - Source: Wikimedia Commons
Don't bring your selfie stick to Disney World.
Officials announced that a ban takes effect Wednesday at all four Disney theme parks in Orlando, Florida. Selfie sticks will also be banned at Disneyland Resort in California and at Disney's parks in Paris and Hong Kong starting July 1.
Spokeswoman Kim Prunty tells the Orlando Sentinel that selfie-sticks have become a "growing safety concern for both our guests and cast."
Officials say guests will have the option of turning in their selfie sticks for pick-up later, or returning them to their cars or hotel rooms.
The sticks have been banned at a growing list of museums, music festivals and sports venues.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Horrifying explosion injures hundreds at Taiwan waterpark</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/horrifying-explosion-injures-hundreds-taiwan-waterpark-6348237?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Unknown powder set off fire near stage spreading into crowd of 1,000 spectators.</Description>
        <MainBody>Horrifying explosion injures hundreds at Taiwan waterpark
Published: 5:13AM Sunday June 28, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200 people, authorities said.
An accidental explosion of an unknown powder set off the fire near the stage in front of about 1,000 spectators, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command center.
Wang said 83 people had serious injuries and 131 others have light injuries.
Taiwan's Central News Agency reported the fire at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City near the island's capital was quickly brought under control.
Video showed rescue workers and bystanders carrying burned and injured people on their backs, in inflatable boats and on stretchers to get medical treatment.
CNA reported witnesses as saying the fire spread quickly after the colored powder was blown into the air.
It wasn't clear if the powder was part of a performance. The cause of the fire is being investigated.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police still on the hunt for last standing prison escapee </title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/police-still-hunt-last-standing-prison-escapee-6348320?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Police hope little food, sleep, biting bugs and another night of rain will wear the escaped prisoner down. </Description>
        <MainBody>Police still on the hunt for last standing prison escapee
Published: 11:20AM Sunday June 28, 2015 Source: AP
Escaped New York murderer involved in shootout with police video
With one escaped prisoner shot dead, police hoped that the other one still on the run in a remote New York forest will quickly be worn down by lack of sleep, little food, biting bugs and another night of rain.
Richard Matt, who once vowed never to be taken alive, was fatally shot during an encounter with border patrol agents yesterday, almost three weeks after he and David Sweat staged an elaborate breakout from a maximum-security prison.
More than 1,200 searchers remained focused intensely on 56 sq. kilometres of thick forests and heavy brush around where Matt was killed.
"Anyone in the woods and on the run from the law, so to speak is not getting a full eight hours sleep, they're not eating well and they have to keep moving," Franklin County Sheriff Kevin Mulverhill said of Sweat. "He's fatigued, tired, and he's going to make a mistake."
Sweat also could have an even tougher time now without someone to take turns resting with and watch his back, said Clinton County Sheriff David Favro. "And I'm sure fatigue is setting in for him as well, knowing the guy he was with has already been shot."
The manhunt broke open when a person towing a camper heard a loud noise and thought a tire had blown. Finding nothing, the driver drove on before looking again and finding a bullet hole in the trailer. A tactical team responding to the scene of the gunshot smelled gunpowder inside a cabin and saw evidence that someone had fled.
A noise, perhaps a cough, ultimately did Matt in. A border patrol team discovered the escaped prisoner, who was shot after failing to obey a command to raise his hands.
Matt had a shotgun. He and Sweat apparently had been relying on the region's many hunting camps and seasonal dwellings for supplies.
Matt, who turned 49 the day before he died, was serving 25 years to life at Clinton Correctional Facility for the killing and dismemberment of his former boss.
Sweat, 35, was serving a sentence of life without parole in the killing of a sheriff's deputy. Mulverhill said investigators believe he may be armed.
Advertisement
While there have been no confirmed sightings of Sweat since the escape, police said investigators saw a second set of tracks near where Matt was shot. Searchers hoped for one last break before heavy rains forecast for tomorrow come in.
Ultimately, how the chase ends is up to Sweat, Mulverhill said.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Absolutely disgusting': Man wanted by police after riding moose</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/absolutely-disgusting-man-wanted-police-after-riding-moose-6348304?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A video has been posted on YouTube showing a man jumping on and riding a swimming moose.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

Canadian police are on the hunt for a group of boaties who posted a video of a man riding a moose.
The YouTube clip shows a group of men chasing a moose that was wading across a river in British Colombia before one of the men jumps on its back and rides it.
The others can be heard laughing at their friend from the boat.
Now police are looking for the group, who could be fined over $100,000 for the incident.
"I was absolutely disgusted," says Steve Wolfe, a hunter who saw the video online.
"It's not illegal, it's absolutely unethical. That moose was chased around for who knows how long."
Under the British Columbia Wildlife Act the actions are classed as illegal and conservation officers are keen to take action against the group.
According to media reports the incident was believed to have taken place last July on Tuchodi Lakes in Northern Rocky Mountains Provincial Park.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> 'Hasta la vista' - Arnold Schwarzenegger shames anti-gay marriage fan</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/hasta-vista-arnold-schwarzenegger-shames-anti-gay-marriage-fan-6348269?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Yesterday America's Supreme Court voted in favour of granting same-sex couples the right to marry regardless of where they lived in the country. </Description>
        <MainBody>Miley Cyrus bonds with Arnold Schwarzenegger
Arnold Schwarzenegger has shamed a Facebook fan who disagreed with his decision to change his profile picture to one offering support to same-sex marriage.
The actor and former politician changed his picture to one of him as the Terminator with a rainbow overlay.
While most supported Schwarzenegger's move, one fan commented: "What's wrong with U Arnie? I have to unlike."
His reply was perfect: "Hasta la vista".
Yesterday America's Supreme Court voted in favour of granting same-sex couples the right to marry regardless of where they lived in the country.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman scales flagpole to remove Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/woman-scales-flagpole-remove-confederate-flag-6348252?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The protest comes as renewed calls are made for the Confederate flag to be removed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman scales flagpole to remove Confederate flag
Published: 7:30AM Sunday June 28, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

The Confederate flag was temporarily removed from the front of the South Carolina Statehouse when a woman climbed the flagpole removing the banner.
Bree Newsome, 30, of Charlotte, North Carolina, was about halfway up the more than 9-metre steel flagpole just after dawn (local time) when officers of the South Carolina Bureau of Protective Services told her to get down. Instead, she continued climbing to the top and removed the banner. The flag was flown by forces supporting the pro-slavery, secessionist southern states in the American Civil War.
Newsome and a man who had climbed over a 1.2-metre wrought-iron fence to get to the flag were arrested.
The flag, which is protected by state law, was raised about 45 minutes later.
Later today, dozens of people holding up Confederate flags held a rally at the monument to support keeping the flag flying there. A similar rally was held outside the Alabama State Capitol in Montgomery, after the state's Republican governor, Robert Bentley, acted by executive order to take down Civil-War era flags outside the building.
Sherri Iacobelli, a spokeswoman for the South Carolina Department of Public Safety, said that Newsome and James Ian Tyson, 30, also of Charlotte, have been charged with defacing monuments on state Capitol grounds. That's a misdemeanour that carries a fine of up to $US5,000 and a prison term of up to three years or both.
A staff member at the Alvin Glenn Detention Center where the two were taken said she did not know if the two had attorneys. About the time of her arrest, Newsome released an email statement to the media.
"We removed the flag today because we can't wait any longer. We can't continue like this another day," it said. "It's time for a new chapter where we are sincere about dismantling white supremacy and building toward true racial justice and equality."
Advertisement
Authorities said Newsome was from Raleigh. However, Mervyn Marcano, a spokesman for the small group of activists who worked together to take down the flag, said she had recently moved to Charlotte.
Calls for removing the flag have been renewed since nine black churchgoers were killed in what police characterized as a racist attack at a Charleston, South Carolina church last week.
South Carolina lawmakers took the initial steps last Tuesday toward removing the Confederate battle flag from the Statehouse grounds by agreeing to allow discussion of the matter during the legislative session.
The agreement came a day after Republican Gov. Nikki Haley reversed course and called for the divisive symbol to come down. The flag has flown in front of the state Capitol for 15 years after being moved from atop the Statehouse dome.
The momentum in South Carolina sparked further calls from politicians across the state and country for flags and Confederate symbols to be removed from public displays in other states.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:26:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fifteen Britons among dead in Tunisian beach massacre</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/fifteen-britons-among-dead-in-tunisian-beach-massacre-6348249?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The wounded included 24 Britons, seven Tunisians, three Belgians, and a German, Russian and Ukrainian. </Description>
        <MainBody>Fifteen Britons among dead in Tunisian beach massacre
Published: 7:26AM Sunday June 28, 2015 Source: AP
Three ISIS 'linked' terror attacks, dozens killed in Tunisian slaughter video
Thousands of tourists fled from Tunisia after the country's worst terrorist attack killed 38 people - including 15 Britons - as the government struggles to prevent future jihadi attacks against the all-important tourism sector.
New measures to increase the numbers of troops on the streets and crack down on organizations with radical links, however, won't bring the tourists back in the short-term, further threatening the fragile economy.
When a 24-year-old Master's student at Kairouan University strolled on to the Sousse beach and pulled out a Kalashnikov assault rifle and grenades hidden inside his beach umbrella, he was sounding the death knell for Tunisia's 2015 tourist season.
Tunisian authorities identified the attacker as Seifeddine Rezgui, saying he killed 38 people, 15 of them British, as well as German, Irish, Belgian and Portuguese victims, and sent thousands of tourists fleeing to airports.
The wounded included 24 Britons, seven Tunisians, three Belgians, and a German, Russian and Ukrainian.
"It's the first time I've ever been on holiday and feared for my life," said British tourist Matthew Preece, adding it was his third time visiting Tunisia and likely his last. "So obviously you can't come back somewhere it's not safe."
Tourists and employees are returning home with tales of horror cowering in rooms or offices as the killer stalked through the hotel wearing shorts.
European countries and tour operators sent planes to evacuate their citizens. By midday Saturday, nine flights had whisked away 1,400 people, according to Mohammed Walid Ben Ghachem, manager of the Enfidha-Hammamet Airport near Sousse.
At the Imperial Marhaba Hotel itself, the guests had left, according to manager Mohammed Becheur.
Advertisement
"We may have zero clients today, but we will keep our staff," he said, lamenting the 75-percent occupancy rate the day before. "This summer will be hard, but we are very confident for the long term."
On the beach, there were still a few tourists from neighboring hotels. Some laid flowers at the site of the attack while police patrolling on horseback moved down the beach and security boats patrolled the waters.
Armed men on the beach may well become a more common sight in Tunisia, as Prime Minister Habib Essid announced a raft of new security measures that many have questioned why they weren't implemented after the last horrific attack against tourists in March at the National Bardo Museum that killed 22.
"It's clear that the government's security policy requires a massive revision, in the sense that most of the tourist sites weren't well-protected," Tunisian security analyst Alaya Allani said. "If the measures announced are well implemented, we could reduce but not eradicate terrorism."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sandstorm and earthquake strike Egypt on the same day</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/sandstorm-and-earthquake-strike-egypt-same-day-6348248?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Egypt has been hit by a 5.2 magnitude earthquake the same day a sandstorm hits the country.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sandstorm and earthquake strike Egypt on the same day
Published: 7:24AM Sunday June 28, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

A couple observe a sandstorm that shrouds the capital city from an observation deck of the Cairo Tower in Zamalek, Cairo. - Source: AP
Egypt faced treacherous weather conditions as a sandstorm blanketed the north of the country and a magnitude-5.2 earthquake centred in the Sinai peninsula shook buildings more than 200 miles away in the capital, Cairo.
The epicentre of the quake was 4 kilometres southeast of the beachside town of Nuweiba in the Sinai, and about 75 kilometres south of Egypt's border with Israel, according to the US Geological Survey.
Airports near Alexandria and Marsa Matrouh, along the Mediterranean coast, closed and diverted flights to Cairo due to poor visibility from the day's sandstorm, Civil Aviation Minister Hossam Kamel said in a statement. Visibility reached as low as 500 meters at the Burg al-Arab airport near Alexandria, he said.
Fierce winds whipped through the capital as many residents took cover from the sand by staying indoors. Others were seen braving the storm wearing surgical masks or covering their faces with clothing, as the wind sent rubbish and dust swirling.
At its peak, the sandstorm covered the capital in a thick orange cloud, dramatically reducing visibility.
In the Red Sea town of Dahab, 68 kilometres south of the epicentre of the quake in the Sinai peninsula, the tremor shook loose clouds of dust that enveloped nearby mountains, according to a witness. The quake appeared to startle local residents and tourists. It also shook the nearby Gaza strip. No serious damage was immediately reported from the earthquake in Egypt or in Gaza.
The Egyptian Ministry of Health said in a statement that there were no reports of deaths or injuries anywhere in Egypt due to the quake.
Advertisement
Israeli media reported that very mild aftershocks of the earthquake were felt in some places in the south of the country, but that no damage or injuries were caused.
The extreme weather conditions provided fodder for social media humour. Some wondered which of the nine Biblical plagues would come next, while the popular Zamalek football club tweeted that it wasn't actually an earthquake--just preparation for their match tonight.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:29:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French terror suspect took selfie with beheaded victim</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/french-terror-suspect-took-selfie-beheaded-victim-6348241?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The unknown man has been arrested for the beheading of his boss Herve Cornara.  </Description>
        <MainBody>French terror suspect took selfie with beheaded victim
Published: 6:29AM Sunday June 28, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

The top suspect in the beheading of a businessman that French authorities are calling terrorist attack took a "selfie" photo with the slain victim and sent the image via WhatsApp to a Canadian mobile phone number.
French investigators were working to confirm the identity of the recipient, but weren't able to immediately confirm media reports that it was an unspecified person now in Syria, where the radical Islamic State group has seized territory, the security officials said.
Leading suspect Yassine Salhi, a truck driver with a history of radical Islamic ties, as well as his sister and wife remained in custody in the city of Lyon a day after he allegedly crashed a truck into an US-owned chemical warehouse and hung his employer's severed head on a factory gate, officials say.
One of the security officials said the selfie was forwarded via WhatsApp, the globally popular instant messaging system owned by Facebook, to a phone number in Canada.
No group immediately claimed responsibility. The severed head appeared to mimic Islamic State's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see, and came days after the militants urged attacks during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan. French authorities say Salhi had links to radical Salafists in the past.
Paris prosecutor's office spokeswoman Agnes Thibault-Lecuivre said that Salhi was refusing to speak to police investigators. She said that one of the other suspects initially arrested yesterday was released without being charged.
Investigators have not turned up any motive or possible foreign connection, Thibault-Lecuivre said. Under French anti-terrorism laws, Salhi and the women can be held up to four days before either being released or handed preliminary charges and locked up.
Separately today, hundreds of people turned out in the region to honour slain businessman Herve Cornara and denounce the violence. Dozens turned out for a minute of silence in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, the town southeast of Lyon where yesterday's attack took place at an Air Products chemicals warehouse.
Advertisement
Several hundred people also gathered outside a housing project in the town of Fontaines-sur-Saone to honour Cornara, 54, the manager of a transportation company that had employed Salhi since March. They recalled a kind, humble man who was active in the community of the Lyon suburb.
"He lived on the fifth floor, me on the fourth. He spoke with all the young people in the neighbourhood. He didn't differentiate between (non-Muslim) French and Muslims," said Leila Bouri, a 24-year-old cafeteria cashier. "If you ever had a problem, you would go see him."
"When I heard this, I was shocked. It's shameful," she said. "I am a Muslim, but you can't kill like this. It's not who we are. In Islam, we're not told to slit throats. We only slit the throats of sheep. You don't slit the throats of people."
The suspected killer, she added, "isn't a Muslim in my opinion."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 09:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Escaped New York murderer involved in shootout with police</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/escaped-new-york-murderer-involved-in-shootout-police-6347906?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>An official with knowledge of the manhunt said Richard Matt was killed by police and David Sweat is still on the run. </Description>
        <MainBody>Escaped New York murderer involved in shootout with police
Published: 8:49AM Saturday June 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
US police check out new lead on escaped New York prisoners video
One of two convicted killers who staged a brazen escape from a northern New York state maximum-security prison is engaged in a gunbattle with police just hours of the other was shot and killed shot and killed three weeks after they escaped.
An official with knowledge of the manhunt said Richard Matt was killed by police and David Sweat is still on the run.
The official wasn't authorized to talk about the development publicly and spoke to The Associated Press on the condition of anonymity.
Matt and Sweat used power tools to saw through a steel cell wall and several steel steam pipes, bashed a hole through a brick wall, squirmed through pipes and escaped early June 6 from Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, near the Canadian border.
Sweat was serving a sentence of life without parole in the killing of a sheriff's deputy in 2002. Matt was serving 25 years to life for the killing and dismembering of his former boss.
A civilian worker at the prison has been charged with helping the killers flee by giving them hacksaw blades, chisels and other tools.
Prosecutors said Joyce Mitchell, a prison tailoring shop instructor who got close to the men while working with them, had agreed to be their getaway driver but backed out because she felt guilty for participating.
Mitchell pleaded not guilty June 15 to charges including felony promoting prison contraband.
Authorities said the men had filled their beds in their adjacent cells with clothes to make it appear they were sleeping when guards made overnight rounds. On a cut steam pipe, the prisoners left a taunting note containing a crude caricature of an Asian face and the words "Have a nice day."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 09:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gay couples rush to tie the knot after US same-sex marriage decision</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/gay-couples-rush-tie-knot-after-us-same-sex-marriage-decision-6347931?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>But the reaction wasn't so welcoming in some of the 14 states that had been the last holdouts against same-sex marriages. </Description>
        <MainBody>Supreme Court declares same-sex couples right to marriage in all 50 U.S. States
Benjamin Moore and Tadd Roberts wore matching tuxedos to the county clerk's office in Louisville to get married, and the mayor greeted them with a bottle of champagne.
They were among a rush of gay couples across the South and Midwest who celebrated the Supreme Court's ruling legalizing same-sex marriage with spontaneous weddings.
They were young and old, they wore gowns and suits or T-shirts and jeans, they kissed and waved flags that read "love wins."
"It's just been incredible and historic and amazing to live this moment," Moore said, after the mayor took commemorative photos of him and Roberts getting their license.
But the reaction wasn't so welcoming in some of the 14 states that had been the last holdouts against same-sex marriages.
In rural Alabama, the heart of the battle against gay marriage, Pike County Probate Judge Wes Allen said he would stop issuing all marriage licenses to avoid having to give them to gay couples.
Allen said Alabama law gives judges the option of granting licenses, and "I have chosen not to perform that function."
Governors in Louisiana, Mississippi and Texas also railed against the ruling. And clerks in some of the affected states refused to issue licenses, citing a three-week grace period allowed by the Supreme Court or forms now out of date that specify "bridge" and "groom."
Other clerks scrambled to issue licenses as gay couples rushed to their offices.
Advertisement
In Arkansas, Pulaski County Clerk Larry Crane held a hand to his heart after the Supreme Court's ruling.
"It is a special day," he said, choking up. "I'm honored to be a part of it."
Jessica Dent and Carolee Taylor got married a few blocks from the courthouse in Montgomery, Alabama.
"Never thought it would happen in our lifetime," said Taylor.
After their ceremony, they returned to the courthouse to file their license, making them officially married in the conservative state that had fought back against efforts to legalize gay marriage.
After a federal judge ruled earlier this year that the state's gay marriage ban was unconstitutional, about 500 same-sex couples were married before the Alabama Supreme Court directly ordered probate judges to stop issuing the licenses.
"We waited so long. When it came through, I can't think of a better way to celebrate, the decision and our love," said Dent, walking out of the courthouse holding a sign that said "All love is equal."
The Human Rights Campaign sent letters to the governors of the 14 affected states warning that delaying issuing marriage licenses would be unlawful.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 09:21:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Three ISIS 'linked' terror attacks, dozens killed in Tunisian slaughter</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/three-isis-linked-terror-attacks-dozens-killed-in-tunisian-slaughter-6347862?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Tourists described hearing what sounded like fireworks and then running for their lives when they realised it was gunfire.</Description>
        <MainBody>Three ISIS 'linked' terror attacks, dozens killed in Tunisian slaughter
Published: 1:18AM Saturday June 27, 2015 Source: AP/ONE News

Dozens of tourists killed in Tunisian bloodbath - Source: ONE News
A young man pulled a Kalashnikov from a beach umbrella and sprayed gunfire at European sunbathers at a Tunisian resort, killing at least 39 people - one of three deadly attacks Friday from Europe to North Africa to the Middle East that followed a call to violence by Islamic State extremists.
The shootings in the Tunisian resort of Sousse happened at about the same time as a bombing at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait and an attack on a U.S.-owned factory in France that included a beheading.
It was unclear if the violence was linked but it came days after the IS militants urged their followers "to make Ramadan a month of calamities for the nonbelievers."
In all, the assailants killed at least 65 people.
The SITE Intelligence Group reported later that the IS claimed credit for the Tunisia attack on its Twitter account and identified the gunman as Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani.
The attack in Tunisia, the country's worst ever, comes just months after the March 18 massacre at the national Bardo museum in Tunis that killed 22 people, again mostly tourists, and has called into question the newly elected government's ability to protect the country.
"Once again, cowardly and traitorous hands have struck Tunisia, targeting its security and that of its children and visitors," President Beji Caid Essebsi told reporters at the RIU Imperial Marhaba hotel, near the beach rampage site.
Essebsi promised "painful but necessary" measures, adding: "No country is safe from terrorism, and we need a global strategy of all democratic countries."
Advertisement
Rafik Chelli, the secretary of state of the Interior Ministry, told The Associated Press that the attack was carried out by a young student not previously known to authorities. At least 36 people were reported wounded in the shooting spree, which ended when the gunman was shot to death by police.
The Islamic State group claimed responsibility for the suicide bombing at the Shiite mosque in Kuwait City that killed at least 27 people and wounded scores of other worshippers at midday prayers - the first such attack in the mostly quiet and relatively secure Gulf Arab nation in more than two decades.
In southeastern France, a man with ties to Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory, touching off an explosion that injured two people. Authorities arriving at the site made a grisly discovery: the severed head of the driver's employer was found hanging at the plant entrance.
The suspect, Yassine Salhi, was seized by an alert firefighter, authorities said, and French President Francois Hollande said the attacker's intention had been to cause an explosion.
A security alert for the southeast region was raised to its highest level for the next three days, and the U.S. Embassy in Paris warned American citizens to be vigilant.
In an audio recording released Tuesday, the Islamic State called on its supporters to increase attacks during Ramadan and "be keen on waging invasion in this eminent month and commit martyrdom."
In Britain, police said they were tightening security at major events after the attacks in France, Kuwait and Tunisia, including for the weekend events of Armed Forces Day and the Pride London gay and lesbian festival.
The attacks were condemned by the United Nations, the U.S., Israel and others.
"We stand with these nations as they respond to attacks on their soil today," the White House said. Pentagon spokesman Col. Steve Warren added it was "too soon to tell whether or not these various and far-flung attacks were coordinated centrally or whether they were coincidental."
The carnage in Tunisia began on the beach, where tourists described hearing what sounded like fireworks and then running for their lives when they realized it was gunfire. Video of the aftermath showed medics using beach chairs as stretchers to carry away people in swimsuits.
"He had a parasol in his hand. He went down to put it in the sand and then he took out his Kalashnikov and began shooting wildly," Chelli said of the gunman.
He then entered the pool area of the Imperial Marhaba hotel before moving inside, killing people as he went.
British tourist Gary Pine told AP he was on the beach with his wife around noon when heard the shooting. They shouted for their son to get out of the water, grabbed their bag and ran for the hotel. Their son told them he saw someone shot on the beach.
There was "sheer panic" at the hotel, Pine said. "There were a lot of concerned people, a few people in tears with panic and a few people - older guests - they'd turned their ankles or there was a few little minor injuries and nicks and scrapes."
Elizabeth O'Brien, an Irish tourist who was with her two sons, told Irish Radio she was on the beach when the shooting began.
"I thought, 'Oh my God. It sounds like gunfire,' so I just ran to the sea to my children and grabbed our things" before fleeing to their hotel room, she said.
Since overthrowing its secular dictator in 2011, Tunisia has been plagued by terror attacks, although only recently have they targeted the tourism sector, which makes up nearly 15 percent of GDP. Tourism is especially important in coastal resorts like Sousse.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 05:43:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'I'm so glad she followed her instincts' - Kiwi avoids joining doomed Alaskan sightseeing plane</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/i-m-so-glad-she-followed-her-instincts-kiwi-avoids-joining-doomed-alaskan-sightseeing-plane-6347907?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A Kiwi woman's last minute decision to pull out of flight in Alaska has saved her life.</Description>
        <MainBody>A map showing the location of a sightseeing plane crash in Alaska - Source: Google Maps
Related
Kiwi's near miss as sightseeing plane crashes in Alaska
A Kiwi woman's last minute decision to pull out of flight in Alaska has saved her life.
Sam Caughey's mother was due to fly on a sightseeing plane which crashed near Ella Lake in Alaska yesterday, killing all eight cruise ship passengers and the pilot on board.
But she pulled out at the last minute.
"Mum thought the weather looked too dangerous and it was making her nervous," Ms Caughey told ONE News.
Ms Caughey says her mum and a friend were on a similar cruise as the Holland America passengers who took the flight which crashed 250m above a lake on a cliff face.
"Mum and her friend had been planning a float plane flight all week and likely would have been on the same plane as the one that crashed."
It was in Seoul while waiting for a flight to London for her brother's wedding that Ms Caughey got the message from her mum saying she had just heard from the cruise's captain that the plane had crashed.
"I was really shocked. It's so crazy that such a simple choice can be life or death and I'm so glad she followed her instincts.
Advertisement
"We all just feel shattered for the people on board and their families. Awful, awful news."
Alaska State Troopers hope to retrieve the bodies from the crash site today after poor weather hampered the mission yesterday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two more attacked by sharks off U.S. East Coast </title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/two-more-attacked-sharks-off-u-s-east-coast-6348031?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Six people have been bitten by sharks off the coast of the Carolinas in the past two weeks. </Description>
        <MainBody>Two more attacked by sharks off U.S. East Coast
Published: 1:51PM Saturday June 27, 2015 Source: AP
Why would you do this? Men surf on the back of a rare shark (+video) video
Authorities say two men were bitten by sharks off the coasts of the Carolinas, bringing to six the number of attacks in the past two weeks.
A 47-year-old man was bitten multiple times in the back in waters off North Carolina's Outer Banks today.
The other, a 43-year-old man, was attacked by a shark near Hilton Head Island, South Carolina. Both were taken to hospitals with non-life-threatening injuries.
Sharks have attacked several children along North Carolina's coast this month, including a 13-year old girl who lost her left arm below the elbow and a 16-year old boy who lost his left arm above the elbow.
 Mike Will (@miketwill2003) June 26, 2015

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 01:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Barack Obama sings Amazing Grace to mourners of church shooting</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/barack-obama-sings-amazing-grace-mourners-church-shooting-6347925?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The US president called on Americans not to "lose our way again" in his eulogy for Reverend Clementa Pinckney.</Description>
        <MainBody>Barack Obama sings Amazing Grace to mourners of church shooting
Published: 10:55AM Saturday June 27, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

Invoking scripture and song, President Barack Obama stood before those grieving the deaths of nine black people slain in church and sang Amazing Grace to the mourners of last week's church shooting.
He closed his rousing address which called on Americans to confront the "uncomfortable truths" of the racial prejudices that still infect American society by singing the words to the famous Christian hymn Amazing Grace.
The US president also called on Americans not to "lose our way again" by failing to reckon with the questions stirred in the past week.
Eulogizing the Rev. Clementa Pinckney, the pastor and legislator that was killed in the attack, Obama said it would be a betrayal of everything the man stood for "if we allowed ourselves to slip into a comfortable silence again once the eulogies have been delivered, once the TV cameras move on."
He pleaded with Americans not "to go back to business as usual."
Obama, in his 40-minute address, spoke movingly of all that Pinckney had done in his life, then confronted the hard questions raised by his death and the deaths of eight others slain by a white man.
He said it was time to remove the Confederate flag from American flagpoles, saying that action would "not be an insult to the valor of Confederate soldiers" but an acknowledgement that "the cause for which they fought, the cause of slavery, was wrong," as was racial segregation and resistance to civil rights efforts.
The Confederate battle flag represented the southern states in the 19th century US civil war, in which northern states fought to abolish slavery and the South fought to preserve it.
Advertisement
Removing the flag, he said, "would be one step in an honest accounting of America's history, a modest but meaningful balm for so many unhealed wounds."
The president called, too, for an American reckoning with the nation's history of gun violence, saying "for too long we've been blind to the mayhem that gun violence inflects upon this nation."
The deaths of Pinckney and eight others sparked spirited debate in Southern states over the Confederate battle flag, which for years has flown at a monument on the grounds of the South Carolina statehouse.
Following the service for Pinckney, the president was expected to meet privately with the families of other victims.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 00:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Love won' - Ellen DeGeneres celebrates historic same-sex marriage vote</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/love-won-ellen-degeneres-celebrates-historic-same-sex-marriage-vote-6347877?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>America's Supreme Court declared overnight that same-sex couples have the right to marry anywhere in the country.</Description>
        <MainBody>There has been an outpouring of celebration after America's Supreme Court declared overnight that same-sex couples have the right to marry anywhere in the country.
Gay and lesbian couples already can marry in 36 states and the District of Columbia.
The court's 5-4 ruling means the remaining 14 states, in the South and Midwest, will have to stop enforcing their bans on same-sex marriage.
The outcome is the culmination of two decades of Supreme Court litigation over marriage, and gay rights generally.
The decision saw celebrities take to social media to celebrate the decision.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 23:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French beheading suspect previously investigated for radical Islamic ties </title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/french-beheading-suspect-previously-investigated-radical-islamic-ties-6347844?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The suspect is the latest French citizen implicated in extremist bloodshed in recent years after being flagged to authorities, then falling off the radar.</Description>
        <MainBody>French beheading suspect previously investigated for radical Islamic ties
Published: 10:55PM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

A truck driver once under surveillance for radical Islamic ties crashed into an American-owned chemical warehouse in southeastern France and hung his employer's severed head on a factory gate, along with banners with Arabic inscriptions.
The attack, which triggered an explosion that wounded two people, came on a day of violence that spanned three continents.
The suspect is the latest French citizen implicated in extremist bloodshed in recent years after being flagged to authorities, then falling off the radar.
Police were put on higher alert in the Lyon area after the assault, which revived fearful memories of attacks in January on a kosher market and satirical newspaper that left 20 dead.
"Islamist terrorism has again struck France," Prime Minister Manuel Valls said.
The attack in France came on the same day that a gunman mowed down scores of European tourists on a beach in Tunisia and a suicide bomber killed more than two dozen worshippers at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait - violence that
followed a call by Islamic State extremists to target "nonbelievers."
No group immediately claimed responsibility for the factory attack in France.
The severed head appeared to mimic the Islamic State group's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see, and came days after the militants urged attacks during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan.
The bloodshed was condemned by the United Nations, the United States, Israel and others.
The French attack began when Yassine Salhi drove a utility truck to the gate of the Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon, authorities said.
Prosecutor Francois Molins said Salhi was known to factory staff because he regularly made deliveries there, and they let him in the gate. Once beyond the sight of security cameras, Salhi plowed his truck into gas canisters in a factory warehouse, touching off an explosion, Molins said.
A knife and the decapitated body of Salhi's employer were found at the site of the explosion, and the severed head was posted on a gate at the factory entrance with two flags bearing proclamations of Islamic faith, the prosecutor said.
Firefighters apprehended Salhi, and he was in custody along with his wife, sister and another person, while police sweeps of the vehicle and the suspect's apartment were continuing, the prosecutor said.
Authorities described Salhi as a father of three who was married for more than 10 years, and who had been monitored for links to radical Islam from 2006-2008. "He continued to attract the attention of intelligence services from time to time from 2011 to 2014 for his links to the Salafist movement in the Lyon region," Molins said.
Advertisement
He is the latest Frenchman to have been on authorities' radar before staging attacks in recent years. Others include Mohamed Merah, who attacked a Jewish school in 2012, Mehdi Nemmouche, chief suspect in a 2014 attack on Brussels
Jewish Museum, and two of the gunmen in the January shootings in Paris.
"We are dealing with 'sleeper' terrorists who are able to disappear from the surveillance radar for years and then reappear," Parliament member Georges Fenech, on a commission for surveillance of jihadist networks, told reporters near the factory.
"It's really important to reflect and act to make sure that this surveillance lasts as long as possible. If not, we can have perpetrators of attacks who have been located, but who disappear off all surveillance."
President Francois Hollande raised the security alert for the southeastern region to its highest level for the next three days. Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said security was tightened at religious sites around the country.
Three French officials said the man who was decapitated ran a local transportation company that employed Salhi. The victim's name was not released. One official said the businessman was believed to have been killed before the attack on the factory. The officials were not authorized to speak to the media and requested anonymity.
Hollande said the key question was determining whether there were any accomplices.
Others, including Salhi's wife, were seen on television being taken into custody from his apartment building in the Lyon suburb of Saint Priest hours after the attack.
The Paris Mosque condemned the attack, and a Muslim forklift operator who lives next to the factory described his horror and fear of reprisals.
"Doing this during Ramadan is disrespectful," said Mehdi, a 23-year-old who did not want his full name published out of security concerns. Wearing a long white Muslim robe, he said: "There are Muslims who have nothing to do with these
things. Now they find themselves mixed up in this story for nothing."
No further details were released about the two people injured in the explosion, though Hollande said their injuries were light.
The gas factory belongs to Air Products, an American chemical company based in Allentown, Pennsylvania, and owned by Seifi Ghasemi, an Iranian immigrant. The company said all its employees had been accounted for and were evacuated from the premises but did not say if any had been injured.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 22:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Czech Republic anti-immigration and Islam protests turn violent</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/czech-republic-anti-immigration-and-islam-protests-turn-violent-6347897?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Police had to separate pro and anti-immigration group while being pelted with beer cans.</Description>
        <MainBody>
Protesters shout slogans during a far right demonstration in Brno, Czech Republic. - Source: AP
Hundreds of far right supporters have rallied against immigration and Islam in the Czech Republic's second largest city Brno, while others gathered nearby in support of immigration.
The rally follows a similar demonstration in the Slovak capital of Bratislava today which turned violent. They reflect the rising tensions surrounding immigration Europe, even in countries that have not been significantly hit by the recent wave of asylum-seekers.
Riot police separated the groups and were pelted with objects such as beer cans and bottles by the anti-migrants protesters.
Tomas Vandas, the leader of the far right Workers Party of Social Justice condemned the decision of EU leaders to relocate 40,000 migrants from Italy and Greece in Europe and demanded they are sent back to their countries of origin.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:14:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court declares same-sex couples right to marriage in all 50 U.S. States</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/supreme-court-declares-same-sex-couples-right-marriage-in-all-50-u-s-states-6347869?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Ruling from U.S. Supreme Court means remaining 14 states must stop banning same-sex marriage.</Description>
        <MainBody>
Gay rights activist outside the U.S. Supreme Court - Source: AP
The Supreme Court declared Friday that same-sex couples have a right to marry anywhere in the United States.
Gay and lesbian couples already can marry in 36 states and the District of Columbia. The court's 5-4 ruling means the remaining 14 states, in the South and Midwest, will have to stop enforcing their bans on same-sex marriage.
The outcome is the culmination of two decades of Supreme Court litigation over marriage, and gay rights generally.
"No union is more profound than marriage," wrote Justice Anthony Kennedy, joined by the court's four more liberal justices.
The ruling will not take effect immediately because the court gives the losing side roughly three weeks to ask for reconsideration.
But some state officials and county clerks might decide there is little risk in issuing marriage licenses to same-sex couples.
The cases before the court involved laws from several states that define marriage as the union of a man and a woman.
Advertisement
Those states have not allowed same-sex couples to marry within their borders and they also have refused to recognize valid marriages from elsewhere.
Just two years ago, the Supreme Court struck down part of the federal anti-gay marriage law that denied a range of government benefits to legally married same-sex couples.
The decision in United States v. Windsor did not address the validity of state marriage bans, but courts across the country, with few exceptions, said its logic compelled them to invalidate state laws that prohibited gay and lesbian couples from marrying.
The number of states allowing same-sex marriage has grown rapidly. As recently as October, just over one-third of the states permitted same-sex marriage.
There are an estimated 390,000 married same-sex couples in the United States, according to Williams Institute at the University of California, Los Angeles, which tracks the demographics of gay and lesbian Americans. Another 70,000 couples living in states that do not currently permit them to wed would get married in the next three years, the institute says.
Roughly 1 million same-sex couples, married and unmarried, live together in the United States, the institute says.
The Obama administration backed the right of same-sex couples to marry. The Justice Department's decision to stop defending the federal anti-marriage law in 2011 was an important moment for gay rights and President Barack Obama declared his support for same-sex marriage in 2012.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:53:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Women gush over brooding gorilla with 'ripped muscles'</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/women-gush-over-brooding-gorilla-ripped-muscles-6347806?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Young girls have gone bananas for perhaps the most handsome ape in captivity.</Description>
        <MainBody>Women gush over brooding gorilla with 'ripped muscles'
Published: 8:53PM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: ONE News

Young girls have gone bananas for perhaps the most handsome ape in captivity.
Shabani, a western lowland gorilla, has been described as a "heart-throb" and responsible for a huge spike in female visitor numbers at the Higashiyama Zoo and Botanical Gardens in Japan, News Corp reports.
Originally from Sydney's Taronga Zoo, Shabani has been admired for his "brooding poses", "ripped muscles" and "flirtatious glances".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kiwi's near miss as sightseeing plane crashes in Alaska</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/kiwi-s-near-miss-sightseeing-plane-crashes-in-alaska-6347700?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A Kiwi on holiday in Alaska very nearly boarded a tourist flight which has crashed today.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kiwi's near miss as sightseeing plane crashes in Alaska
Published: 6:16PM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: ONE News

A map showing the location of a sightseeing plane crash in Alaska - Source: Google Maps
A Kiwi on holiday in Alaska very nearly boarded a tourist flight which has crashed today.
The sightseeing plane crashed near Ella Lake in Alaska, the Holland America cruise line said in a statement today, and the condition of the plane and its passengers was not known.
The United States Coastguard and Alaskan authorities were on their way to the site, more than 250m above a lake on a cliff face.
Kiwi Sam Caughey tweeted that her mother was very nearly on that flight.
"Just got word from my mum...she pulled out of a scenic flight in Alaska...plane just reported as crashed," she wrote.
"What a near miss. So sorry to all those on board."
Eight passengers and a pilot were aboard the floating plane owned by Promech Air.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 06:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Oh, sorry!' - police let white comedienne who tries to sell them drugs walk away</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/oh-sorry-police-let-white-comedienne-tries-sell-them-drugs-walk-away-6347638?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>An American comedienne faced no consequences after trying to sell two police officers antidepressants in a video she made to illustrate white privilege.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

US comedienne Jessie Kahnweiler tries to sell prescription drugs to police with no consequences - Source: Jessie Kahnweiler/YouTube
Watch Video
Comedian offers to sell drugs to pair of cops (0:44)
An American comedienne faced no consequences after trying to sell two police officers antidepressants in a video she made to illustrate white privilege.
Jessie Kahnweiler, 30, posted a video to YouTube which she captioned: "Jessie sets out to see if white privilege really exists and can she get arrested or will her whiteness prevent it?"
The video comes at a time when racial tensions in parts of America with police are high, with several high-profile cases of undue police force against minorities hitting the headlines recently.
"My one black friend told me that because I'm white, I have all of these privileges, and I get treated totally different by the cops than black people get treated," she says in the video.
In the video, she drinks in public, cartwheels naked in front of a restaurant and ultimately tries to sell prescription medicine to police officers - with no apparent consequences.
"Those are prescribed drugs, and you are becoming a drug dealer by selling them," a police offer tells her.
"Oh, sorry!" she says, and walks away.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Promise of 'gay conversion' therapy a fraud - US jury finds</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/promise-gay-conversion-therapy-fraud-us-jury-finds-6347547?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>An organisation's claim that it could turn gay men straight violated New Jersey's Consumer Fraud Act.</Description>
        <MainBody>
Arthur Goldberg - Source: AP
A nonprofit organisation that claimed it could turn gay men straight violated New Jersey's Consumer Fraud Act, a jury concluded in a civil trial that an attorney for the plaintiffs called "a momentous event" for LGBT rights.
The jury said that Jews Offering New Alternatives for Healing, co-founder Arthur Goldberg and counsellor Alan Downing made misrepresentations and engaged in unconscionable business practices.
Three men and two parents were awarded more than $100,000 in damages.
The judge will rule later on their request to revoke the company's license, plaintiffs' attorneys said.
"This is a momentous event in the history of LGBT rights," attorney David Dinielli said. "The same lies that motivate gay conversion therapy motivate homophobia - that gay people are broken and need to be fixed. The strength of our plaintiffs brought that to light."
Attorneys for the plaintiffs argued during the trial that the group, known by the acronym JONAH, claimed a success rate that wasn't backed up by actual statistics and used therapy methods that had no scientific basis, including having one client beat a pillow, meant to represent his mother, with a tennis racket.
In an emailed statement, defence attorney Charles LiMandri called the verdict "a sad day, not just for my clients, but for America."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Irate French taxi drivers smash cars in strike against Uber</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/irate-french-taxi-drivers-smash-cars-in-strike-against-uber-6347512?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The taxi drivers went on the offensive against Uber, smashing cars, setting tires ablaze and blocking traffic.</Description>
        <MainBody>Irate French taxi drivers smash cars in strike against Uber
Published: 11:19AM Friday June 26, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

French taxi drivers pulled out the throttle in an all-out confrontation with the ultra-cheap Uber car service, smashing livery cars, setting tires ablaze and blocking traffic during a nationwide strike that caught tourists and celebrities alike in the mayhem.
Travellers going to and from the airport were forced to walk alongside highways with their bags, while others, including singer Courtney Love, had their cars set upon by striking taxi drivers.
Dude @kanyewest we may turn back to the airport and hide out with u.picketers just attacked our car #ParisUberStrike pic.twitter.com/MtanurybOO
 Courtney Love Cobain (@Courtney) June 25, 2015

The French government was aghast, with Prime Minister Manuel Valls lamenting: "These incidents give a deplorable image to visitors of our country."
Taxi drivers justified their rage, saying Uber's lowest-cost service UberPop was ruining their livihoods.
Despite repeated rulings against it and an October law that explicitly outlaws UberPop, its drivers continue to ply French roads and the American ride-hailing company is actively recruiting drivers and passengers alike. Uber claims to have a total of 400,000 customers a month in France.
Advertisement
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve rushed back from a trip to Marseille to meet with taxi unions, declaring afterward that UberPop must be shut down and its vehicles seized if caught by police carrying passengers. He said 70 vehicles had been damaged around France in yesterday's protests and 10 people were arrested.
Taxi drivers in other European countries also complain that car services like Uber unfairly undercut them.
A judge ordered a temporary suspension in Spain, and in the Netherlands a Dutch court has ruled that UberPop must stop service. A world away, in China, the government banned drivers of private cars from offering services through an app.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
