<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="tvnz">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Judith Collins says historic health and safety bill needs 'tweaking'</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/judith-collins-says-historic-health-and-safety-bill-needs-tweaking-6322757?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The Health and Safety Reform bill has passed its first reading in Parliament but is now stuck at select committee.</Description>
        <MainBody>Judith Collins says historic health and safety bill needs 'tweaking'
updated 12:14
By ONE News Political Reporter Katie Bradford
Published: 10:13AM Wednesday May 27, 2015
New health and safety guidance for mine managers
Judith Collins denies there has been a backbench revolt over health and safety changes, but says a bill needs some "tweaking" before it progresses through Parliament.
The biggest health and safety changes in 20 years have been delayed because National MPs can't reach agreement.
The Health and Safety Reform bill has passed its first reading in Parliament but is now stuck at select committee after MPs failed to reach agreement on how far the changes to health and safety should go.
ONE News has been told by multiple sources that National MPs have been under pressure from business, fishing, forestry and farming groups to ensure the changes don't affect them dramatically.
It's understood there's been heated arguments within National about the bill, and that pressure has seen National MPs weaken some of the proposed reforms.
Most specifically a proposal to ensure all workplaces have a health and safety representative in it has been changed so that workplaces with fewer than 20 employees are no longer bound by that rule.
One of those said to be agitating for changes is former cabinet Minister Judith Collins, although she maintained today there was no caucus division over the issue.
"I don't think there are any bad things, I just think it needs a bit of tweaking and that's the right thing to do."
She would not elaborate what changes needed to be made, but said "it needs to be a little bit more practical for people".
The Prime Minister said on Monday that changes will have to be made to the bill because of unhappiness within National's caucus.
Advertisement
He says they've been lobbied extensively on the issue.
A spokeswoman for Workplace Relations Minister Michael Woodhouse says the bill has been delayed to ensure the government "gets it right".
It will be at least another two months before the Transport and Industrial Relations committee reports back on it.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hunters picked up by family after going missing in Kaimai Ranges</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/hunters-picked-up-family-after-going-missing-in-kaimai-ranges-6322788?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The two men spent last night in the bush after going missing yesterday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hunters picked up by family after going missing in Kaimai Ranges
updated 12:50

Snow on the Kaimai ranges, taken from Okauia. - Source: Samuel Harris
Two hunters have been found safe and well after being missing in the Kaimai Ranges overnight.
The pair made their way out to State Highway 29 near Ngamuwahine Road where they were able to use their mobile phone to contact family at 11am.
They have been picked up by family and are tired and cold but require no medical assistance.
The search and rescue teams have now stood down after additional teams from Waikato joined the operation this morning.
The two men, aged 44 and 20, reportedly entered the bush from Whakamarama Road at 4am yesterday and were due to return at 9am.
Police were made aware the pair were missing yesterday afternoon.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:43:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sir Bob Jones stays quiet on report he was booted off flight</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/sir-bob-jones-stays-quiet-report-he-booted-off-flight-6322883?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A representative at Sir Bob's office said the company was "aware of the matter".</Description>
        <MainBody>Sir Bob Jones stays quiet on report he was booted off flight
updated 12:43
Happier times: Sir Bob Jones (L) and Joseph Parker - Source: Photosport
Watch Video
Sir Bob Jones demands removal of TAB and pokies
Bob Jones is refusing to comment on a report he was booted off a flight from Auckland to Wellington.
Singer Lizzie Marvelly tweeted that a man "who looked a lot like Bob Jones" was removed from a flight by aviation security this morning.
A flight captain apologised for the incident, saying the airline couldn't accept passengers that don't comply with crew instructions, she said.
A man who looked a lot like Bob Jones was just removed from a flight to wellington by aviation security.
 Lizzie Marvelly (@LizzieMarvelly) May 26, 2015
The flight was NZ421 from Auckland to Wellington.
A representative at Sir Bob's Wellington office said the company was "aware of the matter" but was not making comment.
She said Sir Bob would not speak about the incident.
Civil Aviation Authority spokesman Mike Richards says his organisation has called Wellington Airport to get the latest information on the allegation.
Advertisement
He couldn't confirm if it happened or if Sir Bob was involved.
Back Benches host Wallace Chapman was a passenger on the flight.
He said he couldnt confirm it was Sir Bob as he was seated at the back of the plane.
"All I heard was there was little commotion and then people started clapping," he said. Then there was an announcement over the PA by the captain saying 'we will not tolerate any disregard of CAA rules'."
Mr Wallce says the incident delayed the flight by 15-20 minutes.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crackdown on Queen's Birthday weekend speedsters with 4km/h threshold back</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/crackdown-queen-s-birthday-weekend-speedsters-4km-h-threshold-back-6322917?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Police will be enforcing a reduced speed threshold and extra police will be patrolling the roads.</Description>
        <MainBody>Crackdown on Queen's Birthday weekend speedsters with 4km/h threshold back
Published: 12:42PM Wednesday May 27, 2015

Police officer hold speed camera - Source: ONE News
Motorists thinking of speeding this Queen's Birthday weekend are being warned that they could be fined for travelling more than 4km/h over the limit.
Police have confirmed they will be enforcing a reduced speed threshold and extra police will be patrolling the roads.
Anyone travelling more than 4km/h over the limit may be ticketed and all speed cameras will be set to the reduced threshold.
"We're doing this because we know reductions in speed can save lives," Inspector Alison Brand said.
Police are urging motorists to be prepared for their journey and to take extreme care on the roads.
Police say they will be actively targeting drink and drug impaired drivers, speedsters, and those who don't wear a safety belt or fail to buckle their in children in.
Last year five people were killed on New Zealand roads during the Queen's Birthday weekend and 117 were injured.
Advertisement
The official holiday period begins from 4pm on Friday May 29 and finishes at 6am on Tuesday June 2.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>No long sabbaticals for All Blacks stars Brodie Retallick and Julian Savea</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/rugby-news/no-long-sabbaticals-all-blacks-stars-brodie-retallick-and-julian-savea-6322419?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The pair join Jerome Kaino and Steven Luatua in staying in New Zealand after the World Cup. </Description>
        <MainBody>No long sabbaticals for All Blacks stars Brodie Retallick and Julian Savea
updated 12:39
Dan Carter happy with improvement, but says he's facing 'plenty of competition' for All Blacks' jersey video
Neither Brodie Retallick and Julian Savea's new contracts include provisions for lengthy overseas sabbaticals.
NZRU Chief Executive Steve Tew confirmed in Wellington that the pair had resigned today. The new deals mean both players will be signed to their Super 15 clubs until 2019.
The duo are two of rugby's most feared players, with Chiefs lock Retallick, 23, the current World Rugby Player of the Year and Hurricanes wing Savea, 24, a try scoring machine, having crossed for 30 tries in 33 Test matches.
Tew said the contracts did not include provisions for long overseas deals, increasingly popular with modern players.
"Even though they are still relatively young, they are now very experienced rugby players," All Blacks coach Steve Hansen says. " They are also very valuable team members who are both world-leading players."
New Zealand rugby is set to be drained of plenty of talent after this year's World Cup, with Colin Slade, Charles Piutau, Conrad Smith, Ma'a Nonu and Daniel Carter all heading overseas.
Jerome Kaino and Steven Luatua have already resigned with the New Zealand Rugby Union.
Retallick says he wanted to continue learning from the best coaches in the game.
"I am only young and still have plenty to learn about the game," he says. "There is a lot I want to achieve and I firmly believe that New Zealand is the best place for me to grow my game and accomplish my goals."
Savea says it was an easy decision to make.
Advertisement
"There are still a lot of things I want to achieve in New Zealand rugby and I love playing for both the Hurricanes and the All Blacks, love the jerseys, want to continue to grow as a player and help both teams succeed and add to the legacy."
He will make a decision about whether he will commit to sevens ahead of the Rio Olympics in due course.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Usain Bolt cruises to victory in Golden Spike meet</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/othersports-news/usain-bolt-cruises-victory-in-golden-spike-meet-6322914?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Usain Bolt cruised to victory in the 200 meters race at the Golden Spike meet today.</Description>
        <MainBody>Usain Bolt cruises to victory in Golden Spike meet
Published: 12:36PM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: AP
Text size + -

Usain Bolt crosses the finish line winning the 200 meters men event at the Golden Spike Athletic meeting in Czech Republic - Source: supplied by AP
Usain Bolt cruised to victory in the 200 meters race at the Golden Spike meet today, as the Jamaican star prepares for the world championships after a season marred by injuries.
Facing rain and cold at the IAAF World Challenge event, Bolt had the slowest reaction of all the sprinters, his traditional problem.
"It was one of my slowest reactions in a long time," Bolt said. "For me it was not a perfect day. It wasn't a perfect curve."
Still, the six-time Olympic champion came out of the bend slightly ahead and breezed unchallenged to victory, crossing the line in 20.13. Isiah Young of the United States finished second in 20.35 and Lykourgos Stefanos Tsakonas of Greece was third in 20.62.
"The shape that I'm in, and I'm coming back, I don't really know what to say is a decent time, or not," Bolt said. "I think I just need races, need to run a lot."
Bolt improved on his previous season's best of 20.20, clocked in April in Jamaica, though both are still far from his world record of 19.19 set in 2009. Today, it was more about dipping below 20 seconds.
"You can't be satisfied if I don't break 20.0, I really wanted to," Bolt said. "The conditions didn't allow. And I'm coming back from injuries, so it's going to take time."
Advertisement
He said he was not worried by not running fast times just yet. Tuesday was his first race in Europe this season as he prepares for the worlds in August in Beijing.
"I don't really try to stress too much over time," Bolt said. "I just want to get everything together and start feeling better."
He will have more chances to improve his times in the Diamond League meets in New York in June, and in Paris and Lausanne, Switzerland, the following month.
"The more I run the better I feel, the faster I can go," Bolt added. "Hopefully, in New York (there) are better conditions and I'll be able to push myself."
His countryman Asafa Powell won the 100 in 10.04, ahead of Young in 10.13 and while Britain's Richard Kilty clocked 10.31 in third.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:31:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kiwi-born England hooker Dylan Hartley charged over 'headbutt'</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/rugby-news/kiwi-born-england-hooker-dylan-hartley-charged-over-headbutt-6322875?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>England's hot-headed Rotorua-born hooker could miss vital games for England if found guilty.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

Northampton and England hooker Dylan Hartley will face a disciplinary panel tonight after being charged with headbutting an opponent.
Hartley, 29, was cited after an incident involving Jamie George during Saracens' 29-24 victory in Sunday's Premiership semi-final.
England coach Stuart Lancaster has previously warned New Zealand-born Hartley, who has been banned five times, over his discipline, the BBC reports.
He is likely to miss at least the World Cup warm-up games if found guilty.
The entry point for the offence is four weeks and disciplinary regulations state any ban must include matches.
That would mean Hartley - who has missed 50 weeks of his career through suspensions for offences ranging from gouging and biting to abusing a referee - would be sidelined for England's three fixtures in the lead-up to the World Cup.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:09:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boy taken to hospital after spending freezing night near Mt Taranaki</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/boy-taken-hospital-after-spending-freezing-night-near-mt-taranaki-6322437?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Phillip Pierson was found by a DOC worker who was in the area at the time checking stoat traps. </Description>
        <MainBody>Boy taken to hospital after spending freezing night near Mt Taranaki
updated 12:09
Text size + -

The 14-year-old boy missing in bush near Mt Taranaki has been found, police have confirmed to ONE News.
Phillip Pierson spent the night missing in freezing conditions near Mt Taranaki overnight.
The teen was cold and wet but uninjured police say. He has been taken to hospital.
Phillip was found at 11am by a DOC worker who was in the area at the time checking stoat traps. The worker was aware of the search and was looking out for the teen.
The Hawera High School student went missing in bush near Mt Taranaki yesterday after reportedly becoming lost while doing a navigation exercise.
About a dozen people searched on foot for the 14-year-old. A dog unit and helicopter were also involved.
The missing teen was part of Taranaki Outdoor Pursuits Education Centre group on the Egmont National Park's northern Mangaoraka Track yesterday when he became lost.
Advertisement
Inspector Keith Burrell said Phillip was wearing suitable clothing and has the appropriate outdoor equipment but he has had "limited outdoor experience".
Temperatures on the lower part of Mt Taranaki got down to -3 degrees overnight according to MetService.
Phillip's parents, Mark and Kirsten Pierson, had returned to the search scene at dawn after being there until 3am, The Taranaki Daily News reported.
This incident is not the first time Topec's safety has been called into question.
In 2013 Topec was ordered to pay nearly $270,000 to victims' families and survivors after an ill-fated trip in 2012, in which three people died.
Spotswood College students Stephen Kahukaka-Gedye and Felipe Melo, both 17, and their instructor Bryce Jourdain, 42, died after being swept out to sea while climbing around Paritutu Rock at New Plymouth.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:59:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Now's the chance to have your say on the future of NZ's fire service</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/now-s-chance-have-your-say-future-nz-fire-service-6322889?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A Govt study is looking at possibly the biggest changes to our fire services in 70 years.</Description>
        <MainBody>Now's the chance to have your say on the future of NZ's fire service
Published: 11:59AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Fire engine at Linwood fire. - Source: ONE News
Related
Blazes keep Fire Service busy in Canterbury video
The public can now have its say on proposed changes to New Zealand's fire services.
A discussion document has been released, which is described as looking at possibly the biggest fundamental changes to New Zealand's fire services since the 1940s.
People have until July 10 to make submissions.
The discussion document is in response to an independent review in 2012 which called for reform of the fire service.
Internal Affairs Minister Peter Dunne says government officials and the fire service have consulted more than 20 key organisations, "and found an appetite for change".
Mr Dunne says that consultation has identified three key problems, which he says place our fire services under increasing pressure: a lack of coordination and variable leadership and inconsistent investment decisions.
The three options suggested in the Government's discussion document are:
1. Enhanced status quo - Urban, rural and volunteer fire services would remain as separate entities. There would be increased support for volunteers.
Advertisement
2. Better support for volunteers and rural firefighters to include training and equipment. New fire districts would be established and new Rural Fire Authorities would be established.
3. One national fire service - This would integrate urban and rural, volunteer and career fire services into one national organisation.
Fire stations could be staffed by career (paid) firefighters, volunteer firefighters, or a mix.
Mr Dunne says there are problems with the insurance-based fire levy, including that it does not reflect the range of activities the New Zealand Fire Service provides, and it can be confusing to calculate.
Mr Dunne says the cost of making any changes to the fire services will depend on which option is chosen, and he says detailed financial modelling will take place to work out the cost of whichever option is chosen.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>One person injured after train and car collide in Canterbury</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/one-person-injured-after-train-and-car-collide-in-canterbury-6322823?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>One patient was taken by ambulance to Christchurch Hospital following the crash on Keens Road.</Description>
        <MainBody>One person injured after train and car collide in Canterbury
updated 11:23

Ambulance - Source: ONE News
One person was hurt when a Tranz Alpine train and a car collided at a railway crossing near Springfield in Canterbury this morning.
One patient was taken by ambulance to Christchurch Hospital following the crash at a level crossing on Keens Road. The level crossing had stop signs.
The train was travelling from Christchurch to Greymouth with 56 passengers and three staff on-board when the incident happened just after 9am. No one on the train was injured.
Because of the collision, the Tranz Alpine will no longer be operating today. Bus replacements will be provided for affected passengers.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Want to get paid millions? Run a media company</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/want-get-paid-millions-run-media-company-6322853?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Six of the 10 highest-paid CEOs last year worked in the media industry, according to a study.</Description>
        <MainBody>Want to get paid millions? Run a media company
Published: 11:23AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: AP
Yahoo chief executive Marissa Mayer. Photo / AP
Related
Added 08:50 Helen Clark just behind Beyonce in world's most powerful women list
They're not Hollywood stars, they're not TV personalities and they don't play in a rock band, but their pay packages are in the same league.
Six of the 10 highest-paid CEOs last year worked in the media industry, according to a study carried out by executive compensation data firm Equilar and The Associated Press.
The best-paid chief executive of a large American company was David Zaslav, head of Discovery Communications, the pay-TV channel operator that is home to Shark Week. His total compensation more than quadrupled to US$156.1 million in 2014 after he extended his contract.
Les Moonves, of CBS, held on to second place in the rankings, despite a drop in pay from a year earlier. His pay package totaled US$54.4 million.
The remaining four CEOs, from entertainment giants Viacom, Walt Disney, Comcast and Time Warner, have ranked among the nation's highest-paid executives for at least four years, according to the Equilar/AP pay study.
One reason for the high level of pay in the industry is that its CEOs are dealing with well-paid individuals.
"The talent, the actors and directors and writers, they're being paid a lot of money," said Steven Kaplan, a professor of finance at the University of Chicago Booth School of Business. "In industries where the talent makes a lot of money, the CEO makes a lot of money as well."
Pay packages for CEOs overall grew for the fifth straight year in 2014, driven by a rising stock market that pushed up the value of executive stock awards.
Advertisement
Median compensation for the heads of Standard &amp; Poor's 500 companies rose to a record US$10.6 million, up from US$10.5 million the year before, according to the Equilar/AP pay study.
Among other findings:
 Female CEOs again had a median pay package worth more than their male counterparts. Last year, women chief executives earned US$15.9 million compared with the median salary for male CEOs of US$10.4 million. The number of female CEOs included in the study rose to 17 from 12 in the previous year. Yahoo CEO Marissa Mayer was the highest paid, earning US$42.1 million, which placed her fifth among CEOs in the survey.
 The industry with the biggest pay increase was basic materials, which includes oil, mining and chemical companies. Median pay at these companies rose by 15 percent last year. Exxon Mobil CEO Rex Tillerson was the highest paid, making US$28.4 million last year.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mystery as projectiles smash into bus parked by playground</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/mystery-projectiles-smash-into-bus-parked-playground-6322827?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Police say the pair of projectiles shattered glass on the passenger side of the bus.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mystery as projectiles smash into bus parked by playground
Published: 11:02AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News

Police car - Source: ONE News
A bus window was smashed in by projectiles fired at it while it was parked opposite a Wellington playground.
Police say the Go Wellington bus was stopped by Kekerenga playground at about 7.10pm on Monday when the projectiles hit, shattering glass on its passenger side.
Investigators found two points of impact, police say.
No-one was hurt.
Anyone with information on the incident can call Wellington police on 04 381 2000.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man hands himself in to police after alleged attempted child abduction</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/man-hands-himself-in-police-after-alleged-attempted-child-abduction-6322826?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Yesterday police said a 10-year-old girl was walking her younger brother to school when a man began following them.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man hands himself in to police after alleged attempted child abduction
Published: 11:00AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Added 17:00 This man is wanted by police after sister foils attempted abduction of her little brother
A man has handed himself into police over an alleged attempted abduction of a five-year-old boy outside a Hastings school yesterday.
Police yesterday say a 10-year-old girl was walking her younger brother to St Matthews Primary School in King St, Hastings when a man began following them.
The man allegedly grabbed the boy and tried to lead him down a road.
He was released after they cried out, and the girl spoke to an adult at school.
The man went to the Hastings police station last night and was being interviewed today.
No charges have been laid yet, and police are appealing for anyone who may have seen the incident to come forward.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:43:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cops confident of identity of man found dead in Rotorua stream</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/cops-confident-identity-man-found-dead-in-rotorua-stream-6322804?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Police say they will not speculate on the circumstances of the death.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cops confident of identity of man found dead in Rotorua stream
Published: 10:43AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News

New Zealand Police - Source: ONE News
Police believe they know the identity of the man found dead in a Rotorua stream yesterday.
A post mortem examination is taking place this morning to establish the cause of death.
In the meantime police are completing a search of the stream where the man was found, and also the walkway behind Ruth Street remains closed.
Police say they will not speculate on the circumstances of the death.
No details will be released until the identity is formally confirmed and his family have been notified.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Six fire crews battle Upper Hutt house fire</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/six-fire-crews-battle-upper-hutt-house-6322791?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Everyone from the residence is accounted for and no neighbouring properties are in danger.</Description>
        <MainBody>Six fire crews battle Upper Hutt house fire
Published: 10:37AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Firefighters battle a blaze. - Source: iStock
Related
Five storey Porirua building evacuated after fire breaks out video
The Fire Service is currently dealing with a fire in the roof of a single story home in Upper Hutt.
Fire crews were alerted to the blaze on Whitemans Valley Rd just before 10am and there are six appliances in attendance.
Everyone from the residence is accounted for and no neighbouring properties are in danger.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:28:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mosquito-borne virus causes fears for Pacific visitors</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/mosquito-borne-virus-causes-fears-pacific-visitors-6322781?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The chikungunya virus causes intense joint pain and can last for several months.</Description>
        <MainBody>
Beach at Cook Islands - Source: ONE News
Visitors to the Pacific are being warned to seek medical help if they suspect they have the mosquito-borne chikungunya virus which has hit the region.
The virus has so far affected half of the Pacific's 22 countries and territories, with both the Cook Islands and Marshall Islands currently reporting cases that are either peaking or increasing.
Symptoms include high fever and recurring intense joint pain similar to dengue - and it can last several months.
Surveillance experts at the Secretariat of the Pacific Community (SPC) say the virus was first reported in 2011 and is rapidly spreading through the region.
The Cook Islands Public Health Service has stepped up efforts to control the spread of chikungunya and are considering widening its spraying programme.
Director of Community Health Services Dr Neti Herman told Cook Islands News 536 cases have been reported in the last 20 weeks but believe it's now on the decline.
Visitors to affected areas can avoid contracting the disease by protecting themselves from mosquito bites.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Large swells force Cook Strait ferry cancellations</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/large-swells-force-cook-strait-ferry-cancellations-6322776?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The large swells and rough weather forced the cancellation of the Aratere sailings this morning. </Description>
        <MainBody>Large swells force Cook Strait ferry cancellations
Published: 10:24AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: NZN
The Interislander ferry Aratere. - Source: ONE News
Related
Replacement for Interislander veteran Arahura revealed
Massive waves in the Cook Strait have disrupted inter-island ferry sailings for a third day.
The large swells and rough weather forced the cancellation of the Aratere sailings this morning and freight and passengers would be transferred to the larger Kaitaki, Interislander says.
Bluebridge also says its sailings are affected.
Interislander cancelled sailings on Monday and yesterday as heavy swells of 5.9 metres and winds of up to 50 knots blew through the strait.
KiwiRail spokeswoman Julie Buchanan says it expects to carry passengers on the Kaitaki today but warned the swells could rise to exceed safe passenger limits.
"These large swells are likely to continue on the Cook Strait for the next few days and we will advise if they reach any sailing cut-off levels."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:19:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boy's family forgive woman who snatched hero's football jersey and tried to sell it for $3k</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/boy-s-family-forgive-woman-snatched-hero-football-jersey-and-tried-sell-3k-6322771?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Cameras caught the moment Vickie Trimbell yanked the shirt out of Ted Dockray's hands.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boy's family forgive woman who snatched hero's football jersey and tried to sell it for $3k
Published: 10:19AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

The family of a young boy who had a prized football jersey wrenched from him on live television say they aren't angry at the woman who snatched the shirt.
Ted Dockray, 8, caught a shirt thrown by striker Jermaine Beckford after he scored a hat-trick in Preston North End's League One playoff win over Swindon at Wembley Stadium over the weekend.
Cameras caught the moment the shirt was stolen from him by Vickie Timbrell, 31, who reportedly went on to try sell it for $3000 on an online auction site.
Ted's aunt Claire Dockray says the family knows Timbrell, who lives about 2km away from them in Manchester, the Daily Mail reports. They have no hard feelings towards her, Dockray said.
"[Ted] was a bit disappointed but he's fine.
"My family would never want any trouble for the woman over a football shirt. I'm sure it will be a happy ending for everyone involved."
Trimbell said she plans to clear the air with the Dockray family, in posts on social media.
She said the media have twisted what happened, and she would soon tell her side of the story.
Advertisement
"People have made me out to be an absolute idiot," said Ms Timbrell. "I will be speaking to the family, I actually know them, they're friends."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Video busts pair robbing Auckland liquor store with gun, machete - do you know them?</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/video-busts-pair-robbing-auckland-liquor-store-gun-machete-do-you-know-them-6322762?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Police say they arrived in a stolen vehicle which was later found and has been examined by police.</Description>
        <MainBody>Auckland police are on the hunt for two armed men who allegedly robbed a liquor store with a shotgun and machete on Monday evening.
They held up the Oaks Tavern and Liquor Store on Great South Rd, Penrose.
One had a shotgun, the other a long knife or machete.
Police say they arrived in a stolen vehicle which was later found and has been examined by police.
They are keen to hear from anyone who may have any information about the incident.
Call or send a message to Detective Sergeant James Robson on 021 191 2963. If you want to remain anonymous, call Crimestoppers on 0800 555 111.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chinese man covers himself in a million bees, gets stung 2000 times</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/chinese-man-covers-himself-in-million-bees-gets-stung-2000-times-6322747?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Gao Bingguom casually smoked a cigarette as 109.1kg of bees swarmed over his body.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chinese man covers himself in a million bees, gets stung 2000 times
Published: 10:08AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

A Chinese beekeeper has covered himself in a world record-breaking one million bees while casually smoking a cigarette.
Gao Bingguom, from China's northern Shandong province, was reportedly stung more than 2000 times during his world record attempt yesterday.
He placed 12 queen bees on himself, then waited for about three hours as worker bees swarmed on his body, the Daily Mail reports.
By the end of the attempt, only Bingguom's mouth - and cigarette - were visible.
He was recording as having 109.1kg, or about 1.1 million, bees on his body, reclaiming the world record he lost to a fellow bee enthusiast last year.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man's body found in submerged car on Auckland's North Shore</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/man-s-body-found-in-submerged-car-auckland-north-shore-6322508?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Emergency services are at the scene in the Auckland suburb of Greenhithe. </Description>
        <MainBody>Man's body found in submerged car on Auckland's North Shore
updated 10:03
'I miss you so much bro' - NZ Army recruit pays tribute to drowned comrade
A man's body has been found in a semi submerged car in the North Shore suburb of Greenhithe.
It was found by a member of the public near the Salthouse boat builders at the end of Rame Rd just after 7am.
Emergency services, including a dive team, are at the scene.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Black Caps skipper Brendon McCullum stars in Dwayne Bravo music video</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/cricket-news/black-caps-skipper-brendon-mccullum-stars-in-dwayne-bravo-music-video-6322680?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The Windies all-rounder made the video for Chalo! Chalo! with the popular Trinidad and Tobago crossover artist Nisha B.</Description>
        <MainBody>Black Caps skipper Brendon McCullum stars in Dwayne Bravo music video
Published: 9:50AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

Black Caps captain Brendon McCullum has made a brief guest appearance in a music video released by West Indies player Dwayne Bravo.
The Windies all-rounder made the video for Chalo! Chalo! with the popular Trinidad and Tobago crossover artist Nisha B.
As well as McCullum, the likes of Ms Dhoni, Suresh Raina and Chris Gayle appear.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cyclist fighting for life after Auckland truck crash</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/cyclist-fighting-life-after-auckland-truck-crash-6322649?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The incident happened on Sarsfield St in Herne Bay just before 8am.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cyclist fighting for life after Auckland truck crash
Published: 9:44AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
A cyclist is in a critical condition after becoming trapped underneath a truck in Auckland this morning.
The incident happened on Sarsfield St in Herne Bay just before 8am.
The cyclist has been taken to hospital and police are investigating.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ronchi could make Black Caps Test debut with Watling, Anderson battling injury</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/cricket-news/ronchi-could-make-black-caps-test-debut-watling-anderson-battling-injury-6322496?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Black Caps wicketkeeper BJ Watling and all-rounder Corey Anderson are in doubt for the second cricket Test against England starting at Headingly on Friday</Description>
        <MainBody>Ronchi could make Black Caps Test debut with Watling, Anderson battling injury
Published: 8:50AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

Black Caps wicketkeeper BJ Watling and all-rounder Corey Anderson are in doubt for the second cricket Test against England starting at Headingly on Friday.
Watling suffered a knock to his knee on the opening day of the first Test at Lord's while Anderson had problems with his back.
Watling handed the gloves over to Tom Latham in the Lord's match, although he did managed to bat, scoring half centuries in each innings.
Anderson had problems in the field and with the ball, only managing 8 overs.
"Coach Mike Hesson rates Watling as 50-50, while he says Anderson was in a fair amount of pain during the game, so they'll have to continue monitoring him.
"BJ's not 10%, clearly his knee is still an issue," coach Mike Hesson said.
"He struggles to push off and get a lot of power so he's a 50-50 at this stage. From Corey's perspective bowling was painful and so was fielding so we'll need to monitor that."
If Watling is ruled out, Luke Ronchi will make his Test debut behind the stumps while Doug Bracewell looms as Anderson's most likely replacment.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Helen Clark just behind Beyonce in world's most powerful women list</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/helen-clark-just-behind-beyonce-in-s-most-powerful-women-list-6322497?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The former PM was named in a diverse set of luminaries that includes Taylor Swift and Hilary Clinton.</Description>
        <MainBody>Helen Clark just behind Beyonce in world's most powerful women list
Published: 8:50AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Taylor Swift, Helen Clark and Hillary Clinton. Photos / Creative Commons
Watch Video
Kevin Rudd quashes rumours of taking on Helen Clark for UN role
Helen Clark has been named alongside luminaries including Hillary Clinton and Taylor Swift in Forbes' rundown of the world's 100 most powerful women.
The former New Zealand Prime Minister was ranked 23 on the annual list - two spots behind pop superstar Beyonce.
Ms Clark is tipped as a contender to succeed Ban Ki-moon as UN Secretary-General when his term finishes in 2016.
She talked to Forbes about leadership strategy , in an interview drawing on her previous experience in New Zealand politics.
"If you don't believe in yourself, how can you expect others to believe in you?" she said. "You haveto have avery strong sense of self-belief to rise to and stay in leadership positions."
Meanwhile, popstar Taylor Swift made her debut entry at number 64 on the list.
Other entertainers to make the list include Beyonce, Oprah, actress Sofia Vergara and talk show host Ellen DeGeneres.
German chancellor Angela Merkel was ranked number one for the fifth year running.
Former US First Lady Hillary Clinton was number two, while current First Lady Michelle Obama came in at 10.
Advertisement
Forbes top 10 most powerful women:
1. Angela Merkel, Chancellor of Germany
2. Hillary Clinton, US Presidential candidate
3. Melinda Gates, Co-chairwoman, Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation
4. Janet Yellen, Chairwoman, US Federal Reserve Bank
5. Mary Barra, CEO, General Motors
6. Christine Lagarde, Managing Director, International Monetary Fund
7. Dilma Rousseff, President of Brazil
8. Sheryl Sandberg, CEO of Facebook
9. Susan Wojcicki, CEO of Youtube
10. Michelle Obama, US First Lady
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kiwi troops in Iraq 'could be executed' by ISIS - expert</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/kiwi-troops-in-iraq-could-executed-isis-expert-6322489?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>New Zealand troops are stationed just over 90km from an ISIS controlled city.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

New Zealand troops in Iraq are in danger of being executed by Islamic State fighters, an international law professor says.
Iraqi forces lost the city of Ramadi to ISIS around two weeks ago. Ramadi is just over 90km from Taji where 143 New Zealand troops are based.
Professor Al Gillespie told TVNZ's Breakfast programme this morning the Kiwi troops are at risk from ISIS.
This assessment is at odds with Prime Minister John Key's assertion this week the ISIS advance isn't putting the New Zealand troops in danger.
"The risk is if ISIS get through to our soldiers they could be executed," Mr Gillespie said.
"There's no crime ISIS hasn't committed. Rape, execution of prisoners, looting - it's all there. There's nothing they haven't done."
Mr Gillespie says it's becoming more likely Western group troops will be deployed in Iraq.
Currently the New Zealand troops in Iraq are only tasked with training Iraqi Army troops.
Advertisement
But if the United States decide to deploy ground troops to fight ISIS, Mr Gillespie believes it's likely New Zealand will be asked to contribute fighting troops as well.
Earlier this week Mr Key was asked if there was an exit strategy for New Zealand troops.
He said there are early warnings situations that determine whether things need to be reviewed and at this point those warnings have not been triggered.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ozone hole would be 40% bigger if not for CFC ban</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/ozone-hole-would-40-bigger-if-not-cfc-ban-6322483?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A very large Arctic ozone hole would have occurred in the northern hemisphere in 2011 as well.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ozone hole would be 40% bigger if not for CFC ban
Published: 8:33AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
A projection of the super-sized ozone hole that was avoided - Source: ONE News
Related
Young mum shares shocking selfie after tanning bed caused skin cancer
The deadly hole in the ozone layer over Antarctica could be half as big as it currently is if not for an agreement to stop using chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs).
Research carried out by scientists in New Zealand and the United Kingdom estimates that if the protocol to stop using the ozone depleting CFCs had not been agreed in 1989, the ozone hole over the Antarctic would have been 40 per cent bigger by 2013.
A very large Arctic ozone hole would have occurred in the northern hemisphere in 2011 as well.
CFCs were common in a range of products from hair spray, to refrigerators and air conditioning units. In 1987 what would become known as the Montreal Protocol was signed phasing out their commercial use.
The study, published in Nature Communications today, also found that cancer-causing surface ultraviolet radiation in Australia and New Zealand could have increased by as much as 12 per cent. Australia and New Zealand currently have the highest mortality rates from skin cancer in the world.
The report includes work from New Zealand National Institute of Water and Atmospheric Research (NIWA) staff as well as the English teams and used a state-of-the art 3D atmospheric chemistry model.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:21:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Auckland University unfazed by rival's quip over housing headache</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/auckland-university-unfazed-rival-s-quip-over-housing-headache-6322479?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>University of Canterbury launched a tongue-in-cheek campaign offering to help Aucklanders facing a housing crisis. </Description>
        <MainBody>Auckland University unfazed by rival's quip over housing headache
Published: 8:21AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: NZN
New housing regulations: 'More holes than a slice of Swiss cheese' video
The University of Auckland says it is not worried the city's expensive housing will cause it to lose students.
University of Canterbury launched a tongue-in-cheek campaign yesterday offering to help Aucklanders facing a housing crisis get out of the city.
Its vice-chancellor, Rod Carr, said Christchurch offered freedom from the long commutes and expensive housing of Auckland.
"It's a fact that some students in Auckland travel 90 minutes or more to tertiary study from flats they can afford," he said.
"In Canterbury, 90 minutes gets you to a ski field."
But University of Auckland vice-chancellor Stuart McCutcheon said he was not fazed by such arguments.
"The University of Auckland has actively supported the University of Canterbury in its recovery from the earthquakes and we fully understand why they would want to attract students from Auckland," he said.
"However, having constructed over 1100 beds in our halls of residence over the last four years, we are well positioned to accommodate our students."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:16:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Australian Trevor Bayliss appointed England cricket coach</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/cricket-news/australian-trevor-bayliss-appointed-england-coach-6322474?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Enland hired Trevor Bayliss as its new head cricket coach on Tuesday, and the Australian's first task will be to recapture the Ashes against his native country</Description>
        <MainBody>Australian Trevor Bayliss appointed England cricket coach
Published: 8:15AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: AP
Australian Trevor Bayliss appointed England cricket coach - Source: Getty Images
Related
Defiant McCullum claims Black Caps did everything needed to win (+ video) video
Enland hired Trevor Bayliss as its new head cricket coach on Tuesday, and the Australian's first task will be to recapture the Ashes against his native country.
The 52-year-old Bayliss never played international cricket for Australia but has had success around the world as a coach.
He led Sri Lanka to the 2011 World Cup final, won the Indian Premier League twice at the helm of Kolkata Knight Riders and has coached New South Wales, the side he departs for England, to two Sheffield Shield titles in Australia. He has also won the Australian Big Bash and Champions League with the Sydney Sixers.
"It is an honor to be appointed England coach," Bayliss said. "What particularly excites me about the role is the chance to work with a very talented group of players. I firmly believe that the team has a bright future and I'll be doing everything I can to help them realize their potential and achieve success on a consistent basis."
England is currently halfway through a two-test series against New Zealand, which it leads 1-0. Bayliss will begin his tenure with the opening Ashes test on July 8, in Cardiff, with England looking to avenge its 5-0 whitewash from 2013-14.
With a proven track record in the white ball format of the game, Bayliss will also be tasked with rejuvenating the side for one-day and T20 fixtures.
England disappointed at the World Cup earlier this year, eliminated in the group stage of the competition in Australia and New Zealand with four defeats in six games.
There are three major upcoming tournaments in the shorter editions of cricket that Bayliss will look to galvanize England for. The World T20 is in India in 2016, before the ICC Champions Trophy in 2017 and the Cricket World Cup in 2019, which will both be held in England and Wales.
"There's a great opportunity to help (test and one-day captains) Alastair Cook and Eoin Morgan shape the direction and development of their respective teams," Bayliss said.
England and Wales Cricket Board director Andrew Strauss spoke of Bayliss' success in limited overs cricket as a distinguishing factor in searching for a replacement for Peter Moores, who Strauss fired as head coach.
Advertisement
"His expertise in the shorter forms of the game will be vital," Strauss said. "Trevor has an outstanding record as coach, has global experience and is very highly regarded in the game. He has proved himself in both domestic and international cricket, has a strong reputation for man-management and has shown how to build winning teams in all three formats."
Paul Farbrace, England's temporary coach following the dismissal of Moores, was the No. 2 to Bayliss with Sri Lanka and will be an assistant coach when he takes over with England.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kiwi bike ace in horrifying crash after brakes fail (+video)</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/othersports-news/kiwi-bike-ace-in-horrifying-crash-after-brakes-fail-video-6322470?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Kiwi adventure junkie Kelly McGarry has survived a horrifying crash while competing in an event in China.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kiwi rider makes history at Red Bull Rampage video
Kiwi adventure junkie Kelly McGarry has survived a horrifying crash while competing in an event in China.
The mountain bike ace went over his handlebars after his brakes failed near the end of a ramp filled with navigation hazards such as stairs and jumps at the Tianmenshan Red Bull event.
He was left motionless before receiving medical attention at the weekend event.
La escalofriante cada de Kelly McGarry en la Red Bull Sky Gate Mountain - http://t.co/DprkJfjxT9 pic.twitter.com/VHEuv7ZJ2R
 Planet Mountain Bike (@Planet_MTB) May 26, 2015
"Hey team thanks for the messages, I'm all good, munched my foot a bit and got two cuts on arm totalling 7 stitches," he wrote in a message that was posted by Vital MTB.
"Brakes cooked and pulled to the bar half way down course ( 1000 ft of 50 degree stairs + 97 kg bloke at race pace) ...was on a runaway train ...Scary moment for sure .Stoked to be ok. Cheers".
McGarry has gained widespread acclaim for his death-defying stunts, including landing a 22-metre backflip in Utah.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Horror Texas flooding: Family washed away in holiday house</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/horror-texas-flooding-family-washed-away-in-holiday-house-6322440?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Others killed include a 14-year-old who was found with his dog in a storm drain.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cars in floodwaters in Houston. Photo / AP
Related
Texas, Mexico smashed by 'relentless tsunami-type' floods and tornado video
Floodwaters are still rising across Texas as rescuers search for 30 missing people, including a group trapped in a vacation home that washed away and slammed into a bridge.
Houston authorities recovered three more bodies from the floodwaters overnight, bringing to 11 the number of people killed by the storms in Oklahoma and Texas.
Among the missing was the group in the vacation home that was swept away in the flooded Blanco River in Central Texas.
Crews also searched for victims just across the Texas-Mexico border in Ciudad Acuna, where a tornado killed an infant who was ripped from its mother's arms yesterday.
Firefighters in Houston carried out more than 500 water rescues, mostly stranded motorists.
At least 2500 vehicles were abandoned on the streets by drivers, said Rick Flanagan, Houston's emergency management coordinator.
"It's absolutely massive," Texas Governor Greg Abbott said after touring the destruction.
Some motorists were stuck on Interstate 45 all night, sleeping in their cars.
NBA fans at a Houston Rockets game were asked not to leave the arena because of the severe weather. About 400 people remained in their seats at 1.30am, choosing to stay in the building.
Advertisement
Some of the worst flooding damage in Texas was in Wimberley, a popular tourist town where the vacation home was swept away.
A spokeswoman for the flood district of Harris County, which includes Houston, said up to 700 homes had some level of damage.
The deaths in Texas included a 14-year-old who was found with his dog in a storm drain; a student who died after her car was caught in high water; and a man whose mobile home was destroyed by a tornado.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:21:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Redundant Stockton Mine workers will struggle to find jobs - MP</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/redundant-stockton-mine-workers-struggle-find-jobs-mp-6322447?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Solid Energy yesterday confirmed it was cutting 113 jobs at the Westport mine.</Description>
        <MainBody>Stockton mine. - Source: ONE News
Related
West Coast reeling from job cuts at beleaguered Stockton mine video
Redundant Stockton Mine workers will have difficulty finding jobs, says West Coast MP Damien O'Connor.
Solid Energy yesterday confirmed it was cutting 113 jobs at the Westport mine after announcing earlier this month staff numbers would be cut from 397 to 246.
There are 38 vacant positions, leaving 113 workers redundant.
"The impact of these jobs will be severe," Mr O'Connor said.
"They will struggle to find alternative employment in the short term... there's an urgent need for new economic opportunities on the West Coast."
State-owned Solid Energy says the changes are necessary as it cuts production at the mine from 1.4 million tonnes a year to one million tonnes from July in an attempt to stem losses which have averaged $2.1 million a month this financial year.
Earlier this month, Buller District Mayor Garry Howard said he felt a sense of relief at the announcement which had been causing a lot of anxiety while it hung over the small community.
"It could have been a lot worse," he told NZ Newswire.
Advertisement
The cuts come as the price of coal falls to $US83 ($110.50) a tonne - much lower than the benchmark price of $US120 mid last year.
Last year 185 jobs went at the mine and Solid Energy previously mothballed its Spring Creek underground mine on the West Coast.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Radio DJ bludgeons baby bunny live on air - and then refuses to apologise</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/radio-dj-bludgeons-baby-bunny-live-air-and-then-refuses-apologise-6322443?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The stunt was aimed at exposing Danes' "hypocrisy" on animal welfare, the radio station says.</Description>
        <MainBody>'You're disgusting': Animal rights activist crash Kim Kardashian's book signing (0:23)
A radio DJ is unapologetic after bludgeoning a baby rabbit to death with a bicycle pump live on air.
Danish radio presenter Asger Juhl killed the bunny with repeated blows to the head in his show on Radio24syv this week.
The station has defended the stunt as an attempt to raise awareness about animal cruelty.
It aimed to expose Danes' "hypocrisy" on animal welfare, the station wrote on Facebook .
"Every day in the nation of Denmark, thousands and thousands of animals are put down to fill the meat counters in our super markets. Danish agriculture is one of the most industrialized in the world. But we do not seem to focus much on animal welfare," it wrote.
"These animals have often endured horrific suffering on their way to our dinner tables. These animals are killed according to the same controlled conditions as our studio rabbit, and without it invoking any strong reactions or calls for boycott.
"We at least believe that the studio rabbit have had a comfortable existence."
The bunny was killed according to instructions from a professional animal caretaker at a Danish zoo, the station says.
Juhl reportedly severed the bunny's spinal column by hitting it on the neck with the bicycle pump. He later took the animal home, where he skinned it and cooked it for his family.
Read Radio24syv's statement:

Every day in the nation of Denmark, thousands and thousands of animals are put down to fill the meat counters in our...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Maui's dolphin could be extinct in 15 years - research</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/maui-s-dolphin-could-extinct-in-15-years-research-6322436?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Estimates indicate there are only between 43 and 47 left alive and only 10 are mature females.</Description>
        <MainBody>NZ criticised for failing to protect Maui's dolphin
The Maui's dolphin could be extinct within 15 years unless something is done, researchers warn.
Estimates by Germany-based conservation group Nabu International indicate there are only between 43 and 47 of this rarest dolphin left alive and only 10 are mature females.
The researchers called for more to be done to protect the animal, including tighter laws around fishing nets and extending fishing bans in the dolphin's habitat.
Nabu head of endangered species Barbara Maas described the findings as a "wake-up call" for New Zealand to take the risk of extinction more seriously.
The Green Party called for "all the stops" to be pulled out by the Government to try to save the dolphin.
"We either do everything we can to save these unique animals, the population of which can only withstand one human-induced death every 10 to 23 years, or we lose them," conservation spokeswoman Eugenie Sage said.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hopes new forestry safety council will cut industry's high death toll</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/hopes-new-forestry-safety-council-cut-industry-s-high-death-toll-6322429?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Since 2010, 25 bushmen have been killed on the job and 800 more seriously injured.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hopes new forestry safety council will cut industry's high death toll
By ONE News Reporter Ryan Boswell
Published: 6:44AM Wednesday May 27, 2015
Text size + -

It's hoped the forest industry's new safety council will save lives and enlighten other dangerous workplaces.
The Forest Industry Safety Council (FISC) was launched at Parliament last night and will be chaired by Dame Alison Paterson.
The board will be made up of forest owners, contractors, workers, unions and Worksafe New Zealand.
It was a key recommendation put forward last year by the Independent Safety Review Panel, set up to review the industry after a record number of deaths and injuries.
Since 2010, 25 bushmen have been killed on the job and 800 more seriously injured.
The Safety Council will work to implement the review's recommendations, which have a strong focus on training and making sure bushmen are well looked after.
Forest Owners Association president Paul Nicholls told ONE News that bushmen will be involved at every step.
"Unless we've got them involved in this Forest Industry Safety Council we've not going to achieve anything. It's getting everyone working together."
Advertisement
Mr Nicholls says "if a job can't be done safely, it shouldn't be done at all".
The Minister for Workplace Relations and Safety Michael Woodhouse is optimistic about forestry's future.
"The establishment of FISC is the evidence that the sector must be the author of improving its own health and safety destiny," Mr Woodhouse says.
Worksafe New Zealand is helping fund the council along with ACC and the industry.
Worksafe's chief executive Gordon MacDonald says the transformation of the industry will be "remarkable", "fundamental" and a model for other sectors to adopt.
The Council of Trade Unions president Helen Kelly was acknowledged for her commitment to protecting bushmen and their families.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eugenie Bouchard stunned at French Open</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/tennis-news/eugenie-bouchard-stunned-french-open-6322422?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Eugenie Bouchard's disappointing season continues after a first-round exit at the French Open</Description>
        <MainBody>Eugenie Bouchard stunned at French Open
Published: 6:32AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: AP
Eugenie Bouchard's disappointing season continues after a first-round exit at the French Open.
The sixth-seeded Canadian was stunned 6-4, 6-4, by France's Kristina Mladenovic.
Bouchard showed some fight, battling back from 5-0 down in the second set. But
her comeback started too far too late.
The Westmount, Que., native reached the semifinal at Roland Garros last year in a breakout season that also saw her advance to the Wimbledon final and the
semifinals at the Australian Open.
This year has been the complete opposite for Bouchard, who has struggled after reaching the quarter-finals at the Australian Open.
Advertisement
Bouchard has lost seven of her last eight matches, and most of the defeats have been to players well below her in the WTA rankings.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:52:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Drunk food vendor kills one with SUV at concert</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/drunk-food-vendor-kills-one-suv-concert-6322418?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Officials say Bill Jason Carson got in his Toyota 4-Runner with a gun and started spinning the SUV.</Description>
        <MainBody>Drunk food vendor kills one with SUV at concert
Published: 5:52AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: AP
Driver suffering a stroke pepper-sprayed by US police (+video) video
A food vendor at a country music concert is accused of starting a fight and hitting several people with his SUV, killing one.
The Scott County Sherriff's Office tells WBIR-TV that Bill Jason Carson was intoxicated and started the fight near singer Trace Adkins' concert in Tennessee on Sunday.
Officials say Carson then got in his Toyota 4-Runner with a gun and started spinning the SUV.
Witnesses say Carson hit an ATV and another car and ran over four men. One died at the scene. Two were airlifted to a hospital.
Officials say a Jeep rammed into Carson's SUV to stop him, and security staff detained him.
Carson is charged with homicide and felony reckless endangerment.
The sheriff's office didn't immediately return a call from The Associated Press to find out whether Carson had a lawyer who could comment on the case.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:38:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The polar blast has gone but don't get rid of the woolly jumper just yet</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/polar-blast-has-gone-but-don-t-get-rid-woolly-jumper-just-yet-6322417?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>There will still be some frosty nights to come and says to keep the extra layers handy.</Description>
        <MainBody>The polar blast has gone but don't get rid of the woolly jumper just yet
Published: 5:38AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
'It's the most I've ever seen': Cold blast dumps 30cm of snow on South Island (0:52)
New Zealand will today say goodbye to the polar blast which hit the country with ferocity this week.
ONE News weather presenter Dan Corbett says "we've finally kicked the polar blast out the back door" and things will slowly improve over the coming days.
Corbett expects there will be a chilly start this morning, with scattered showers across the country, but says it is expected to slowly warm up later in the day.
He warns there will still be some frosty nights to come and says to keep the extra layers handy.
Corbett predicts "some lovely days" on Thursday and Friday ahead of the long weekend.
Temperatures plunged below freezing overnight Tuesday, with Marlborough reaching -5 degrees Celsius and Masterton -4.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:29:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> 'They're just bloody scrooges' – dad looking after special needs kids has pay cut by DHB</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/they-re-just-bloody-scrooges-dad-looking-after-special-needs-kids-has-pay-cut-dhb-6322416?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>For many years the Government refused to pay Mr Robinson and the many other full time family carers.</Description>
        <MainBody>'They're just bloody scrooges'  dad looking after special needs kids has pay cut by DHB
Published: 5:30AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

A nearly 80-year-old father is fighting the Government so he can continue to look after his two special needs children after his pay was reduced.
Solo dad Cliff Robinson has been caring for his two adult children, Marita and Johnny, for 50 years.
For most of those years the Government refused to pay Mr Robinson and the many other full time family carers.
"They're just bloody scrooges, they're just scrooges," he told Seven Sharp.
"Just think what we have sacrificed to love our kids and live a decent life and if you were in the same position would you expect any less?"
Wanting to be paid like a professional care giver, Mr Robinson took the Government to court and won in a historic case.
But recently the Government reduced his working hours after a botched DHB assessment determined he was getting too old.
The DHB now wants to pay an additional carer to help Mr Robinson, despite a Government initiative that has $23 million set aside for about 200 families receiving money under the family care scheme.
Advertisement
However, only about $5 million has been spent on those families.
"I cant' believe they can be so incompetent," Mr Robinson said.
"No man can cuddle a daughter like I can give her a cuddle ... Just let them stay here for a couple of days and see what a fellow like me does."
Associate Health Minister Sam Lotu-Iiga said an evaluation was currently underway for the scheme which was implemented a year ago.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> 'I'm extremely lucky' - Strangers help give cancer sufferer’s family their dream home</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/i-m-extremely-lucky-strangers-help-give-cancer-sufferer-s-family-their-dream-home-6322415?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>"How do you say thank you? Words aren't really enough," says Ty Archibald.</Description>
        <MainBody>Young mum shares shocking selfie after tanning bed caused skin cancer
A carpenter who has terminal cancer says he does not know how to express his gratitude to the dozens of tradies and strangers who helped him build his family's dream home.
Seven Sharp met Ty Archibald just over three months ago as he set out to build a new home for his family.
The 34-year-old's quest become a rallying cry for at least 200 tradies and strangers, who Mr Archibald says appeared out of nowhere, offering up their time, skills and materials to help him in the process.
The house, which has four bedrooms and two bathrooms, is now built and he says it is what he had been waiting for "for so long".
"This is more than I could ever hope for really. I am extremely lucky aye, extremely lucky," he added.
Mr Archibald says half of the house "is for the adults" while the other half is for his children "so they can grow up and have their own space".
The 34-year-old's young daughters think the result is "really good".
His former boss Tony, who helped in the build, says it didn't feel like a big effort because so many people helped out.
Mr Achibald's best friend Ben gave up his job in Australia to come to Mahana, near Nelson, to help with the house, with stone work being his speciality.
"He's been here four months now with no pay, so I take my hat off to him, because I couldn't have done it without him," Mr Archibald says.
Ben says he was blown away by the "massive gang of brilliant people" in the community who offered up their skills.
Advertisement
"The fact everyone has come together and worked as hard as they have, it is just mind-blowing."
Mr Archibald says he does not know how to convey to everyone involved just how thankful he is.
"How do you say thank you? Words aren't really enough.
"For me it's just, look I can rest easy now."
And he says his family will have plenty of time in the house "to make good memories and just enjoy life, which is what it's all about".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Renting has a negative impact on children - study</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/renting-has-negative-impact-children-study-6322414?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Children most likely to live in low-income families are also the children most likely to move frequently.</Description>
        <MainBody>
Rental property prices are edging up - Source: Photos.com
Students moving homes and jumping from one school to the next will lead to problems in the classroom, a new study has found.
Research into transience in Auckland primary schools will be released today at Manurewa East School by the Child Poverty Action Group (CPAG).
The study also found that children in poorer families are also likely to be forced to move because their parents are renters.
The group surveyed 52 schools in south and west Auckland and found that transience was a significant issue for low decile schools.
CPAG's chief researcher Donna Wynd said: "Transience can no more be dealt with by the education sector than rheumatic fever can be dealt with by throat swabs."
"Both issues have at their heart a lack of affordable housing. We must address the causes of transience by introducing housing policies that actively address the shortage of secure, affordable housing in the areas where low-income families live, particularly in South Auckland."
She said the reports also showed a lack of progress for some transient students, which pulls down schools' national standards achievement results.
Ms Wynd added that the children most likely to live in low-income families are also the children most likely to move frequently.
Advertisement
CPAG's survey found decile 1 schools had a median roll turnover of 30%, while higher-decile schools had far lower turnover rates, (although the small sample of higher-decile schools in this study may not reflect the experience of all schools in higher deciles).
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Marina Erakovic just falls short of mighty Petra Kvitova upset</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/tennis-news/marina-erakovic-just-falls-short-mighty-petra-kvitova-upset-6322412?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>New Zealand tennis player Marina Erakovic came close to a mighty upset at the French Open last night</Description>
        <MainBody>Marina Erakovic just falls short of mighty Petra Kvitova upset
Published: 4:54AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

New Zealand tennis player Marina Erakovic came close to a mighty upset at the French Open last night.
Erakovic, ranked 82th in the world, pushed fourth seed Petra Kvitova all the way before going down 6-3 3-6 6-4 in a match which lasted two hours and 27 minutes on Court Philippe Chatrier.
The left hander from the Czech Republic racked up 47 unforced errors, but came up with 38 winners to avoid a shock early exit in the second slam of the year.
The 27-year-old Aucklander made 33 unforced errors but actually won more points than the Czech - 109 to 106 - but Kvitova came up with the crucial winners at the crucial times.
Kvitova was up against it in the first set when Erakovic broke to lead 3-2, but the world number four battled back by winning four games in a row to take the first set.
Erakovic has only beaten one top 10 opponent in her career but gave herself a great chance of claiming another big scalp by breaking in the first game of the second set and forcing a further two breaks to level the match.
Kvitova, who won her 16th WTA title and her second on clay in Madrid earlier this month, was broken a further two times in the deciding set but claimed three breaks of her own before serving out the match to love.
"I have to say the conditions weren't really easy for me. I think it was quite cold and the balls are really heavy, and they didn't really fly," said Kvitova, who will next take on Silvia Soler-Espinosa of Spain.
Advertisement
"For me it was really difficult to go for the shots. It was tough to make any winners or, you know, ace from the serve or something like that.
"It was very difficult today. It was quite a long match, big fight. Sometimes I couldn't win my serve. So it was a little bit difficult. But that's how it is in the first round of grand slams."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Tue May 26 13:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Austrian boy, 14, on trial for train station bomb plot</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/austrian-boy-14-trial-train-station-bomb-plot-6322330?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The boy, with alleged ties to Islamist extremists, allegedly planned a bombing in Vienna.</Description>
        <MainBody>Austrian boy, 14, on trial for train station bomb plot
Published: 8:52PM Tuesday May 26, 2015 Source: ONE News

Vienna Westbahnhof train station - Source: Metro Centric/ Wikimedia Commons
A 14-year-old Austrian schoolboy with alleged ties to Islamist extremists has gone on trial, accused of intending to bomb a Vienna train station.
New agency reports say the defendant, named only as Mertkan G, was arrested in October 2014 and faces up to five years in prison.
He allegedly had contact with supporters of the Islamic State jihadist group and al-Qaeda, the court in his hometown of Sankt-Poelten said, AFP reports.
"In addition, he is suspected of obtaining instructions on how to make an explosive device from an al-Qaeda website ... in order to carry out an attack in Vienna," the court said.
Reuters reports the boy's lawyer said his client is accused of researching how to build a bomb, after downloading plans onto his Playstation games console.
According to the charge sheet, cited by AFP, the teenager, who emigrated from Turkey in 2007, wanted to carry out the attack before travelling to join "holy war" in Syria and was in contact with IS recruiters in Vienna.

Police had said at the time of the arrest that the boy made "concrete enquiries about buying ingredients" for a bomb and "planned to explode the devices in public places, such as the Vienna Westbahnhof," a major train station.

His lawyer Rudolf Mayer said his client - who turns 15 next week - had only been "playing with the idea" of making a bomb.

He has been in custody since January after breaking the terms of his parole.

Unconfirmed press reports said that IS jihadists had offered to pay him 25,000 ($37,500) if he managed to carry out the attack.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Tue May 26 13:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Katy Perry slams 'inappropriate' Australian journalist for rehashing quotes</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/entertainment-news/katy-perry-slams-inappropriate-australian-journalist-rehashing-quotes-6322372?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Katy Perry says an Australian reporter rehashed three-year-old quotes for a new article.</Description>
        <MainBody>Katy Perry slams 'inappropriate' Australian journalist for rehashing quotes
Published: 10:11PM Tuesday May 26, 2015 Source: ONE News
Artist slammed by Katy Perry's lawyers for left shark figurine
Katy Perry has hit out at an Australian reporter who she says rehashed three-year-old quotes for a new article.
The quotes were used in a story about her ex-husband Russell Brand which was published in Sydney's Daily Telegraph last week.
In the Daily Telegraph piece, she is quoted as saying, "He hasn't spoken to me since he texted me saying he was filing for divorce. I don't want to talk about him - my songs will say what I need to say."
The Roar hitmaker took notice of the article and took to Twitter to fire back at writer Chris Knowles for reportedly reprinting an interview from 2012.
Perry posted: "It's really inappropriate when journalists repurpose interviews done 3 yrs ago in context of promoting a film &amp; then stamp a new date on it."
She followed the tweet with a thumbs down emoticon and said: "The Daily Telegraph &amp; Chris Knowles."
The original interview took place when she was promoting her documentary Katy Perry: Part of Me.
Her heartbreak following her split with the British comedian in 2011 was captured in the documentary, and it appeared like the singer had revisited this heartbreak in the interview with Knowles.
Perry also spoke of her text message split from Brand in another interview with Vogue in 2013, saying, "He's a very smart man, and I was in love with him when I married him. Let's just say I haven't heard from him since he texted me saying he was divorcing me December 31, 2011."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Tue May 26 13:05:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraq launches operation to drive IS from Anbar</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/iraq-launches-operation-drive-anbar-6322361?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Iraqi forces have surrounded the provincial capital, Ramadi, from three sides.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iraq launches operation to drive IS from Anbar
Published: 9:51PM Tuesday May 26, 2015 Source: AP
Iraqi army gets slammed for failing to protect Ramadi from ISIS (1:26)
Iraq today announced the launch of a military operation to drive the Islamic State group out of the western Anbar province, where the extremists captured the provincial capital, Ramadi, earlier this month.
Iraqi state TV declared the start of the operation, in which troops will be backed by Shiite and Sunni paramilitary forces, but did not provide further details.
A spokesman for Iraq's Shiite militias said the operation will "not last for a long time" and that Iraqi forces have surrounded the provincial capital, Ramadi, from three sides.
Ahmed al-Assadi, who is also a member of parliament, told reporters that new weapons are being used in the battle "that will surprise the enemy".
The Islamic State group seized large parts of Anbar starting in early 2014 and captured Ramadi earlier this month. The fall of the city marked a major defeat for Iraqi forces, which had been making steady progress against the extremists over the past year with the help of US-led airstrikes.
Security forces and Sunni militiamen who had been battling the extremists in Ramadi for months collapsed as IS fighters overran the city. The militants gained not only new territory 115 kilometres west of Baghdad, but also large stocks of weapons abandoned by government forces as they fled.
Defense Secretary Ash Carter said on Sunday that Iraqi forces had "vastly outnumbered" the IS militants in Ramadi but "showed no will to fight".
Saad al-Hadithi, a spokesman for Iraq's Prime Minister Haider al-Abadi, said the government was surprised by Carter's remarks, and that the defense secretary "was likely given incorrect information".
Al-Abadi has called on Shiite militias to help Iraqi troops retake the Sunni province. The militiamen have played a key role in clawing back territory from the IS group elsewhere in Iraq, but rights groups accuse them of looting, destroying property and carrying out revenge attacks. Militia leaders deny the allegations.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Tue May 26 11:28:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kenyan police officers killed in al-Shabab ambush</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/kenyan-police-officers-killed-in-al-shabab-ambush-6322318?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Several Kenyan police officers were killed in an attack by suspected Somali militants, police said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kenya university terrorist identified as 'brilliant lawyer'
Several Kenyan police officers were killed in an attack by suspected Somali militants in the northeastern Garissa county, where 148 students were massacred last month, police said.
A police spokesman, George Kimoti, confirmed there was an attack on Monday night in the Garissa region, and two security officials said many police officers had been killed in an al-Shabab ambush but could not give an exact death toll.
Kenya's Daily Nation newspaper reported that at least 20 police officers were feared dead in the attack in Garissa's Yumbis village.
The victims - who were on their way to rescue another team of officers wounded in an attack earlier on Monday - were moving in a convoy of four vehicles that the militants then burned. In the earlier attack, three police officers had been injured when their vehicle ran over a land mine, the officials said.
The same area was in the spotlight last week after suspected al-Shabab militants raided mosques and started to preach to congregations of Muslims. The militants reportedly hoisted flags before the security forces arrived. Kenya's interior ministry said on Friday it had "thwarted an attempted attack" on Thursday evening after the residents of Yumbis residents spotted armed militants in the area and alerted the authorities.
The Islamic extremist group al-Shabab has carried out several attacks in Kenya in retaliation for Kenya's military involvement in Somalia, where Kenyan troops are part of an African Union force bolstering the Western-backed central government in Mogadishu.
Despite major setbacks in 2014, al-Shabab continues to wage an insurgency against Somalia's government and remains a threat in the East African region.
The group claimed responsibility for a deadly assault last month on a college in Garissa town, as well as a 2013 assault on an upscale mall in the capital, Nairobi, in which at least 67 people were killed.
Kenyan officials are reportedly pondering the construction of a wall along the border with Somalia as part of the government's efforts to stem the attacks.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
