<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="tvnz">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman sees her dead brother's donated face on another man</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/woman-sees-her-dead-brother-s-donated-face-another-man-6325956?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Richard Norris, 39, accidentally blew off part of his face with a shotgun in 1997, severely disfiguring him.</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman sees her dead brother's donated face on another man
Published: 1:41PM Friday May 29, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

A man who received a full face transplant after being disfigured by a shotgun has come face-to-face with the sister of the man who gave it to him.
Richard Norris, 39, accidentally blew off part of his face with a shotgun in 1997, severely disfiguring him, and he had received public ridicule and fought with addiction.
In 2012, Mr Norris received a full face transplant from Joshua Aversano, who died after being hit by a van in 2012.
His family donated his face for transplant, and doctors also transplanted the teeth, jaw and tongue to Mr Norris, after more than 30 previous operations left him with little improvement.
Rebekah Aversano, Joshua's sister, has since seen the face of her brother on someone else, after meeting him for the first time for a 60 Minutes piece.
Joshua's mother Gwen told CTV: "We are just so pleased we have been able to help him, even though we had such a tragic loss, we were able to give someone else the benefit of our son."
The 36-hour elective operation was considered controversial as Mr Norris had only a 50% chance of survival.
The transplant was carried out at the Maryland Medical Centre by Dr Eduardo Rodriguez and a team of 150 doctors and nurses.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'I never cheated my workmates' - $16.7m Lotto winner rejects claims he ripped off syndicate</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/i-never-cheated-my-workmates-16-7m-lotto-winner-rejects-claims-he-ripped-off-syndicate-6325847?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>But Mr Baron says he bought the winning ticket himself and denies cheating his workmates.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

The Australian man accused of cheating his lotto syndicate workmates out of their share of a huge cash win has spoken out in his own defence.
Gary Baron claimed a $16.7 million (NZ$17.7m) Powerball win last October before quitting his job at a courier company.
Mr Baron, from Melbourne, had been buying lottery tickets in a syndicate with workmates, 15 of whom have taken him to court over the win, Nine News reports.
The only person from the syndicate not involved in the legal proceedings is Jeanette Clancy, who Mr Baron is reportedly in a relationship with.
But Mr Baron says he bought the winning ticket himself and denies cheating his workmates.
In a statement released by his lawyers Mr Baron said: "I have never cheated my workmates and I am disappointed that the matter has become so public and that my name, family and home have become so widely publicised", Nine News reports.
Mr Baron went on to say in the statement : "The syndicate games were purchased on a different day, through a different medium and using the value of funds the syndicate had to purchase tickets with".
But the now rich Melbournite says he regrets not being more transparent with his workmates over the win.
Advertisement
"In hindsight, I should have explained the circumstances to syndicate members at the time. I just want to get on with my life and enjoy time with my family."
Since his windfall Mr Baron is believed to have purchased a BMW convertible, a house for himself and a house for his son.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Polish man entered bear's enclosure to fight it - and lost</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/polish-man-entered-bear-s-enclosure-fight-and-lost-6325580?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A man who tangled with a brown bear at Warsaw's zoo, leaving traces of blood, was later found in hospital.</Description>
        <MainBody>
A Polish man who entered a bear enclosure looking for a fight - Source: IMGUR
A man who went missing after tangling with a brown bear at Warsaw's zoo, leaving traces of blood, was later found in the hospital.
The 32-year-old man, being treated for an arm wound, refused to tell police why he entered the enclosure on Monday and approached the bear.
Maria Krakowiak, head of the animals of prey section at the zoo, said the man's stunt was "very dangerous" and "could have ended much worse."
Blood was found Sunday outside the enclosure. A witness then posted photos on the Internet showing the man inside, bare-footed and in shorts.
In one photo he has his right arm in the bear's mouth.
From other photos it appears the bear, a female named Sabina, tried to bite his arm and that the man hit the bear.
From the photos it is not clear which happened first.
However, the tabloid Fakt, citing witnesses, reported it was the man who first attacked Sabina, hitting the 200-kg bear with his fists.
"He survived only thanks to a miracle," Fakt wrote.
Krakowiak said the zoo is hoping city authorities will now install cameras to monitor the bear's enclosure. A popular fixture in Warsaw for decades, the enclosure is on a busy street, a few hundred metres from the zoo proper.
Police spokeswoman Paulina Onyszko told The Associated Press that police informed the man that he could face a fine of up to 1000 zlotys (NZ$368) if found guilty of provoking the animal into aggression and the case was being sent to court.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:58:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Swollen rivers cause Texas cities to worry about more flooding</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/swollen-rivers-cause-texas-cities-worry-more-flooding-6325575?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>In Central Texas, crews continued searching for nine people feared dead in a swollen river</Description>
        <MainBody>Swollen rivers cause Texas cities to worry about more flooding
Published: 5:58AM Friday May 29, 2015 Source: AP
Texas, Mexico smashed by 'relentless tsunami-type' floods and tornado video
Many Texas cities remain in danger though a barrage of deadly thunderstorms has tapered, as officials warn about the possibility of more flooding from rain-swollen rivers.
The storms and floods in Texas and Oklahoma this week have left at least 21 people dead and at least 10 others missing.
In suburban Houston, the rains have pushed the San Jacinto River above flood stage, and its waters were expected to cover streets in subdivisions along the west fork of the river, possibly stranding people in their homes for days if they don't leave.
In Wharton, about 96 kilometres southwest of Houston, the mayor asked residents to voluntarily evacuate about 300 homes on the west side of the city due to the predicted rise of the Colorado River.
In the Parker County town of Horseshoe Bend in North Texas, officials asked about 250 residents to leave their homes as the Brazos River was expected to rise above its flood stage of 6.4 metres today.
Meanwhile, in Central Texas, crews continued searching for nine people feared dead after the swollen Blanco River smashed through Wimberley, a small tourist town between San Antonio and Austin, over the Memorial Day weekend.
In Houston, residents whose homes were flooded by torrential rains on Monday and Tuesday also continued their cleanup efforts.
While the Houston area got a respite from rainy weather for most of yesterday, the heavy rains from earlier in the week were still making their way downstream. By late yesterday, the San Jacinto was at feet 15 metres, nearly one metre above its flood stage, said Kim Jackson, a spokeswoman for the Harris County Flood Control District.
In Houston, between 800 and 1,400 homes have already been damaged by the flooding. Thousands of homes were also damaged or destroyed in the central Texas corridor that includes Wimberley - 744 of them in San Marcos alone.
Advertisement
This has been the wettest month on record for Texas, even with several days left. The state climatologist's office said Thursday that Texas has gotten an average of 19.15 centimetres of rain in May, breaking the old record 16.92 centimetres, set in June 2004.
While rain is in the forecast the next couple of days for many of the affected areas, the chances for showers are greater during the weekend.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter rejects demands from UEFA for him to resign, blames 'individuals'</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/football-news/blatter-rejects-demands-uefa-him-resign-blames-individuals-6325568?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>FIFA President Sepp Blatter rejects calls from UEFA for his resignation, with majority backing opposing candidate Prince Ali of Jordan.</Description>
        <MainBody>Blatter rejects demands from UEFA for him to resign, blames 'individuals'
Published: 4:24AM Friday May 29, 2015 Source: AP
FIFA hit by corruption claims - 'many millions' of sponsorship dollars in jeopardy video
FIFA President Sepp Blatter says he intends to help restore trust in world soccer after a pair of corruption investigations brought "shame and humiliation" on the sport.
Blatter spoke publicly for the first time since the corruption scandals broke Wednesday and threw FIFA into crisis ahead of Friday's presidential election.
Blatter blamed the "actions of individuals" and said corruption "has to be stopped now" to prevent FIFA's reputation from being "dragged through the mud."
Blatter rejected demands from European association UEFA that he resign. He is expected to win a fifth term in Friday's election against Prince Ali of Jordan.
American and Swiss authorities are pursuing separate federal investigations into racketeering and the 2018 and 2022 World Cup votes.
UEFA President Michel Platini says some European countries might pull out of FIFA and the World Cup if Sepp Blatter wins a fifth term as FIFA president.
Speaking at a news conference in Zurich, Platini said through a translator that the European football body will be "open to all options" but insisted that he opposes a boycott of FIFA - even if longtime president Blatter beats Prince Ali of Jordan in Friday's election.
Platini says he expects that a majority of European countries - at least 45 - will vote for the Jordanian royal in the 209-nation election after UEFA backed down from a threat to boycott the FIFA Congress.
Platini said he told Blatter directly in a meeting on Thursday morning to stand down before the ballot - but the FIFA chief refused.
Platini lamented "too many scandals" and said "FIFA doesn't deserve to be treated that way."
Advertisement
With FIFA engulfed by a corruption scandal prompted by an investigation by U.S. authorities announced Wednesday, Platini said that Ali "doesn't need money because he is a prince."
American and Swiss authorities are pursuing separate federal investigations into racketeering and the 2018 and 2022 World Cup votes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 11:35:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'I'm not angry' - Paralysed bride doesn't resent friend who pushed her in pool</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/i-m-not-angry-paralysed-bride-doesn-t-resent-friend-pushed-her-in-pool-6325471?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>In 2010, Rachelle Friedman was playfully pushed into a pool on her hen's party. </Description>
        <MainBody>
Rachelle Friedman on her wedding day - Source: Twitter @FollowRachelle
A woman who was rendered a quadriplegic on her hen's night says she is not angry at the friend responsible for the accident.
In 2010, Rachelle Friedman was playfully pushed into a pool on her hen's party. She hit her head on the bottom, leaving her legs paralysed and limited movement in her arms and hands.
After five years, Ms Friedman has moved on, marrying her fiance and having a baby via a surrogate.
In an Ask Me Anything session on Reddit, she says she holds no resentment towards her friend.
"I am not angry about the push itself. It was an accident and I've done it a million times. I think most people can say they've pushed someone into a pool playfully," she says.
"I was not, I am not and never will be angry that she pushed me. Now there have been some moments years later where I feel like everything wasn't perfect. But five years later I'm a mum and I'm almost 30. We are not the same people we were when I was 24.
"We both just have completely different lives."
Advertisement
While the media interest in her story has led to television appearances, a book deal and a one hour TV special that will air in the US documenting her life as a quadriplegic, wife, and new mum, Ms Friedman said she would give it all up just to walk again.
"Everything was perfect before this accident and I would give anything to go back to that life.
"You never really become content with an injury like this. Every day I wake up with pain and they are new struggles I have to face. I'd give anything to go back to the life before but I have no choice. I think when the element of choice is taking out, you really have no other way of handling it but to handle it."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 09:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mum sues daughter to reclaim million dollar lottery jackpot</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/mum-sues-daughter-reclaim-million-dollar-lottery-jackpot-6325270?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A US mum claims her teenage daughter stole the lottery winnings and fled town.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mum sues daughter to reclaim million dollar lottery jackpot
Published: 6:39PM Thursday May 28, 2015 Source: ONE News

US money - Source: Thinkstock
A mother-daughter feud erupted when an American woman, who won $1million from a $5 scratchy, claimed her child stole the money and fled town.
Brooklyn mother Barabara Quiles said she "authorised" her teenage daughter, Linza Ford, to cash the winning lottery ticket in 2012, but that the 19-year-old took the money and ran.
"I felt like she stabbed me not in the back but right in the heart and twisted the knife," she told The New York Post.
Ms Quiles has launched a Supreme Court lawsuit to reclaim the cash, after she said the pair entered a "lottery agreement' where the teen would claim the money but not retain the winnings.
"I'm the one who went out to buy the ticket with my money," the 51-year-old mum said.
However, Ms Ford told The Post the ticket was all hers.
"It was my ticket, signed by me," she said.
Advertisement
"I went to the office in the Bronx. She even went with me to claim the ticket."
Ms Ford said the money was placed into her personal account, but her mother claims she was meant to have access to the funds with a debit card, which stopped working in April 2014.
Ms Quiles said her daughter then fled town and seven months later the account was closed and all the winnings withdrawn.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 09:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US state abolishes death penalty in landmark vote</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/us-state-abolishes-death-penalty-in-landmark-vote-6325233?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The vote was backed by an unusual coalition of conservatives who oppose capital punishment.</Description>
        <MainBody>US state abolishes death penalty in landmark vote
Published: 6:14PM Thursday May 28, 2015 Source: AP

Nebraska lawmakers vote to abolish the death penalty - Source: AP
Nebraska has abolished the death penalty in a landmark veto-override vote backed by an unusual coalition of conservatives who oppose capital punishment.
Senators in the one-house Legislature voted 30-19 to override Governor Pete Ricketts, a Republican who supports the death penalty. The vote makes Nebraska the first traditionally conservative state to eliminate the punishment since North Dakota in 1973.
"Whenever anything historic occurs, it's never the doing of one person," said independent Senator Ernie Chambers, an independent who introduced a repeal measure 38 times.
"I've been pushing for this for 40 years, but all of this time it's never been done. If it could be done by one man, it would have been done a long time ago."
Nebraska joins 18 other states and the District of Columbia in banning the ultimate punishment.
Some senators said they philosophically support the death penalty, but are convinced the state will never carry out another execution because of legal obstacles. Nebraska hasn't executed an inmate since a 1997 electrocution, and the state has never done so with its current lethal injection protocol.
Nebraska lost its ability to execute inmates in December 2013, when one of the three lethal injection drugs required by state law expired.
Advertisement
Ricketts announced this month that the state has purchased two of the drugs that the state now lacks, but opponents have said they still aren't convinced Nebraska will be able to resume executions. On Tuesday, Republican Attorney General Doug Peterson implored lawmakers to give state officials more time to prepare.
Nebraska's action to repeal the death penalty is unusual because of its traditionally conservative leanings. Maryland was the last state to end capital punishment, in 2013. Three other moderate-to-liberal states have done so in recent years: New Mexico in 2009, Illinois in 2011 and Connecticut in 2012.
The last time lawmakers passed a death penalty repeal bill was in 1979, but senators at the time didn't have enough votes to override a gubernatorial veto.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 09:05:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Don't delay: Study confirms early treatment is best for HIV</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/don-t-delay-study-confirms-early-treatment-best-hiv-6325224?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A major international study says starting HIV medication soon after diagnosis helps keep people healthy longer.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

Dr Anthony Fauci, Director, National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, National Institutes of Health - Source: AP
Related
Stigma and fear still surrounds HIV - NZ survivor video
A major international study says HIV patients shouldn't delay in seeking treatment - starting medication soon after diagnosis helps keep people healthy longer.
People who started anti-AIDS drugs while their immune system was strong were far less likely to develop AIDS or other serious illnesses than if they waited until blood tests showed their immune system was starting to weaken, the US National Institutes of Health announced.
The findings are preliminary, but the NIH found them so compelling that it stopped the study a year early, so that all the participants could receive medication as researchers continue to track their health.
How soon should treatment begin?
"The sooner the better," said Dr Anthony Fauci, director of NIH's National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, which funded the work.
The findings support current US guidelines that already recommend early treatment for HIV, but could alter care recommendations in other countries.
HIV may not trigger symptoms for years, raising the question of how soon after diagnosis patients should begin taking expensive medications that may cause side effects. Previous studies have made clear that treatment dramatically lowers the chances that someone with HIV spreads the virus to a sexual partner. But there was less evidence that the HIV patient's own health would benefit.
The START trial - Strategic Timing of AntiRetroviral Treatment - sought proof by randomly assigning still healthy patients either to receive early therapy or to delay therapy until their CD4 cells, a key sign of immune system health, dropped into a worry zone.
Advertisement
While the US guidelines back treatment regardless of patients' CD4 counts, the World Health Organisation's guidelines recommend that HIV-infected people begin treatment when their CD4 levels fall below normal, to 500 or below. But that doesn't happen in many poor countries, where often people are sicker before they receive treatment and global funding to expand care is tight.
Even in the US, many people don't seek or stick with early care. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recently reported that only about 30 percent of Americans with HIV have the virus under control.
The START trial enrolled 4,685 people in 35 countries, all of whom had CD4 counts in the healthy range - above 500 - and had never taken anti-HIV medication. Researchers tracked deaths, the development of AIDS-related illnesses and the development of serious non-AIDS events such as cancer, heart disease and kidney or liver disease.
Over about three years, the risk of serious illness or death was reduced by 53 percent in the early treatment group, NIH said.
The actual numbers of bad outcomes in both groups were very low, given that patients were so healthy when they enrolled in the study - 41 cases in the early-treatment group compared with 86 in the group that delayed treatment until their CD4 count dropped to near 350.
The results, once final, will need careful scrutiny to see if they apply to people with the highest CD4 counts, cautioned Dr Jay Levy of the University of California, San Francisco, who wasn't involved in the new study.
"I'm still concerned about putting everyone on therapy," Levy said.
But Fauci said the study offers "another reason why we should be more aggressive in seeking out voluntary testing" and getting people care. "It tells you that you will benefit from therapy at whatever your CD4 count is."
Fauci acknowledged that expanding early treatment would cost more up-front. But he contended that "there's no doubt that it's going to be less expensive to treat people early," and try to avoid the more expensive care of full-blown AIDS.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 06:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> J K Rowling doesn't mince words when slamming 'bigoted' anti-gay Baptist Church</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/j-k-rowling-doesn-t-mince-words-slamming-bigoted-anti-gay-baptist-church-6324819?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The Harry Potter author has come out swinging against an anti-gay marriage US church.</Description>
        <MainBody>Author J.K. Rowling - Source: AP
Related
Ireland becomes first country to legalise gay marriage by popular vote video
Novelist J K Rowling has blasted a fundamentalist United States church after it suggested it would "picket" a gay wedding between fantasy characters Gandalf and Dumbledore.
The Harry Potter author replied to a tweet from the Westboro Baptist Church, which has displayed its disregard for Ireland voting in favour of same sex marriage.
"So @jk_rowling wants Dumbledore &amp; Gandalf to marry in Ireland; if it happens, WBC will picket! #NotBanned," the tweet read.
So @jk_rowling wants Dumbledore &amp; Gandalf to marry in Ireland; if it happens, WBC will picket! #NotBanned @pinknews pic.twitter.com/zY7hT09Nv4
 WBCSays (@WBCsigns) May 26, 2015

The 49-year-old British author used some colourful language in her reply, saying: "Alas, the sheer awesomeness of such a union in such a place would blow your tiny bigoted minds out of your thick sloping skulls."
. @WBCsigns Alas, the sheer awesomeness of such a union in such a place would blow your tiny bigoted minds out of your thick sloping skulls.
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) May 26, 2015

A Rowling fan said that the church was seeking attention from Rowling's millions of followers.
"While I am in total agreement with you, giving them attention is counterproductive. That's what they want," the twitter user wrote.
Rowling tweeted back: "I don't care about WBC. I think it's important that scared gay kids who aren't out yet see hate speech challenged."
Sir Ian McKellen, who plays Gandalf in the Lord of the Rings and The Hobbit film trilogies, is openly homosexual.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:06:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tension in Tonga as women's rights divides kingdom</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/tension-in-tonga-women-s-rights-divides-kingdom-6324629?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The opening of Tonga's parliament today is overshadowed by controversy over women's rights.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tension in Tonga as women's rights divides kingdom
By ONE News Pacific Correspondent Barbara Dreaver
Published: 12:13PM Thursday May 28, 2015

Protesters at a march in Tonga earlier in May, 2015 - Source: Matangi Tonga
The official opening of Tonga's parliament today is being overshadowed by growing controversy over women's rights dividing the Kingdom.
The government has signalled its intention to sign the UN's Convention on the Elimination of all forms of Discrimination against Women (CEDAW) but opponents claim it will open the door for same sex marriage and abortion.
But at the centre of the objections is the fear ratifying CEDAW will mean changes to Tonga's land laws which gives every male over the age of 16 entitlement to a plot of land - women are allowed to lease but can't inherit or mortgage hereditary lands.
Protest marches led by church ministers have been held and petitions with 15,000 signatures presented to King Tupou VI - with supporters expected to take their own petition to the King this week.
Tension has been brewing for months - earlier this year at a CEDAW roundtable discussion involving community groups one church minister was reported by Matangi Tonga online as shouting at the group "You women should know your place".
Supporters of CEDAW have joined together under the Civil Society Forum and say there's a lot of misconception over the convention - and it's about giving women a voice.
Prime Minister Akilisi Pohiva has told Radio Tonga there is likely to be a referendum on the issue.
Photos: Matangi Tonga
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 01:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jon vs Goliath - the moment kayaker pulls up monster catch</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/jon-vs-goliath-moment-kayaker-pulls-up-monster-catch-6324320?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>A video posted to YouTube shows a fisherman bringing a huge fish to the surface while he rides a sea kayak.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

A video posted to YouTube shows a fisherman bringing a huge fish to the surface while he rides a sea kayak.
The footage, of fisherman Jon Black, was taken in Sanibel, Florida, and the fish is an enormous Atlantic goliath grouper.
The fish was reportedly more than two metres long and 185cm in circumference, and Mr Black estimated it weighed about 250kg.
The world record for a hook and line-captured specimen is 309kg, which was caught off Fernandina Beach, Florida, in 1961.
However, the fisherman believes this may be a record for the heaviest fish caught on a kayak.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed May 27 23:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'It makes us incredibly angry' - Kiwi triplets' parents blast Qatar over mall blaze</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/makes-us-incredibly-angry-kiwi-triplets-parents-blast-qatar-over-mall-blaze-6323763?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Jane and Martin Weekes have expressed their frustration after losing their two-year-old triplets.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

The Kiwi parents of triplets who perished in a fire at a kindergarten in a Qatar shopping mall are "incredibly angry" their children's convicted killers have not served any jail time.
Jane and Martin Weekes believe Qatar authorities don't consider their children's lives "important enough to follow through on".
"It makes us incredibly angry and it's really upsetting and it feels like the justice system there isn't fair for people who aren't from Qatar," Jane Weekes told TVNZ's Breakfast programme today.
Three years ago today, Jane and Martin Weekes lost their two-year-old triplets Lillie, Jackson and WIlsher in a fire at the Villaggio mall in Doha.
Last month, they asked Prime Minister John Key to raise the issue with the Emir of Qatar why Ali Bin Jasim Bin Thani Al Thani has not yet served any of his six-yearr prison sentence for involuntary manslaughter.
Al Thani is currently serving as Qatar's Ambassador to the European Union while his appeal is considered, along with his co-convicted wife, Iman Al Kuwari.
Al Thani and his wife have continually failed to appear in court.
Mr Key confirmed he spoke with the Emir on April 14 who publicly announced he was "utterly committed to making sure those who are responsible will be held to account."
Advertisement
Mr Al Thani, based in Brussels, refused to appear in the Appeal Court at Qatar this month. Closing arguments begin on June 7, with a verdict likely to be released at the end of the month.
Mrs Weekes says the continued court case means "there is no closure" for her and her husband.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed May 27 20:53:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More rain threatens to complicate the cleanup in Houston</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/more-rain-threatens-complicate-cleanup-in-houston-6323768?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The forecast was for 5 to 8cm more of rain in the Houston area, a day after flooding triggered by nearly a foot of rain </Description>
        <MainBody>More rain threatens to complicate the cleanup in Houston
Published: 5:54AM Thursday May 28, 2015 Source: AP
Storms in Texas and Oklahoma leave 17 dead
More rain fell on Houston on overnight, threatening to complicate the cleanup after a long holiday weekend of storms and floods that left at least 17 people dead and more than a dozen others missing in Texas and Oklahoma.
The forecast was for 5 to 8cm more of rain in the Houston area, a day after flooding triggered by nearly 30cm of rain in a matter of hours swamped neighbourhoods and highways and stranded hundreds of motorists.
Crews resumed the search for 11 people missing and presumed dead after the swollen Blanco River surged through the small tourist town of Wimberley, between San Antonio and Austin. Houston Mayor Annise Parker said two people whose boat capsised during a rescue effort were also missing.
In Houston, warnings from the National Weather Service buzzed on mobile phones, but city officials say they haven't installed a system that would allow them to alert residents with more targeted warnings.
The city is still working with the Federal Emergency Management Agency to get that system running, said Michael Walter, spokesman for Houston's Office of Emergency Management.
Floodwaters in Houston affected virtually every part of the city and paralysed some areas. Firefighters carried out more than 500 water rescues, most involving stranded motorists. At least 2,500 vehicles were abandoned by drivers, and up to 700 Houston-area homes were damaged, officials said.
Thousands of homes were damaged or destroyed in the central Texas corridor that includes Wimberley - 744 of them in San Marcos alone, said Kenneth Bell, emergency management coordinator for San Marcos.
More than 380,000 litres of sewage spilled Tuesday from a flooded-out Houston treatment plant, officials said. They said that the spill was contained and that residents don't have to boil their water, but they shouldn't swim in areas around the plant.
The death toll stood at 13 in Texas and four in Oklahoma.
The deaths in Texas included a man whose body was pulled from the Blanco; a 14-year-old who was found with his dog in a storm drain; a high school senior who died Saturday after her car was caught in high water; and a man whose mobile home was destroyed by a reported tornado.
Advertisement
The forecast called for a 20 to 40 percent chance of thunderstorms through the rest of the week in Houston, and more storms were also in store for central Texas.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed May 27 12:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India appoints first transgender person as head of college</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/india-appoints-first-transgender-person-head-college-6323687?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description> A transgender woman will head a women's college in West Bengal.</Description>
        <MainBody>India appoints first transgender person as head of college
Published: 9:35PM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: AP

Entrance of Royal Palace, Krishnanagar , Nadia, West Bengal, India - Source: Susantab/ Wikimedia Commons
India has for the first time appointed a transgender person as the principal of a college, a top education official said today.
Manabi Banerjee, a transgender woman, will head the Krishnagar Women's College in the eastern Indian state of West Bengal, said Dipak K. Kar, chairman of an education panel that selects college principals in the state.
Banerjee is expected to start her new job on June 9, Kar said.
"She has been teaching in a college for more than 20 years, and had the necessary administrative experience. She was chosen through the usual selection process," said Kar.
India's transgender activists hailed the appointment as a proud day for a community that usually faces discrimination.
"This is a proud moment for us. It's great that people have begun accepting transgenders. Everybody should feel proud about this decision," said Rudrani Chettri, director of Mitr Trust, a group working for transgender rights.
Last year, India's Supreme Court declared the transgender community as a legal third gender, granting them minority rights and privileges to education, employment and health benefits. Since then, some colleges have offered a choice in indicating their gender in application forms.
Advertisement
Krishnagar Women's College offers undergraduate courses in the sciences and humanities. It is located in Krishnanagar, a town about 105 kilometres north of Kolkata, the capital of West Bengal.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed May 27 09:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jail awaits ISIS terrorist's wife trying to go home to Australia</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/jail-awaits-isis-terrorist-s-wife-trying-go-home-australia-6323396?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The woman's in Syria and her young son was photographed clutching a severed head.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jail awaits ISIS terrorist's wife trying to go home to Australia
Published: 6:14PM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
'We're not winning the war against ISIS' - international law expert (0:30)
The wife of an Australian Islamic State recruit, and mother of a young boy who was photographed holding a severed head, will go to jail if she returns from Syria.
The shocking family photo of the seven-year-old boy holding a severed head showed the world the brutality of ISIS.
But now his mother, Tara Nettleton, wants to return to Australia with her five children, saying she's had enough of life in Syria.
Prime Minister Tony Abbott says Ms Nettleton will face the full force of the law if she returns to Australia.
"The beheadings, the crucifixions, the mass executions, the sexual slavery -  and people that are involved in that are doing evil things," he says.
Allegedly involved is the young boy's father, one of the most notorious faces of Australian terror, Khaled Sharrouf.
He left Sydney in 2013 to fight in Syria. His wife moved their five children to the warzone soon after.
"Let's not for a second forget the evil barbarism which the Daish death cult is perpetating across wide swathes of the Middle East," Mr Abbott says.
Advertisement
But, Sharrouf's wife, Ms Nettleton, has reportedly had enough and wants to bring her children home.
Immigration Minister Peter Dutton says the children could be placed in state care.
"It depends on the circumstance, the ages of the children. If they're infants, for example, then they would be in state care as we've seen with some people who have decided to abandon their children and go off and fight," he says.
Around 100 Australians are believed to be fighting with terror groups in Iraq and Syria.
Legislation to strip dual nationals, like Sharrouf, of citizenship is imminent. It's a compromise for Tony Abbott who would rather stop all those who leave from ever coming back.
"Crime is crime is crime," he says.
Ms Nettleton's father and the children's grandfather, Peter Nettleton, says he doesn't know their wherabouts or what they are doing.
"I only know through the newspapers and television where they are," he says.
"I still love my daughter and I hope she comes home safely."
That could be the only warm welcome Ms Nettleton gets, with Australian authorities promising a long stint in jail if she returns.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed May 27 08:21:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Storms in Texas and Oklahoma leave 17 dead</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/storms-in-texas-and-oklahoma-leave-17-dead-6322440?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Floodwaters have deepened across much of Texas as storms dumped almost 30 centimeters of rain on the Houston area.</Description>
        <MainBody>Storms in Texas and Oklahoma leave 17 dead
Published: 7:15AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: AP
Cars in floodwaters in Houston. Photo / AP
Related
Texas, Mexico smashed by 'relentless tsunami-type' floods and tornado video
Floodwaters deepened across much of Texas as storms dumped almost 30 centimeters of rain on the Houston area, stranding hundreds of motorists and inundating the famously congested highways that serve the fourth-largest US city.
Meanwhile, the search went on for about a dozen people who were still missing, including a group that disappeared after a vacation home was swept down the river and slammed into a bridge.
Several more fatalities were reported - four in Houston and four more in Central Texas. That brought to 17 the number of people killed by the holiday weekend storms in Texas and Oklahoma.
Similar search efforts unfolded just south of the Texas-Mexico border, where crews tried to track down the missing and assess the damage in the city of Ciudad Acuna after a tornado killed 13 people on Monday (Tuesday NZT).
In Houston, the water rose sharply overnight as about 28 more centimeters of rain fell, much of it in a six-hour period. By Tuesday evening (today NZT), most rivers had receded back within their banks.
The floodwaters affected virtually every part of the city and paralysed some areas. Firefighters carried out more than 500 water rescues, most involving stranded motorists. At least 2,500 vehicles were abandoned by drivers seeking higher ground, officials said.
The flooding closed several highways, and the ones that stayed open became a gridlocked mess.
Interstate 45 near downtown was backed up for miles on Tuesday morning, and a handful of motorists travelled the wrong way on the highway to retreat from high water.
Advertisement
The small cars weaved between massive 18-wheelers as other drivers stared at them in disbelief. With no end to the backup in sight, some drivers got off the freeway, only to be held up again by water covering nearby access roads.
Some motorists were stuck on I-45 all night, sleeping in their cars until the backup was cleared about 8am.
NBA fans overnight in arena
NBA fans at the Toyota Center, where the Houston Rockets hosted a Western Conference finals game against Golden State on Monday, were asked with about two minutes left in the game not to leave the arena because of the severe weather.
The game ended before 11pm, but about 400 people remained in their seats at 1.30am, choosing to stay in the building rather than brave the flooded roads that awaited them outside. Up to 150 people stayed all right, according to arena officials.
A spokeswoman for the flood district of Harris County, which includes Houston, said up to 700 homes sustained some level of damage.
Some of the worst flooding in Texas was in Wimberley, a popular tourist town along the Blanco in the corridor between Austin and San Antonio. That's where the vacation home was swept away.
The "search component" of the mission ended Monday night, meaning no more survivors were expected to be found, said Trey Hatt, a spokesman for the Hays County Emergency Operations Center.
Eight people missing from the destroyed house were friends and family who had gathered for the holiday, said Kristi Wyatt, a spokeswoman for the City of San Marcos. Three children were among the missing.
The Blanco crested above 12 metres - more than triple its flood stage of 3.9 metres. Rescuers used pontoon boats and a helicopter to pull people out.
Hundreds of trees along the Blanco were uprooted or snapped, and they collected in piles of debris up to six metres high.
In Ciudad Acuna, Mayor Evaristo Perez Rivera said 300 people were treated at local hospitals after the twister, and up to 200 homes had been completely destroyed in the city of 125,000 across from Del Rio, Texas.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed May 27 08:09:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Mate, they're women' - Good Samaritan intercepts tradies abusing Muslim women on train</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/mate-they-re-women-good-samaritan-intercepts-tradies-abusing-muslim-train-6323271?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>He would do the same again, despite being punched himself.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

A Good Samaritan who defended three Muslim women being verbally abused on a Melbourne train says he would do the same again, despite being punched himself.
But Jason Cias, 36, does not blame other commuters for not stepping in.
Mr Cias supported the three women who were being vilified by two tradesmen on a Craigieburn-bound train on Friday, May 15.
The train had left Melbourne Central station when the tradesmen began abusing the women, telling them their headscarfs should not be worn in Australia.
"One of them made reference to her headscarf, saying 'You shouldn't be wearing that s*** in Australia,'" Mr Cias told Fairfax.
He said one of the women appeared to try to calm the situation in Arabic, which was met with another barb from the men.
"The comment was, 'You shouldn't be speaking that s*** in Australia,'" Mr Cias said.
The women stepped off the train at North Melbourne, and it was when one of the men called after them "I'll f***ing smash ya" that Mr Cias stepped in.
Advertisement
"I said to the guy, 'Mate, they're women'. The implication there was you don't threaten people, particularly women," he said.
Mr Cias said he was told to mind his own business, before one of the men stood over him and punched him in the face.
Another passenger on the train filmed the incident on her mobile phone and tried to raise the alarm via the emergency button, but Mr Cias said he understood why others did not step in with him.
"You always have to be aware of your safety, but it's a matter of weighing up your own sense of what's right."
Mr Cias said he was humbled by the response from the public to the footage of the incident.
Police met Mr Cias and the witnesses near Kensington station, taking statements and copies of the video and images of the offenders, and  are investigating the incident Fairfax reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Want to get paid millions? Run a media company</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/want-get-paid-millions-run-media-company-6322853?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Six of the 10 highest-paid CEOs last year worked in the media industry, according to a study.</Description>
        <MainBody>Want to get paid millions? Run a media company
Published: 11:23AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: AP
Yahoo chief executive Marissa Mayer. Photo / AP
Related
Helen Clark just behind Beyonce in world's most powerful women list
They're not Hollywood stars, they're not TV personalities and they don't play in a rock band, but their pay packages are in the same league.
Six of the 10 highest-paid CEOs last year worked in the media industry, according to a study carried out by executive compensation data firm Equilar and The Associated Press.
The best-paid chief executive of a large American company was David Zaslav, head of Discovery Communications, the pay-TV channel operator that is home to Shark Week. His total compensation more than quadrupled to US$156.1 million in 2014 after he extended his contract.
Les Moonves, of CBS, held on to second place in the rankings, despite a drop in pay from a year earlier. His pay package totaled US$54.4 million.
The remaining four CEOs, from entertainment giants Viacom, Walt Disney, Comcast and Time Warner, have ranked among the nation's highest-paid executives for at least four years, according to the Equilar/AP pay study.
One reason for the high level of pay in the industry is that its CEOs are dealing with well-paid individuals.
"The talent, the actors and directors and writers, they're being paid a lot of money," said Steven Kaplan, a professor of finance at the University of Chicago Booth School of Business. "In industries where the talent makes a lot of money, the CEO makes a lot of money as well."
Pay packages for CEOs overall grew for the fifth straight year in 2014, driven by a rising stock market that pushed up the value of executive stock awards.
Advertisement
Median compensation for the heads of Standard &amp; Poor's 500 companies rose to a record US$10.6 million, up from US$10.5 million the year before, according to the Equilar/AP pay study.
Among other findings:
 Female CEOs again had a median pay package worth more than their male counterparts. Last year, women chief executives earned US$15.9 million compared with the median salary for male CEOs of US$10.4 million. The number of female CEOs included in the study rose to 17 from 12 in the previous year. Yahoo CEO Marissa Mayer was the highest paid, earning US$42.1 million, which placed her fifth among CEOs in the survey.
 The industry with the biggest pay increase was basic materials, which includes oil, mining and chemical companies. Median pay at these companies rose by 15 percent last year. Exxon Mobil CEO Rex Tillerson was the highest paid, making US$28.4 million last year.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:28:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mosquito-borne virus causes fears for Pacific visitors</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/mosquito-borne-virus-causes-fears-pacific-visitors-6322781?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The chikungunya virus causes intense joint pain and can last for several months.</Description>
        <MainBody>
Beach at Cook Islands - Source: ONE News
Visitors to the Pacific are being warned to seek medical help if they suspect they have the mosquito-borne chikungunya virus which has hit the region.
The virus has so far affected half of the Pacific's 22 countries and territories, with both the Cook Islands and Marshall Islands currently reporting cases that are either peaking or increasing.
Symptoms include high fever and recurring intense joint pain similar to dengue - and it can last several months.
Surveillance experts at the Secretariat of the Pacific Community (SPC) say the virus was first reported in 2011 and is rapidly spreading through the region.
The Cook Islands Public Health Service has stepped up efforts to control the spread of chikungunya and are considering widening its spraying programme.
Director of Community Health Services Dr Neti Herman told Cook Islands News 536 cases have been reported in the last 20 weeks but believe it's now on the decline.
Visitors to affected areas can avoid contracting the disease by protecting themselves from mosquito bites.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:19:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boy's family forgive woman who snatched hero's football jersey and tried to sell it for $3k</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/boy-s-family-forgive-woman-snatched-hero-football-jersey-and-tried-sell-3k-6322771?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Cameras caught the moment Vickie Trimbell yanked the shirt out of Ted Dockray's hands.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boy's family forgive woman who snatched hero's football jersey and tried to sell it for $3k
Published: 10:19AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

The family of a young boy who had a prized football jersey wrenched from him on live television say they aren't angry at the woman who snatched the shirt.
Ted Dockray, 8, caught a shirt thrown by striker Jermaine Beckford after he scored a hat-trick in Preston North End's League One playoff win over Swindon at Wembley Stadium over the weekend.
Cameras caught the moment the shirt was stolen from him by Vickie Timbrell, 31, who reportedly went on to try sell it for $3000 on an online auction site.
Ted's aunt Claire Dockray says the family knows Timbrell, who lives about 2km away from them in Manchester, the Daily Mail reports. They have no hard feelings towards her, Dockray said.
"[Ted] was a bit disappointed but he's fine.
"My family would never want any trouble for the woman over a football shirt. I'm sure it will be a happy ending for everyone involved."
Trimbell said she plans to clear the air with the Dockray family, in posts on social media.
She said the media have twisted what happened, and she would soon tell her side of the story.
Advertisement
"People have made me out to be an absolute idiot," said Ms Timbrell. "I will be speaking to the family, I actually know them, they're friends."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chinese man covers himself in a million bees, gets stung 2000 times</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/chinese-man-covers-himself-in-million-bees-gets-stung-2000-times-6322747?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>Gao Bingguom casually smoked a cigarette as 109.1kg of bees swarmed over his body.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chinese man covers himself in a million bees, gets stung 2000 times
Published: 10:08AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Text size + -

A Chinese beekeeper has covered himself in a world record-breaking one million bees while casually smoking a cigarette.
Gao Bingguom, from China's northern Shandong province, was reportedly stung more than 2000 times during his world record attempt yesterday.
He placed 12 queen bees on himself, then waited for about three hours as worker bees swarmed on his body, the Daily Mail reports.
By the end of the attempt, only Bingguom's mouth - and cigarette - were visible.
He was recording as having 109.1kg, or about 1.1 million, bees on his body, reclaiming the world record he lost to a fellow bee enthusiast last year.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Helen Clark just behind Beyonce in world's most powerful women list</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/helen-clark-just-behind-beyonce-in-s-most-powerful-women-list-6322497?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The former PM was named in a diverse set of luminaries that includes Taylor Swift and Hilary Clinton.</Description>
        <MainBody>Helen Clark just behind Beyonce in world's most powerful women list
Published: 8:50AM Wednesday May 27, 2015 Source: ONE News
Taylor Swift, Helen Clark and Hillary Clinton. Photos / Creative Commons
Watch Video
Kevin Rudd quashes rumours of taking on Helen Clark for UN role
Helen Clark has been named alongside luminaries including Hillary Clinton and Taylor Swift in Forbes' rundown of the world's 100 most powerful women.
The former New Zealand Prime Minister was ranked 23 on the annual list - two spots behind pop superstar Beyonce.
Ms Clark is tipped as a contender to succeed Ban Ki-moon as UN Secretary-General when his term finishes in 2016.
She talked to Forbes about leadership strategy , in an interview drawing on her previous experience in New Zealand politics.
"If you don't believe in yourself, how can you expect others to believe in you?" she said. "You haveto have avery strong sense of self-belief to rise to and stay in leadership positions."
Meanwhile, popstar Taylor Swift made her debut entry at number 64 on the list.
Other entertainers to make the list include Beyonce, Oprah, actress Sofia Vergara and talk show host Ellen DeGeneres.
German chancellor Angela Merkel was ranked number one for the fifth year running.
Former US First Lady Hillary Clinton was number two, while current First Lady Michelle Obama came in at 10.
Advertisement
Forbes top 10 most powerful women:
1. Angela Merkel, Chancellor of Germany
2. Hillary Clinton, US Presidential candidate
3. Melinda Gates, Co-chairwoman, Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation
4. Janet Yellen, Chairwoman, US Federal Reserve Bank
5. Mary Barra, CEO, General Motors
6. Christine Lagarde, Managing Director, International Monetary Fund
7. Dilma Rousseff, President of Brazil
8. Sheryl Sandberg, CEO of Facebook
9. Susan Wojcicki, CEO of Youtube
10. Michelle Obama, US First Lady
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kiwi troops in Iraq 'could be executed' by ISIS - expert</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/national-news/kiwi-troops-in-iraq-could-executed-isis-expert-6322489?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>New Zealand troops are stationed just over 90km from an ISIS controlled city.</Description>
        <MainBody>Text size + -

New Zealand troops in Iraq are in danger of being executed by Islamic State fighters, an international law professor says.
Iraqi forces lost the city of Ramadi to ISIS around two weeks ago. Ramadi is just over 90km from Taji where 143 New Zealand troops are based.
Professor Al Gillespie told TVNZ's Breakfast programme this morning the Kiwi troops are at risk from ISIS.
This assessment is at odds with Prime Minister John Key's assertion this week the ISIS advance isn't putting the New Zealand troops in danger.
"The risk is if ISIS get through to our soldiers they could be executed," Mr Gillespie said.
"There's no crime ISIS hasn't committed. Rape, execution of prisoners, looting - it's all there. There's nothing they haven't done."
Mr Gillespie says it's becoming more likely Western group troops will be deployed in Iraq.
Currently the New Zealand troops in Iraq are only tasked with training Iraqi Army troops.
Advertisement
But if the United States decide to deploy ground troops to fight ISIS, Mr Gillespie believes it's likely New Zealand will be asked to contribute fighting troops as well.
Earlier this week Mr Key was asked if there was an exit strategy for New Zealand troops.
He said there are early warnings situations that determine whether things need to be reviewed and at this point those warnings have not been triggered.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Radio DJ bludgeons baby bunny live on air - and then refuses to apologise</title>
        <Link>http://tvnz.co.nz/world-news/radio-dj-bludgeons-baby-bunny-live-air-and-then-refuses-apologise-6322443?ref=rss</Link>
        <Description>The stunt was aimed at exposing Danes' "hypocrisy" on animal welfare, the radio station says.</Description>
        <MainBody>'You're disgusting': Animal rights activist crash Kim Kardashian's book signing (0:23)
A radio DJ is unapologetic after bludgeoning a baby rabbit to death with a bicycle pump live on air.
Danish radio presenter Asger Juhl killed the bunny with repeated blows to the head in his show on Radio24syv this week.
The station has defended the stunt as an attempt to raise awareness about animal cruelty.
It aimed to expose Danes' "hypocrisy" on animal welfare, the station wrote on Facebook .
"Every day in the nation of Denmark, thousands and thousands of animals are put down to fill the meat counters in our super markets. Danish agriculture is one of the most industrialized in the world. But we do not seem to focus much on animal welfare," it wrote.
"These animals have often endured horrific suffering on their way to our dinner tables. These animals are killed according to the same controlled conditions as our studio rabbit, and without it invoking any strong reactions or calls for boycott.
"We at least believe that the studio rabbit have had a comfortable existence."
The bunny was killed according to instructions from a professional animal caretaker at a Danish zoo, the station says.
Juhl reportedly severed the bunny's spinal column by hitting it on the neck with the bicycle pump. He later took the animal home, where he skinned it and cooked it for his family.
Read Radio24syv's statement:

Every day in the nation of Denmark, thousands and thousands of animals are put down to fill the meat counters in our...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
