<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="UPI">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:12:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>SpaceX launching Falcon 9 in third attempt to land on ship</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/28/SpaceX-launching-Falcon-9-in-third-attempt-to-land-on-ship/4721435499930/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla., June 28 (UPI) -- SpaceX is set to launch the Falcon 9 reusable rocket that will attempt to guide itself back to Earth and land on a drone ship in the ocean after two failed, fiery attempts.
SpaceX, owned by Elon Musk, will launch the Falcon 9 at 10:21 a.m . The main objective in the mission is to deliver a SpaceX Dragon capsule to the International Space Station as part of a $1.6 billion contract with NASA.
The Dragon capsule is filled with more than two and a half tons of supplies.
"After seven successful missions to the International Space Station, including six official resupply missions for NASA, SpaceX's Falcon 9 rocket and Dragon spacecraft are set to liftoff from Launch Complex 40 at the Cape Canaveral Air Force Station, Florida, for their seventh official Commercial Resupply Services (CRS) mission to the orbiting lab," SpaceX said in a statement. "If all goes as planned, Dragon will arrive at the station approximately two days after liftoff. Dragon is expected to return to Earth approximately five weeks later for a parachute-assisted splashdown off the coast of southern California. Dragon is the only operational spacecraft capable of returning a significant amount of supplies back to Earth, including experiments."
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:00:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Central Bank to 'maintain' Greek emergency funding</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/28/European-Central-Bank-to-maintain-Greek-emergency-funding/8711435497439/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
FRANKFURT, Germany, June 28 (UPI) -- The European Central Bank will maintain Emergency Liquidity Assistance (ELA) for Greece but will not raise it, capping it at 89 billion and resulting in mounting pressure for capital controls.
Greek banks are under the threat of running out of money as people in the country make bank runs to withdraw their funds due to fear that their account balances will soon be meaningless.
The ECB has been raising its ELA for Greece steadily this year , raising it from about 60 billion to the current cap of 89 billion -- meaning Greece's emergency funds will run out soon.
"The Bank of Greece, as a member of the Eurosystem, will take all measures necessary to ensure financial stability for Greek citizens in these difficult circumstances," Governor of the Bank of Greece Yannis Stournaras said in a statement.
Greece could implement capital controls, such as restrictions on bank withdrawals, to allow Greece to function until next Sunday, when a referendum is set to take place.
The surprise referendum is to decide whether the terms made by Greek's creditors are acceptable.
"We continue to work closely with the Bank of Greece and we strongly endorse the commitment of Member States in pledging to take action to address the fragilities of euro area economies," ECB President Mario Draghi said in a statement.
Greek bailout funds expire on Tuesday, the same day Greece is due to make a 1.5 billion payment to the International Monetary Fund, which Greece is under the threat of defaulting.
The financial crisis in Greece threatens to push the country out of the Eurozone financial bloc, which includes France, Germany, Italy, the Netherlands, Portugal and Spain.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:50:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than 500 injured in Taiwan water park fire</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/27/More-than-500-injured-in-Taiwan-water-park-fire/3821435439191/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>More than 500 injured in Taiwan water park fire
By Amy R. Connolly and Doug G. Ware | June 27, 2015 at 6:50 PM
Comments
TAIPEI, Taiwan, June 27 (UPI) -- More than 500 people were injured -- including some 200 with life-threatening burns -- after a flammable powder that was sprayed into a crowd at a water park exploded into a fireball.
About 4,500 people had gathered at Formosa Fun Coast for "Color Play Asia." A colored powder was released into the crowd and apparently exploded midair. Officials said 524 people were injured, 194 of them seriously. . Most of the victims suffered severe burns or inhaled large amounts of carbon dust from the colored powder.
Up to 183 patients need urgent skin grafts as a result of severe burns. Taiwan's health department sent out a call to organ donations centers and other medical facilities for donated skin, artificial skin and other biologic necessities. The injured were being treated at 43 area hospitals.
Event organizer Lu Chung-chi was questioned by the Taipei Shilin District Prosecutors Office, released on bail and prohibited from leaving the country.
New Taipei's mayor, Eric Chu, called the incident the "worst incident of mass injury (ever) in New Taipei."
Early on, officials thought some 80 people received serious injuries, some with burns over 40 percent of their bodies, officials said. BBC News initially reported that 215 people were injured, in total.
"It started on the left side of the stage. At the beginning I thought it was part of the special effects of the party but then I realized there was something wrong and people started screaming and running," one witness said.
Taiwan has received criticism in recent years over multiple deadly fires that some say resulted from poor construction and failure to enforce fire and safety codes.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 18:43:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kurdish forces drive out Islamic State from Syria's Kobane</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/27/Kurdish-forces-drive-out-Islamic-State-from-Syrias-Kobane/7711435415553/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
KOBANE , Syria, June 27 (UPI) -- Kurdish forces have gained control of Syria's Kobane from the Islamic State after days of violent clashes, said the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights Saturday.
The Islamic State's attack on the town, located on the border of Turkey, killed over 300 people, including women and children, during a surprise attack launched Thursday, Al Jazeera reports.
An activist told Al Jazeera IS fighters "knocked on doors claiming they were here to help, they spoke Kurdish, then barged into homes and shot everyone in front of them."
The militants reportedly disguised themselves in Kurdish People's Protection Units (YPG) and Syrian Free Army uniforms during the attacks.
"The situation is under control, we do not think the jihadists are hiding in the city anymore," Redur Xelil, a spokesman for the YPG told the Telegraph , adding that Kurdish fighters were sweeping the city to find any remaining militants.
According to Xelil, the fight was less about gaining control of the city for IS and more about remaining feared.
The fighting continues in the city of Hassakuh.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 17:41:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greeks rush to take out cash after call for referendum</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/27/Greeks-rush-to-take-out-cash-after-call-for-referendum/1831435411438/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
| License Photo
ATHENS, Greece, June 27 (UPI) -- Greeks are rushing to ATMs after Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras called for a July 5 referendum on the final offer made by bailout creditors, leaving the country's citizens uncertain about their future with the European currency.
According to the Financial Times , the Greek banking system is relying on the European Central Bank for special support due to thousands of people lining up to get cash out of concern their account balances will soon be worthless.
"Tsipras is playing a very dangerous game with the referendum. The real question is 'in or out of the euro,' and from what he said yesterday, he wants out. He lied to the electorate and is playing with people's livelihoods," Nikos Stavrakakis, a lawyer, told the Wall Street Journal .
Downtown Athens, at a National Bank of Greece ATM. #Greferendum #dimopsifisma pic.twitter.com/BNfOilmPQO
 Vassilis Goulandris (@goulandris) June 27, 2015
During an early morning press conference held Saturday, Tsipras announced a deal that could leave Greece's future with the European Union up to a popular vote.
"Our responsibility is for the future of our country. This responsibility obliges us to respond to the ultimatum through the sovereign will of the Greek people," he said.
The current bailout program is set is expire Tuesday, which could lead the country's banks to collapse.
Former Prime Minister Costas Karamanlis called the referendum a "foolish choice," reports Voice of America . "The nation's most vital interests demand that the country remains at the heart of Europe. The EU's actual shortcomings do not, in any way, negate this...," he said.
Finance ministers from 19 countries are set to gather in an emergency session to discuss the situation at hand in Brussels, Belgium, Saturday.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 07:52:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek gov't rejects terms of relief funds, risks expulsion from euro</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/27/Greek-govt-rejects-terms-of-relief-funds-risks-expulsion-from-euro/3911435378876/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Greek gov't rejects terms of relief funds, risks expulsion from euro
By Doug G. Ware | June 27, 2015 at 12:52 AM
Comments
| License Photo
ATHENS, Greece, June 27 (UPI) -- Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' government on Friday once again rejected international creditors' offer to provide billions in relief funds that would allow Athens to make a $1.7 billion payment to the International Monetary Fund -- and avoid default -- on Tuesday.
For weeks, Tsipras has been reluctant to accept the terms of the offer because they call for a cut in government spending -- cuts the prime minister believes would take money from Greek workers' wages and state-funded pensions.
The European Central Bank and IMF have been negotiating with Greece for weeks to reach an agreement, which would release the remaining funds from a $7 billion bailout fund Athens has drawn from in the past. Greece, though, has resisted.
Creditors haven't backed down from their demands for cuts in spending because they say such a reduction is necessary to facilitate economic growth and mitigate future repayment risk. Athens must make a $1.7 billion repayment to the IMF by Tuesday to avoid default, possible bankruptcy and possible exclusion from the euro.
Tsipras, however, has already said multiple times that the Greek government doesn't have the money to fulfill the payment.
Eurozone finance ministers will meet again Saturday to try and reach a solution, but some analysts believe that is unlikely because both sides reportedly remain far apart on the terms of a deal. Officials said Thursday that the weekend negotiations will be the last chance to strike a deal.
Friday, Tsipras said he will recommend voters in his country reject the proposed bailout terms in a July 5 referendum .
Most economic policy makers were surprised by Tsipras' call for a referendum, although he informed German Chancellor Angela Merkel and French President Francois Hollande about the vote beforehand, the Wall Street Journal reported .
If Greece can't reach a deal with creditors, it would become the first developed nation in history to default on the IMF.
Defaulting on the loan, analysts say, might cause the ECB to curtail funding it has provided to Greek banks in recent weeks to keep them operating during the crisis. Account holders in those banks have so far withdrawn tens of billions of euros as the stalemate has escalated.
Tsipras said Friday that, although he opposes creditors' terms, he will respect the outcome of the public's July 5 vote. By then, however, it might be too late, analysts say -- because the payment is due by June 30 and it's unlikely those creditors will provide an extension, given Athens' refusals of previous relief offers.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 06:19:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Widow of SKorea President Kim Dae-jung to visit North Korea</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Widow-of-SKorea-President-Kim-Dae-jung-to-visit-North-Korea/9551435373432/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Widow of SKorea President Kim Dae-jung to visit North Korea
Kim Jong Un had extended a formal invitation to Lee Hee-ho last December.
By Elizabeth Shim | June 26, 2015 at 11:19 PM
Comments
SEOUL, June 26 (UPI) -- South Korea's former first lady is to visit Pyongyang in July and a meeting with North Korean leader Kim Jong Un is likely, according to South Korea sources.
Lee Hee-ho, the widow of erstwhile South Korean President Kim Dae-jung, made her plans public on Friday, according to news agency Yonhap , but her request to meet with the North's Kim has yet to receive a response from Pyongyang.
Kim Sung-jae, an official at South Korea's Kim Dae-jung Peace Center, said North Korea has proposed a June 30 meeting in Kaesong, North Korea, to discuss details of Lee's upcoming trip.
The North Korean city is the site of a jointly operated factory park.
South Korean newspaper Donga Ilbo reported North Korea's Kim had extended a formal invitation to Lee for a visit last December.
The state of the 92-year-old Lee's health, however, twice delayed a visit that could have advanced North-South reconciliation, according to the spokesman at Kim Dae-jung Peace Center.
During his term of office, South Korea's Kim made a historical visit to Pyongyang in June 2000 and met with then-North Korean leader Kim Jong Il. Together, they signed the June 15th NorthSouth Joint Declaration that subsequently led to an increase in inter-Korea exchange for nearly a decade.
Seoul's Unification Ministry welcomed the announcement as a positive step forward in the civic exchange between North and South.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 23:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pakistan trains teachers, students to use weapons after attack on school</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Pakistan-trains-teachers-students-to-use-weapons-after-attack-on-school/81425073437846/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>1 of 8
| License Photo
PESHAWAR, Pakistan (News Lens Pakistan) -- Khyber Pakhtunkhwa province in Pakistan's northwest is running a weapons training program for students, teachers and lower-level staff in response to the December attack on the Army Public School in Peshawar.
Provincial Information Minister Mushtaq Ahmad Ghani announced Jan. 13 that teachers and other staffers would be allowed to keep their own guns while at school so they could hold off militants until police arrived. They will receive training in proper use of the weapons.
The government, he said, wants to improve security at 35,000 public schools, colleges and universities. He said the province's 65,000 police officers cannot secure all those facilities.
The December attack left more than 100 children and staff dead, and 126 others wounded. The Tehreek-e-Taliban Pakistan claimed responsibility for the attack.
Saleem Marwat, district police officer in Swat, northeast of Peshawar, said police would train 2,000 watchmen as part of the program to use guns, but emphasized that protection of schools and students would not be left solely to them.
"The police and army are in the region, and on a quick response we can come for the security of children and teachers," he said during a training session.
According to the Khyber Pakhtunkhwa police department, 10,727 school security guards were to be trained in the first quarter of this year across the province while 10,610 more guards are awaiting training.
In addition, eight female teachers from the Frontier College for Women, a government college, received training in using guns.
Samiullah Jan, 27, a watchman in a government school in Swat was one of the trainees.
"I had seen guns, but hadn't fired one. It's the first time I fired one. Now if God willing, I will be ready to confront the rivals attacking my school," he said.
The fear of another school attack persists, but weapons training may not help parents and children who fear schools are unsafe.
Eleven-year-old Ikhtiar, a student of Warsak Model School and College next to the Army Public School, is being kept home from the school by his mother, who he said became scared after the December attack.
"I think of myself, how I should get myself escape if such thing happens in my school," he told News Lens Pakistan. Ikhtiar is reluctant to show his fear but when he goes outside at night he asks an elder to accompany him.
His mother, though, is even more concerned that schools could be a target since hearing about the weapons training initiative and the fact that teachers would now be armed.
"These schools can be attacked again, so my children are dearer to me than their studies," Rukhsana Muqqadas Khan said. "I would like to find a low-profile school in the neighborhood where my children would keep on their studies.
"Things are changed now we see school teachers are trained to use guns, so how would we believe that our children at school are safe?" she said.
There is also criticism that arming guards and teachers is not a solution to the security problem.
Muhammad Ali Babakhel, Deputy Inspector General of Police in Khyber Pakhtunkwa, told News Lens, "I think we as a society shall work for deweaponization instead of proliferation of weapons.
"Teachers are supposed to teach. The state is supposed to provide a secure environment. If every person is to secure and defend his life and property then it's anarchy and not a state," security analyst Saad Muhammad, who recently retired from the Pakistan army, told News Lens.
Erum Irshad, head of the University of Peshawar's psychology department, said the attack on the Army Public School, the barbed wire on school boundary walls, armed staff and the gun training are all affecting the personalities of children.
Irshad, who also works as a psychotherapist in Peshawar and has treated children, said the fear and anger can lead to post-traumatic stress and depression in children.
She said they need psychotherapy and meditation.
"I went and observed the schoolchildren. Most of them are shocked with the news they have lost their friends," she said, adding that one such student is now unable to even talk.
With the passage of time, they will recover if they get better care, she said.
"In such a traumatized situation, we need psychologists to treat these children; I don't think army has enough teams and human resources in this regard."
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 21:00:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin phones Obama to discuss Ukraine, Islamic State</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Putin-phones-Obama-to-discuss-Ukraine-Islamic-State/7421435335869/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
| License Photo
WASHINGTON, June 26 (UPI) -- Russian President Vladimir Putin discussed Ukraine and the Islamic State by phone with U.S. President Barack Obama , the first contact between the two since February.
The White House said the call, from Putin to Obama, came Thursday evening adding that Obama stressed the importance of Russia's adherence to the Minsk agreement, which calls for a cease-fire in Ukraine.
"President Obama reiterated the need for Russia to fulfill its commitments under the Minsk agreements, including the removal of all Russian troops and equipment from Ukrainian territory," a White House statement said. Gen. Philip Breedlove , NATO Supreme Allied Commander, noted several weeks ago the continuous arrival of military supplies to contested eastern Ukraine from Russia.
A statement from the Kremlin said Obama and Putin agreed implementation of the Minsk accord will be discussed by U.S. Assistant Secretary of State Victoria Nuland and Russian Deputy Foreign Minister Grigory Karasin .
The phone call also included discussions on Syria's civil war, in which Russia has been a strong supporter of President Bashar al-Assad 's regime, and of the Islamic State (IS), the Kremlin added. Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov and U.S. Secretary of state John Kerry will meet to discuss IS next week.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:44:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Monsoon rains cause widespread damage in Gujarat, India</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Monsoon-rains-cause-widespread-damage-in-Gujarat-India/1671435323988/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Monsoon rains cause widespread damage in Gujarat, India
By Tharadjyne Orisma | June 26, 2015 at 1:44 PM
GUJARAT, India, June 26 (UPI) -- Monsoon rains have killed 70 people, collapsed houses and caused other major damage, prompting 10,000 to flee to higher ground.
About 1,000 people have been airlifted to safety.
Although Gujarat is accustomed to heavy flooding during the monsoon season, this week's floods are the worst in 90 years.
The district of Amreli has experienced the worst of the floods, with 600 of 838 villages ravaged by heavy rains, leaving many stranded on top of buildings.
The Indian Air Force (IAF), disaster relief organizations, and the state government launched rescue operations to evacuate those in need of aid.
Four IAF choppers made 19 sorties to drop 15,000 food packets for villagers who were trapped on their terraces since Wednesday. Over 400 villages have roads that are shut down or have been washed away.
Local farmers have been the most affected as large areas of crop have been spoiled and cattle has been washed away.
Chief Minister Anandiben Patel said that after an "aerial survey" of the land has been conducted financial assistance will given to farmers.
Gujarat floods IAF in action. Salute the Air Warriors pic.twitter.com/4K0VG6ijyN
 Aviator Anil Chopra (@Chopsyturvey) June 26, 2015
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:03:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Diplomat's $8 million NY apartment sparks criticism back home in New Zealand</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Diplomats-8-million-NY-apartment-sparks-criticism-back-home-in-New-Zealand/2581435337252/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Diplomat's $8 million NY apartment sparks criticism back home in New Zealand
By Elizabeth Shim | June 26, 2015 at 1:03 PM
Comments
NEW YORK, June 26 (UPI) -- An upscale Manhattan apartment estimated to be worth $8 million has sparked debate over "wasteful spending" in New Zealand.
The three-bedroom, three-bathroom unit is the residence of New Zealand's ambassador to the U.N., Gerard van Bohemen, according to The Sydney Morning Herald .
The location is ideal for the diplomat, who can take a simple stroll across the road to his office at the U.N. headquarters.
After a long day at work, he could enjoy a view of the East River from home, but the residential perks of the apartment at 50 U.N. Plaza did not sit comfortably with New Zealand politicians.
Radio New Zealand reported the dismay among leaders.
New Zealand Labour Party foreign affairs spokesman David Shearer said the building was home to Hollywood celebrities, and that Manhattan is too expensive.
"That's an awful lot of money when New Zealanders here can't get into the property market because [it] is out of control," he said.
An online listing of the apartment described it "large and impressive," and ready for "large scale" entertaining. The listing described the master bathroom as "white marble" with heated floors.
New Zealand's Green Party co-leader James Shaw said the apartment is wasteful spending.
"[The] Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Trade really needs to front with why they bought this particular apartment and the process that was behind choosing it," he said.
A former foreign minister defended the ambassador and said he is "simply doing his job."
"The men responsible for this out-of-control spending are Foreign Minister Murray McCully and Finance Minister Bill English - why aren't they being photo-imaged?" asked Winston Peters .
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:50:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As MERS dwindles, two South Korea hospitals removed from isolation</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/As-MERS-dwindles-two-South-Korea-hospitals-removed-from-isolation/9931435335109/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>As MERS dwindles, two South Korea hospitals removed from isolation
Daejeon, South Koreas fifth-largest city, has not witnessed new cases since June 21.
By Elizabeth Shim | June 26, 2015 at 12:50 PM
Comments
DAEJEON, South Korea, June 26 (UPI) -- South Korea's MERS cases are dwindling, and two hospitals outside Seoul have lifted restrictions that were placed in response to an outbreak among patients.
Konyang University Hospital and Daechung Hospital, both in Daejeon, said Friday that the hospitals would no longer serve as sites of cohort isolation and have reopened to the public, South Korean newspaper JoongAng Daily reported.
Both hospitals said there have been no new confirmed cases of MERS in the last 14 days.
Daejeon, South Korea's fifth-largest city, has not witnessed new cases since June 21, according to South Korean newspaper Kyunghyang Sinmun.
Park Chang-il, director of Konyang, said the restrictions were removed a month after the first South Korea MERS case was reported.
Taking a friendly jab at the situation up north in Seoul, the country's capital, Park said, "MERS may have spread through the hospital community in Seoul, but here in Daejeon it was contained through the hard work of the community."
Park said he and his colleagues continue to monitor nationwide infections.
Seoul has redesignated Konyang as a "safe" hospital but its ICU is expected to extend the cohort isolation for another three days. There are 21 confirmed MERS patients in treatment at the hospital.
Konyang hospital's head nurse said she was "overjoyed" to hear the news, according to JoongAng Daily.
Lee Ji-eun said she had stayed in self-imposed isolation for the last 14 days upon orders. The hardest part of being away, she said, was not being able to be there for her colleagues.
On Friday Seoul said 31 people have died from MERS and a total of 181 have been infected.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:49:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vatican formally recognizes Palestine as a state</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Vatican-formally-recognizes-Palestine-as-a-state/5651435334265/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
VATICAN CITY, June 26 (UPI) -- The Vatican formally recognized Palestine as a state Friday, with the signing of a treaty, the product of 15 years of negotiations.
The agreement involves "essential aspects of the life and activity of the Catholic Church in the State of Palestine," a Vatican statement said.
The acknowledgement of Palestine's identity , Vatican ambassador Archbishop Paul Gallagher said, is meant to be a "stimulus to bringing a definitive end to the longstanding Israeli-Palestinian conflict, which continues to cause suffering for both parties." He added he hoped the "much desired two-state solution may become a reality as soon as possible."
Gallagher and Palestinian Authority Foreign Minister Raid al-Malki signed the treaty in a ceremony at the Vatican, which was announced in May .
The Israeli Foreign Ministry expressed its disappointment at the diplomatic maneuver, calling it a "hasty step" which "distances the Palestinian leadership from returning to direct and bilateral negotiations" with Israel over a two-state solution to their conflict.
Since 2012 the United Nations has considered Palestine a "non-member observer state."
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:18:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sochi, Russia, flooded after rainstorm</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Sochi-Russia-flooded-after-rainstorm/4011435331891/</Link>
        <Description>Ed Adamczyk</Description>
        <MainBody>Comments
SOCHI , Russia, June 26 (UPI) -- Rain and flooding forced the evacuation Friday of residents of Sochi, Russia, the resort city which hosted the 2014 Winter Olympics.
Trains were stopped, road were flooded and the city's airport was closed after several hours of heavy rain descended on the Black Sea resort. The Formula 1 car racing track in the nearby town of Adler was completely underwater, and police said Friday they rescued over 250 people from stalled vehicles, first-floor residences and bridges.
Police added 70 people in Adler, passengers who departed a bus and sought shelter under a footbridge, were rescued from rising water beneath the bridge .
Sochi Mayor Anatoly Pakhomov announced a state of emergency was declared. There were no reports of casualties.
Meteorologists warned tornadoes could form from the storm and move inland. The crisis is similar to, but more severe than, incidents last week further south in Georgia, where severe flooding in the capital of Tbilisi killed 19 people, caused extensive damage and led to the escape of animals from the local zoo.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:23:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Attack on Somalia base kills at least 30</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Attack-on-Somalia-base-kills-at-least-30/7481435324910/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
MOGADISHU, Somalia, June 26 (UPI) -- At least 30 people were killed Friday in a morning attack, blamed on the militant Islamist group al-Shabab, on an African Union military base in Somalia.
The African Union Mission in Somalia (AMISOM) confirmed its base in Leego, on the road in southern Somalia between the city of Baidoa and the capital of Mogadishu, was struck in a dawn raid. The base is maintained by soldiers from Burundi, part of a unified effort by the 54-nation bloc to bring stability to Somalia. Burundi currently has over 20,000 troops in Somalia.
The ANISOM message only confirmed mentioned the attack, without referring to casualties or its outcome. Al-Shabab, which is fighting to control the country and its government, said in a statement it had taken control of the base.
Witnesses said the attackers used a suicide bomb in the lead car as its convoy approached the base entrance, then fired machine guns and rocket-propelled grenades.
Al-Shabab has previously announced it would step up attacks during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, which began this week. The United Arab Emirates ambassador to Somalia survived a suicide attack on his convoy near Mogadishu Wednesday.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:16:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former North Korea political prisoner submits report to U.N.'s Seoul office</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Former-North-Korea-political-prisoner-submits-report-to-UNs-Seoul-office/3541435330729/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Former North Korea political prisoner submits report to U.N.'s Seoul office
Jeong Kwang-il identified 180 missing captives and urged the U.N. to launch an investigation into their whereabouts.
By Elizabeth Shim | June 26, 2015 at 11:16 AM
Comments
SEOUL, June 26 (UPI) -- A defector who once piled dead bodies at a North Korean political prison camp submitted a report to the new U.N. human rights office in Seoul.
In his report on Friday Jeong Kwang-il identified 180 missing captives and urged the U.N. to launch an investigation into their whereabouts, Yonhap reported.
Yodok, the political prison camp where Jeong once served time, was dismantled last October. Voice of America reported the camp began to disappear from satellite images in 2014.
North Korea denies it operates massive prison camps for the politically insubordinate and their relatives  but Jeong and an affiliated group, the International Coalition to Stop Crimes against Humanity in North Korea, said between 80,000 and 120,000 political prisoners are still languishing in North Korea detention.
Jeong said the abysmal conditions in these prison camps led to countless deaths. Prisoners like himself who remained alive had to pile the dead bodies in a shed, then use pitchforks to drag them out in the spring.
After defecting to the South, Jeong has become a spokesman for defectors with a similar past in political prisons. He served prison time between 2000 and 2003, but now his projects include smuggling in movies and DVDs to the North.
On Friday, Jeong said the political prisons hosted anti-state activists little known to the outside world, including those charged with plotting to overthrow the Kim Jong Il regime between 1997 and 2000, and a group of North Korean students who plotted a coup in 1989, while they studied in Germany.
Jeong said he also wanted an investigation into the prison personnel who released him in 2003. In total, 400 people have gone missing since Yodok shuttered in October 2014.
Seoul's spy agency said last October Yodok may have been relocated to Kilju in North Hamkyong Province, and that punishment has escalated for those charged with political crimes inside the country.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:02:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Russian Prime Minister Primakov dies at 85</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Former-Russian-Prime-Minister-Primakov-dies-at-85/7251435329228/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
| License Photo
MOSCOW, June 26 (UPI) -- Evgeny Primakov, Soviet and Russian statesman, and Prime Minister during Boris Yeltsin 's presidency, died Friday in Moscow. He was 85.
"He was a statesman, a scientist, a politician and left an enormous legacy," Dmitry Peskov, spokesman for Russian President Vladimir Putin, said.
Primakov began his career as a journalist, writing as a Middle East correspondent for the Russian newspaper Pravda, and later was the head of the Soviet Academy of Sciences' Institute for Oriental Studies and the Institute of the World Economy and International Relations.
In the Russian government , he served as parliament member, special envoy to Iraq, First Deputy Chairman of the intelligence agency KGB, director of the Foreign Intelligence Service, foreign minister and days after Russia defaulted on $40 billion of debt and devalued the ruble in 1998, Prime Minister Primakov's government introduced tax reforms to defuse the situation.
While traveling to the United States in 1999, he famously ordered his plane turned around over the Atlantic Ocean to return to Russia when he learned NATO had begun airstrikes in Serbia.
In an e-mailed statement Friday, U.S. ambassador to Russia John Tefft called Primakov "without doubt one of the great statesmen and diplomats of both Soviet and modern Russian history. He will be missed."
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:30:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Armenia gives church to Russian military</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Armenia-gives-church-to-Russian-military/7981435327017/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
GYUMRI , Armenia, June 26 (UPI) -- Armenia announced Friday an Orthodox Christian cathedral will be handed over to an adjoining Russian military base.
What military base deputy commander Archimandrite Andrey called "the biggest Russian Orthodox church in Armenia," built in the 1920s, will become a clerical cultural center and permanent part of the Russian military installation in Armenia's northwestern Gyumri region. Russia obtained a 49-year extension of its presence at the base in 2010.
The transfer of the church is an indication of the close ties between Armenia, a former Soviet republic, and Russia. Each is part of the six-member Collective Security Treaty Organization (CSTO), a mutual security bloc modeled after NATO and led by Russia. Its other members are Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, and Uzbekistan.
At a CSTO meeting Friday in Moscow, plans were discussed to establish a crisis response center to be used when member states encounter security threats. The information-sharing complex will be installed at an unidentified military base near Moscow.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:21:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Seoul blacklists Taiwan, Syria firms for North Korea dealings</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Seoul-blacklists-Taiwan-Syria-firms-for-North-Korea-dealings/6461435326621/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Seoul blacklists Taiwan, Syria firms for North Korea dealings
Seven people and organizations in total were placed under Seouls new financial sanctions.
By Elizabeth Shim | June 26, 2015 at 10:21 AM
Comments
SEOUL, June 26 (UPI) -- Taiwanese businesses with ties to North Korea were placed under South Korea financial sanctions on Friday.
Seoul's Foreign Ministry said in a statement that Taiwanese firms Global Interface Co. Inc., Trans Merits and Trans Multi Mechanics Co. Ltd., as well as a handful of Taiwanese people were banned from normal trade with South Korea entities, Yonhap reported.
Taiwanese businessman Tsai Hsien-tai of Global Interface was charged with selling precision machine tools to North Korea  equipment that could be refurbished as weapons. Tsai has been charged in a northern Illinois U.S. court for selling the weapons, and was sentenced to two years in prison last March.
The North Korea entity Tsai dealt with, Korea Mining Development Trading Corp., has been under U.S. Treasury sanctions since January 2009. KOMIC is also under U.N. sanctions.
South Korea's Friday announcement marks the first time Seoul is taking action against third-party nationals and businesses for their links to North Korea.
Seoul is aligning itself with Washington's policy of financially isolating supporters of weapons of mass destruction proliferation, according to Yonhap. U.S. Executive Order 13382 has frozen the assets of proliferators of WMDs and their supporters since 2005.
Global Interface subsidiary Trans Merits was charged with supporting North Korea's weapons development. Currently under U.S. sanctions, Trans Merits is banned from regular dealings with South Korea entities, effective Friday.
Tsai's spouse, Su Lu-chi, was blacklisted for abetting North Korea, and Chang Wen-fu of Trans Multi Mechanics is now under both U.S. and South Korea sanctions.
Seven people and organizations in total were placed under Seoul's new financial sanctions, South Korean newspaper Kyunghyang Sinmun reported. They have been added to the government's list of 12 North Koreans and 20 North Korea firms previously blacklisted by Seoul.
A Syrian firm, Scientific Studies and Research Center, was blacklisted for supporting North Korea weapons proliferation. The Damascus-based firm specializes in the development of WMDs, chemical weapons and missile development.
South Korea individuals illicitly dealing with blacklisted firms are to face penalties: a fine of $267,000, or three years in prison.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:45:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU agrees to relocate 40,000 migrants from Italy and Greece</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/EU-agrees-to-relocate-40000-migrants-from-Italy-and-Greece/7041435321085/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
BRUSSELS, June 26 (UPI) -- A plan to relocate 40,000 asylum seekers from Italy and Greece to other European Union countries was revealed Friday after marathon talks in Brussels.
Involvement in the plan by the 28 members of the economic bloc is voluntary, with no quotas involved; Hungary, which Tuesday indefinitely suspended an existing EU rule requiring migrants to be processed in the country in which they arrive, and Bulgaria were omitted from the new plan. Both countries have requested a reduction in the burden of settling refugees. The negotiations demonstrated the contentious nature of European countries agreeing to take in some of those fleeing poverty and violence in North Africa and the Middle East.
"The discussion was long and there were some moments of tension," French President Francois Hollande commented.
Frontex, the European border security agency, estimated earlier this week 153,000 migrant have been observed at borders thus far this year, a 149 percent increase over the same period in 2014. A United Nations report said 103,000 had arrived by sea in Italy, Greece, Malta and Spain.
The plan calls for relocation of 40,000 people by the end of 2016, with a distribution pattern to be announced by the end of July. Another 20,000 currently living outside the EU but in need of asylum will also be resettled; those found not in need of protection will be returned to their home countries, in part to discourage the influx of refugees, the overwhelming majority of whom take a hazardous and often deadly trip across the Mediterranean Sea to Europe.
There has also been an increase in the number of those who travel from the Middle East to the EU's eastern Balkan countries.
"I have no doubt that it will take much time to build new European consensus on migration. But first and foremost, we need to contain illegal migration and this should be our priority. Today we have no consensus among member states on mandatory quotas for migrants. But at the same time the voluntary scheme cannot be an excuse to do nothing," said EU Council President Donald Tusk .
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:17:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait City mosque bombing kills 27</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Kuwait-City-mosque-bombing-kills-27/5611435323161/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>1 of 6
| License Photo
KUWAIT CITY, June 26 (UPI) -- Twenty-seven people were killed Friday as the crowded Imam Sadiq Mosque in Kuwait City was struck by a suicide bomber, officials said.
In addition to the 27 dead, Kuwaiti Health Minister Ali al-Obaidi told Kuwait News Agency 227 others were injured. About 2,000 people were in the mosque at the time of the incident. Kuwaiti parliament member Khalil Al Salih said prayers were in progress when a loud explosion tore through the building.
A group affiliated with the Islamic State (IS), the "Islamic State in the Province of Najd," a reference to central Saudi Arabia, claimed responsibility for the attack on the Shia mosque , near the Kuwaiti Interior Ministry, in al-Sawaber, a neighborhood in eastern Kuwait City. It identified the bomber as Abu Sulaiman Al Muwahhid, and referred to the mosque as the "temple of the rejectionists." Kuwait's rulers are Sunni Muslims, although the country has a large Shia majority regarded by IS as heretics.
Similar recent attacks, blamed on IS, have occurred in Saudi Arabia and Yemen. Kuwait has been relatively free of terrorist incidents.
Guarded by heavy security, Shaikh Sabah Al Ahmad, Emir of Kuwait, later visited the area of the blast, as the country declared a state of emergency.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:04:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen open fire at Sousse, Tunisia, hotel; 37 dead</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Gunmen-open-fire-at-Sousse-Tunisia-hotel-37-dead/2511435321693/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
SOUSSE, Tunisia, June 26 (UPI) -- The death toll in an attack on a seaside resort in Sousse, Tunisia, has risen to 37, officials said.
Officials said tourists were among those killed at the Imperial Marhaba hotel. At least one of the gunmen was also killed and a second was being pursued, the BBC reported .
The British Foreign Minister said five Britons and one Irish woman were among those killed, The Guardian reported .
Sources told Al Jazeera the gunmen exchanged fire with security forces before one man fled.
British tourist Gary Pine told Sky News he thought at first that "fire crackers" were going off at the hotel.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach," he said. "My son was in the sea at the time and myself and my wife were shouting at him to get out and as he ran up he said 'I've just saw someone get shot.'"
A top security official in Tunisia said a gunman from Kairouan, Tunisia, hid a Kalashnikov under an umbrella and opened fire on tourists on the beach. He then moved to the hotel, shooting guests as he did.
Hotel officials said 13 people were injured, including nine guests and four hotel employees.
No group has claimed responsibility for the attack, though sources said the gunmen may have intentionally targeted tourists at the hotel and possibly two other hotels.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:17:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man beheaded in terrorist attack at French factory; suspect arrested, identified</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Man-beheaded-in-terrorist-attack-at-French-factory-suspect-arrested-identified/7411435314211/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man beheaded in terrorist attack at French factory; suspect arrested, identified
By Tharadjyne Orisma and Danielle Haynes | June 26, 2015 at 8:17 AM
Comments
| License Photo
GRENOBLE, France, June 26 (UPI) -- French President Francois Hollande said Friday one person was killed in a terrorist attack at a gas factory.
A man's decapitated head covered in Arabic writing was pinned to the factory gates, Sky News reported. His body was found yards away.
The man's identity has not been released, though the company where the attack took place said all its employees were accounted for . The factory is owned by Air Products &amp; Chemicals, out of Pennsylvania.
"We can confirm that an incident occurred at our facility in L'Isle-d'Abeau, France this morning," the company said in a statement. "Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for," the company said. "Emergency services are on site and have contained the situation. The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities. Further information will be released as soon as it becomes available."
Loud explosions were heard, and an Islamic flag was raised near the factory.
"The intent was without doubt to cause an explosion. It was a terrorist attack," Hollande told a press conference in Belgium, where he was attending a European Union summit.
A suspect, identified by French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve as Yassine Salhi. The suspect has no criminal past , but he had been suspected of radicalization in 2006.
Police said the suspect -- a 30-year-old man who identifies himself as a member of the Islamic State -- may have had help. Two people were seen carrying Islamic flags, and a source described seeing multiple people inside a vehicle driving into the factory. They saw the suspect detonate several minor explosives.
French authorities had some indications that some kind of attack was being planned.
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls said security was being tightened at "sensitive sites."
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:54:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mass rally in Pyongyang denounces 'U.S. imperialists'</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/26/Mass-rally-in-Pyongyang-denounces-US-imperialists/1231435300065/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Mass rally in Pyongyang denounces 'U.S. imperialists'
The rally attended by 100,000 people marked the 65th anniversary of the Korean War.
By Elizabeth Shim | June 26, 2015 at 2:54 AM
Comments
SEOUL, June 26 (UPI) -- North Korea vowed to struggle against the United States on Thursday, the 65th anniversary of the outbreak of the Korean War.
In its "Pyongyang Mass Rally on the Day of the Struggle Against the U.S.," around 100,000 North Koreans gathered at Pyongyang's Kim Il Sung Stadium to show support for the country's nuclear development program, South Korean news agency Yonhap reported.
State-operated media network KCNA broadcast the rally that featured North Koreans in civilian clothing, shouting slogans in unison and holding cloth banners that vowed revenge against "U.S. imperialists."
North and South Korea both observe the anniversary of the Korean War, but Pyongyang's history of the war differs remarkably from what is commonly known among U.S. and South Korean historians.
On Tuesday North Korea blasted the United States and South Korea for masterminding the Korean War, a day ahead of the conflict's 65th anniversary on Thursday.
North Korea claims the U.S. began the armed conflict by invading north of the 38th parallel  a story that lacks historical basis and conceals the fact Kim Il Sung ordered troops to cross into the South and overtake Seoul.
The rally on Thursday included speeches about self-reliance and the importance of the country's "Byungjin," or parallel development policy that could "relentlessly strengthen" the country's military power, according to Cha Hee Rim, the chair of Pyongyang's People's Committee.
Cha said 10 million North Korean soldiers are boiling over with rage at the thought of "U.S. imperialists and their South Korean running dogs" who "invaded 65 years ago" are showing signs of provoking another war.
"The United States is running around madly, stubbornly pursuing ways to provoke a new war," Cha said.
Neither did Pak Song Cho, the chairman of Kim Il Sung University's Youth Alliance mince his words when addressing North Korea's foes.
"If the U.S. imperialists and its puppets at any time even send a spark our way, five million guns and bombs will be used, and not a single bastard will be left alive."
South Korean television network KBS reported North Korea has designated the weeks between June 25 and July 27 as "June 25 Month of Anti-U.S. Struggle."
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:17:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Creditors: Greece must agree to bailout terms Saturday to get funds</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/06/25/Creditors-Greece-must-agree-to-bailout-terms-Saturday-to-get-funds/4221435282961/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Creditors: Greece must agree to bailout terms Saturday to get funds
By Doug G. Ware | June 25, 2015 at 10:17 PM
Comments
ATHENS, Greece, June 25 (UPI) -- International creditors have set a weekend deadline for the Greek government to agree to terms to receive billions in relief funds, allowing it to pay $1.7 billion to the International Monetary Fund by Tuesday's cutoff.
The deadline, set Thursday, is the firmest stance yet that creditors have taken against Athens -- which has been negotiating for weeks to unlock billions in remaining bailout funds. The funds would allow them to keep up payments to the IMF.
Negotiators have been meeting in Belgium this week to try and come up with a solution -- as well as plan for the possibility that Greece is booted from the euro. As of Thursday, no deal had been reached .
Eurozone finance ministers will meet again Saturday in an effort to get a deal done before the markets open Monday -- a stipulation mandated by German Chancellor Angela Merkel , the Guardian reported .
Some in the European Union have said both sides remain far apart, and Merkel even claimed that Greece was taking steps back on some issues.
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' administration has been steadfast in its resistance to adhere to creditors' demands that Athens cut government spending as a condition of receiving the remainder of more than $7.83 billion in bailout funds previously authorized by the IMF to Greece.
Creditors say cost-cutting is a necessary step to ensure financial growth, but Tsipras has refused to make the cuts because he believes they would take money from Greek wages and pensions -- two key issues the prime minister ran on prior to his taking office in January.
If a deal isn't reached Saturday, analysts believe it is unlikely that Greece will be able to make the $1.7 billion payment to the IMF before it is due Tuesday.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
