<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="UPI">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:22:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Korea rescues 5 North Korean sailors</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/07/South-Korea-rescues-5-North-Korean-sailors/7851436274841/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
South Korea rescues 5 North Korean sailors
The sailors had drifted south of a maritime border, and of the five three have expressed a desire to defect to the South.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 7, 2015 at 9:22 AM
Comments
| License Photo
SEOUL, July 7 (UPI) -- Five North Korean sailors were rescued near South Korea's eastern coastline, and three of the five have said they wish to defect to the South.
Seoul's Unification Ministry said on Tuesday the sailors had drifted south of a maritime border when they were found near Ulleungdo, a sparsely populated South Korean island with around 10,000 inhabitants.
South Korea coast guard rescued the North Korean vessel and the five sailors onboard on Saturday, South Korean news agency Yonhap reported.
Seoul said it has delivered the message of the rescue to Pyongyang, using a direct phone line of the South Korea Red Cross.
South Korea's attempt to repatriate the two of the five sailors who wished to return to the North, however, was met with a rebuttal.
On Tuesday, Pyongyang returned the South's message, and said all five North Koreans must be repatriated. Seoul said the three who said they wished to defect would not be returned on humanitarian grounds.
South Korean media outlet No Cut News reported Seoul said the remaining two sailors who expressed a desire to return to North Korea are to be repatriated at Panmunjom, the truce village between North and South Korea.
A Unification Ministry spokesman said the North Korean ship had been flooded at the time of the rescue and was sinking.
The damage to the ship was impossible to repair, and the ship was discarded after the rescue.
North and South Korea have stood by the practice of returning citizens who are found to have drifted into the other's territory.
On June 16, South Korea rescued a North Korean fisherman trapped on an inoperative squid boat.
The North Korean said he wished to defect to the South, according to Seoul.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:49:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WHO urges stronger tobacco taxes</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/07/WHO-urges-stronger-tobacco-taxes/2271436271464/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WHO urges stronger tobacco taxes
By Tomas Monzon | July 7, 2015 at 8:49 AM
Comments
GENEVA, Switzerland, July 7 (UPI) -- The World Health Organization (WHO) released a report Tuesday saying that heavily taxing cigarettes is one the most effective ways to reduce tobacco use.
The WHO's report on global tobacco use says that although more than half of the world's countries have implemented tobacco-control policies, too few governments levy high enough taxes or taxes at all.
The organization says tobacco taxes are the least implemented form of smoking prevention because of the myth that higher taxes will create an illegal trade. WHO argues this has been disproved and that a crackdown on illicit trade should take place anyway in order to minimize corruption and maximize government revenue.
The WHO recommends cigarettes should be taxed at 75 percent of their value or more in order to stymie consumption. WHO noted tax revenue would assist government spending in other areas.
In Turkey, a 13 percent reduction in smoking among the population between 2009 and 2014 followed a 50 percent increase in tobacco taxes. Increased tobacco prices in China and France also led to lower tobacco-induced deaths, such as lung cancer.
The WHO's recommendation has been heeded by 33 countries including Bangladesh, Croatia and New Zealand, which tax cigarettes at more than three-fourths of their value.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:03:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suicide bomber attacks NATO convoy</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/07/Suicide-bomber-attacks-NATO-convoy/8481436269029/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Suicide bomber attacks NATO convoy
By Tomas Monzon | July 7, 2015 at 8:03 AM
KABUL, Afghanistan, July 7 (UPI) -- A North Atlantic Treaty Organization military convoy led by the United States was attacked by a Taliban suicide bomber Tuesday in Kabul, Afghanistan .
Four civilians were wounded but no NATO troops were killed.
A white Toyota Corolla that was part of the convoy detonated as it approached the house of Pacha Khan Zadran, a former member of the Afghan Parliament. Its passengers moved quickly into one of the two armored S.U.V.s that were part of the convoy and departed the scene.
Following the suicide bomb attack, reports surfaced of armed men entering a building close to an Afghan intelligence agency installation and possibly causing gunfire and explosions.
This marks the second time the NATO coalition is attacked by a suicide bomber even though their military presence in Afghansitan is receding.
The Taliban launched its offensive in Afghanistan in April. Two weeks ago, the group attacked the Afghan parliament directly, killing five people and even losing seven of its own members.
In the first four months of 2015, civilian casualties have jumped 16 percent higher than the first four months of 2014.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:55:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek PM Alexis Tsipras prepared to present proposals to creditors</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/07/Greek-PM-Alexis-Tsipras-prepared-to-present-proposals-to-creditors/8061436263891/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>1 of 2
| License Photo
ATHENS, Greece, July 7 (UPI) -- Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras is prepared to present new proposals to international creditors as to avoid defaulting further on the country's $356 billion debt.
The plan reportedly includes demands for the Greek debt to be cut by up to 30 percent, according to BBC News . Banks will remain closed on Tuesday and Wednesday.
Greece outright rejected the austerity demands by international creditors as to release billions in loans to the country.
In the referendum held Sunday, the Greek people were asked if they accepted the terms of an international bailout submitted by the European Commission, the International Monetary Fund and the European Central Bank -- 61 percent of Greek participants voted "no."
The creditors reacted differently to the referendum. If a deal is not reached, Greece could be removed from the Eurozone economic bloc.
The European Central Bank maintained its about $97 billion cap on emergency liquidity assistance (ELA) for Greece but is treating treating government bonds, used as collateral, as riskier and taking that into account when calculating how much liquidity it can provide. Banks may find it more difficult to qualify for ELA.
European Commission Vice President Valdis Dombrovsk said the vote of "no" is "neither legally nor factually correct," also adding that the Commission will not negotiate with the Greek government until it receives a mandate from the Eurozone's finance ministers who meet Tuesday.
Christine Lagarde , head of the IMF, said in a statement that her organization "has taken note of yesterday's referendum held in Greece. We are monitoring the situation closely and stand ready to assist Greece if requested to do so."
The leaders of the majority of Greek political parties released a joint statement, insisting that the country stay in the eurozone.
"The recent verdict of the Greek people is not a mandate for rupture, but a mandate to continue and strengthen the effort to reach a socially fair and economically viable deal," the statement said.
On June 30, Greece became the first developed nation in history to default on a loan from the IMF.
Needing to pay a $1.7 billion payment to the International Monetary Fund by the end of June, but not having the cash to do so, Athens engaged in numerous negotiations over the last four months -- hoping to strike a deal to unlock the remainder of $7 billion in relief cash previously granted by the organization.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:28:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin reassures PM Alexis Tsipras after 'no' referendum vote in Greece</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/07/Putin-reassures-PM-Alexis-Tsipras-after-no-referendum-vote-in-Greece/2841436189670/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Putin reassures PM Alexis Tsipras after 'no' referendum vote in Greece
President Putin reached out to Greece following historic "no" referendum vote on potential financial bailout.
By Jared M. Feldschreiber | July 7, 2015 at 6:28 AM
Comments
| License Photo
ATHENS, Greece, July 6 (UPI) -- Russian President Vladimir Putin called Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras and lent his support in their hopes for overcoming future financial difficulties.
A Greek government official said Putin initiated the phone call . This comes just one day after 61 percent of Greek voters voted 'no' on a referendum on a lenders-proposed bailout, which dealt with spending cuts and tax increases in exchange for further financial assistance to the Mediterranean country, Sputnik News reported. The overwhelming rejection of this financial bailout comes as talks between Greece and the financial creditors had collapsed in recent weeks. The vote was seen as a harsh rebuke to the shared values and tenets of the European Union.
Prime Minister Tsipras said the voters made a "very brave choice" in a televised address on Sunday night. After voters overwhelmingly rejected tough austerity terms set by international creditors, Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis resigned, ITV News reported. Several rounds of talks between Athens and major international creditors, including the European Central Bank, the International Monetary Fund and the Eurogroup collapsed in recent weeks.
The Kremlin released a statement on Monday: "[The sides] discussed the outcome of the referendum that took place in Greece on the conditions of international creditors providing Athens with financial aid, as well as several issues of further development of Greek-Russian cooperation." Putin personally "expressed support for the Greek people in overcoming the difficulties facing the country," the statement also read.
On June 19, President Putin and Prime Minister Tsipras met on the sidelines at the St. Petersburg International Economic Forum to discuss possible routes of transporting Russia natural gas to Europe via the Turkish Stream pipeline. The Greek and Russian energy ministers also signed a memorandum to set up a joint company for the construction of the Turkish Stream pipeline across Greek territory. This would supply 47 billion cubic meters of gas a year, Russian news agencies also reported.
At the time, Putin said: "If the EU wants Greece to pay its debt then it should be interested in the Greek economy growing. The EU should be applauding us. What's bad about creating new jobs in Greece?"
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 08:26:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia poll indicates low enthusiasm for soccer despite hosting 2018 World Cup</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/07/Russia-poll-indicates-low-enthusiasm-for-soccer-despite-hosting-2018-World-Cup/1831436211359/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
Russia poll indicates low enthusiasm for soccer despite hosting 2018 World Cup
A new poll shatters Russian officials hopes to kickstart the nation's pride and prestige in the world's most popular sport.
By Jared M. Feldschreiber | July 7, 2015 at 1:26 AM
Comments
MOSCOW, July 6 (UPI) -- While the nation has its grand sights set on hosting the 2018 World Cup, a new poll by the Russian Public Opinion Centre (WCIOM) indicated that 73 percent of its citizens feel "indifferent" overall about the sport.
Only 19 percent said that they were "interested in it from time to time" while just 8 percent described themselves as regular soccer fans. The latest survey sampled 1,600 Russians across 46 regions, Russia Beyond the Headlines reported.
"Interest in football isn't high now," said Sports Minister Vitaly Mutko in comments made to state news agency Tass. Mutko pointed to the sport's lack of popularity to "many scandals," a boring domestic league and the national team's paltry performance during the 2014 World Cup in Brazil where attendance in the Russian Premier League has dwindled to just 10,000 spectators a game, a 19-year low. Infighting within the Russian Football Union has caused financial debts leading to its president's ouster.
The 2018 FIFA World Cup is scheduled to take place between June 14 and July 15, 2018, and is the first time the tournament will be held within the former Soviet Union and the first since 2006 to be held in Europe. The opening match and the final are expected to take place in Moscow at the Luzhniki Stadium.
Other poll numbers reveal 25 percent of Russians do not follow the SOGAZ Russian Football Premier League, and 57 percent of Russians could not indicate a professional they admired as a person.
Despite its setbacks, Mutko is confident Russia will rise to the challenge of hosting the World Cup in a big way. "Russia is full of resolve to host one of the best World Cups and fulfill all its obligations," he said at a press conference on preparations for the event to be held in Samara. "The world cup in the main football event and Russia, which has received this right is approaching its work very responsibly and is fulfilling all its obligations to FIFA."
U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch announced at a news conference in late May that bribes in FIFA have taken place over the course of 24 years with officials soliciting bribes from sports marketing firms. 14 people were hit with federal charges, and on Monday Harold Mayne-Nicholls was suspended by its ethics committee for seven years.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 07:23:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>England deletes 'sexist' tweet about Women's World Cup team</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/07/England-deletes-sexist-tweet-about-Womens-World-Cup-team/7171436241468/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
England deletes 'sexist' tweet about Women's World Cup team
The English Football Association tweeted that its Women's World Cup team could "go back to being mothers, partners and daughters."
Comments
LONDON, July 6 (UPI) -- England's Football Association has come under fire for tweeting what some see as a "sexist" comment about its national Women's World Cup team, the Lionesses.
England finished third in the tournament, which concluded Sunday in Vancouver, Canada, and were welcomed home Monday at London's Heathrow Airport.
The FA's @England Twitter accounted celebrated their return with a tweet that said the Lionesses could "go back to being mothers, partners and daughters, but they have taken on another title -- heroes."
Many social media users slammed the tweet for linking women athletes to their roles as wives and mothers.
"Women only exist in relation to other people, apparently," wrote one Twitter user .
In a statement , the FA said the tweet was "taken out of context."
"The full story was a wider homecoming feature attempting to reflect the many personal stories within the playing squad as has been told throughout the course of the tournament," the FA said.
"However, we understand that an element of the story appears to have been taken out of context and the opening paragraph was subsequently revised to reflect that fact."
The tweet has since been deleted.
I see that @england have deleted their breathtakingly sexist tweet about the Lionesses. But here's a screenshot. pic.twitter.com/omWFJ9tOrs
 Josephine Liptrott (@JoLiptrott) July 6, 2015
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:29:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Widow of SKorea President Kim Dae-jung confirmed to visit Pyongyang</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Widow-of-SKorea-President-Kim-Dae-jung-confirmed-to-visit-Pyongyang/8571436234567/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
Widow of SKorea President Kim Dae-jung confirmed to visit Pyongyang
The invitation to the former first lady to visit came directly from Kim Jong Un, and North Korea is showing unusual willingness to accommodate Lee Hee-ho, who previously served as first lady.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 6, 2015 at 10:29 PM
Comments
SEOUL, July 6 (UPI) -- South Korea's former First Lady Lee Hee-ho is confirmed to travel to North Korea in early August, a representative from the Kim Dae-jung Peace Center said Monday.
Kim Sung-jae, the director of the Peace Center named after the former South Korean president, said the 92-year-old Lee is to visit a children's hospital, a maternity home and a nursery in Pyongyang, according to Voice of America .
Plans for Lee to meet with North Korean leader Kim Jong Un, however, were not confirmed, but Kim told South Korean newspaper Donga Ilbo that his North Korea counterpart did not rule out the possibility during preliminary discussions on Monday in Kaesong, North Korea.
The invitation to the former first lady to visit came directly from Kim Jong Un, and North Korea is showing unusual willingness to accommodate Lee, who had canceled previous trips for health reasons.
Kim Sung-jae said Pyongyang has offered an air route from Seoul to Pyongyang exclusively for Lee's visit. Kim's North Korea counterpart Maeng Kyong Il said Pyongyang was willing to send an Air Koryo aircraft, if needed, to transport Lee and her aides to North Korea.
During her visit, Kim Jong Un has requested Lee stay at North Korea's State Guest House Baek Hwa Won, where South Korean President Kim Dae-jung was housed during the inter-Korea summit of 2000.
Maeng told Kim on Monday that North Korea is always ready for talks  and that it's the South Korean government that should mend its ways.
"If it does, there are no reasons not to talk," said Maeng, according to Kim Sung-jae.
Chang Yong-seok, an analyst at Seoul National University's Institute for Peace and Unification, said the Lee visit would be used by North Korea to bolster Kim Jong Un's image as a leader who favors unification.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 01:19:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Duma approves construction of $4 billion bridge to Crimea</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Duma-approves-construction-of-4-billion-bridge-to-Crimea/1041436217205/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
Duma approves construction of $4 billion bridge to Crimea
The State Duma approved plans to build a bridge from the Russian mainland to Crimea as part of $4 billion project.
By Jared M. Feldschreiber | July 6, 2015 at 6:19 PM
Comments
MOSCOW, July 6 (UPI) -- The State Duma, the lower house of the Federal Assembly of the Russian Federation, approved plans Monday to build a bridge from the Russian mainland to Crimea as part of $4 billion project.
The bill has simplified permit and licensing procedures for companies involved in the project, which will be managed by Stroigazmontazh (SGM), The Moscow Times reported . The company is owned by Arkady Rotenberg, a personal friend of President Vladimir Putin. The bill is headed toward the upper house, the Federation Council, for approval before going to the president to sign into law.
The project is slated to be completed by December 2018. Rotenberg was quoted in Kommersant, a daily newspaper, last year that the project would cost 228.3 billion rubles or $4 billion.
Rotenberg has an estimated personal wealth of $1.4 billion in 2015, making him the country's 60th richest man, and was one of the first Russians to be hit with U.S. sanctions as punishment for the Kremlin's annexation of Crimea from Ukraine last year.
President Putin has furthersecurity plans for Crimea. Interfax news agency reported that Russia will deploy the first Bastion silo-based surface-to-ship missile system in the Crimean Peninsula by 2020. It will be positioned in the region as part of Russia's plans to increase its control over the Black Sea.
"The first Bastion silo-based surface-to-ship missile system will be deployed in Crimea within the next five years," a source within the Russian navy told Interfax. "It will use both the currently existing Yakhont anti-ship [missiles] and prospected missile systems being developed at the moment, which will be capable of destroying any target in the Black Sea area."
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:27:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russian business magnate Alishar Usamanov makes bid to buy CTC</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Russian-business-magnate-Alishar-Usamanov-makes-bid-to-buy-CTC/4501436200017/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
Russian business magnate Alishar Usamanov makes bid to buy CTC
Alisher Usamanov offers $200 million for a controlling stake in local media broadcaster CTC Media Inc.'s operating business Modern Times Group (MTG).
By Jared M. Feldschreiber | July 6, 2015 at 2:27 PM
Comments
MOSCOW, July 6 (UPI) -- Russian billionaire Alisher Usamanov, the country's fifth wealthiest man, offered $200 million for a controlling stake in local media broadcaster Modern Times Group (MTG), an international digital entertainment group.
Usamanov is the part owner of CTC Media , which made the bid. MTG was formed out of the media holdings investment company Kinnevik, which in 1997 was distributed to the company stockholders. The company operates free TV channels in 10 countries.
Russia's CTC, in which Sweden's MTG owns a 38 percent stake, has been looking for a buyer for months to comply with a new Russian law limiting foreign ownership in media companies to 20 percent beginning January 1, 2016.
Usamanov, the Uzbek-born oligarch, reportedly made the offer for 75 percent of the company's operating assets, The Moscow Times is reporting . Usamanov is also a leading shareholder in Russian Internet Group, Mail.ru. A spokeswoman for Usmanov, whose holding company USM owns 50 percent of UTH, declined to publicly comment on his company's offer.
Modern Times Group said it would reclassify its CTC Media stake as a "discontinued operation," showing that the holding is currently for sale.
President Vladimir Putin signed a media law in October 2014 to control foreign Internet companies. At the time, Kremlin's critics said it was a measure to counter an "information war" with the U.S. and Europe, and a move to curtail freedom of information. Russia has said it is a necessary security measure to protect against spying.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:46:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kenyan bishop warns Obama against pro-gay policy</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Kenyan-bishop-warns-Obama-against-pro-gay-policy/7061436203156/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
NAIROBI, Kenya, July 6 (UPI) -- Anti-gay activists in Nairobi, Kenya, warned U.S. President Barack Obama Monday against advocating tolerance for homosexuality when he visits Kenya in August.
At a demonstration led by Bishop Mark Kariuki , chairman of the Evangelical Alliance of Kenya, marchers chanted, "We want Obama, we want Michele, and we want a child. We do not want Obama and Obama, we do not want Michele and Michele. We want Obama and Michele and we want a child."
Kariuki stressed his group favored family values, adding support for homosexuality is "an attack on the family. Most of the issues that are going on today that have to do with population control are issues that are against the family. Homosexuality, condoms to young children in school, in Genesis 1: 26, 27 and 28, God said that we should be fruitful and multiply."
"So when Obama comes, we are asking him to respect the morals of Kenyans, to respect the faith of Kenyans, he is coming for a commercial visit, let him talk about the conference but he should not talk about gayness because he is a world leader and our young people will start thinking that is a way of life."
Kariuki's Biblical citations refer to God's making of man and woman "in his own image."
The demonstration occurred a day after Kenyan Deputy President William Ruto dismissed any possibility the administration would legalize gay rights, and suggested gay people in Kenya leave to found their own country.
Gay support networks in Kenya note blackmail and extortion of gay people is common, and homosexuality remains unaccepted. Fourteen years imprisonment is a common sentence for those convicted of "acts of gross indecency." Secretly-installed video cameras provide evidence that "they tell you they can send to your wife, they can send it to your employer if you are not going to pay 300,000 Kenyan shillings ($3,200)," said Eric Gitari of the National Gay and Lesbian Human Rights Commission of Kenya.
Prosecution of blackmailers is very rare in Kenya.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:45:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than 80 percent of North Korean defectors are women, says report</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/More-than-80-percent-of-North-Korean-defectors-are-women-says-report/1801436203526/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
More than 80 percent of North Korean defectors are women, says report
Women in North Korea are not subject to the same strict surveillance as North Korean men, and are allowed more freedom of movement.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 6, 2015 at 1:45 PM
Comments
| License Photo
SEOUL, July 6 (UPI) -- North Korean defectors are overwhelmingly women, according to a South Korean government report released Sunday.
The preliminary data from Seoul's Unification Ministry indicated of the 535 North Koreans who sought asylum in South Korea in 2015, 444 were women, South Korean news agency Yonhap reported .
Women in North Korea are not subject to the same strict surveillance in place for North Korean men, according to South Korean newspaper Hankyoreh.
The North Korean state employs men in higher numbers, and a prolonged absence from the workplace is likely to raise a red flag.
While Pyongyang maintains a system that discourages men from fleeing the country, North Korean women who are registered as "housewives" in the country are allowed more freedom.
Women participate in North Korea's unofficial economy at higher rates and the country's gray markets have continued to proliferate as the state looks the other way.
In the absence of scrutiny, North Korean women also cross the China-North Korea border in larger numbers -- an option not available to North Korean men, according to South Korean press.
Once in China, North Korean women sometimes work as household help to earn money that could be then used to hire a broker who could help them make their way to a third country.
The ratio of women defectors to men has been higher since 2002, reaching 70 percent in 2006.
In 2014, North Korean women composed 78 percent of the newly arrived defector population in South Korea.
The number of defectors has fallen steadily since 2011, a year before Kim Jong Un fully assumed power in 2012.
Stricter border controls since Kim took the leadership position were cited as a reason for the reduction in defections.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:14:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Korean same-sex couple to fight for marriage rights</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/South-Korean-same-sex-couple-to-fight-for-marriage-rights/1931436198723/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>South Korean same-sex couple to fight for marriage rights
The couple made the statement ahead of a court hearing regarding their appeal against the marriage ban.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 6, 2015 at 1:14 PM
Comments
SEOUL, July 6 (UPI) -- An openly gay South Korean couple has appealed a government decision to deny legal recognition of their marriage.
The South Korean filmmaker Kim Chokwangsu and his life partner Kim Seung -hwan said they had attempted to file their marriage with a Seoul district office but the registration was denied, Yonhap reported .
The 50-year-old filmmaker said at a press conference on Monday the couple and their attorneys intend to win their case by appealing to the "spirit of the South Korean constitution."
The couple made the statement ahead of a court hearing regarding their appeal against the marriage ban, South Korean newspaper JoongAng Daily reported.
"Today is an important day for our marriage, and an important day for South Korea's sexual minorities," said Kim Chokwangsu.
Kim's life partner Kim Seung-hwan said, "Love between two people is sufficient for the right to love. The law will recognize [our love] for the sake of the happiness of all [South Korean] citizens."
Ryu Min-hee, a human rights lawyer representing the couple, said the denial of same-sex marriage recognition is unlawful according to South Korean civil law.
Ryu said South Korean courts must fix the marriage registration system for same-sex couples.
The filmmaker and his partner tied the knot on Sept. 7, 2013, during a public wedding ceremony where both families and 2,000 observers were in attendance.
Their marriage registration was subsequently denied in December of that year. The Seoul district office refused to recognize the marriage as a civil union.
The couple filed a lawsuit last May.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:00:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Singapore blogger Amos Yee gets one-month sentence</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Singapore-blogger-Amos-Yee-gets-one-month-sentence/8561436200829/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
SINGAPORE, July 6 (UPI) -- A Singapore blogger received a one-month sentence Monday for an obscene picture and disparagement of Christians on the Internet.
Amos Yee, 16, was found guilty in May of presenting a video contravening a Singapore law forbidding the publication of material injurious to religious feelings, as well as a depiction of former British Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher deemed obscene, in posts on YouTube and on his blog. The sentence he received Monday was considered more lenient than expected, and since he already served 50 days in jail, awaiting his sentence, he was allowed to go free after the court proceedings.
The case drew international interest as an early indication of Singapore's strict governance of online speech in the era following the death in March of founding Prime Minister Lee Kuan Yew . Protests in Singapore and Hong Kong demanding Yee's release had drawn as many as 500 people.
The offense against religion could have brought Yee a three-year jail term and a fine; the offense against obscene Internet material has a one-month penalty and a fine.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:45:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Egypt arrests 13 in plot to bomb Suez Canal; drafts anti-terrorism bill against journalists</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Egypt-arrests-13-in-plot-to-bomb-Suez-Canal-drafts-anti-terrorism-bill-against-journalists/3441436199501/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
| License Photo
CAIRO, July 6 (UPI) -- Egypt arrested 13 Muslim Brotherhood members Monday, suspected of installing explosives around the Suez Canal to disrupt shipping.
The canal is the prime maritime shipping route between Asia and Europe and an important source of hard currency for Egypt. Security sources said the group of 13 includes an employee of the Suez Canal authority. Prosecutors contend they planted bombs on beaches adjoining the canal , and in sanitation and electrical facilities along the 120-mile-long route.
The government of Egyptian President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi has cracked down on the Muslim Brotherhood, a group supportive of former President Mohammad Morsi since Morsi was ousted from power in 2013. Egypt regards the Muslim Brotherhood in the same category as the Islamic State and other Islamist militant groups intent on disrupting peace, as well as government policies and functions.
The announcement of the arrests comes the same day the government declared harsh new measures against journalists in a cabinet draft anti-terrorism bill threatening jail terms for journalists who contradict the government line on matters which include contradicting official death tolls when reporting militant attacks.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:18:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi plane accidentally bombs Baghdad, at least 5 die</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Iraqi-plane-accidentally-bombs-Baghdad-at-least-5-die/8011436195214/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
BAGHDAD, July 6 (UPI) -- An Iraqi military plane accidentally bombed civilians in Baghdad's Ni'riya neighborhood Monday, killing at least five.
The plane, a Russian-built Sukhoi fighter plane, was on its way to Al Salam Air Base near Baghdad after completing an airstrike mission against the Islamic State (IS) in western Iraq. A bomb, which was to have been dropped on IS targets, failed to release six times during the bombing run but detached from the plane as it flew over the residential neighborhood, a ministry of defense official said.
"The bomb fell out and destroyed three houses," noted Interior Ministry spokesman Brig. Gen. Saad Maan, adding the unidentified pilot was among the Iraqi Air Force's most qualified.
The Interior Ministry said five were killed , including women and children; Iraq's Health Ministry claimed seven civilians died, and others were injured. Maan said the government immediately organized a committee to investigate the incident.
Iraq is using older fighter planes, such as the Sukhoi, to fight IS, which controls about one-quarter of the country.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:15:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosions in Jos, Nigeria, kill at least 44</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Explosions-in-Jos-Nigeria-kill-at-least-44/5951436190359/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
JOS, Nigeria, July 6 (UPI) -- At least 44 people died in two bomb attacks, believed to have been initiated by the militant Boko Haram, in Jos, Nigeria.
The attacks came Sunday night, shortly after the Ramadan fast ended. A bomb at a crowded restaurant killed 23, and another bomb killed 21 at a mosque, the country's National Emergency Management Agency reported, noting the explosive device at the Shagalinku restaurant was planted, while a suicide bomber entered the crowded mosque . The bombs exploded 15 minutes apart.
The mosque's leader, Shiekh Muhammad Sani Yahya Jingir, is a prominent critic of Boko Haram, the anti-western militant group responsible for numerous attacks in Nigeria in the past three years. He has also been a frequent target of assassination attempts.
Over 200 people have been killed in similar incidents in Nigeria in recent days, including five who died in a church bombing Sunday.
Boko Haram members typically operate in the northeastern part of the country and although Jos, a city of about 900,000 in central Nigeria has been the site of incidents, it has blamed on Boko Haram, in the past. Fifteen people died in an explosion in February and 30 were killed in a blast in Jos in December 2014.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:58:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea requests medical aid from U.N. agencies</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/North-Korea-requests-medical-aid-from-UN-agencies/4171436193400/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
North Korea requests medical aid from U.N. agencies
In addition to water scarcity, food also is in short supply. If dry weather persists in North Korea, rice and corn production is expected to yield 30 to 40 percent less than last season.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 6, 2015 at 10:58 AM
Comments
SEOUL, July 6 (UPI) -- North Korea is seeking U.N. medical assistance as it continues to battle what it says is the "worst drought in 100 years."
Authorities in Pyongyang have requested medication that could help prevent water-borne diseases, South Korean newspaper Chosun Ilbo reported on Sunday.
The request was sent after the U.N.'s Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs, the Food and Agriculture Organization, and the World Health Organization had conducted a survey of conditions in the North Korean province of Hwanghae in June, South Korean news agency Yonhap reported.
In its recent report, the joint team of U.N. investigators said women and children under the age of five were the most vulnerable to water-borne diseases in North Korea.
The international team said North Korea has been affected by a severe drought for the last 18 months, resulting in a lack of drinking water and the deterioration of water quality in the country.
In Hwanghae province, where two different crops are planted annually, barley crop production was forecasted to be 40 to 50 percent less than the previous year.
If dry weather persists in North Korea, rice and corn production is expected to yield 30 to 40 percent less than the last season.
The international team said North Korea had said it does not have the capability to cope with the drought independently  and that U.N. support is needed.
Other agencies involved in the relief effort are UNICEF, Save the Children International and two French aid organizations.
It is estimated 70 percent, or 18 million North Koreans are experiencing some kind of food shortage.
In the area of healthcare, the U.N. said in April 25 percent of North Koreans cannot receive basic vaccines, and 27.9 percent of children under the age of 5 are suffering from chronic malnutrition. A lack of drinking water for 7 million North Koreans also leads to malnutrition and disease.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:48:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama calls for discredit of Islamic State's 'twisted thinking'</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Obama-calls-for-discredit-of-Islamic-States-twisted-thinking/3811436193380/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>1 of 6
| License Photo
WASHINGTON, July 6 (UPI) -- Though there have been some setbacks, U.S. President Barack Obama says he remains committed to the "destruction" of the Islamic State, emphasizing a "larger battle for hearts and minds."
Obama spoke Monday after making a rare visit to the Pentagon to be briefed on the Defense Department's efforts to defeat IS -- also identified as Daesh and by the acronyms ISIS and ISIL.
He said efforts to defeat the terror group shouldn't just be focused on military might. He called for governments and individuals alike to "discredit their ideology, their twisted thinking," which draws extremists to their ranks.
"Ideologies are not defeated by guns, they're defeated by better ideas, a more attractive and much more compelling vision," he said.
Additionally, Obama said it was important to been seen in words and deeds that the United States is not at odds with the Muslim faith.
"This larger battle for hearts and minds is going to be a generational struggle," he said. "It's ultimately not going to be won or lost by the United States alone. It will be decided by the countries and communities that terrorists like ISIL target."
He said the United States, along with a coalition of 60 countries, has caused IS to lose key locations it once held, including the Mosul Damn, Mount Sinjar and Kirkuk in Iraq, as well as Kobani and Tell Abyad in Syria.
Obama said the fight against IS "will not be quick," but the U.S. military has increased its training and support of Iraqi forces. He announced in June that 450 additional U.S. troops would be sent to advise and train Iraqi troops attempting to recapture the city of Ramadi, which fell to IS fighters in May. The arrival of the U.S. soldiers will bring their number in Iraq to 3,550.
"In many places in Syria and Iraq, including urban areas, [IS has] dug in among innocent civilian populations," he said. "It will take time to root them out. Doing so must be the job of local forces on the ground with training and air support from our coalition."
He said there are currently no plans to send any ground troops to fight IS.
"The strong consensus is that in order for us to succeed longterm we have to develop local security forces that can sustain progress," Obama said. "It's not enough for us to simply send in American troops to temporarily setback organizations like ISIL, but then as soon as we leave to see that void filled with extremists.
"If we try to do everything ourselves all across the Middle East, all across north Africa, we'll be playing whack-a-mole."
An anti-IS coalition in Syria, with which the United States is involved, conducted 18 airstrikes in Raqqa, Syria , over the weekend; it also launched 26 airstrikes in Iraq.
The Pentagon visit comes a day prior to Secretary of Defense Ashton Carter's scheduled testimony before the Senate Armed Services Committee on progress in the Middle East. Joint Chiefs of Staff chairman Gen. Martin Dempsey will also testify Tuesday.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:44:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Germany breaks temperature record during European heat wave</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Germany-breaks-temperature-record-during-European-heat-wave/2511436186869/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
BERLIN, July 6 (UPI) -- Germany broke its heat record on Sunday after a 104.5 degree Fahrenheit temperature was documented, the hottest since records began in 1881.
The previous record of 104.3 degrees Fahrenheit was set in 1983 and matched in 2003. The new record was broken in the town of Kitzingen , a town of about 20,000 people located in southern Bavaria.
About 12 people died due to drowning in lakes, ponds, rivers and pools throughout the country in efforts by Germans to keep cool .
Europe has been experiencing a record-breaking heatwave. Britain endured its hottest day in July on Wednesday, causing roads to melt, train schedules to be disrupted and emergency calls to rise.
The official temperature of 98 degrees Fahrenheit broke a record set in 2006, and prompted a Level 3 "heatwave action" to be declared by the Meteorological Office in Britain.
Weather alerts were issued across Western Europe, as Britain, Spain, France, Belgium, the Netherlands, Switzerland and northern Italy expected temperatures to reach temperatures of about 104 degrees Fahrenheit.
Ed Adamczyk contributed to this report.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:26:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran anticipates nuclear deal, readies oil increase</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Iran-anticipates-nuclear-deal-readies-oil-increase/3001436185601/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
| License Photo
VIENNA, July 6 (UPI) -- Iran is ready to double its oil exports as soon as economic sanctions are lifted, Mansour Moazami, the country's deputy oil minister, said.
As Tuesday's deadline for a deal in Vienna between Iran and Western powers nears, one in which Iran would curtail its nuclear program in exchange for a lifting of sanctions, Iran is attempting to persuade the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) to return to an abandoned quota system, Moazami said in an interview. He said Iranian oil production could quickly reach 2.3 million barrels per day, up from present production of 1.2 million per day.
While the boost would bring much-needed revenue to Iran, which has the fourth-largest oil reserves on earth and a production capability of four million barrels per day, it would run counter to regional rival Saudi Arabia's attempt to raise its own oil exports. Saudi Arabia opposes a return to limits on OPEC members' production of oil.
If production was unrestricted, Iran could be OPEC's second-largest oil producer, behind Saudi Arabia, and Iran is eager to accelerate all phases of its economy a soon as sanctions are lifted. An agreement emerging from the negotiations, which are currently in their 21st month, still requires the consent of the U.S. Senate and the Iranian government.
"We are like a pilot on the runway, ready to take off. This is how the country is, right now," Moazami said.
Quickly increasing oil exports is problematic, analysts suggest. An increase as envisioned by Iran could take six to 12 months.
"They've got to meet the requirements of any agreement, and that's going to take time," Jeff Currie, head of commodities research at Goldman Sachs Group, told the Middle East North Africa Financial Network Monday. "When you shut these fields in to that significant of a degree, your ability to bring back production to previous levels will be limited because you've done damage to the fields that will require significant investment."
Foreign oil producers will be unlikely to jump back into major production schedules until the legal implications of a deal are evident, Harry Tchilingurian of BNP Paribas SA said. He added Iran could eventually add one million barrels per day to the world's totals.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:09:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kim Jong Un had terrapin farm manager executed, says source</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Kim-Jong-Un-had-terrapin-farm-manager-executed-says-source/3151436190404/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home / Top News / World News
Kim Jong Un had terrapin farm manager executed, says source
Kim Jong Un had ordered the execution to make an example of the manager  and to reinforce North Koreas politics of fear.
By Elizabeth Shim | July 6, 2015 at 10:09 AM
Comments
SEOUL, July 6 (UPI) -- Kim Jong Un may have executed the manager of a terrapin farm the North Korean leader visited in May, according to a source in Pyongyang.
The terrapin farm had made headlines after May 19, when Kim expressed his displeasure regarding its operation. South Korean news outlet Daily NK reported Kim might have executed the farm manager for not supplying sufficient water to aquarium tanks.
According to the news source, Kim Jong Un ordered the execution of the manager after providing field guidance at the Taedonggang terrapin farm.
"Food and water for the turtles were not being supplied sufficiently, that was the reason for execution by gun," the source said.
South Korean news outlet Newsis reported North Korea's charges of incompetence ignored the real reason for the supply issues.
Power outages were common at the farm, said the source, and the farm was not provided with adequate amounts of food for the turtles.
Kim Jong Un had ordered the execution to make an example of the manager  and to reinforce North Korea's politics of fear, according to South Korea press.
During his visit in May, Kim reportedly reprimanded the farm's management and said the managers were ruining the North Korean leader's mission and the farm could not resume normal production levels.
"Ten million loyal citizens and military personnel are tirelessly preparing gifts for the 70th anniversary of the Korean Workers' Party, by night and by day. I don't know what this farm is planning for the celebrations in October," Kim had said.
Daily NK's source said the execution of the manager follows an ongoing trend in North Korea.
Subordinates at the turtle farm who wished to display their ultimate loyalty to Kim might have facilitated the death of the manager, said the source.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:45:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China issues travel warning in Turkey after protests</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/China-issues-travel-warning-in-Turkey-after-protests/5191436188611/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
ANKARA, Turkey, July 6 (UPI) -- China's embassy in Ankara, Turkey, issued a travel warning Monday, claiming some Chinese tourists were attacked during protests in Turkey.
Anti-Chinese demonstrations in Istanbul over the weekend focused on alleged mistreatment of ethnic Uighurs in western China. Protesters were seen chasing a group of Korean tourists whom they mistook as Chinese, the Turkish-owned "Happy China" restaurant was attacked and Chinese flags were burned.
A diplomatic note was sent last week by Turkey to China, expressing concern that Uighurs, a Muslim minority within China, were forbidden from fasting during the holy month of Ramadan.
Beijing denied that any restrictions were placed on Uighur religious practices.
Turkey has close ties with the Uighur population, in religious, ethnic and cultural connections.
In a statement, the Chinese embassy advised Chinese tourists in Turkey to avoid traveling alone, or to photograph protesters. Ethnic tensions in western China have increased with the arrival of majority Han Chinese in western China, particularly in the provincial capital of Xinjiang, and increased complaints by indigenous Uighurs they face discrimination and persecution.
Last week Chinese state media accused Turkey of fermenting tension in China.
"The Turkish government has already on multiple occasions unreasonably interfered in Chinese internal politics, which indicates 'Pan-Turkism' still exists in modern Turkish society. We can see that Turkey has ulterior motives regarding interference in the Xinjiang issue," Xinjiang University professor Adilijan Ablet in a state-run newspaper.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:01:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Civilians killed in Yemen airstrikes as U.N. works for Ramadan cease-fire</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Civilians-killed-in-Yemen-airstrikes-as-UN-works-for-Ramadan-cease-fire/3381436183801/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
| License Photo
ADEN, Yemen, July 6 (UPI) -- Between eight to 30 civilians were killed in airstrikes conducted by the coalition led by Saudi Arabia in Aden, Yemen, as the United Nations hopes to broker a cease-fire.
The battle between the Saudi-led coalition and the Houthi rebels began in March. About 21.1 million people, more than 80 percent of the Yemen's population, needs humanitarian assistance .
More than 160 health care centers have been forced to close, affecting thousands, 13 million people are struck with a food security crisis and 9.4 million have no access to water, according to the United Nations.
The U.N. is hoping to implement a potential cease-fire between the warring factions until the end of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, July 17, which will allow for humanitarian aid to be delivered. War has continued even as international actors are hoping for a truce in the conflict.
"We are intensifying our efforts to reach a peaceful resolution to this crisis that, in truth, as you know, has resulted in a humanitarian catastrophe for the Yemeni people," U.N. envoy Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed said Sunday after arriving in Sana'a, Yemen's capital.
"We were optimistic, but the central issue that we are focusing on is a long-term peaceful resolution and to bring back the issues to the negotiating table so the Yemeni people can return to a peaceful political process," he added.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 13:53:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Euclid Tsakalotos becomes Greece's new finance minister; deal remains elusive</title>
        <Link>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2015/07/06/Euclid-Tsakalotos-becomes-Greeces-new-finance-minister-deal-remains-elusive/3971436177383/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments
1 of 5
ATHENS, Greece, July 6 (UPI) -- Oxford-educated economist Euclid Tsakalotos is set to become the new minister of finance for Greece but the prospect of a potential deal remains complicated.
Former Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis resigned Monday shortly after helping lead a historic financial referendum that rejected bailout demands from international creditors.
Varoufakis said he resigned because many creditors did not want him present during further negotiations and as to continue his support for Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras.
In response to the referendum , European Commission Vice President Valdis Dombrovsk said the vote of "no" is "neither legally nor factually correct," also adding that the Commission will not negotiate with the Greek government until it receives a mandate from the Eurozone's finance ministers who meet tomorrow.
In the referendum, the Greek people were asked if they accepted the terms of an international bailout submitted by the European Commission, the International Monetary Fund and the European Central Bank.
The IMF is prepared to respond as needed following the Greek referendum.
"The IMF has taken note of yesterday's referendum held in Greece. We are monitoring the situation closely and stand ready to assist Greece if requested to do so," Christine Lagarde , head of the IMF, said in a statement.
With a voter turnout of 63 percent, 61 percent of those voters cast "OXI" or "No" ballots, effectively rejected the creditors' terms.
"The referendum of July 5th will stay in history as a unique moment when a small European nation rose up against debt-bondage," Varoufakis said on his blog . "Soon after the announcement of the referendum results, I was made aware of a certain preference by some Eurogroup participants, and assorted 'partners,' for my... 'absence' from its meetings; an idea that the prime minister judged to be potentially helpful to him in reaching an agreement. For this reason I am leaving the ministry of finance today."
Varoufakis is considered by many to be outspoken, combative and quarrelsome. He's often clashed with creditors during and outside negotiations .
"I shall wear the creditors' loathing with pride," he said, adding that he will support the new finance minister and Tsipras' leftist, anti-establishment Syriza government.
Needing to pay a $1.7 billion payment to the International Monetary Fund by the end of June, but not having the cash to do so, Athens engaged in numerous negotiations over the last four months -- hoping to strike a deal to unlock the remainder of $7 billion in relief cash previously granted by the organization.
However, demands by creditors for Athens to cut government spending in exchange for the relief aid proved to be the deal breaker.
Tsipras repeatedly rejected the offers, saying the cuts would affect Greek workers' wages and state-funded pensions.
Greece has a public debt of $361 billion from previous loans keeping the country afloat for the past five years. On June 30, Greece became the first developed nation in history to default on a loan from the IMF.
Like Us on Facebook for more stories from UPI.com
Related UPI Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
