<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="USATODAY">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:35:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than 500 injured in fire at Taiwan water park</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98170296/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~More-than-injured-in-fire-at-Taiwan-water-park/</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of spectators had gathered in front of the stage at the "Color Play Asia" event at the Formosa Water Park.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
More than 500 injured in fire at Taiwan water park
More than 500 people were injured at a water park in Taiwan, after a colored powder that was sprayed from a music stage onto party-goers ignited, authorities said Sunday.
Post to Facebook
More than 500 injured in fire at Taiwan water park More than 500 people were injured at a water park in Taiwan, after a colored powder that was sprayed from a music stage onto party-goers ignited, authorities said Sunday. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Il0Nmz
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
18
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
More than 500 injured in fire at Taiwan water park
Jane Onyanga-Omara , USA TODAY 9:35 a.m. EDT June 28, 2015
A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200 people, authorities said. ( June 27)
People carry an injured man at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in the Pali district of New Taipei City on June 27, 2015.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
603 CONNECT 250 TWEET 4 LINKEDIN 18 COMMENTEMAILMORE
More than 500 people were injured at a water park in Taiwan, after a colored powder that was sprayed from a music stage onto party-goers ignited, authorities said Sunday.
Around 1,000 spectators had gathered in front of the stage at the "Color Play Asia"  event at the Formosa Water Park, just outside the capital of Taipei on Saturday night, local media reported.
The powder ignited along the ground and mainly burned people's lower bodies, Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command center, told the Associated Press. He said 516 people were reported to have burn injuries by Sunday morning.
Official Chinese news agency Xinhua reported that 194 people were seriously injured but no deaths have been reported, according to the New Taipei City health bureau. Taiwan's Central News Agency reported that eight people had life-threatening injuries.
Fire injures scores at Taiwan water park party
The health department said most of the victims suffered over 50% burns, and inhaled large amounts of black carbon dust, Xinhua reported. The injured have been sent to a number of hospitals.
Lee Lih-jong, deputy chief of the health bureau, told Agence France-Presse: "The reason why the burns were so severe was that in addition to burns to the skin, there were also injuries caused by burns to the respiratory organs from the large amount of color powder inhaled. The next 24 hours will be critical for those severely injured."
The incident is the worst mass injury in New Taipei City's history, Xinhua said.
Taiwan Premier Mao Chih-kuo visited some of the injured people and announced a ban on such parties unless their safety can be assured, AFP reported.
Central News Agency said that police were questioning two park workers who launched the powder as well as the party's on-site organizer and two technicians, according to the AP. They may face charges of professional negligence causing serious injuries and endangering the public.
An investigation into the exact cause of the fire is still underway.
Taiwanese President Ma Ying-jeou shakes hands with a victim injured in an accidental explosion during a music concert, as he visits a local hospital in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Sunday, June 28, 2015.
(Photo: Uncredited, AP)
Life guards carry a young woman suffering from facial burns to an ambulance at the Formosa Fun Coast park in the Bali District of New Taipei City, northern Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
(Photo: Stringer, EPA)
Taiwanese carry young man suffering from burns to an ambulance while a man looks after another injured at the Formosa Fun Coast park in the Bali District of New Taipei City, northern Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
(Photo: Stringer, EPA)
Police investigators inspect the stage area after an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, early Sunday, June 28, 2015.
(Photo: AP)
Local investigators arrive at the water park in Pali district, in New Taipei City, on June 28, 2015.
(Photo: Sam Yeh, AFP/Getty Images)
In this screen grab taken from ETTV, an injured concert spectator is treated after an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Saturday, June 27, 2015.
(Photo: AP)
A man carries an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Saturday, June 27, 2015.
(Photo: Central News Agency, AP)
Injured victims from an explosion during a music concert are tended to at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Saturday, June 27, 2015.
(Photo: STR, AP)
A police officer walks past debris at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in the Pali district of New Taipei City early June 28, 2015.
(Photo: SAM YEH, AFP/Getty Images)
Injured victims are treated after an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Saturday, June 27, 2015.
(Photo: Central News Agency, AP)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:32:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taiwan water park fire leaves more than 500 injured</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98208958/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Taiwan-water-park-fire-leaves-more-than-injured/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Taiwan water park fire leaves more than 500 injured
Taiwanese President Ma Ying-jeou shakes hands with a victim injured in an accidental explosion during a music concert, as he visits a local hospital in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Sunday, June 28, 2015.
Post to Facebook
Taiwan water park fire leaves more than 500 injured Taiwanese President Ma Ying-jeou shakes hands with a victim injured in an accidental explosion during a music concert, as he visits a local hospital in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Sunday, June 28, 2015. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IlqHXj
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Taiwan water park fire leaves more than 500 injured
Taiwanese President Ma Ying-jeou shakes hands with a victim injured in an accidental explosion during a music concert, as he visits a local hospital in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Sunday, June 28, 2015.
Uncredited, AP
Life guards carry a young woman suffering from facial burns to an ambulance at the Formosa Fun Coast park in the Bali District of New Taipei City, northern Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Stringer, EPA
Taiwanese carry young man suffering from burns to an ambulance while a man looks after another injured at the Formosa Fun Coast park in the Bali District of New Taipei City, northern Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Stringer, EPA
Police investigators inspect the stage area after an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, early Sunday, June 28, 2015.
AP
Local investigators arrive at the water park in Pali district, in New Taipei City, on June 28, 2015.
Sam Yeh, AFP/Getty Images
In this screen grab taken from ETTV, an injured concert spectator is treated after an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Saturday, June 27, 2015.
AP
A man carries an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Saturday, June 27, 2015.
Central News Agency, AP
Injured victims from an explosion during a music concert are tended to at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Saturday, June 27, 2015.
STR, AP
A police officer walks past debris at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in the Pali district of New Taipei City early June 28, 2015.
SAM YEH, AFP/Getty Images
Injured victims are treated after an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Saturday, June 27, 2015.
Central News Agency, AP
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:02:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saving schools by seating older people next to kids (OZY)</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98199042/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Saving-schools-by-seating-older-people-next-to-kids-OZY</Link>
        <Description>How do seniors in Italy save schools? Some join kids in the classroom.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saving Schools  by Seating Old People Next to Kids
By Silvia Marchetti
Sign Up For Ozy Emails
email address
Hey, it looks like you're on our list already!
Please check that the information you have provided is correct.
Sign Up
Thank you
For signing up to Ozy
In Bassiano, a tiny mountain village with 1,678 residents just south of Rome, Valentina and Latino Lorenzi sit side by side in the towns one and only school. But these unlikely desk-mates arent siblings or even cousins. Valentina, whos 12 years old, better knows Latino, 83, as Grandpa. Ill teach him how to use an iPad and stuff like that, says Valentina.
Renowned for its premium ham, Bassiano is now becoming known in Italy for an odd experiment being carried out by its mayor, Domenico Guidi. To avoid shutting the school down because there werent enough students, Guidi enrolled 47 enthusiastic pensioners who didnt have a chance to study earlier in their lives; he succeeded in raising the total number of pupils to 164. We have bitterly fought to keep our school open, and were so glad to have found a solution, says Alessandro Colandrea, the father of another student, Valeria, who says she looks forward to learning about her grandparents experiences during the war.
Italian law calls for compulsory education until the age of 18, though theres no rule that limits the age for returning to school.
The mayors crusade comes as a result of Italys prolonged recession, which has pushed the central government to boost austerity by curbing spending and, among other acts, closing village schools. In the last three years alone, more than 235 mountain schools have been shut down, according to ANIEF, Italys lobby for schoolteachers. Many other schools  some located on islands, where there are often just one or two kids  are also at risk of closure. Other mayors, including those in regions such as Sicily and Marche, are planning to mix youngsters and seniors in the same classrooms should the need arise.
Part of the reason this is an issue in Italy in the first place is that more and more people are moving to larger cities and towns in search of a better, easier life or to study at high school and university. In the last 15 years, the countrys small towns have lost more than 90 percent of their population  a trend thats on the rise. All told, there are around 6,000 ghost villages that have been abandoned due to mass emigration as well as natural calamities, according to the Polytechnic University of Milan, while another 15,000 are slowly dying out.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:46:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait authorities identify mosque suicide bomber</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98197298/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Kuwait-authorities-identify-mosque-suicide-bomber/</Link>
        <Description>The country's Ministry of Interior named the bomber as Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Gabbaa.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Kuwait authorities identify mosque suicide bomber
A Saudi citizen has been identified as the suicide bomber behind an attack on a Shiite mosque in Kuwait on Friday that killed 27 people and injured 227, authorities said Sunday.
Post to Facebook
Kuwait authorities identify mosque suicide bomber A Saudi citizen has been identified as the suicide bomber behind an attack on a Shiite mosque in Kuwait on Friday that killed 27 people and injured 227, authorities said Sunday. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1NpWMww
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
6
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Kuwait authorities identify mosque suicide bomber
Jane Onyanga-Omara , USA TODAY 8:46 a.m. EDT June 28, 2015
This undated photo released by Kuwait News Agency, KUNA, shows Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Gabbaa. Kuwaiti authorities on Sunday identified al-Gabbaa as a Saudi citizen who flew into the Gulf nation just hours before he blew himself in an attack on one of Kuwait's oldest Shiite mosques during midday Friday prayers.
(Photo: uncredited, AP)
22 CONNECT 155 TWEET 4 LINKEDIN 6 COMMENTEMAILMORE
A Saudi citizen has been identified as the suicide bomber behind an attack on a Shiite mosque in Kuwait on Friday that killed 27 people and injured 227, authorities said Sunday.
In a statement carried by the official Kuwait News Agency (KUNA), the country's Ministry of Interior named the bomber as Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Gabbaa, who was born in 1992.
It said he arrived on a flight to Kuwait International Airport at dawn Friday, hours before carrying out the attack after Friday prayers at the Imam Al-Sadiq Mosque in the country's capital.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How the "law" of war lets Islamic State slavery thrive: Column</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98194630/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~How-the-law-of-war-lets-Islamic-State-slavery-thrive-Column/</Link>
        <Description>The Islamic State uses concerns for civilian casualties to slaughter civilians.</Description>
        <MainBody>How the "law" of war lets Islamic State slavery thrive: Column
The more we care about civilian casualties, the longer savages can keep slaughtering civilians.
Post to Facebook
How the "law" of war lets Islamic State slavery thrive: Column The more we care about civilian casualties, the longer savages can keep slaughtering civilians. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Ilisur
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
How the "law" of war lets Islamic State slavery thrive: Column
James S. Robbins 7:02 a.m. EDT June 28, 2015
The more we care about civilian casualties, the longer savages can keep slaughtering civilians.
Smoke rises after an airstrike by the U.S.-led coalition on Islamic State group positions in Ramadi, May 2015.
(Photo: AP)
10 CONNECT 21 TWEET LINKEDIN 1 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Islamic State troops parade safely through Ramadi in broad daylight, flags waving, with no U.S. aircraft in sight. American intelligence agencies identify the Islamic State's main headquarters buildings in Raqqa, but they remain untouched .
These seem like natural targets in the continuing American air campaign against the Islamic State. However in both cases they were in built-up, densely populated areas. Even the most precise attacks could not be conducted without the possibility of causing civilian casualties, which runs afoul of restrictive U.S. rules of engagement . The enemy knows this, and has turned entire city populations into collective human shields.
The Obama administration's air-only strategy is helpless against this kind of countermeasure. Western countries have voluntarily raised the bar of the laws of armed conflict so high that even precision attacks on legitimate military targets invite the wrath of international investigators .
Leave no interpreter behind: Column
Israel is learning that even war conducted with the best intentions does not go unpunished. On Monday, the United Nations Human Rights Council released a report on the conduct of Operation Protective Edge, the six-week conflict in Gaza that took place last summer.
Israel used the same kind of precision aerial bombing that has been the mainstay of the U.S. effort against the Islamic State. However the U.N. alleges that "regardless how precise the bomb is," civilians might still be inadvertently killed. Therefore, "attacks, which used this type of weapon in densely populated, built up areas of Gaza, are likely to constitute a violation of the prohibition of indiscriminate attacks." The only way for a pilot to avoid accidentally committing a war crime under this extremely high standard is to call off any attack in which civilians are even suspected of being in the blast area. According to Yoav Kisch , an Israeli Air Force pilot and member of the Knesset, this is exactly what they did.
Mike Huckabee: Fight gay marriage judicial tyranny
In other cases Israel attempted to prevent civilian casualties by "roof knocking," dropping nonlethal munitions on residential buildings being used by Hamas to warn civilians and terrorists alike that a counter-strike was coming. But the U.N. slammed even this level of concern for the lives of noncombatants because it was not 100% effective. Some people did not understand the knock, some on lower floors of tall buildings may not have heard it, others thought they heard knocks where there were none, and so forth. Yet the U.N. did not criticize Hamas for turning private residences into military targets in the first place. And when has a suicide bus bomber ever prompted passengers to get off at the stop before their attack?
A study of the 2014 Gaza war by senior retired U.S. military officers and academics commissioned by the Jewish Institute for National Security Affairs noted that Hamas intentionally placed civilians in jeopardy as a tactical enabler, knowing that either Israel would call off attacks or bear the blame for any innocents caught in the crossfire. The report concluded that Hamas "weaponized" the law of armed conflict, exploiting Israel's concern for noncombatants to their advantage, knowing they would never be held to account. Hamas was right  the U.N. report noted that "little information was available to the commission" regarding Hamas' "alleged serious violations of international humanitarian and gross violations of international human rights law."  Little information was available because Hamas chose not to provide it.
The Islamic State, by contrast, proudly loads evidence of its barbarities onto Youtube. In March, the UNHRC released a report charging ISIL with genocide, torture and other systematic violations of human rights, including "enslavement, selling of women and girls, rape, forced transfer, and other inhuman and degrading treatment." These crimes will continue so long as there are innocents available to victimize.
It raises the question whether the Coalition's kid-gloves approach to airstrikes is simply another enabler for ISIL atrocities. The theoretical standard of zero civilian casualties in an airstrike is unrealistic and unattainable. The real balancing test should be between the remote possibility of noncombatants being killed by the United States by accident, or innocents being beheaded by the Islamic State on purpose.
James S. Robbins writes weekly for USA TODAY and is the author of The Real Custer: From Boy General to Tragic Hero .
In addition to its own editorials, USA TODAY publishes diverse opinions from outside writers, including our Board of Contributors .To read more columns like this, go to the Opinion front page .
10 CONNECT 21 TWEET LINKEDIN 1 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1Ilisur
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:52:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98194370/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Bus-carrying-British-schoolchildren-crashes-in-Belgium/</Link>
        <Description>Belgian media said the person killed was an adult accompanying the children and the driver was also reportedly hurt.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium
BRUSSELS (AP)  A bus carrying British schoolchildren has gone off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast.
Post to Facebook
Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium BRUSSELS (AP)  A bus carrying British schoolchildren has gone off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1NpPSY1
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium
Associated Press 7:52 a.m. EDT June 28, 2015
Rescue teams and firefighters at the scene of a bus crash on the E40 highway in Middelkerke, Belgium, June 28, 2015.
(Photo: Oliver Hoslet, EPA)
7 CONNECT 110 TWEET 3 LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
BRUSSELS (AP)  A bus carrying British schoolchildren has gone off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast.
The mayor of Middelkerke, Janna Rommel-Opstaele, said one person was killed in the Sunday morning accident on the E-40 highway. The mayor said all of the children survived.
Belgian media said the person killed was an adult accompanying the children and the driver was also reportedly hurt.
Belgian highway authorities said the vehicle apparently went out of control, struck the pillar of a bridge, then shot off the road.
The Flemish broadcasting company VTM said the bus had been carrying 34 children and six adults. Some of the children were taken to Middelkerke to be treated for minor injuries.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1NpPSY1
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:05:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Despite money laundering scandals, Switzerland slow to change</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98191202/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Despite-money-laundering-scandals-Switzerland-slow-to-change/</Link>
        <Description>The nation has long been known as a haven for hiding money.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Despite money laundering scandals, Switzerland slow to change
The FIFA corruption scandal is prompting fresh efforts to stem money laundering in Switzerland, but whether the changes can actually take hold in a nation long seen as a haven for dirty money remains to be seen.
Post to Facebook
Despite money laundering scandals, Switzerland slow to change The FIFA corruption scandal is prompting fresh efforts to stem money laundering in Switzerland, but whether the changes can actually take hold in a nation long seen as a haven for dirty money remains to be seen. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Ilfx51
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Despite money laundering scandals, Switzerland slow to change
Helena Bachmann, Special for USA TODAY 6:05 a.m. EDT June 28, 2015
People walk in front of the FIFA headquarters in Zurich, Switzerland, on May 27, 2015.
(Photo: Ennio Leanza, AP)
16 CONNECT 160 TWEET 4 LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
GENEVA  The FIFA corruption scandal is prompting fresh moves to stem money laundering in Switzerland, but the nation long known as a haven for hiding money may be slow to change.
The Swiss government announced new measures this month  following the investigation of soccer's governing body to tighten control over real estate transactions, the commodities industry, foundations and free ports  areas at high risk for laundering schemes that aren't covered under current law.
Even with improved oversight, scrubbing the nation of all financial corruption is likely to prove difficult. "We still have a long way to go before we can control financial flows," said Jean-Pierre Man, president of the Swiss chapter of Transparency International.
As the U.S. and Swiss inquiry into corruption charges at the world soccer's governing body continues, investigators here are looking into 53 counts of possible money laundering and 104 suspicious bank transactions linked to FIFA's bidding contests for the 2018 and 2022 World Cup.
A new law that goes into effect next year will allow top executives of sporting federations  like those arrested in the FIFA case  to be designated as "politically exposed persons," subjecting them to greater financial scrutiny.  FIFA and 60 other international sports organizations headquartered in Switzerland are currently exempt from anti-corruption laws.
Lax Swiss laws led to less scrutiny of FIFA
If past experience is any indication, however, the changes may fall short because financial institutions here have been known to turn a blind eye to rules and regulations. Even though Switzerland has had anti-money laundering legislation since 1997, tens of millions of dollars in illicit assets have trickled into Swiss banks in recent years.
An investigation this year into money laundering at an HSBC branch in Geneva revealed the bank knowingly broke the law and accepted illegal funds from arms dealers and blood diamond traders.
Other recent money-laundering cases include undeclared millions stashed in an account belonging to Luis Barcenas, a Spanish politician implicated in a corruption scandal, as well as money placed by Malaysian official Abdul Taib Mahmud, which authorities traced back to criminal activities.
Illegal assets still find their way into Switzerland because financial institutions are willing to look the other way.  "The banks can get away with being negligent and give in to business interests to the detriment of compliance," Gretta Fenner, managing director of Switzerland's Basel Institute for Governance told Swiss Broadcasting Corporation.
The government itself conceded in a June report that the country's banks, which house around $2.1 trillion, or 34%, of offshore wealth, "are not immune to fraud, embezzlement, corruption" and other crimes mostly committed abroad.
"This is astonishing, because Switzerland has been struggling for years to get rid of the stigma as a money-laundering haven," says Mark Pieth, an anti-corruption adviser to the World Bank and a criminal law professor at the University of Bern.
Fenner said the way to stave off money-laundering attempts is obvious: "We've got to start enforcing (the laws) we have. I don't think we are doing enough of that in Switzerland."
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1Ilfx51
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:15:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japan mourns passing of 'goddess' stationmaster cat</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98187904/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Japan-mourns-passing-of-goddess-stationmaster-cat/</Link>
        <Description>The calico cat was appointed stationmaster at the Kishi station in western Japan in 2007.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Japan mourns passing of 'goddess' stationmaster cat
TOKYO (AP)  Tama the stationmaster, Japan's feline star of a struggling local railway, was mourned by company officials and fans and elevated into a goddess at a funeral Sunday. The calico cat was appointed
Post to Facebook
Japan mourns passing of 'goddess' stationmaster cat TOKYO (AP)  Tama the stationmaster, Japan's feline star of a struggling local railway, was mourned by company officials and fans and elevated into a goddess at a funeral Sunday. The calico cat was appointed Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1NpAzic
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
5
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Japan mourns passing of 'goddess' stationmaster cat
Associated Press 5:15 a.m. EDT June 28, 2015
In this April 29, 2015 photo, Tama, a cat stationmaster, Japans feline star of a struggling local railway, receives a birthday cake on her 16th birthday in Kinokawa, Wakayama Prefecture, western Japan.
(Photo: AP)
836 CONNECT 141 TWEET 2 LINKEDIN 5 COMMENTEMAILMORE
TOKYO (AP)  Tama the stationmaster, Japan's feline star of a struggling local railway, was mourned by company officials and fans and elevated into a goddess at a funeral Sunday.
The calico cat was appointed stationmaster at the Kishi station in western Japan in 2007. In her custom-made stationmaster's cap and a jacket, Tama quietly sat at the ticket gate welcoming and seeing off passengers. The cat quickly attracted tourists and became world-famous, contributing to the railway company and local economy.
Tama died of a heart failure on June 22. During Sunday's Shinto-style funeral at the station where she served, Tama became a goddess. The Shinto religion has a variety of gods, including animals.
Wakayama Electric Railway President Mitsunobu Kojima thanked the cat for her achievement, and said Tama will be enshrined at a nearby cat shrine next month.
Before Tama's arrival, the local Kishigawa Line was near-bankrupt; and the station was unmanned as it had lost its last staff.
Kojima said appointing Tama as stationmaster was initially an excuse to keep the cat at the station.
"But she was really doing her job," he said. The rest was a miracle, and his company's success story also gave hope for dozens of other struggling tiny local train lines, he said.
"Tama-chan really emerged like a savior, a goddess. It was truly my honor to have been able to work with her," Kojima said in his speech.
During her tenure, Tama had contributed an estimated 1.1 billion yen ($8.9 million) to the local economy, Kojima said.
Kojima said that when he visited Tama at an animal hospital the day before she died, the cat woke up and reached out to him with her paws, as if asking for a hug, and looked straight into his eyes. He said he told Tama to get well so they can celebrate the cat's upcoming 10th anniversary as a stationmaster, and said the cat responded with a "meow."
Tama had climbed the corporate ladder from stationmaster to "ultra-stationmaster" and vice president of the company before receiving the additional title Sunday of "honorable eternal stationmaster."
She will be succeeded by another calico cat, Nitama, now an apprentice stationmaster.
836 CONNECT 141 TWEET 2 LINKEDIN 5 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1NpAzic
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:32:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S., Iranian negotiators pledge to work hard on nuclear deal</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98123218/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~US-Iranian-negotiators-pledge-to-work-hard-on-nuclear-deal/</Link>
        <Description>Negotiators face a self-imposed Tuesday deadline.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
U.S., Iranian negotiators pledge to work hard on nuclear deal
Secretary of State John Kerry and Iranian Foreign Minister Javad Zarif met Saturday in Vienna, Austria, to seek a deal on Iran's nuclear program but were noncommittal about the prospects of success before a Tuesday deadline.
Post to Facebook
U.S., Iranian negotiators pledge to work hard on nuclear deal Secretary of State John Kerry and Iranian Foreign Minister Javad Zarif met Saturday in Vienna, Austria, to seek a deal on Iran's nuclear program but were noncommittal about the prospects of success before a Tuesday deadline. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IkhOx4
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
8
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
U.S., Iranian negotiators pledge to work hard on nuclear deal
Oren Dorell , USA TODAY 4:32 p.m. EDT June 27, 2015
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry, left, talks to reporters alongside U.S. Under Secretary for Political Affairs Wendy Sherman as they meet with the Iranian delegation  in Vienna, Austria, Saturday, June 27, 2015.
(Photo: Carlos Barria, AP)
14 CONNECT 57 TWEET LINKEDIN 8 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Secretary of State John Kerry and Iranian Foreign Minister Javad Zarif met Saturday in Vienna, Austria, to seek a deal on Iran's nuclear program but were noncommittal about the prospects of success before a Tuesday deadline.
"I think it's fair to say that we're hopeful.  We have a lot of hard work to do," Kerry said.
Zarif said: "I agree maybe not on the issues, but on the fact that we need to work really hard in order to be able to make progress and move forward."
An agreement to limit Iran's nuclear program, in exchange for lifting international sanctions, is being negotiated with Tehran by the five permanent members of the United Nations Security Council  the United States, United Kingdom, France, Russia and China  plus Germany. Negotiators face a self-imposed Tuesday deadline.
Legislation passed by Congress gives it 30 days to review a deal reached by July 9. However, if the talks run longer, Congress would have a 60-day review period, providing opponents more time to reject an agreement.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:47:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tourists flee as chilling details emerge in Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98065528/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Tourists-flee-as-chilling-details-emerge-in-Tunisia/</Link>
        <Description>The second terror attack this year could cripple Tunisia's tourism industry.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Tourists flee as chilling details emerge in Tunisia
Stories of terror and bravery emerged Saturday as foreign visitors rushed to leave Tunisia by the busload after a gunman opened fire on a beach resort, killing 38 people.
Post to Facebook
Tourists flee as chilling details emerge in Tunisia Stories of terror and bravery emerged Saturday as foreign visitors rushed to leave Tunisia by the busload after a gunman opened fire on a beach resort, killing 38 people. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Ijr5Wn
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
107
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Tourists flee as chilling details emerge in Tunisia
Oren Dorell , USA TODAY 3:47 p.m. EDT June 27, 2015
Dozens of people, mostly tourists, were killed when a lone gunman stormed a resort in Tunisia and opened fire. He was shot dead by security forces. Wochit
The morning after a lone gunman killed dozens of people at a beach resort in Sousse, Tunisia, busloads of tourists are evacuating to their home countries.
(Photo: Darko Vojinovic, AP)
432 CONNECT 544 TWEET 5 LINKEDIN 107 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Stories of terror and bravery emerged Saturday as foreign visitors rushed to leave Tunisia by the busload after a gunman opened fire on a beach resort, killing 38 people.
At least 39 people were wounded in the nation's deadliest onslaught Friday before the shooter was killed by security forces. The gunman was identified as Seifeddine Rezgui, 24, by Tunisian Prime Minister Habib Essid.
"The fight against terrorism is a national responsibility," Essid said Saturday as his government announced a raft of new measures to right terrorism. "We are at war against terrorism which represents a serious danger to national unity during this delicate period that the nation is going through."
Tunisia pledges tougher security measures after attack
Busloads of tourists were cutting their vacations short Saturday and making their way to the Enfidha-Hammamet airport with the hope of returning home, the Associated Press reported. Britain announced at least 15 of its citizens were among the dead and said that toll could rise.
Among the Britons killed in the attack were Carly Lovett, a fashion photographer, and Lorna Carty, a mother of two, according to The Daily Express of London.
Among the injured was gas engineer Matthew James, 30, who was shot in the shoulder, chest and hip as he acted as a human shield to save his fiancee, Sarah Wilson, the paper said.
"He took a bullet for me. I owe him my life because he threw himself in front of me when the shooting started," Wilson, 26, told the paper from the hospital in Tunisia where James was recovering from surgery.
Briton Tom Richards, 22, who was at the hotel with his mother, Sam, and his brother, Calum, 16, told the British newspaper The Guardian he came face to face with the shooter, but escaped with only minor injuries.
Tom and Sam Richards were at the pool when they heard gunfire at the beach and ran for cover inside the hotel. Tunisian staff ushered them to an upper floor, where they huddled with about 20 other confused and frightened guests, he said. But the gunman followed the same route on his rampage.
"He shot two people, through the head," as they were standing on the stairs, Richards said.
Then he pointed his gun at Richards. "He looked right at me, I thought I was dead... He had long black hair and a beard," he said.
But when the man fired, he fired at the ground, wounding Richards, his mother and others in the area with shards of marble. Richards told the paper he and his mother hid in a nearby bathroom, where he bandaged wounds to his wrist and her ankle with toilet paper.
Outside the bathroom, they heard more shooting and people screaming that they were wounded, "but we couldn't step out to see," Richards said. He did help a young woman who had a large shard of marble embedded in her thigh, and together the three waited until security officials arrived and told them they were safe.
The Islamic State claimed responsibility for the attack, according to SITE Intelligence Group, a U.S.-based organization that monitors terrorists' activity online.
Rezgui  whom the Islamic State called by his jihadi pseudonym, Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani  was radicalized at mosques in Kairouan, where he earned his degree in electronics and enrolled in a master's program at a local sciences and technology university, Radio Mosaique reported. Kairouan is located about 40 miles west of Sousse.
Rezgui was not known to authorities before the attack, Essid said. He was from a village in a poor central region of Tunisia and had never traveled abroad, local media reported. Rezgui's parents were arrested at their home, where police also seized documents linked to extremism, according to the Tunisialive news site.
Rezgui's neighbors said he was a normal young man in college  respectable, friendly and quiet, Radio Mosaique reported. Nobody saw signs of radicalization in his behavior. Radio Mosaique reported that Rezgui trained in a extremist camp, but the location of the camp isn't clear. Other reports have said he never traveled outside of Tunisia.
Tunisian security forces had been on alert since March when two Tunisian gunmen opened fire on the Bardo museum in Tunis, killing 22 people, mostly tourists. Two gunmen were killed in that attack, for which the Islamic State also claimed credit.
The second terrorist attack this year to center on tourists is likely to deal a heavy blow to the country's tourism industry, which accounts for nearly 15% of Tunisia's gross domestic product.
The Tunisian attack was one of three deadly terror incidents to hit three separate nations Friday. In France, a man once placed on a "radicalization list" drove his truck into a U.S.- owned gas factory, triggering an explosion as his boss' severed head was found at the entrance, authorities said. In Kuwait, about two dozen people were killed in an Islamic State attack on a Shiite mosque during prayers.
Dorell reported from McLean, Va. Contributing: Moenes Sboui in Tunis, Tunisia.
432 CONNECT 544 TWEET 5 LINKEDIN 107 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1Ijr5Wn
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:43:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia pledges tougher security measures after attack</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98116712/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Tunisia-pledges-tougher-security-measures-after-attack/</Link>
        <Description>Tunisian government will shutter unsanctioned mosques and organizations that could have ties to Islamic extremism.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Tunisia pledges tougher security measures after attack
The Tunisian government will shutter unsanctioned mosques and organizations that could have ties to Islamic extremism, step up security at tourist spots and deploy troops elsewhere in the wake of the country's worst terror attack ever.
Post to Facebook
Tunisia pledges tougher security measures after attack The Tunisian government will shutter unsanctioned mosques and organizations that could have ties to Islamic extremism, step up security at tourist spots and deploy troops elsewhere in the wake of the country's worst terror attack ever. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IkeO41
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
19
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Tunisia pledges tougher security measures after attack
Moenes Sboui and John Dyer, Special for USA TODAY 3:43 p.m. EDT June 27, 2015
A woman grieves as she lays flowers at the beach next to the Imperial Marhaba hotel on June 27, 2015 in Souuse, Tunisia.
(Photo: Jeff J Mitchell, AP)
923 CONNECT 82 TWEET 3 LINKEDIN 19 COMMENTEMAILMORE
TUNIS, Tunisia  The Tunisian government will shutter unsanctioned mosques and organizations that could have ties to Islamic extremism, step up security at tourist spots and deploy troops elsewhere in the wake of the country's worst terror attack ever.
"The fight against terrorism is a national responsibility," Prime Minister Habib Essid said Saturday as his government announced a raft of new measures. "We are at war against terrorism which represents a serious danger to national unity during this delicate period that the nation is going through."
Essid spoke a day after a gunman hid an assault rifle under an umbrella and killed 38 people at the Imperial Marhaba hotel in the coastal city of Sousse. Most of the victims were European tourists. The Islamic State claimed responsibility for the attack.
Tunisian police shot and killed the gunman, Seifeddine Rezgui, a student who used the jihadi pseudonym of Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani, according to SITE Intelligence Group, which monitors terrorists' activity online.
"The attack is an isolated operation of the sort that could affect anyone," said Rafik Chelli, the secretary of state of the Interior Ministry. He said Tunisian security officials thwarted two other planned attacks two days before.
Tourists flee as chilling details emerge in Tunisia
Tunisian security forces had been on alert since March when two Tunisian gunmen opened fire on the Bardo museum in Tunis, killing 22 people, mostly tourists. Two gunmen were killed in that attack, for which the Islamic State also claimed credit.
The attack on the resort and museum threatens not only to upset the political stability of Tunisia, but also undermine its tourism industry, which comprises around 15% of its gross domestic product.
Timeline: Attacks on tourists over the past 30 years
Tourists comfort one and other at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort after unknown assailants detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels, killing more than 20, including Germans, Brits and Belgians and wounding several others - some while they were sunbathing.
(Photo: Mohamed Messara, epa)
A glass door shattered by a bullet at Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort in al-Sousse,Tunisia.
(Photo: Mohamed Messara, epa)
In the wake of today's shootings the pool and deck chairs at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel are deserted.
(Photo: Mohamed Messara, epa)
Fullscreen
Medics help an injured man in al-Sousse, Tunisia. According to local reports unknown assailants detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels, killing at least 27, mostly foreigners, and wounding several others, some while they were sunbathing.
(Photo: epa)
A tourist walks past blood stains on the ground at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort town of al-Sousse, a popular tourist destination in Tunisia.
(Photo: Mohamed Messara, epa)
In this screen grab taken from video provided by Tunisia TV1, injured people are treated on a Tunisian beach after two gunmen rushed from the beach into a hotel in the Tunisian resort town of Sousse. 
(Photo: Tunisia TV1 via , ap)
Injured people are treated on a Tunisian beach in the resort town of Sousse.
(Photo: Tunisia TV1 via AP)
An Instagram photo from one of the resort properties in Sousse, Tunisia where gunmen killed at least 27 people, mostly tourists.
(Photo: vracarics, via Instagram)
Security tries to control the scene as people gather on the streets in al-Sousse near the resorts where gunmen killed more than 25 people.
(Photo: epa)
A victim lies on a beach in al-Sousse, Tunisia. At least 27 people, mostly foreigners, are reported dead. While many others have been wounded.
(Photo: epa)
Members of the Tunisian security forces escort a man through a street in al-Sousse, Tunisia after assailants detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels.
(Photo: epa)
An Instagram photo from one of the resort properties in Sousse, Tunisia where gunmen killed at least 27 people, mostly tourists.
(Photo: truemvp, via Instagram)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:06:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds injured in fire at Taiwan water park</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98115774/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Hundreds-injured-in-fire-at-Taiwan-water-park/</Link>
        <Description>A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200 people, authorities said. ( June 27)</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Hundreds injured in fire at Taiwan water park
A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200 people, authorities said. ( June 27)
Post to Facebook
Hundreds injured in fire at Taiwan water park A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200 people, authorities said. ( June 27) Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IkdMVs
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Hundreds injured in fire at Taiwan water park
A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200 people, authorities said. ( June 27)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:43:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Egypt sees sandstorm and earthquake on the same day</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98112752/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Egypt-sees-sandstorm-and-earthquake-on-the-same-day/</Link>
        <Description>Egypt faced treacherous weather conditions Saturday</Description>
        <MainBody>Egypt sees sandstorm and earthquake on the same day
Egypt faced treacherous weather conditions Saturday
Post to Facebook
Egypt sees sandstorm and earthquake on the same day Egypt faced treacherous weather conditions Saturday Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IkbNAw
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Egypt sees sandstorm and earthquake on the same day
AP 2:43 p.m. EDT June 27, 2015
114 CONNECT 72 TWEET LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
CAIRO (AP)  Egypt faced treacherous weather conditions Saturday as a sandstorm blanketed the north of the country and a magnitude-5.2 earthquake centered in the Sinai peninsula shook buildings more than 200 miles away in the capital, Cairo.
The epicenter of the quake was 4 kilometers (2.5 miles) southeast of the beachside town of Nuweiba in the Sinai, and about 75 kilometers (46 miles) south of Egypt's border with Israel, according to the U.S. Geological Survey.
Airports near Alexandria and Marsa Matrouh, along the Mediterranean coast, closed and diverted flights to Cairo due to poor visibility from the day's sandstorm, Civil Aviation Minister Hossam Kamel said in a statement.  Visibility reached as low as 500 meters at the Burg al-Arab airport near Alexandria, he said.
Fierce winds whipped through the capital as many residents took cover from the sand by staying indoors.  Others were seen braving the storm wearing surgical masks or covering their faces with clothing, as the wind sent rubbish and dust swirling.
At its peak, the sandstorm covered the capital in a thick orange cloud, dramatically reducing visibility.
In the Red Sea town of Dahab, 68 kilometers (42 miles) south of the epicenter of the quake in the Sinai peninsula, the tremor shook loose clouds of dust that enveloped nearby mountains, according to a witness.  The quake appeared to startle local residents and tourists.  It also shook the nearby Gaza strip.  No serious damage was immediately reported from the earthquake in Egypt or in Gaza.
The Egyptian Ministry of Health said in a statement that there were no reports of deaths or injuries anywhere in Egypt due to the quake.
Israeli media reported that very mild aftershocks of the earthquake were felt in some places in the south of the country, but that no damage or injuries were caused.
The extreme weather conditions provided fodder for social media humor. Some wondered which of the 10 Biblical plagues would come next, while the popular Zamalek football club tweeted that it wasn't actually an earthquake--just preparation for their match tonight.
114 CONNECT 72 TWEET LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1IkbNAw
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:15:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fire injures scores at Taiwan water park party</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98110032/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Fire-injures-scores-at-Taiwan-water-park-party/</Link>
        <Description>Authorities say more than 200 people were injured in a fire at a water park in Taiwan.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fire injures scores at Taiwan water park party
Authorities say more than 200 people were injured in a fire at a water park in Taiwan.
Post to Facebook
Fire injures scores at Taiwan water park party Authorities say more than 200 people were injured in a fire at a water park in Taiwan. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1NnxZJv
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Fire injures scores at Taiwan water park party
AP 3:15 p.m. EDT June 27, 2015
A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200 people, authorities said. ( June 27)
Injured victims are treated after an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan. The New Taipei City fire department says 200 people were injured in an accidental explosion of colored theatrical powder Saturday night near a performance stage where about 1,000 people were gathered for party.
(Photo: Central News Agency, AP)
352 CONNECT 48 TWEET LINKEDIN 1 COMMENTEMAILMORE
A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200 people, authorities said.
An accidental explosion of an unknown powder set off the fire near the stage in front of about 1,000 spectators, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command center.
Wang said 83 people had serious injuries and 131 others have light injuries.
Taiwan's Central News Agency reported the fire at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City near the island's capital was quickly brought under control.
Video showed rescue workers and bystanders carrying burned and injured people on their backs, in inflatable boats and on stretchers to get medical treatment.
CNA reported witnesses as saying the fire spread quickly after the colored powder was blown into the air.
It wasn't clear if the powder was part of a performance. The cause of the fire is being investigated.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1NnxZJv
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:12:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait conducts mass funeral as police question suspects</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98091850/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Kuwait-conducts-mass-funeral-as-police-question-suspects/</Link>
        <Description>The Islamic State claimed responsibility for the attack that killed 27.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Kuwait conducts mass funeral as police question suspects
Thousands of people in Kuwait took part in a mass funeral procession Saturday for 27 people killed in a suicide bombing that targeted a Shiite mosque a day earlier.
Post to Facebook
Kuwait conducts mass funeral as police question suspects Thousands of people in Kuwait took part in a mass funeral procession Saturday for 27 people killed in a suicide bombing that targeted a Shiite mosque a day earlier. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IjWsA2
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Kuwait conducts mass funeral as police question suspects
Oren Dorell , USA TODAY 1:12 p.m. EDT June 27, 2015
The Islamic State claimed responsibility for a bombing attack on a Shiite mosque in Kuwait on Friday, which killed at least 24 people just after midday prayers. Reports of the death toll varied. USA TODAY
Mourners carry the body of one of the victims of the Al-Imam Al-Sadeq mosque bombing, during a mass funeral at Jaafari cemetery in Kuwait City on June 27, 2015.
(Photo: Yasser Al-Zayyat, AFP/Getty Images)
17 CONNECT 114 TWEET LINKEDIN 1 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Chanting "Sunnis and Shiites are brothers!" Saturday, thousands of mourners joined a mass funeral procession in Kuwait City for 27 people killed in a suicide bombing at a Shiite mosque a day earlier.
Sunni groups in Kuwait and leaders from across the Middle East condemned the attack, for which the Islamic State claimed responsibility. Gulf authorities believe the militants want to provoke a sectarian war between the region's Sunni and Shiite sects, the Associated Press reported.
The government helped plan Saturday's mass funeral for those killed, according to the AP.
At least 27 dead in ISIL-claimed Kuwait attack
About a third of Kuwait's 3.6 million residents are Shiite Muslims. The majority of Kuwaitis are Sunni Muslims.
The blast at the Imam Al-Sadiq Mosque during Friday prayers in Kuwait's capital also injured 227 people, 40 of whom remained hospitalized Saturday, according to the official Kuwait News Agency or KUNA.
The Islamic State also claimed responsibility for Friday's attack on a beachfront hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, where a gunman killed 39 people.  In France, a man with extreme Islamist ties was arrested after authorities say he beheaded his boss and caused an explosion Friday at an American-owned gas plant.
France on edge day after 2nd terror attack in 6 months
Official and public reactions to Kuwait's first major terrorist attack in 20 years were swift.
Police arrested 18 suspects, according to the Kuwait Times newspaper. They include the owner of the car driven by the bomber to the mosque. The bomber died when he detonated his bomb among worshipers.
Kuwait's ruler, Sheikh Ahmad al-Sabah, condemned the blast during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan. "The blast was meant to tear asunder the fabric of the well-knitted Kuwaiti society by fomenting sectarian divisions and conflicts," al-Sabah said in an official statement. "But that would not happen as Kuwaitis value their unity and societal solidarity."
Some 1,250 Kuwaitis have volunteered to give blood since Friday's attack, Rana Abdulrazzaq, an official at the Kuwait Blood Bank told KUNA.
Kuwait's minister of justice and Islamic affairs, Yaqoub Al-Sanea, said the incident shows the need to improve surveillance and counter extremist ideology, KUNA reported. The ministry created a committee to produce sermons demonstrating the moderation of Islam for Friday prayers, the Muslim Sabbath, Al-Sanea said.
"It does not need only to install surveillance cameras, but also to address the extremist thought, which is a stranger to the Kuwaiti society," he said.
U.S. counterterrorism officials, however, has previously said oil-rich Kuwait is a major source of funding for Sunni Muslim terrorist groups operating across the Middle East. The U.S. Treasury last year sanctioned two Kuwaitis it accused of providing money, fighters and weapons to extremists with the Islamic State in Iraq and Syria.
Treasury's David Cohen, under secretary for terrorism and financial intelligence, said in March 2014 that "a number of fundraisers" in Kuwait and Qatar solicit donations for extremist groups, including al-Qaeda's affiliate in Syria, the al-Nusrah Front, and the Islamic State. Much of the fundraising happens in Kuwaiti mosques under the guise of helping the Syrian people embroiled in a civil war, Cohen said.
"Our ally Kuwait has become the epicenter of fundraising for terrorist groups in Syria," Cohen said in a speech to the Center for a New American Security in Washington.
U.S. officials had urged Kuwait to stem the flow of money to terrorists, and offered help in that effort, Cohen said.
Security forces, officials and civilians gather outside of the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a deadly blast struck after Friday prayers in Kuwait City.
(Photo: AP)
A Kuwaiti man with blood-stained clothes gathers himself at the site of a suicide bombing that targeted the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque.
(Photo: Yasser Al-Zayyat, AFP/Getty Images)
Kuwaiti security forces and emergency personnel gather outside the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers.
(Photo: Yasser Al-Zayyat, AFP/Getty Images)
Kuwaiti rescue workers carry a victim following a blast at Imam Sadiq Mosque in al-Sawaber, Kuwait City. At least eight people were killed in an explosion at the Shiite mosque during Friday prayers.
(Photo: Raed Qutena, epa)
A Kuwaiti man reacts at the site of a suicide bombing that targeted the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque.
(Photo: Yasser Al-Zayyat, AFP/Getty Images)
The aftermath of a deadly blast at the mosque in Kuwait City. A posting on a Twitter account known to belong to the Islamic State group claimed that the explosion was work of a suicide bomber wearing an explosive belt. 
(Photo: Kuwaitna News via, AP)
Kuwaiti security inspect the site of a suicide bombing that targeted the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City.
(Photo: Yasser Al-Zayyat, AFP/Getty Images)
Fullscreen
A man in a blood-soaked dishdasha following a deadly blast at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait City. A posting on a Twitter account known to belong to the Islamic State group claimed that the explosion was work of a suicide bomber wearing an explosive belt. 
(Photo: AP)
An injured man is helped to safety following a blast at Imam Sadiq Mosque in al-Sawaber, Kuwait City.
(Photo: Raed Qutena, epa)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:51:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The day in pictures</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/95533850/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~The-day-in-pictures/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
The day in pictures
Flowers and a note reading 'Why? Warum?' are placed on a sun lounge at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, after two assailants with hand grenades and rifles opened fire on tourists at two hotels, killing more than 30 people and wounding several others.
Post to Facebook
The day in pictures Flowers and a note reading 'Why? Warum?' are placed on a sun lounge at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, after two assailants with hand grenades and rifles opened fire on tourists at two hotels, killing more than 30 people and wounding several others. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1SbnRa4
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
The day in pictures
Flowers and a note reading 'Why? Warum?' are placed on a sun lounge at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, after two assailants with hand grenades and rifles opened fire on tourists at two hotels, killing more than 30 people and wounding several others.
Andreas Gebert, epa
The first Bubble Soccer tournament takes place in Hitzkirch, Switzerland. Bubble Soccer, also known as Zorb Soccer, is becoming increasingly popular around the world.
Urs Flueeler, epa
Sweepee Rambo, a 16-year-old Chinese Crested dog, competes in the World's Ugliest Dog Contest at the Sonoma-Marin Fair, in Petaluma, Calif. She won the runner-up award. 
Noah Berger, AP
Fullscreen
A woman withdraws money from a bank cash machine from a National Bank branch while another reacts behind her in central Athens. Anxiety over Greece's future swelled with people lining up at banks to withdraw cash after Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' call to have the people vote on a proposed bailout deal.
Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP
A law enforcement official stands guard on Studley Road where the search for convicted murderer David Sweat continues in Duane, N.Y. 
Mary Altaffer, AP
Fullscreen
Bree Newsome of Charlotte, N.C., climbs a flagpole to remove the Confederate battle flag at a Confederate monument in front of the Statehouse in Columbia, S.C. She was taken into custody when she came down and the flag was raised again by Capitol workers about 45 minutes later. 
Bruce Smith, AP
Russian swamp football players fight for the ball during the Cup of Russia match outside Saint Petersburg.
Olga Maltseva, AFP/Getty Images
Participants take part in a fitness training event during the Velo Picnic Open Air festival in Minsk, Belarus.
Maxim Malinovsky, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A man is detained by a Burundi policeman during a scuffle with residents angered by a search operation in Bujumbura. Parliamentary elections are set to be held on June 29, 2015, and a presidential vote on July 15, despite months of turmoil sparked by President Pierre Nkurunziza's bid for a third term in office. 
Marco Longari, AFP/Getty Images
Rainbow-colored lights shine on the White House to celebrate the U.S. Supreme Court's ruling in favor of same-sex marriage.
Mark Wilson, Getty Images
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:55:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France on edge day after 2nd terror attack in 6 months</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98089260/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~France-on-edge-day-after-nd-terror-attack-in-months/</Link>
        <Description>"It feels that these attacks are now happening back to back," a student in Paris said.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
France on edge day after 2nd terror attack in 6 months
PARIS  A day after a man was decapitated at a gas factory in France's second terror attack in six months, residents questioned whether the nation is doing enough to stop terrorists.
Post to Facebook
France on edge day after 2nd terror attack in 6 months PARIS  A day after a man was decapitated at a gas factory in France's second terror attack in six months, residents questioned whether the nation is doing enough to stop terrorists. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Nn393L
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
37
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
France on edge day after 2nd terror attack in 6 months
Maya Vidon-White and Jennifer Collins, Special for USA TODAY 1:55 p.m. EDT June 27, 2015
White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest says "the United States condemns in the strongest terms the terrorist attacks in France, Kuwait and Tunisia today." Wochit
Police officers stand guard at a cordon in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier on June 27, 2015, at the site where a decapitated body was discovered following a suspected Islamist attack on U.S.-owned Air Products factory.
(Photo: Philippe Desmazes, AFP/Getty Images)
133 CONNECT 202 TWEET 3 LINKEDIN 37 COMMENTEMAILMORE
PARIS  A day after a man was decapitated at a gas factory in France's second terror attack in six months, residents questioned whether the nation is doing enough to stop terrorists.
"It feels that these attacks are now happening back to back," said Ilan Cohn, 21, a student in Paris. "I am afraid that there will be more and more, just recently Charlie Hebdo and now this?"
Yaccine Salhi, 35, a man once placed on a "radicalization list" drove his truck into a U.S.-owned gas factory in the southeastern French city Lyon on Friday, triggering an explosion as his boss' severed head was found at the entrance, authorities said.
Beheading, attack at gas factory in France; suspect detained
Two people were injured in the explosion of gas canisters. "Islamist terrorism has again struck France," Prime Minister Manuel Valls said. He warned Saturday that France faces even more attacks.
Officials told the Associated Press and AFP on Saturday that Salhi took a selfie with the slain victim and sent the image to at least one recipient.
French security forces had been on high alert since Islamic extremist gunmen targeted the Paris office of satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo in January, setting off several days of attacks in the city that left 20 people dead.
"These were the actions of a few isolated men but what if it's not the case next time  we could have a mass attack by an organized network of fundamentalists," Cohn said. "That's really scary. It doesn't feel like the authorities are able to prevent anything."
The Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, after a suspected Islamist assault in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates on June 26.
(Photo: Jean-Philippe Ksiazek, AFP/Getty Images)
French President Francois Hollande arrives for a news conference regarding the attack on the Air Products factory. Hollande cut short a visit to Brussels where he was participating in a European Union summit.
(Photo: Julien Warnand, epa)
In this screen grab taken from video provided by BFM TV, police stand at the scene outside the factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, France.
(Photo: AP)
President Hollande referred to the incident as a "terrorist attack," and said a "terrorist" in his thirties had been arrested.
(Photo: Julien Warnand, epa)
The french president said the decapitated body was found near the factory with inscriptions written on it in Arabic. Authoritieshave opened an anti-terrorism investigation.
(Photo: Laurent Cipriani, AP)
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, in eastern France.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
Investigating police officers work outside the plant, which is operated by Air Products, which is headquartered in Allentown, Pa.
(Photo: Laurent Cipriani, AP)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 16:24:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia attack leaves dozens dead at resort</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98084170/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Tunisia-attack-leaves-dozens-dead-at-resort/</Link>
        <Description>Dozens of people, mostly tourists, were killed when a lone gunman stormed a resort in Tunisia and opened fire. He was shot dead by security forces.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Tunisia attack leaves dozens dead at resort
Dozens of people, mostly tourists, were killed when a lone gunman stormed a resort in Tunisia and opened fire. He was shot dead by security forces.
Post to Facebook
Tunisia attack leaves dozens dead at resort Dozens of people, mostly tourists, were killed when a lone gunman stormed a resort in Tunisia and opened fire. He was shot dead by security forces. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IjN6UP
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Tunisia attack leaves dozens dead at resort
Dozens of people, mostly tourists, were killed when a lone gunman stormed a resort in Tunisia and opened fire. He was shot dead by security forces. Wochit
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 10:30:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State claims responsibility for Tunisian resort attack</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/97913718/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Islamic-State-claims-responsibility-for-Tunisian-resort-attack/</Link>
        <Description>Security forces killed the attacker who reportedly hid his rifle under a folded beach umbrella.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Islamic State claims responsibility for Tunisian resort attack
TUNIS, Tunisia  A lone gunman hiding a Kalashnikov under his umbrella opened fire on a Tunisian beach resort, killing 39 people, mostly tourists  one of three deadly attacks Friday from Europe to the Middle East.
Post to Facebook
Islamic State claims responsibility for Tunisian resort attack TUNIS, Tunisia  A lone gunman hiding a Kalashnikov under his umbrella opened fire on a Tunisian beach resort, killing 39 people, mostly tourists  one of three deadly attacks Friday from Europe to the Middle East. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1NiylRK
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
230
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Islamic State claims responsibility for Tunisian resort attack
Doug Stanglin and Moenes Sboui , USA TODAY 3:30 a.m. EDT June 27, 2015
Dozens of people, mostly tourists, were killed when a lone gunman stormed a resort in Tunisia and opened fire. He was shot dead by security forces. Wochit
Medics help an injured man in Sousse, Tunisia, on June 26, 2015 after gunmen opened fire on a resort beach.
(Photo: epa)
3244 CONNECT 385 TWEET 17 LINKEDIN 230 COMMENTEMAILMORE
TUNIS, Tunisia  A lone gunman hiding a Kalashnikov under his umbrella opened fire on a Tunisian beach resort, killing 39 people, mostly tourists  one of three deadly attacks Friday from Europe to the Middle East.
The Islamic State claimed responsibility for the attack at the Imperial Marhaba hotel, according to SITE Intelligence Group, a U.S.-based organization that monitors terrorists' activity online.
At least 36 people were wounded in the nation's deadliest onslaught before the shooter was killed by security forces. The gunman was identified by the Islamic State as Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani, according to SITE.
"Tunisia is in a constant war against terrorism," said President Beji Caid Essebsi, vowing to crack down on terrorism in his country. "Tunisian state is concerned about this issue, and it will take its responsibilities and take measures that could be painful but necessary."
The president said he would revoke the right of political parties and groups to assemble, if necessary, if they advocated militancy or expressed solidarity with the Islamic State.
Witnesses at the resort town of Sousse said bodies were strewn in the sand alongside beach chairs as the gunman opened fire on sunbathers.
The interior ministry initially said at least two gunmen were involved, but revised its report as investigators examined the chaotic scene and decided there was a single shooter.
"A terrorist infiltrated the buildings from the back before opening fire on the residents of the hotel, including foreigners and Tunisians," Ministry of the Interior spokesman Mohamed Ali Laroui said.
Tunisia beach attack threatens economy, secular rule
Tourists comfort one and other at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort after unknown assailants detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels, killing more than 20, including Germans, Brits and Belgians and wounding several others - some while they were sunbathing.
(Photo: Mohamed Messara, epa)
A glass door shattered by a bullet at Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort in al-Sousse,Tunisia.
(Photo: Mohamed Messara, epa)
In the wake of today's shootings the pool and deck chairs at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel are deserted.
(Photo: Mohamed Messara, epa)
Fullscreen
Medics help an injured man in al-Sousse, Tunisia. According to local reports unknown assailants detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels, killing at least 27, mostly foreigners, and wounding several others, some while they were sunbathing.
(Photo: epa)
A tourist walks past blood stains on the ground at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort town of al-Sousse, a popular tourist destination in Tunisia.
(Photo: Mohamed Messara, epa)
In this screen grab taken from video provided by Tunisia TV1, injured people are treated on a Tunisian beach after two gunmen rushed from the beach into a hotel in the Tunisian resort town of Sousse. 
(Photo: Tunisia TV1 via , ap)
Injured people are treated on a Tunisian beach in the resort town of Sousse.
(Photo: Tunisia TV1 via AP)
An Instagram photo from one of the resort properties in Sousse, Tunisia where gunmen killed at least 27 people, mostly tourists.
(Photo: vracarics, via Instagram)
Security tries to control the scene as people gather on the streets in al-Sousse near the resorts where gunmen killed more than 25 people.
(Photo: epa)
A victim lies on a beach in al-Sousse, Tunisia. At least 27 people, mostly foreigners, are reported dead. While many others have been wounded.
(Photo: epa)
Members of the Tunisian security forces escort a man through a street in al-Sousse, Tunisia after assailants detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels.
(Photo: epa)
An Instagram photo from one of the resort properties in Sousse, Tunisia where gunmen killed at least 27 people, mostly tourists.
(Photo: truemvp, via Instagram)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:23:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia beach attack threatens economy, secular rule</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/97954348/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Tunisia-beach-attack-threatens-economy-secular-rule/</Link>
        <Description>A secularist-led government took power in Tunisia after elections in November.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Tunisia beach attack threatens economy, secular rule
Friday's attack on a Tunisian resort on the Mediterranean coast could crush tourism in the country where the Arab Spring was born and topple the secularist-led government.
Post to Facebook
Tunisia beach attack threatens economy, secular rule Friday's attack on a Tunisian resort on the Mediterranean coast could crush tourism in the country where the Arab Spring was born and topple the secularist-led government. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1NjFQHV
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Tunisia beach attack threatens economy, secular rule
Oren Dorell , USA TODAY 8:23 p.m. EDT June 26, 2015
Tunisian security officers escort a man through a street in al-Sousse, Tunisia, on June 26, 2015, after an assailant detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels at the coastal Mediterranean town.
(Photo: European Pressphoto Agency)
113 CONNECT 182 TWEET 2 LINKEDIN 1 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Friday's attack on a Tunisian resort on the Mediterranean coast could crush tourism in the country where the Arab Spring was born and pressure the secularist-led government.
A lone gunman killed dozens of people, mostly tourists, after opening fire on sunbathers in the resort town of Sousse. The suspect was then shot to death by police.
The Islamic State claimed responsibility for the attack, according to the SITE Intelligence Group, a U.S.-based organization that monitors terrorists' activity online. It comes three months after gunmen opened fire in the National Bardo Museum in the capital, Tunis, and massacred 22 people, most of them tourists. The militants also claimed responsibility in that March attack.
At least 27 dead in ISIL-claimed Kuwait attack
"They are trying to destroy Tunisia's economy,"  terrorism analyst Walid Phares, author of the book The Lost Spring, said Friday. "The extremists want the secular government down."
The government is led by the secular Nida Tounes party and its coalition partner, the Islamist Ennahda party. Ennahda lost power in November's elections after ruling since 2011.
Tunisian President Beji Caid Essebsi vowed Friday to crack down on terrorism in his country. He said Tunisia will "take measures that could be painful but necessary." He said he is willing to revoke the right of political parties and groups to assemble if they advocated militancy or expressed solidarity with the Islamic State.
Essebsi said French President Francois Hollande called him Friday, and the two leaders agreed to work together against Islamic extremism.
Beheading, attack at gas factory in France; suspect detained
Issam Chebbi, head of Tunisia's opposition Republican Party, which promotes secularism, blamed the attack on the civil war in neighboring Libya.
"Libya is the problem and the weakened borders between the two countries is the source of all this misfortune," Chebbi told El Hiwar Ettounsi TV.
Political analyst Slaheddine Jourchi, speaking on Tunisia's national Channel 1, said the country's bitter political rivalries were in danger of undermining its approach to Islamic militancy.
"Tunisia is in real danger," Jourchi said. "A national dialogue is necessary, and we must build a 'war economy' (against terrorism)."
Marina Ottaway, a Middle East fellow at the Wilson Center in Washington said Tunisia does not have "a particularly strong government and certainly it could be disrupted relatively easily. Both the ruling party and  Ennahda are very much against these extremist groups."
Violent extremists in Tunisia have gained strength and become more militant since Ennahda joined the secularist coalition, Ottaway said. "In Tunisia you have people in the Islamist movement who think Ennahda is becoming too moderate," she added.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 02:59:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. condemns attacks in France, Kuwait, Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/98007412/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~US-condemns-attacks-in-France-Kuwait-Tunisia/</Link>
        <Description>White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest says "the United States condemns in the strongest terms the terrorist attacks in France, Kuwait and Tunisia today."</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
U.S. condemns attacks in France, Kuwait, Tunisia
White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest says "the United States condemns in the strongest terms the terrorist attacks in France, Kuwait and Tunisia today."
Post to Facebook
U.S. condemns attacks in France, Kuwait, Tunisia White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest says "the United States condemns in the strongest terms the terrorist attacks in France, Kuwait and Tunisia today." Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1NkRyC9
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
2
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
U.S. condemns attacks in France, Kuwait, Tunisia
White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest says "the United States condemns in the strongest terms the terrorist attacks in France, Kuwait and Tunisia today." Wochit
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:11:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S.: No evidence yet linking Friday's deadly attacks</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/97966230/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~US-No-evidence-yet-linking-Fridays-deadly-attacks/</Link>
        <Description>U.S. officials see no link yet among three terror attacks but continue to investigate.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
U.S.: No evidence yet linking Friday's deadly attacks
U.S. officials say they have seen no evidence yet to suggest that a series of deadly attacks across three continents Friday were linked, but analysts said it is likely they were loosely coordinated.
Post to Facebook
U.S.: No evidence yet linking Friday's deadly attacks U.S. officials say they have seen no evidence yet to suggest that a series of deadly attacks across three continents Friday were linked, but analysts said it is likely they were loosely coordinated. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1NjX1ct
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
12
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
U.S.: No evidence yet linking Friday's deadly attacks
Jim Michaels , USA TODAY 8:11 p.m. EDT June 26, 2015
White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest says "the United States condemns in the strongest terms the terrorist attacks in France, Kuwait and Tunisia today." Wochit
epaselect epa04820003 Medics and security forces gather inside Imam Sadiq Mosque following a suicide bombing in al-Sawaber, Kuwait City, Kuwait, 26 June 2015.
(Photo: RAED QUTENA, EPA)
109 CONNECT 99 TWEET 2 LINKEDIN 12 COMMENTEMAILMORE
WASHINGTON  U.S. officials say they have seen no evidence yet to suggest that Friday's series of deadly attacks across three continents were linked, but they are continuing to investigate.
"At this point it's too soon to tell whether or not these various and far-flung attacks were coordinated centrally or whether or not they were coincidental," said Army Col. Steve Warren, a Pentagon spokesman. "We are continuing to look into this."
In Tunisia, a gunman killed 37 people, mostly tourists, at a seaside resort. In Kuwait, an Islamic State suicide bomber killed at least 27 people at a Shiite mosque. In France, a driver rammed his truck into a U.S.-owned gas factory, where a decapitated body was found with the head hanging at the entrance. In all, at least 65 people were killed across the three continents.
Beheading, attack at gas factory in France; suspect detained
The attacks may not have been centrally directed but were likely loosely coordinated among extremist groups, such as al-Qaeda and the Islamic State, which share similar goals of attacking Western and Shiite Muslim targets, analysts said.
The groups may have been planning attacks separately and agreed among themselves to launch them on the same day, said Rick Nelson, an analyst at the Center for Strategic and International Studies.
"That's just organizations with a common goal loosely operating together to achieve a greater effect," Nelson said. "That's what you have here."
At least 27 dead in ISIL-claimed Kuwait attack
The attacks come as the Islamic State, also known as ISIL or ISIS, has grown in prominence and has begun to overshadow al-Qaeda, which it broke away from. The Islamic State has encouraged followers to create their own attacks.
"We do know that ISIL encourages lone-wolf attacks," said Col. Patrick Ryder, a spokesman for U.S. Central Command, which oversees operations in the Middle East.
A number of extremist groups around the world have rebranded themselves under the Islamic State banner because they see the militants as overtaking al-Qaeda as the premier global terror organization.
Islamic State claims responsibility for Tunisian resort attack
In a video released Tuesday, the Islamic State called on its supporters to increase attacks during Ramadan, the Muslim holy month, and "be keen on waging invasion in this eminent month and commit martyrdom," the Associated Press reported.
Homeland Security Secretary Jeh Johnson encouraged Americans to not be intimidated by the attacks. "We continue to encourage all Americans to attend public events and celebrate this country during this summer season, but always remain vigilant," he said in a statement.
President Obama was briefed on the events throughout the day, White House Deputy Press Secretary Eric Schultz said.
"Obviously these are unfolding circumstances happening in real time," Schultz told reporters aboard Air Force One while heading to Charleston, S.C., where Obama delivered a eulogy for Clementa Pinckney, the pastor and state senator killed in the June 17 church shooting there that left nine people dead.
Schultz said National Security Council staff members are "in touch with their counterparts in the respective countries and continue to offer help and assistance."
The White House issued a statement, saying, "The United States condemns in the strongest terms the terrorist attacks in France, Kuwait, and Tunisia today. ... As the president has discussed with his French, Kuwaiti and Tunisian counterparts in recent weeks, we are resolute and united in our shared effort to fight the scourge of terrorism."
Contributing: Gregory Korte
109 CONNECT 99 TWEET 2 LINKEDIN 12 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1NjX1ct
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 00:03:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly terror attack in France</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/97988986/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Deadly-terror-attack-in-France/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Deadly terror attack in France
The Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, after a suspected Islamist assault in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates on June 26.
Post to Facebook
Deadly terror attack in France The Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, after a suspected Islamist assault in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates on June 26. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1BTkuRo
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Deadly terror attack in France
The Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, after a suspected Islamist assault in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates on June 26.
Jean-Philippe Ksiazek, AFP/Getty Images
French President Francois Hollande arrives for a news conference regarding the attack on the Air Products factory. Hollande cut short a visit to Brussels where he was participating in a European Union summit.
Julien Warnand, epa
In this screen grab taken from video provided by BFM TV, police stand at the scene outside the factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, France.
AP
President Hollande referred to the incident as a "terrorist attack," and said a "terrorist" in his thirties had been arrested.
Julien Warnand, epa
The french president said the decapitated body was found near the factory with inscriptions written on it in Arabic. Authoritieshave opened an anti-terrorism investigation.
Laurent Cipriani, AP
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, in eastern France.
AFP/Getty Images
Investigating police officers work outside the plant, which is operated by Air Products, which is headquartered in Allentown, Pa.
Laurent Cipriani, AP
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 22:44:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia's growing tourist trade could suffer with terror attacks</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/97977244/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Tunisias-growing-tourist-trade-could-suffer-with-terror-attacks/</Link>
        <Description>Tunisia's popularity as a tourist destination has grown since democratic reforms in 2011</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Tunisia's growing tourist trade could suffer with terror attacks
Tourism to Tunisia has been growing in recent years, with the attraction of sugar-sand beaches, historic Punic sites and scenery beautiful enough to be chosen repeatedly for Hollywood movies. But the shootings
Post to Facebook
Tunisia's growing tourist trade could suffer with terror attacks Tourism to Tunisia has been growing in recent years, with the attraction of sugar-sand beaches, historic Punic sites and scenery beautiful enough to be chosen repeatedly for Hollywood movies. But the shootings Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1LATfOx
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Tunisia's growing tourist trade could suffer with terror attacks
Bart Jansen , USA TODAY 3:44 p.m. EDT June 26, 2015
George Lucas talks with Jake Lloyd who plays Anakin Skywalker on the set of the film Star Wars: Episode I The Phantom Menace, which was filmed partially in Tunisia in 1999. The country has become a growing tourist destination after democratic reforms in 2011.
(Photo: KEITH HAMSHERE,  LUCASFILM, LTD.)
131 CONNECT 58 TWEET LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
Tunisia's tourism has grown like a desert flower in recent years with the attraction of white-sand beaches, world renowned archeological sites and scenery beautiful enough to be chosen repeatedly for Hollywood movies.
But the appetite for the Mediterranean destination may wither after two shooting rampages left dozens dead. A lone gunman Friday killed 37 people and wounded 36 on the beach outside the Imperial Marhaba hotel in Sousse, a coastal town 90 miles southeast of Tunis. In March, two gunmen killed 21 people at the Bardo Museum in the capital of Tunis. In both cases, security forces killed the gunmen.
"Tunisia is not a super popular destination as of yet, but it is indeed growing," said Olga Ramudo, CEO of Express Travel in Miami.
"The attacks today will definitely dampen enthusiasm from travelers," Ramudo said. "Any time something like this happens, we see the destinations affected and travelers wanting to book away from anything and everything that could put their lives in danger and turn their vacations into a nightmare."
In the wake of today's shootings the pool and deck chairs at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel are deserted.
(Photo: Mohamed Messara, epa)
Tunisia is a former French colony that gained independence in 1956. A popular revolution in January 2011 at the start of the Arab Spring led to the election in October 2011 of a new government. The U.S. government has committed more than $350 million to the country's democratic transition.
Islamic State claims responsibility for Tunisian resort attack
The White House issued a statement Friday condemning the attacks and vowing to stand united "to fight the scourge of terrorism."
Before the attacks, Tunisia had been making great strides in tourism. Conde Nast magazine declared the country "The Next Big Travel Destination" in January 2014.
"With its tradition of tolerance -- not to mention glorious Roman ruins and Mediterranean beaches -- Tunisia may yet emerge as a beacon of hope in one of the world's most troubled regions," the magazine wrote.
The number of international arrivals grew to 6.2 million in 2013, a 5.3% increase from the year before, according to the United Nations World Tourism Organization. The 5.9 million arrivals in 2012 represented a 24.4% growth from the year before.
International tourism receipts grew to nearly $2.9 billion in 2013 from $2.5 billion in 2011, according to the World Bank.
But the land has been popular for 3,000 years.
It is home to Carthage, a military and trade rival to ancient Rome, which ultimately salted its fields in punishment. Amid the series of Punic wars, Hannibal's army memorably rode elephants across the Alps to challenge Rome with battles up and down the Italian peninsula.
A statue underground, outside the Saint Louis Cathedral.
(Photo: Sarah Lynch)
Roman ruins at Carthage include an amphitheater, remains of houses, columns and the Antonine Baths, a World Heritage Site of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO).
Tourists can visit the Saint Louis Cathedral, a Roman Catholic cathedral built in the late 1800s in Carthage, a city thousands of years old.
(Photo: Sarah Lynch)
Another Punic remnant is the city of Kerkouane, once a thriving metropolis known for its dyes and figurines, according to the country's tourism office. Artifacts at this other World Heritage Site include flasks, bones, jewelry and the sarcophagus of a female identified as the goddess Asarte.
Hollywood has made travelogues of the country's scenery. Movies filmed in Tunisia include "Star Wars," where Ksar Hedada doubled for Luke Skywalker's home planet of Tatooine. "The English Patient" featured numerous locations in Tunisia, which even doubled for Cairo.
Modern amenities include white-sand beaches and bougainvillea-draped resorts. Golf courses are plentiful, as are trips to the Sahara Desert.
Bizerte, for example, is the oldest city in Tunisia and the northernmost city in Africa. Besides its beaches and watersports, one of its attractions is the Kasbah, a Sixth Century Byzantium fort, and Fort Hani around the dock.
Kairouan is the fourth most holy city of the Muslim faith, founded about 670 AD. It remains a major destination as a pilgrimage site for Quranic learning and for buildings such as the Mosque of the Three Doors known for its Arabian design, according to the tourism office.
The Hall of Statues at the Bardo National Museum in Tunis.
(Photo: Fethi Belaid, AFP/Getty Images)
Tourists pose for a photo.
(Photo: Fethi Belaid, AFP/Getty Images)
131 CONNECT 58 TWEET LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1LATfOx
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 22:40:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Toll tops 1,150 in Pakistan's deadliest heat wave on record</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/97938184/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Toll-tops-in-Pakistans-deadliest-heat-wave-on-record/</Link>
        <Description>The death toll in Pakistan's deadliest heat wave on record has now topped 1,100.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Toll tops 1,150 in Pakistan's deadliest heat wave on record
The death toll in Pakistan's deadliest heat wave on record has now topped 1,000, according to the Associated Press
Post to Facebook
Toll tops 1,150 in Pakistan's deadliest heat wave on record The death toll in Pakistan's deadliest heat wave on record has now topped 1,000, according to the Associated Press Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1LzRYHy
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
7
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Toll tops 1,150 in Pakistan's deadliest heat wave on record
Doyle Rice , USA TODAY 3:40 p.m. EDT June 26, 2015
People attempt to cool off near a damaged water pipe in Karachi, Pakistan, on June 25, 2015. More than 1,000 people have died in Pakistan's worst heat wave on record.
(Photo: REHAN KHAN, EPA)
303 CONNECT 201 TWEET 1 LINKEDIN 7 COMMENTEMAILMORE
The death toll in Pakistan's deadliest heat wave on record now topped 1,100, causing morgues to overflow, Reuters reported Friday.
Power outages added to the misery, leaving many without fans, water or light at the beginning of Ramadan, when many Muslims do not eat or drink during daylight hours, according to Reuters.
"By Friday, at least 1,150 people have died in the government-run hospitals," said Anwar Kazmi of the Edhi Foundation, a private charity that runs a network of ambulances and morgues.
The New York Times reported the heat wave has sent more than 14,000 people into government and private hospitals in Karachi, the nation's largest city.
The hot weather comes just weeks after torrid temperatures caused nearly 2,200 deaths in neighboring India, raising fears that South Asia could be seeing some of the devastating effects of human-caused climate change, the Associated Press reported.
Pakistan's previous deadliest heat wave was in 1991, when 523 people died, EM-DAT, the International Disaster Database, reported.
This heat wave looks to be easing slightly, as high temperatures are forecast in the 90s after several days of temperatures over 100 degrees, according to Weather Underground.
The worst of the heat peaked Saturday, when the high temperature hit 112.6 degrees in Karachi; the heat index topping out at a dangerously high 121 degrees.
"Since the monsoon has been slower to get into northwestern India, Karachi has been tremendously dry with intense heat," stated AccuWeather meteorologist Anthony Sagliani.
Cooling monsoon rains are likely to arrive in Pakistan by mid-July, which should mean the region won't see any more temperatures this summer as high as were recorded last weekend, meteorologist Jeff Masters of the Weather Underground said.
The Pakistan heat wave will join this year's heat wave in India as one of the 10 deadliest in world history.
"The deadly heat wave that has killed several hundred people in Karachi, Pakistan, is clearly a harbinger of things to come with the changing climate," Saleemul Huq, director of the International Center for Climate Change and Development in Bangladesh and a prominent climate scientist, told the Associated Press earlier this week.
"Even if this particular event cannot be unequivocally attributed to human-induced climate change, we can certainly expect such heat waves with greater frequency in future," he said.
Abdul Sattar Edhi, head of the charity Edhi Welfare Trust, sits on a wheelchair as he offers funeral prayers along with volunteers for the unclaimed heatwave victims in Karachi on June 26, 2015.
(Photo: RIZWAN TABASSUM, AFP/Getty Images)
303 CONNECT 201 TWEET 1 LINKEDIN 7 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1LzRYHy
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 22:24:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen kill scores of tourists at Tunisia beach resorts</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/97944246/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Gunmen-kill-scores-of-tourists-at-Tunisia-beach-resorts/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Gunmen kill scores of tourists at Tunisia beach resorts
Tourists comfort one and other at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort after unknown assailants detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels, killing more than 20, including Germans, Brits and Belgians and wounding several others - some while they were sunbathing.
Post to Facebook
Gunmen kill scores of tourists at Tunisia beach resorts Tourists comfort one and other at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort after unknown assailants detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels, killing more than 20, including Germans, Brits and Belgians and wounding several others - some while they were sunbathing. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1NjqJhK
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Gunmen kill scores of tourists at Tunisia beach resorts
Tourists comfort one and other at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort after unknown assailants detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels, killing more than 20, including Germans, Brits and Belgians and wounding several others - some while they were sunbathing.
Mohamed Messara, epa
A glass door shattered by a bullet at Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort in al-Sousse,Tunisia.
Mohamed Messara, epa
In the wake of today's shootings the pool and deck chairs at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel are deserted.
Mohamed Messara, epa
Fullscreen
Medics help an injured man in al-Sousse, Tunisia. According to local reports unknown assailants detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels, killing at least 27, mostly foreigners, and wounding several others, some while they were sunbathing.
epa
A tourist walks past blood stains on the ground at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort town of al-Sousse, a popular tourist destination in Tunisia.
Mohamed Messara, epa
In this screen grab taken from video provided by Tunisia TV1, injured people are treated on a Tunisian beach after two gunmen rushed from the beach into a hotel in the Tunisian resort town of Sousse. 
Tunisia TV1 via , ap
Injured people are treated on a Tunisian beach in the resort town of Sousse.
Tunisia TV1 via AP
An Instagram photo from one of the resort properties in Sousse, Tunisia where gunmen killed at least 27 people, mostly tourists.
vracarics, via Instagram
Security tries to control the scene as people gather on the streets in al-Sousse near the resorts where gunmen killed more than 25 people.
epa
A victim lies on a beach in al-Sousse, Tunisia. At least 27 people, mostly foreigners, are reported dead. While many others have been wounded.
epa
Members of the Tunisian security forces escort a man through a street in al-Sousse, Tunisia after assailants detonated at least one bomb then opened fire on tourists at two hotels.
epa
An Instagram photo from one of the resort properties in Sousse, Tunisia where gunmen killed at least 27 people, mostly tourists.
truemvp, via Instagram
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 22:34:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At least 27 dead in ISIL-claimed Kuwait attack</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/97919244/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~At-least-dead-in-ISILclaimed-Kuwait-attack/</Link>
        <Description>Islamic State says it's responsible for an explosion at a mosque in Kuwait City after Friday prayers.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
At least 27 dead in ISIL-claimed Kuwait attack
Islamic State says it is responsible for explosion that struck a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital after Friday prayers.
Post to Facebook
At least 27 dead in ISIL-claimed Kuwait attack Islamic State says it is responsible for explosion that struck a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital after Friday prayers. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Lzsr1b
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
13
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
At least 27 dead in ISIL-claimed Kuwait attack
Matthew Diebel , USATODAY 3:34 p.m. EDT June 26, 2015
The Islamic State claimed responsibility for a bombing attack on a Shiite mosque in Kuwait on Friday, which killed at least 24 people just after midday prayers. Reports of the death toll varied. USA TODAY
Kuwaiti security forces and emergency personnel gather outside the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers.
(Photo: Yasser Al-Zayyat, AFP/Getty Images)
1269 CONNECT 132 TWEET LINKEDIN 13 COMMENTEMAILMORE
A suicide bomber killed at least 27 at a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital after Friday prayers, in the nation's first terrorist attack in more than two decades.
The Islamic State claimed responsibility for the deadly explosion that wounded 227 others, according to the Ministry of the Interior. The militants this week had called for violence during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan.
The bombing in Kuwait City was one of three deadly attacks from Europe to the Middle East on Friday.
Kuwaiti lawmaker Khalil al-Salih,  who witnessed the attack, said the Imam Sadiq mosque was packed with about 2,000 people when the massive explosion went off, Reuters reported.
"It was obvious from the suicide bomber's body that he was young. He walked into the prayer hall during sujood (kneeling in prayer), he looked ... in his 20s, I saw him with my own eyes," he told the news agency.
Sunni-ruled Kuwait has a large Shiite minority. The Islamic State considers Shiites to be heretics.
Updates: Friday's terrorist attacks in Tunisia, France and Kuwait
Video footage showed several bodies on the floor of the mosque amid debris and clouds of heavy smoke, Al Jazeera reported. The nation's head of state, Emir Sabah Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al-Sabah, rushed to the scene.
A posting on a Twitter account known to belong to the Islamic State said the attack was carried out by a suicide bomber wearing an explosive belt, the Associated Press reported. The attack was claimed by an Islamic State affiliate calling itself the Najd Province, the same group that claimed a pair of bombing attacks on Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.
U.S.: No evidence yet linking Friday's deadly attacks
Friday's explosion rocked the al-Sawabir neighborhood, a residential and shopping district. Police formed a cordon around the mosque complex immediately after the explosion, the AP said, banning people from entering or gathering near the area.
"We couldn't see anything, so we went straight to the wounded and tried to carry them out. We left the dead," said witness Hassan al-Haddad, 21.
Abdullah al-Saffar, who was at the mosque, told the AP that the explosion took place just after midday Friday prayers  typically the most crowded of the week. Attendance increases during Ramadan, which started last week.
Another witness, Ahmad al-Shawaf, told the AP that worshipers were standing shoulder to shoulder in group prayer when the explosion struck near the door of the mosque. Al-Shawaf said the explosion took place near the end of a second prayer that is traditional to Shiites.
He said witnesses standing behind him said they saw a man walk in, stand in the back with other congregants and detonate his device.
Beheading, attack at gas factory in France; suspect detained
The attack was a "terrorist and cowardly action which threatens our nation and works at tearing apart the national unity,"  Yacoub al-Sanna, minister of Kuwaiti Justice, Religious Endowment and Islamic Affairs, said in a statement.
Al-Sanna told the official state news agency KUNA that the government would take all necessary measures to ensure protection of houses of worship. "Kuwait was and will remain the oasis of security and safety to all components of the Kuwaiti society and sects," he said.
Islamic State claims responsibility for Tunisian resort attack
Saad al-Ajmi, Kuwait's former information minister, told Al Jazeera the attack was a reminder that no country was immune from terrorism. Kuwait had "a good record" in its relationship between Sunni and Shiite groups, and is a small country with good security without widespread dissent, he said.
"I think that those who want to tip the whole region ablaze in a sectarian war would be behind this attack," he added, "because that is their agenda."
The last massive attack in Kuwait was in 1983, when Iranian-backed Shiite militants from Iraq carried out bombings that killed at least five people and targeted Western embassies.
Security forces, officials and civilians gather outside of the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a deadly blast struck after Friday prayers in Kuwait City.
(Photo: AP)
A Kuwaiti man with blood-stained clothes gathers himself at the site of a suicide bombing that targeted the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque.
(Photo: Yasser Al-Zayyat, AFP/Getty Images)
Kuwaiti security forces and emergency personnel gather outside the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers.
(Photo: Yasser Al-Zayyat, AFP/Getty Images)
Kuwaiti rescue workers carry a victim following a blast at Imam Sadiq Mosque in al-Sawaber, Kuwait City. At least eight people were killed in an explosion at the Shiite mosque during Friday prayers.
(Photo: Raed Qutena, epa)
A Kuwaiti man reacts at the site of a suicide bombing that targeted the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque.
(Photo: Yasser Al-Zayyat, AFP/Getty Images)
The aftermath of a deadly blast at the mosque in Kuwait City. A posting on a Twitter account known to belong to the Islamic State group claimed that the explosion was work of a suicide bomber wearing an explosive belt. 
(Photo: Kuwaitna News via, AP)
Kuwaiti security inspect the site of a suicide bombing that targeted the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City.
(Photo: Yasser Al-Zayyat, AFP/Getty Images)
Fullscreen
A man in a blood-soaked dishdasha following a deadly blast at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait City. A posting on a Twitter account known to belong to the Islamic State group claimed that the explosion was work of a suicide bomber wearing an explosive belt. 
(Photo: AP)
An injured man is helped to safety following a blast at Imam Sadiq Mosque in al-Sawaber, Kuwait City.
(Photo: Raed Qutena, epa)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 23:50:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beheading, attack at gas factory in France; suspect detained</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/97898294/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Beheading-attack-at-gas-factory-in-France-suspect-detained/</Link>
        <Description>Flags with Arabic inscriptions found at the scene.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Beheading, attack at gas factory in France; suspect detained
A man has been decapitated in a suspected "Islamist attack" on a gas factory near the southeastern French city Lyon, authorities said Friday.
Post to Facebook
Beheading, attack at gas factory in France; suspect detained A man has been decapitated in a suspected "Islamist attack" on a gas factory near the southeastern French city Lyon, authorities said Friday. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Lz3zGE
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
217
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Beheading, attack at gas factory in France; suspect detained
Kim Hjelmgaard and Aida Alami, USA TODAY 4:50 p.m. EDT June 26, 2015
A terror investigation is underway after a man was found decapitated and there was an explosion at an American-operated gas factory in France. The attack comes less than six months after the 'Charlie Hebdo' attack. VPC
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, on June 26, 2015.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
1667 CONNECT 397 TWEET 8 LINKEDIN 217 COMMENTEMAILMORE
A man once placed on a "radicalization list" drove his truck into a U.S.-owned gas factory Friday in the southeastern French city Lyon, triggering an explosion as his boss' severed head was found at the entrance, authorities said.
Banners with Arabic inscriptions were also found near the head.  Two people were injured in the explosion of gas canisters.
"Islamist terrorism has again struck France," Prime Minister Manuel Valls said.
The suspect was identified as Yassine Salhi, 35, the father of three children, French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said.
No group immediately claimed responsibility for the attack. It happened the same day as two other attacks, in Tunisia and Kuwait, but it was unknown yet if the incidents were related. A lone gunman attacked a beach resort in Tunisia popular with tourists, killing scores. And about two dozen people were killed in an Islamic State attack on a Shiite mosque in Kuwait during Friday prayers.
U.S.: No evidence yet linking Friday's deadly attacks
Paris Prosecutor Francois Molins said the suspect in the gas factory attack was known to workers because he made regular deliveries there. Molins said a knife and a decapitated body were found near the crashed truck.
He said four people are in custody: the alleged attacker, his wife, sister and another suspect. Investigators are trying to determine whether there are more accomplices.
French decapitation attack suspect was on 'radicalization list'
French police identified the victim as the manager of a transportation company in the Rhne region.
Cazeneuve said Salhi was known to French security forces who had placed him on a "radicalization list" because of suspected ties to the Islamic State, but he had not been previously arrested. Surveillance on Salhi was dropped in 2008.
Nevertheless, French President Francois Hollande described the suspect as a "terrorist" and said an anti-terrorism investigation has been opened.
Two flags  one black and one white  with Islamic declarations were found at the scene, Molins said.
Hollande said there was no doubt that the attacker's objective was to blow up the factory. He raised the region's security-alert status to its highest level for the next three days.
"Be assured that France will be protected and eradicate the groups or individuals responsible for these acts," Hollande said.
The Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, after a suspected Islamist assault in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates on June 26.
(Photo: Jean-Philippe Ksiazek, AFP/Getty Images)
French President Francois Hollande arrives for a news conference regarding the attack on the Air Products factory. Hollande cut short a visit to Brussels where he was participating in a European Union summit.
(Photo: Julien Warnand, epa)
In this screen grab taken from video provided by BFM TV, police stand at the scene outside the factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, France.
(Photo: AP)
President Hollande referred to the incident as a "terrorist attack," and said a "terrorist" in his thirties had been arrested.
(Photo: Julien Warnand, epa)
The french president said the decapitated body was found near the factory with inscriptions written on it in Arabic. Authoritieshave opened an anti-terrorism investigation.
(Photo: Laurent Cipriani, AP)
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, in eastern France.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
Investigating police officers work outside the plant, which is operated by Air Products, which is headquartered in Allentown, Pa.
(Photo: Laurent Cipriani, AP)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Tue May 26 17:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Battling Islamic State militants</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/87524922/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Battling-Islamic-State-militants/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Battling Islamic State militants
Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq.
Post to Facebook
Battling Islamic State militants Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1ChmkJu
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
5
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Battling Islamic State militants
Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters fire at Islamic State positions during a battle near the Baiji oil refinery.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters advance near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Shiite fighters hold a position near the Baiji oil refinery.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters hold a position against Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Sunni fighters battle Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Shiite fighters from the Popular Mobilization Units display an Iraqi national flag in front of an Islamic State mural on April 1 outside a presidential palace in Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government security forces celebrate in Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government soldiers battle Islamic State militants in Tikrit.
European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi counterterrorism forces patrol a street.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces deploy in the city.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi soldier guards a checkpoint.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi army tank advances in Tikrit on March 31 during a battle against Islamic State militants.  Iraqi Prime Minister Haider al-Abadi announced that Iraqi troops, supported by U.S.-led airstrikes, have recaptured most of the town from the Islamic State.
European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke rises during fighting in Tikrit.
European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi security forces conduct a house-to-house search for Islamic State militants on March 30 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces attack Islamic State extremists in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government troops watch an area outside the city. Islamic State militants have booby trapped streets and buildings in Tikrit with explosives.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi officer shouts orders.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces launch a rocket at Islamic State extremists.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security force soldiers run to a position as they surround Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi forces fire rockets at Islamic State positions in Tikrit on March 28.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government vehicles are positioned outside western Tikrit on March 27 during a military operation to retake the city from Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke billows from an air strike as Iraqi government troops hold a position outside Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government vehicles maneuver outside the city.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Explosions rock Tikrit as Iraqi security forces fire rockets against Islamic State militants.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi government vehicle drives to a position.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi security troops fire a mortar at positions held by Islamic State militants.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Smoke rises from buildings during a bombardment in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces fire a rocket at Islamic State militants on March 26 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi helicopter attacks Islamic State positions in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
A member of the Iraqi Shiite militant group the Imam Ali Brigades patrols in Tikrit on March 25.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
A volunteer fighter with the Shiite militant group Jihad Brigades fires his weapon at Islamic State militants on March 21 outside Tikrit, Iraq.
AP
Iraqi fighters with the Saraya al-Salam Brigade, a group formed by Iraqi Shiite Muslim cleric Moqtada al-Sadr, wave their weapons as they leave Najaf to join the fight against Islamic State militants on March 20.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi police leave Najaf to join government and coalition forces battling Islamic State militants in Tikrit.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A U.S. Navy jet takes off on March 19 from the aircraft carrier Carl Vinson on March 19 in the Persian Gulf. The Carl Vinson and French military jets from the French aircraft carrier Charles de Gaulle are flying missions over Iraq against Islamic State militants.
Hasan Jamali, AP
Iraqi security forces and allied Shiite militiamen battle Islamic State fighters in the Qadisiyah neighborhood in Tikrit on March 15.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Members of the group Soldiers of Imam Ali Brigade launch rockets against Islamic State extremists on March 15 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi army armored vehicle prepares to attack Islamic State positions on March 12 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government security forces patrol in Tikrit
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces and allied Shiite militiamen prepare to attack Islamic State extremists at Camp Speicher.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Shiite militiamen prepare to attack Islamic State extremists at Camp Speicher.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Shiite militiamen prepare to fire a mortar at Islamic State extremists in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi government soldier fires at Islamic State militants on March 11 in Tikrit.
AP
Iraqi government soldiers attack Islamic State militants as they attempt to recapture Tikrit. Iraqi soldiers and Shiite militiamen have entered Tikrit, the largest city controlled by the extremists.
AP
Iraqi government forces deploy during a military operation against Islamic State militants near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi government vehicle fires at Islamic State positions near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi pro-government fighters celebrate as they advance into Tikrit. Government forces are conducting a major military operation against Islamic State militants to recapture the city from the jihadist group.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi medics treat wounded fighters at a field hospital.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi fighter from the Popular Mobilization Unit holds a position as pro-government forces advance into Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
A member of a tribal group fighting alongside Iraqi government forces fires at Islamic State militants during a battle in the Hosh district in Ramadi.
Azhar Shallal, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi police officer aims a rocket-propelled grenade during clashes with Islamic State militants in the Hosh district of Ramadi.
Azhar Shallal, AFP/Getty Images
Members of the Popular Mobilization Unit celebrate with a captured Islamic State flag on March 9 after recapturing Albu Ajil village near Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces advance on Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government troops conduct a military operation against Islamic State militants in Albu Ajil village near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces drive toward Al-Alam village on March 8.
Younis Al-Bayati, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi soldier fires at Islamic State positions near Tikrit on March 4.
Iraqi Ministry of Defense via AP
Volunteer pro-government Shiite fighters with the Popular Mobilization Unit fire a howitzer at Islamic State militants on Feb. 28 at Awaynat near Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Egyptian military jet takes off from an undisclosed base on Feb. 16 to strike Islamic State targets in Libya. Egyptian warplanes bombed Islamic State positions in retaliation for the beheading of 21 Egyptian Coptic Christian hostages.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
A video image from an Egyptian warplane shows an airstrike on an Islamic State target in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
A video image shows a bomb hit on an Islamic State position in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
An image from Egypt's television station Al-Masriya shows a Egyptian F-16 fighter jet preparing to take off from an undisclosed location to conduct an airstrike on Islamic State targets in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A United Arab Emirates pilot prepares to take off in an F-16 on Feb. 10 at a base in Jordan. The United Arab Emirates launched airstrikes against Islamic State militants, marking the nation's return to combat operations after it halted flights in late 2014.
WAM via AP
A United Arab Emirates F-16 jet prepares for an airstrike against Islamic State targets at a base in Jordan.
WAM via AP
A Jordanian air force pilot writes a message to Islamic State militants on a missile at Mowafak Al-Salti airbase in Azraq on Feb. 6.
Roya TV via AP
Kayla Mueller speaks to a group on May 30, 2013, in Prescott, Ariz. The White House and her family confirmed the death of Mueller, who was being held by Islamic State militants, on Feb. 10.
Matt Hinshaw, The Daily Courier, via AP
Fullscreen
An image posted by the Islamic State on jihadist forums on Feb. 6 shows a heavily damaged building in Raqa, Syria, after it was allegedly targeted by a coalition airstrike. In a statement posted on jihadist websites the Islamic State group claims a female American hostage had been killed in a raid by coalition warplanes.
AFP/Getty Images
Thousands of people participate in a mass demonstration after Friday prayers near Al Hussein Mosque in Amman, Jordan, to express their solidarity with a Jordanian pilot murdered by the Islamic State group.
Jordan Pix, Getty Images
An image from the Jordanian television on Feb. 5 shows flames erupting from a building hit by an airstrike against Islamic State militants.
AFP/Getty Images
A Jordanian fighter jet takes off from an airbase.
Jordan News Agency via European Pressphoto Agency
A miltary officer writes a message on a missile. The Arabic words reads, "Will show them hell, from the Jordanian air force."
Jordan News Agency via European Pressphoto Agency
Fullscreen
Members of the Kurdish peshmerga forces and the Iraqi security forces patrol on a road as smoke billows from the Khubbaz oil field, some 15 miles west of the northern city of Kirkuk a few days after peshmerga forces and police retook the area from Islamic State group. 
Marwan Ibrahim, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
Members of the Yazidi minority search for clues that might lead them to missing relatives among the remains of those killed by the Islamic State jihadi group, a day after Kurdish forces discovered a mass grave near the Iraqi village of Sinuni, in the northwestern Sinjar area.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
Iraqi Shiite fighters celebrate in al-Mansuriya, in Iraq's Diyala province, after government forces retook the area from Islamic State group's control. Iraqi forces have "liberated" Diyala province from the Islamic State jihadist group, retaking all populated areas of the eastern region.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A Syrian Kurdish sniper sits among the rubble in the Syrian city of Ain al-Arab, also known as Kobani, Syria. The Islamic State group has acknowledged for the first time that its fighters were defeated there, but vowed to attack the town again.
AP
Fullscreen
A Syrian Kurdish sniper sits among the rubble in the Syrian city of Ain al-Arab, also known as Kobani, Syria. The Islamic State group has acknowledged for the first time that its fighters were defeated there, but vowed to attack the town again.
AP
Kurdish peshmerga fighters surround extremists inside a hotel near police headquarters in the oil-rich city of  Kirkuk, 180 miles north of Baghdad. 
AP
A Syrian Kurdish man walks among the rubble in Kobani.
AP
Rubble and damaged buildings are seen in the devastated Syrian city of Kobani.
AP
Fullscreen
Members of the Yazidi minority search for clues that might lead them to missing relatives among the remains of those killed by the Islamic State jihadi group, a day after Kurdish forces discovered a mass grave near the Iraqi village of Sinuni, in the northwestern Sinjar area.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
Members of the Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units stand on the back of a homemade armored vehicle as they patrol Kobani, Syria.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A member of Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units walks through rubble on a street in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A member of Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units walks through rubble in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A Kurdish peshmerga fighter aims his weapon as other fighters cross a bridge on Nov. 30 near Kirkuk, Iraq.
Marwan Ibrahim, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi soldier inspects destroyed trucks used by Islamic State militants near Amerli.
Ali Mohammed, European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi army soldiers deploy in front of a court building run by the Islamic State militants in Sadiyah on Nov. 24.
AP
A Kurdish People's Protection Units fighter looks at damage from a Nov. 19 truck bomb attack in Kobani, Syria.
Jake Simkin, AP
Islamic State militants stand on Tilsehir Hill near the Turkish border before an Oct. 23 airstrike in Yumurtalik village.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A bomb explodes on Tilsehir Hill.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
People in Turkey watch an explosion following an airstrike carried out by coalition forces.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A Kurdish refugee woman from Kobani, Syria, holds a child in a camp in Suruc.
Kutluhan Cucel, Getty Images
People warm themselves on a hilltop outside Suruc, Turkey. They've gathered to watch fighting across the border in Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises from an airstrike in Kobani, Syria. Kobani and its surrounding areas have been under assault by extremists of the Islamic State group since mid-September and are being defended by Kurdish fighters.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
U.S.-led coalition aircraft strike at Islamic State targets on Oct. 20 in Kobani, Syria.
AP
Kurdish people observe smoke rising from the Syrian town of Kobani following an explosion as seen from the southeastern Turkish village of Mursitpinar in the Sanliurfa province on Oct. 20.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A explosion during an allied airstrike rocks Kobani.
AP
People watch from a hill in Turkey as Syrian Kurdish fighters battle militants from the Islamic State in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Allied warplanes strike Islamic State positions.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
Shiite fighters loyal to Grand Ayatollah Ali al-Sistani fire missiles at Islamic State militants on Oct. 19 in Karbala, Iraq.
Mohammed Swaf, AFP/Getty Images
People gather on a hill outside Suruc, Turkey, to watch fighting between Syrian Kurds and Islamic State militants in Kobane, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
U.S. Navy Aviation Boatswain Mate Jessica Brown directs an aircraft on the flight deck of the aircraft carrier USS Carl Vinson as the ship conducts strike operations in Iraq and Syria.
U.S. Navy via European Pressphoto Agency
Syrian refugees walk through a camp in Suruc, Turkey.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A man uses the scope from a sniper rifle to watch fighting in Kobani, Syria, on Oct. 19.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty Images
Islamic State militants fight in Kobani on Oct. 19.
Aamaq News Agency via AFP/Getty Images
Kurdish fighters detonate an Islamic State land mine in Gwer district, northern Iraq.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
A bomb explodes during an Oct. 18 allied airstrike on Islamic State targets in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
A U.S. Air Force B1-B bomber flies above Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Shiite volunteers participate in a training session in Hillah.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
An explosion rocks Kobani, Syria, on Oct. 18 during an allied strike on Islamic State militants.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
An Islamic State fighter fires a heavy machine gun in Kobani on Oct. 17.
Aamaq News Agency via AFP/Getty Images
Thick smoke rises following an airstrike by the US-led coalition in Kobani, Syria as fighting continued between Syrian Kurds and the militants of Islamic State.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Iraqi federal policemen search a car at a checkpoint in Baghdad.
Karim Kadim, AP
A woman in Mursitpinar, Turkey, reacts as smoke rises from explosions after an Oct. 13 allied airstrike on Islamic State targets in Kobani, Syria.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Coalition aircraft bomb Islamic State positions in Kobani, Syria.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
Heavy smoke rises following an airstrike by allied aircraft.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty images
A vendor sells bread to people watching the ongoing bombing campaign in Kobani, Syria, on a hilltop outside Suruc, Turkey.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
People watch fighting between YPG Kurdish fighters and Islamic State militants in Kobani.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke rises from the Syrian town of Kobani after airstrikes on Islamic State fighters.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty Images
Rabia Ali mourns at the grave of her son, Seydo Mehmud, a Kurdish fighter, who was killed during a battle with Islamic State militants.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Civilians and Turkish military personnel watch fighting between Kurds and militants from the Islamic State group.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish Kurds watch fighting in Kobani.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty images
Smoke rises from Kobani near the Turkish-Syrian border.
Stringer, Getty images
Turkish armored vehicles hold a position on a hill above Kobani on Oct. 9.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
A Kurdish man watches fighting in Kobani, Syria, from a hill in Turkey.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke rises from an allied airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
A Turkish Kurd watches an airstrike in Kobani on Oct. 8.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Personnel on a Turkish army tank watch allied warplanes attack Islamic State targets in Kobani, Syria.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A  plume of smoke rises after an airstrike in eastern Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish Kurds watch an airstrike in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises after an allied airstrike against an Islamic State target in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Turkish Kurds in Mursitpinar, Turkey, watch fighting between Kurdish forces and Islamic State militants in Kobani, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
An allied airstrike hits Islamic State targets in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Turkish armored vehicles patrol the Turkish-Syrian border in Sanliurfa province.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke rises after an airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Turkish Kurds in Turkey watch fighting in Kobani, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish troops watch the results of an airstrike in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Fullscreen
Smoke rises after an airstrike by allied forces against Islamic State targets on Oct. 7 in the Syrian town of Kobani near Suruc district, Turkey. Airstrikes targeted three groups of Islamic State militants in the first daytime action in Syria by U.S.-led coalition forces.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke from an explosion after an allied airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Turkish soldiers stand near their armored vehicles as they hold a position outside Suruc, near the Turkey-Syria border.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises from an explosion in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
An Iraqi military vehicle burns after an Islamic State attack in western Anbar province on Oct. 5.
AP
A photograph from the British Ministry of Defense shows the result of a Brimstone missile strike on an armed Islamic State truck on Sept. 30 in Iraq. The Brimstone missile is circled in red moments before impact.
Ministry of Defense via AP
A British Ministry of Defense photograph shows the result of a missile attack on an Islamic State truck in Iraq.
Ministry of Defense via AP
A British Royal Air Force Tornado GR4 aircraft lands after a mission over Iraq at the Akrotiri airbase in Cyprus.
Cpl. Neil Bryden, Royal Air Force, via AP
Iraqi Shiite militiamen battle Islamic State militants on Sept. 29 in Jurf al-Sakhar.
AP
A Department of Defense photograph released on Sept. 29 shows a pair of U.S. Air Force F-15E Strike Eagles flying over northern Iraq on Sept. 23.
Matthew Brusch, U.S. Air Force, via European Pressphoto Agency
A Sept. 26 photograph released by the U.S. Air Force shows a KC-10 Extender refueling an F-22 Raptor fighter aircraft before a strike operation against Islamic State targets in Syria.
Tech. Sgt. Russ Scalf, U.S. Air Force, via AP
Two photographs provided by the Pentagon on Sept. 25 shows before and after images of an airstrike on the Jerible Modular oil refinery in Syria.
Department of Defense via AP
Two photographs provided by the Pentagon shows before and after images of an allied airstrike on the Gbiebi Modular oil refinery.
Department of Defense via AP
A U.S. Navy F-18E Super Hornet receives fuel from a U.S. Air Force KC-135 Stratotanker over northern Iraq after conducting airstrikes on Islamic State targets in Syria.
Staff Sgt. Shawn Nickel, U.S. Air Force, via AP
A formation of U.S. Navy F-18E Super Hornets leaves after receiving fuel from a U.S. Air Force KC-135 Stratotanker over northern Iraq.
Staff Sgt. Shawn Nickel, U.S. Air Force, via AP
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Sat May 23 21:24:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ireland legalizes gay marriage</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/92962503/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Ireland-legalizes-gay-marriage/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Ireland legalizes gay marriage
Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum.
Post to Facebook
Ireland legalizes gay marriage Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Stu56b
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
9
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Ireland legalizes gay marriage
Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Irish Sen. Katherine Zappone, left, kisses her partner, Ann Louise Gilligan, as supporters for same-sex marriage wait for the result of the referendum at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
A man blows bubbles as supporters for same-sex marriage waited for the result of the referendum at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Supporters wait for the final result in the Irish referendum at Dublin Castle.
Peter Morrison, AP
Supporters wait for the final result in the Irish referendum at Dublin Castle.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Peter Morrison, AP
Michael Barron, right, and Jamie Nanci, who were married in Cape Town, South Africa, kiss at the RDS count center in Dublin.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
