<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="USATODAY">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:30:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds of thousands gather for pope Mass in Ecuador</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99511762/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Hundreds-of-thousands-gather-for-pope-Mass-in-Ecuador/</Link>
        <Description>The pope returned to South America for the first time as pontiff Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Hundreds of thousands gather for pope Mass in Ecuador
QUITO, Ecuador (AP)  Pope Francis travels to the Ecuadorean port of Guayaquil on Monday for a Mass expected to draw more than 1 million people, as Latin America's first pontiff tours his home continent bringing a message of compassion for the weak and respect for an ailing planet.
Post to Facebook
Hundreds of thousands gather for pope Mass in Ecuador QUITO, Ecuador (AP)  Pope Francis travels to the Ecuadorean port of Guayaquil on Monday for a Mass expected to draw more than 1 million people, as Latin America's first pontiff tours his home continent bringing a message of compassion for the weak and respect for an ailing planet. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1M6tySV
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
8
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Hundreds of thousands gather for pope Mass in Ecuador
AP 7:30 p.m. EDT July 6, 2015
Ecuadoran President Rafael Correa gave a warm welcome to Pope Francis upon his arrival to the Mariscal Sucre International airport in Quito. Newslook
Pope Francis waves to the crowd during his visit to Guayaquil, Ecuador, July 6, 2015.
(Photo: Leonardo Munoz, EPA)
1661 CONNECT 65 TWEET 1 LINKEDIN 8 COMMENTEMAILMORE
GUAYAQUIL, Ecuador (AP)  Hundreds of thousands of people filled a park in Ecuador's main port city Monday for Pope Francis' first big event of his three-nation South American tour, hoping for a glimpse of Latin America's first pope returning to his home soil for a Mass dedicated to the family.
Many pilgrims spent the night outdoors, and some walked for miles to reach the park on Guayaquil's northern outskirts where the crowd sang hymns and sought pockets of shade to keep cool amid the scorching sun and high humidity. Firefighters sprayed them with water hoses to provide relief.
"I'm tired. I'm hungry, I haven't slept but I'm also full of emotion and joy in my heart," said Vicente Huilcatoma, a 47-year-old retired police officer who walked 25 miles to reach Samanes Park.
The Vatican had originally estimated more than 1 million people would turn out for the Mass, and government organizers put the crowd at above 1 million people in the hour before the service began. But Gabriel Almeida, the government spokesman at the scene, rolled back the estimate to several hundred thousand after officials viewed aerial images of the area.
Across the park, Ecuadoran national flags and papal banners waved above the enormous sea of people, who were divided into quadrants that Francis looped around slowly on his popemobile to cheers of "Francisco! Francisco!"
In his homily, Francis praised families as the bedrock of society  "the nearest hospital, the first school for the young, the best home for the elderly"  and said miracles are performed every day inside a family out of love. But he said sometimes the love and happiness runs out.
"How many women, sad and lonely, wonder when love left, when it slipped away from their lives?" he asked. "How many elderly people feel left out of family celebrations, cast aside and longing each day for a little love?"
Francis has dedicated the first two years of his pontificate to family issues, giving weekly catechism lessons on different aspects of family life and inviting the entire church to study ways to provide better pastoral care for Catholic families, people who are divorced, gays and families in "nontraditional" situations.
A preliminary meeting of bishops on these issues ended last year in bitter divisions between liberals and conservatives, particularly over ministering to gays and to Catholics who divorce and remarry outside of the church. Church teaching holds that Catholics who enter into a second marriage without having the first one annulled cannot receive Communion.
In his homily Monday, Francis said he hoped the second meeting of bishops on family life, scheduled for October, would come up with "concrete solutions to the many difficult and significant challenges facing families in our time."
"I ask you to pray fervently for this intention, so that Christ can take even what might seem to us impure, scandalous or threatening, and turn it ... into a miracle."
"Families today need miracles!" he added.
The Vatican spokesman, the Rev. Federico Lombardi, said Francis wasn't referring to the gay or divorce issue specifically but was making a more general reference that he hoped the bishops would "help the church chart this path of leaving a situation of sin to one of grace."
On his arrival in Guayaquil, the pontiff allowed several acolytes on the tarmac to take selfies with him. He then headed to the Shrine of the Divine Mercy, where 2,000 invitees gathered including child cancer patients, residents of homes for the elderly abandoned by their families and some of Guayaquil's poorest people.
He told those gathered that he would pray for them "and I won't charge you a thing. All I ask, please, is that you pray for me."
The crowd in Los Samanes park was festive, with young and old overjoyed at seeing the first pope in their lives.
"I'll ask the pope to intercede so that God gives me my health," said 90-year-old Guillermina Aveiga Davila, who arrived at dawn from the coastal city of Chone, some 300 kilometers  away. "I want to reach 100."
After the open-air Mass, a private lunch was planned with a group of Jesuits.
A highlight was to be a reunion with the Rev. Francisco Cortes, a priest affectionately known as "Padre Paquito," to whom the Argentina-born pope, then the Rev. Jorge Mario Bergoglio, entrusted his seminarians on study trips to Ecuador years ago.
In a recent interview with The Associated Press, Cortes couldn't fathom that Bergoglio remembered him, much less made a point of coming to have lunch.
"I don't know what to ask him," the soon-to-be 91-year-old Cortes said. "He said he wanted to see me and I'm amazed that he's coming. For the first time, I have known a pope.
The "pope of the poor" returned to Spanish-speaking South America for the first time as pontiff Sunday, stressing the importance of protecting the needy and the environment from exploitation and  in a nation whose president was booed as his vehicle followed the papal motorcade Sunday  to foster dialogue among all sectors of society. It's a message he's expected to repeat during his next stops in Bolivia and Paraguay, South America's two poorest countries.
Francis' only other trip back to Latin America since being elected pope was in 2013, when he visited Brazil, where Portuguese is the main language.
Francis' environmental message  from a pope who last month issued a treatise staking the Earth's preservation as a core mission for humanity  is particularly relevant for Ecuador, a Pacific nation that is home to one of the world's most species-diverse ecosystems but is also an OPEC country heavily dependent on oil. High crude prices allowed Correa to lift 1.3 million people out of poverty in his eight years in office.
But now that prices have fallen, the generous social safety net Correa has woven is threatened. He's had to cut government spending and been buffeted for nearly a month by the most serious anti-government street protests of his tenure.
Along Francis' motorcade route, the crowds alternated chants of adulation for the pontiff with jeers of "Correa out!" when the president's entourage followed.
Correa also has angered environmentalists and the nation's main indigenous group, CONAIE, by moving forward with oil drilling and mining projects in pristine Amazon forests.
1661 CONNECT 65 TWEET 1 LINKEDIN 8 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1M6tySV
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:48:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Olé! The Running of the Bulls festival begins</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99607126/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Ol%c3%a9-The-Running-of-the-Bulls-festival-begins/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Ol! The Running of the Bulls festival begins
People watch as Jandilla fighting bulls and revelers run during the running of the bulls at the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
Post to Facebook
Ol! The Running of the Bulls festival begins People watch as Jandilla fighting bulls and revelers run during the running of the bulls at the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IFoAOl
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
2
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Ol! The Running of the Bulls festival begins
People watch as Jandilla fighting bulls and revelers run during the running of the bulls at the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
Andres Kudacki, AP
A reveler falls while others run with a Jandilla's ranch fighting bull during the running of the bulls of the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP
A reveler is tossed by a cow with dull horns during a celebration held at the bullring after the running of the bulls of the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP
Revelers wearing a local traditional outfit march during the San Fermin procession in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
Andres Kudacki, AP
Revelers gather to watch Jandilla fighting bulls running at the San Fermin festival, in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
Andres Kudacki, AP
Fullscreen
Revelers run with fighting bulls during the running of the bulls at the Fiestas de San Fermin in Pamplona, Spain, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The festival, locally known as Sanfermines, is held annually from July 6-14 in commemoration of the city's patron saint.
Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP
People from around the world gather for the event.
Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP
The 'Toro de Fuego' (flaming bull) chases revelers through the streets during the opening day.
Pablo Blazquez Dominguez
Revelers gathered on City Hall Square celebrate after the firing of the txupinazo rocket, which marks the official beginning of the festival.
Daniel Fernandez, EPA
Fullscreen
A band performs during the opening day or 'Chupinazo.' Hundreds of thousands of visitors from all over the world attend the nine-day fiesta. Many of them participate in the highlight event: The running of the bulls - or encierro - where they attempt to outrun the bulls along an approximately half-mile-long route through the narrow streets of the old city.
Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images
Revelers hold their red scarves as mark the kickoff at noon sharp of the San Fermin Festival.
Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images
Not for the claustrophobic! Revelers squeeze through Pamplona's City Hall Square.
Ander Gillenea, AFP/Getty Images
A man gets some air as he's tossed about during the  launch of the chupinazo rocket.
Alvaro Barrientos, AP
A reveler wearing a bull earring enjoys the atmosphere during the opening day of the Running of the Bulls fiesta.
Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images
Festival goers soak each other with wine.
Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images
Ivy Mix from Brooklyn, N.Y., is given a drink of sangria.
Jim Hollander, EPA
Revelers throw a bucket of water from a balcony onto the crowd.
Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images
And below the balcony, the water lands on party goers.
Alvaro Barrientos, AP
A red-and-white-clad sea of revelers soaked each other with wine in a packed Pamplona square Monday.
Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images
Revelers from around the world kick off the festival. Tuesday is the first of eight days of the running of the bulls.
Alvaro Barrientos, AP
A woman is sprayed with water as she celebrates.
Ander Gillenea, AFP/Getty Images
A sea of participants hold red scarves as they celebrate.
MIGUEL RIOPA, AFP/Getty Images
A reveler jumps from a fountain onto the crowd below.
Andres Kudacki, AP
A  reveler drinks wine during San Fermin Fiestas. Many others wore it, as their formerly white T shirts attest.
Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP
People enjoy the atmosphere during the opening day of the Running of the Bulls festival.
Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images
Streets too much? Some people choose to witness the celebration from balconies.
Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images
Sangria is the drink of choice, taken from a plastic bottle as partying continues.
Jim Hollander, EPA
People-surfing/people-tossing is just part of the atmosphere.
Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images
As long as you wear red and white, anything goes.
Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:12:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Merkel: Door is open but time is short</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99742438/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Merkel-Door-is-open-but-time-is-short/</Link>
        <Description>German Chancellor Angela Merkel is among the European leaders in Brussels trying to seal a last-ditch attempt to secure a rescue deal for Greece to keep the country in the euro region.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Merkel: Door is open but time is short
German Chancellor Angela Merkel is among the European leaders in Brussels trying to seal a last-ditch attempt to secure a rescue deal for Greece to keep the country in the euro region.
Post to Facebook
Merkel: Door is open but time is short German Chancellor Angela Merkel is among the European leaders in Brussels trying to seal a last-ditch attempt to secure a rescue deal for Greece to keep the country in the euro region. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IGGmk8
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Merkel: Door is open but time is short
German Chancellor Angela Merkel is among the European leaders in Brussels trying to seal a last-ditch attempt to secure a rescue deal for Greece to keep the country in the euro region. Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:59:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Little hope in Gaza ruins a year after devastating war</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99740302/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Little-hope-in-Gaza-ruins-a-year-after-devastating-war/</Link>
        <Description>This week marks one year since Israel's devastating war with Palestinian militants in Gaza, and despite a ceasefire that has largely held, there has been little reason for residents caught up in the conflict to believe their suffering will soon end.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Little hope in Gaza ruins a year after devastating war
This week marks one year since Israel's devastating war with Palestinian militants in Gaza, and despite a ceasefire that has largely held, there has been little reason for residents caught up in the conflict to believe their suffering will soon end.
Post to Facebook
Little hope in Gaza ruins a year after devastating war This week marks one year since Israel's devastating war with Palestinian militants in Gaza, and despite a ceasefire that has largely held, there has been little reason for residents caught up in the conflict to believe their suffering will soon end. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MaE2Ri
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Little hope in Gaza ruins a year after devastating war
This week marks one year since Israel's devastating war with Palestinian militants in Gaza, and despite a ceasefire that has largely held, there has been little reason for residents caught up in the conflict to believe their suffering will soon end. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:56:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis celebrates Ecuador mass with huge crowd</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99740304/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Pope-Francis-celebrates-Ecuador-mass-with-huge-crowd/</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis celebrates an open-air mass with hundreds of thousands of faithful under scorching heat in Ecuador on Monday, calling for more help for families on his return to his home region.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Pope Francis celebrates Ecuador mass with huge crowd
Pope Francis celebrates an open-air mass with hundreds of thousands of faithful under scorching heat in Ecuador on Monday, calling for more help for families on his return to his home region.
Post to Facebook
Pope Francis celebrates Ecuador mass with huge crowd Pope Francis celebrates an open-air mass with hundreds of thousands of faithful under scorching heat in Ecuador on Monday, calling for more help for families on his return to his home region. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IGEs34
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Pope Francis celebrates Ecuador mass with huge crowd
Pope Francis celebrates an open-air mass with hundreds of thousands of faithful under scorching heat in Ecuador on Monday, calling for more help for families on his return to his home region. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:41:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tsipras urged to forge speedy deal with creditors</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99737978/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Tsipras-urged-to-forge-speedy-deal-with-creditors/</Link>
        <Description>Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras was given hours to come up with a plan to keep his country in the euro as citizens endure a second week of capital controls. German Chancellor Angela Merkel said "time is running out."</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Tsipras urged to forge speedy deal with creditors
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras was given hours to come up with a plan to keep his country in the euro as citizens endure a second week of capital controls. German Chancellor Angela Merkel said "time is running out."
Post to Facebook
Tsipras urged to forge speedy deal with creditors Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras was given hours to come up with a plan to keep his country in the euro as citizens endure a second week of capital controls. German Chancellor Angela Merkel said "time is running out." Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MaARsW
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Tsipras urged to forge speedy deal with creditors
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras was given hours to come up with a plan to keep his country in the euro as citizens endure a second week of capital controls. German Chancellor Angela Merkel said "time is running out." Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:34:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Today Is the 10th Anniversary of London's 7/7 Bombings</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99737982/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Today-Is-the-th-Anniversary-of-Londons-Bombings/</Link>
        <Description>Bloomberg's Vonnie Quinn highlights photos that illustrate top stories from around the world.</Description>
        <MainBody>Today Is the 10th Anniversary of London's 7/7 Bombings
Bloomberg's Vonnie Quinn highlights photos that illustrate top stories from around the world.
Post to Facebook
Today Is the 10th Anniversary of London's 7/7 Bombings Bloomberg's Vonnie Quinn highlights photos that illustrate top stories from around the world. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Mazs5z
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Today Is the 10th Anniversary of London's 7/7 Bombings
Bloomberg's Vonnie Quinn highlights photos that illustrate top stories from around the world. Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:24:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>2 Americans, 1 Briton gored in Pamplona bull run</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99736138/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Americans-Briton-gored-in-Pamplona-bull-run/</Link>
        <Description>One American was gored in the armpit, while the Briton was gored in the groin.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
2 Americans, 1 Briton gored in Pamplona bull run
Two Americans and a Briton were gored and eight others injured Tuesday as thousands of daredevils dashed alongside fighting bulls through the streets of this northern Spanish city.
Post to Facebook
2 Americans, 1 Briton gored in Pamplona bull run Two Americans and a Briton were gored and eight others injured Tuesday as thousands of daredevils dashed alongside fighting bulls through the streets of this northern Spanish city. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Maz1sb
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
12
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
2 Americans, 1 Briton gored in Pamplona bull run
Alvaro Barrientos and Ciaran Giles, Associated Press 8:24 a.m. EDT July 7, 2015
People watch as Jandilla fighting bulls and revelers run during the running of the bulls at the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
A reveler falls while others run with a Jandilla's ranch fighting bull during the running of the bulls of the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
A reveler is tossed by a cow with dull horns during a celebration held at the bullring after the running of the bulls of the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
Revelers wearing a local traditional outfit march during the San Fermin procession in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
Revelers gather to watch Jandilla fighting bulls running at the San Fermin festival, in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
Fullscreen
Revelers run with fighting bulls during the running of the bulls at the Fiestas de San Fermin in Pamplona, Spain, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The festival, locally known as Sanfermines, is held annually from July 6-14 in commemoration of the city's patron saint.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
People from around the world gather for the event.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
The 'Toro de Fuego' (flaming bull) chases revelers through the streets during the opening day.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez)
Revelers gathered on City Hall Square celebrate after the firing of the txupinazo rocket, which marks the official beginning of the festival.
(Photo: Daniel Fernandez, EPA)
Fullscreen
A band performs during the opening day or 'Chupinazo.' Hundreds of thousands of visitors from all over the world attend the nine-day fiesta. Many of them participate in the highlight event: The running of the bulls - or encierro - where they attempt to outrun the bulls along an approximately half-mile-long route through the narrow streets of the old city.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Revelers hold their red scarves as mark the kickoff at noon sharp of the San Fermin Festival.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Not for the claustrophobic! Revelers squeeze through Pamplona's City Hall Square.
(Photo: Ander Gillenea, AFP/Getty Images)
A man gets some air as he's tossed about during the  launch of the chupinazo rocket.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
A reveler wearing a bull earring enjoys the atmosphere during the opening day of the Running of the Bulls fiesta.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Festival goers soak each other with wine.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Ivy Mix from Brooklyn, N.Y., is given a drink of sangria.
(Photo: Jim Hollander, EPA)
Revelers throw a bucket of water from a balcony onto the crowd.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
And below the balcony, the water lands on party goers.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
A red-and-white-clad sea of revelers soaked each other with wine in a packed Pamplona square Monday.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Revelers from around the world kick off the festival. Tuesday is the first of eight days of the running of the bulls.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
A woman is sprayed with water as she celebrates.
(Photo: Ander Gillenea, AFP/Getty Images)
A sea of participants hold red scarves as they celebrate.
(Photo: MIGUEL RIOPA, AFP/Getty Images)
A reveler jumps from a fountain onto the crowd below.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
A  reveler drinks wine during San Fermin Fiestas. Many others wore it, as their formerly white T shirts attest.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
People enjoy the atmosphere during the opening day of the Running of the Bulls festival.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Streets too much? Some people choose to witness the celebration from balconies.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Sangria is the drink of choice, taken from a plastic bottle as partying continues.
(Photo: Jim Hollander, EPA)
People-surfing/people-tossing is just part of the atmosphere.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
As long as you wear red and white, anything goes.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:27:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Grenades, other explosives stolen from French military site</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99736140/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Grenades-other-explosives-stolen-from-French-military-site/</Link>
        <Description>The break-in comes as France has strengthened its security measures after two deadly attacks by extremists this year.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Grenades, other explosives stolen from French military site
PARIS (AP)  French authorities are investigating the theft of roughly 200 detonators plus grenades and plastic explosives from a military site in southeastern France, officials said Tuesday.
Post to Facebook
Grenades, other explosives stolen from French military site PARIS (AP)  French authorities are investigating the theft of roughly 200 detonators plus grenades and plastic explosives from a military site in southeastern France, officials said Tuesday. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MayqGS
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
6
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Grenades, other explosives stolen from French military site
Associated Press 7:27 a.m. EDT July 7, 2015
A picture taken on July 7, 2015 in the French southern city of Miramas partially shows a regional military ammunition camp where at least 150 detonators and plastic explosives were stolen on the night of July 5 to 6.
(Photo: ANNE-CHRISTINE POUJOULAT, AFP/Getty Images)
5 CONNECT 47 TWEET LINKEDIN 6 COMMENTEMAILMORE
PARIS (AP)  French authorities are investigating the theft of roughly 200 detonators plus grenades and plastic explosives from a military site in southeastern France, officials said Tuesday.
The thefts at the Miramas site, which is operated by a combination of military services west of Marseille, appeared to have occurred overnight from Sunday to Monday. The break-in comes as France has strengthened its security measures after two deadly attacks by extremists this year.
Marseille prosecutor Brice Robin said in a statement that an investigation has started on charges of "theft with break-in carried out by a criminal group" and "fraudulent entry into a military compound."
An official with the gendarmerie police force, which generally runs law enforcement in more rural areas of France, said the thief or thieves appeared to have cut through a fence to enter the high-security site. The official was not authorized to speak publicly because the operation is ongoing.
The Defense Ministry and a top spokesman for the French military did not immediately respond to calls and text messages from The Associated Press seeking details.
Mayor Frederic Vigouroux of Miramas told the AP he did not know precisely what was stolen, but said it was the first theft at the site. He said the outer fences were broken into, and that nine storehouses were affected.
"It wasn't cotton candy that was stolen," he said. "These are dangerous munitions. Everything is inherently dangerous."
France has been on its highest level of alert for terrorism following deadly attacks in January and June.
The base, about 200 hectares (500 acres), sits on the outskirts of the town of 30,000 and stocks munitions of the type used in French military operations in Mali and Afghanistan.
___
5 CONNECT 47 TWEET LINKEDIN 6 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1MayqGS
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:16:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man arrested for flying helium-balloon-assisted lawn chair over Canada</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99734338/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Man-arrested-for-flying-heliumballoonassisted-lawn-chair-over-Canada/</Link>
        <Description>A Canadian man is arrested after parachuting from a lawn chair tied to helium balloons.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man arrested for flying helium-balloon-assisted lawn chair over Canada
A Canadian man is arrested after parachuting from a lawn chair tied to helium balloons.
Post to Facebook
Man arrested for flying helium-balloon-assisted lawn chair over Canada A Canadian man is arrested after parachuting from a lawn chair tied to helium balloons. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MawqOT
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Man arrested for flying helium-balloon-assisted lawn chair over Canada
A Canadian man is arrested after parachuting from a lawn chair tied to helium balloons. Buzz60
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:10:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear talks on verge of missing deadline</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99734342/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Iran-nuclear-talks-on-verge-of-missing-deadline/</Link>
        <Description>The deadline for a nuclear deal between Iran and world powers could be missed. Iranian authorities say an agreement that could lift sanctions isn't assured even as differences between negotiations continue to narrow.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Iran nuclear talks on verge of missing deadline
The deadline for a nuclear deal between Iran and world powers could be missed. Iranian authorities say an agreement that could lift sanctions isn't assured even as differences between negotiations continue to narrow.
Post to Facebook
Iran nuclear talks on verge of missing deadline The deadline for a nuclear deal between Iran and world powers could be missed. Iranian authorities say an agreement that could lift sanctions isn't assured even as differences between negotiations continue to narrow. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IGAreZ
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
2
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Iran nuclear talks on verge of missing deadline
The deadline for a nuclear deal between Iran and world powers could be missed. Iranian authorities say an agreement that could lift sanctions isn't assured even as differences between negotiations continue to narrow. Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:55:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Echoes of 7/7 in Cameron's new anti-terror push</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99731720/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Echoes-of-in-Camerons-new-antiterror-push/</Link>
        <Description>As Britain commemorates the tenth anniversary of the London subway bombings, Prime Minister David Cameron is preparing for a new anti-terrorism push.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Echoes of 7/7 in Cameron's new anti-terror push
As Britain commemorates the tenth anniversary of the London subway bombings, Prime Minister David Cameron is preparing for a new anti-terrorism push.
Post to Facebook
Echoes of 7/7 in Cameron's new anti-terror push As Britain commemorates the tenth anniversary of the London subway bombings, Prime Minister David Cameron is preparing for a new anti-terrorism push. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1MasMVe
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Echoes of 7/7 in Cameron's new anti-terror push
As Britain commemorates the tenth anniversary of the London subway bombings, Prime Minister David Cameron is preparing for a new anti-terrorism push. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:52:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain marks 10th anniversary of 7/7 terror attacks</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99724306/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Britain-marks-th-anniversary-of-terror-attacks/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Britain marks 10th anniversary of 7/7 terror attacks
Britain was on Tuesday marking 10 years since 52 people were killed in a terror attack on London's transport system on July 7, 2005. Prime Minister David Cameron, left, prepares to lay a wreath at the memorial to the victims in Hyde Park, London.
Post to Facebook
Britain marks 10th anniversary of 7/7 terror attacks Britain was on Tuesday marking 10 years since 52 people were killed in a terror attack on London's transport system on July 7, 2005. Prime Minister David Cameron, left, prepares to lay a wreath at the memorial to the victims in Hyde Park, London. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IGvgvw
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Britain marks 10th anniversary of 7/7 terror attacks
Britain was on Tuesday marking 10 years since 52 people were killed in a terror attack on London's transport system on July 7, 2005. Prime Minister David Cameron, left, prepares to lay a wreath at the memorial to the victims in Hyde Park, London.
Anthony Devlin, AFP/Getty Images
Cameron, right, and London Mayor Boris Johnson walk through the memorial with their wreaths.
Matt Dunham, AP
The 7/7 memorial has 52 columns -- one for each victim of the attacks.
Andy Rain, EPA
A flower lies on a plaque bearing the names of the victims.
Matt Dunham, AP
A man prays near a plaque commemorating the victims of the bombing of a double-decker bus near Tavistock Square in central London. Three other bombs were set off in underground train stations during the morning rush hour.
Peter Macdiarmid, Getty Images
A message from David Cameron is pictured among floral tributes in Hyde Park.
Niklas Halle'n, AFP/Getty Images
Members of the emergency services observe a minute's silence to remember the victims under the big screen at Wimbledon.
Adrian Dennis, AFP/Getty Images
The Dean of St Paul's Cathedral, David Ison, greets Lord Mayor of London Alan Yarrow at the anniversary service at the cathedral.
Ian Gavan, Getty Images
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:49:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>African game-hunters defend the right to shoot</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99729852/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~African-gamehunters-defend-the-right-to-shoot/</Link>
        <Description>Some consider it a cruel and barbaric sport -- but South Africa's professional hunters defend trophy hunting as a key element in wildlife conservation, generating money for the country's nature reserves.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
African game-hunters defend the right to shoot
Some consider it a cruel and barbaric sport -- but South Africa's professional hunters defend trophy hunting as a key element in wildlife conservation, generating money for the country's nature reserves.
Post to Facebook
African game-hunters defend the right to shoot Some consider it a cruel and barbaric sport -- but South Africa's professional hunters defend trophy hunting as a key element in wildlife conservation, generating money for the country's nature reserves. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IGziUN
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
African game-hunters defend the right to shoot
Some consider it a cruel and barbaric sport -- but South Africa's professional hunters defend trophy hunting as a key element in wildlife conservation, generating money for the country's nature reserves. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:37:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek banks still closed: what’s next?</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99729860/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Greek-banks-still-closed-what%e2%80%99s-next/</Link>
        <Description>After Greek voters declined the bailout referendum Sunday, the implications of this historic event are still unclear. USA TODAY world editor Owen Ullmann discusses the possible fallout with producer Shannon Rae Green.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Greek banks still closed: whats next?
After Greek voters declined the bailout referendum Sunday, the implications of this historic event are still unclear. USA TODAY world editor Owen Ullmann discusses the possible fallout with producer Shannon Rae Green.
Post to Facebook
Greek banks still closed: whats next? After Greek voters declined the bailout referendum Sunday, the implications of this historic event are still unclear. USA TODAY world editor Owen Ullmann discusses the possible fallout with producer Shannon Rae Green. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IGyoYg
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Greek banks still closed: whats next?
After Greek voters declined the bailout referendum Sunday, the implications of this historic event are still unclear. USA TODAY world editor Owen Ullmann discusses the possible fallout with producer Shannon Rae Green. Owen Ullmann, Shannon Rae Green, Jasper Colt, USA TODAY
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:33:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain marks 10th anniversary of London 7/7 bombings</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99724304/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Britain-marks-th-anniversary-of-London-bombings/</Link>
        <Description>The worst terror attack on U.K. soil killed 52 people and injured nearly 800.</Description>
        <MainBody>Britain marks 10th anniversary of London 7/7 bombings
Britain marks 10th anniversary of 7/7 London terrorist bombings.
Post to Facebook
Britain marks 10th anniversary of London 7/7 bombings Britain marks 10th anniversary of 7/7 London terrorist bombings. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IGvFhr
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
8
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Britain marks 10th anniversary of London 7/7 bombings
Jane Onyanga-Omara , USA TODAY 9:13 a.m. EDT July 7, 2015
As Britain commemorates the tenth anniversary of the London subway bombings, Prime Minister David Cameron is preparing for a new anti-terrorism push. Newslook
A forensic officer walks next to the wreckage of a double-decker bus with its top blown off and damaged cars scattered on the road at Tavistock Square in central London after the terrorist attack on July 7, 2005.
(Photo: Sang Tan, AP)
412 CONNECT 132 TWEET 3 LINKEDIN 8 COMMENTEMAILMORE
LONDON   It's been a decade since Esther Hyman's sister, Miriam, was killed when four suicide bombers unleashed carnage on this city's public transportation system in the worst terrorist attack on British soil.
Miriam Hyman, 32, a picture researcher, was on her way to work on July 7, 2005, when the double-decker bus she was on exploded in Tavistock Square in central London. Three other bombs were detonated in underground stations by four Islamist terrorists during the morning rush hour.
The attacks  killed 52 people and injured nearly 800.
"As I said at her funeral, I can still remember when Miriam was in my mummy's tummy. She was born when I was just over 3 1/2, and I was very, very excited," Esther Hyman told USA TODAY. "She's an irreplaceable person in my life."
Tunisia: 8 suspected in hotel attack probe
Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron and Mayor of London Boris Johnson were  among those who laid wreaths at the memorial to the 52 victims in Hyde Park in the capital on Tuesday morning. The nation later observed a minute of silence. A national service took place at St. Paul's Cathedral and a separate service will be held at the Hyde Park memorial, attended by Prince William, survivors and the families of those killed.
Miriam Hyman was killed in the London bombings on July 7, 2005.
(Photo: Miriam Hyman Memorial Trust)
This nation is also grieving the June 26 attack in the Tunisian resort city of Sousse that killed 38 people  30 of them Britons  when a militant opened fire on tourists at a beachfront hotel.
Prime Minister David Cameron announced Sunday that bank fines for infractions such as manipulating foreign exchange markets will cover the costs for a memorial to those killed in the Tunisia attack and another memorial for all Britons who have died in terrorist attacks overseas.
The 7/7 Tavistock Square Memorial Trust is raising funds for a separate memorial to honor the 13 people killed in the bus explosion.
"In their wicked madness the bombers presumably thought that they were doing something that would be a step toward creating a different city altogether," former government minister and aspiring London mayor Tessa Jowell said last week in delivering the fourth 7/7 Tavistock Square Memorial Trust Lecture.
Esther Hyman, whose sister Miriam Hyman was killed in the 7/7 bombings.
(Photo: Jane Onyanga-Omara, USA TODAY)
"Perhaps they thought they could set the government against the people, race against race, non-Muslims against Muslims, eroding trust and understanding," she continued. "Of course, they failed, and they failed utterly."
Hyman said she pitied the terrorists behind such attacks. "These attacks are happening on a daily, weekly basis globally and my heart goes out to everyone who's involved in any of these kinds of incidents  not only the victims and the families of the victims and those injured, but even for the perpetrators," she said. "I pity them. That they are so damaged that they need to commit these acts."
She said the past decade had been spent "doing as much good work, positive work in Mim's memory as we can.  I feel that we're trying to do her proud."
Those works by the Miriam Hyman Memorial Trust include establishing the Miriam Hyman Children's Eyecare Center in India  Miriam was slightly nearsighted and appreciated the eye care she was given  and launching a website for teachers called Miriam's Vision: A Response to the 2005 London Bombings.
The website is aimed at supporting teachers in educating students about 7/7 and helping young people to develop life skills that will equip them to prevail in the face of adversity.
"As time has gone on, and I don't know if this is a personal truth or an absolute truth and it doesn't matter  but I feel that she finds lots of ways to let me know that she's still right here with me," Hyman said.
"She definitely finds ways to let me know she's around."
Britain was on Tuesday marking 10 years since 52 people were killed in a terror attack on London's transport system on July 7, 2005. Prime Minister David Cameron, left, prepares to lay a wreath at the memorial to the victims in Hyde Park, London.
(Photo: Anthony Devlin, AFP/Getty Images)
Cameron, right, and London Mayor Boris Johnson walk through the memorial with their wreaths.
(Photo: Matt Dunham, AP)
The 7/7 memorial has 52 columns -- one for each victim of the attacks.
(Photo: Andy Rain, EPA)
A flower lies on a plaque bearing the names of the victims.
(Photo: Matt Dunham, AP)
A man prays near a plaque commemorating the victims of the bombing of a double-decker bus near Tavistock Square in central London. Three other bombs were set off in underground train stations during the morning rush hour.
(Photo: Peter Macdiarmid, Getty Images)
A message from David Cameron is pictured among floral tributes in Hyde Park.
(Photo: Niklas Halle'n, AFP/Getty Images)
Members of the emergency services observe a minute's silence to remember the victims under the big screen at Wimbledon.
(Photo: Adrian Dennis, AFP/Getty Images)
The Dean of St Paul's Cathedral, David Ison, greets Lord Mayor of London Alan Yarrow at the anniversary service at the cathedral.
(Photo: Ian Gavan, Getty Images)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:40:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France, Germany warn Athens time is running out</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99676660/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~France-Germany-warn-Athens-time-is-running-out/</Link>
        <Description>Euro zone leaders meet for emergency talks today to coordinate their response to the Greek referendum. Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras says his hand has been strengthened by the vote, but Germany and France signaled their patience is thinning.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
France, Germany warn Athens time is running out
Euro zone leaders meet for emergency talks today to coordinate their response to the Greek referendum. Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras says his hand has been strengthened by the vote, but Germany and France signaled their patience is thinning.
Post to Facebook
France, Germany warn Athens time is running out Euro zone leaders meet for emergency talks today to coordinate their response to the Greek referendum. Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras says his hand has been strengthened by the vote, but Germany and France signaled their patience is thinning. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IG8Ome
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
France, Germany warn Athens time is running out
Euro zone leaders meet for emergency talks today to coordinate their response to the Greek referendum. Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras says his hand has been strengthened by the vote, but Germany and France signaled their patience is thinning. Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:24:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man charged after lifting off in balloon-covered lawn chair</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99659534/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Man-charged-after-lifting-off-in-ballooncovered-lawn-chair/</Link>
        <Description>A Canadian man strapped some balloons to a lawn chair and went on a brief flight Sunday that ended with his arrest.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Man charged after lifting off in balloon-covered lawn chair
A Canadian man strapped some balloons to a lawn chair and went on a brief flight Sunday that ended with his arrest.
Post to Facebook
Man charged after lifting off in balloon-covered lawn chair A Canadian man strapped some balloons to a lawn chair and went on a brief flight Sunday that ended with his arrest. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IG4ByU
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Man charged after lifting off in balloon-covered lawn chair
A Canadian man strapped some balloons to a lawn chair and went on a brief flight Sunday that ended with his arrest. Newslook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:54:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Calderon and Stern: Fight climate change, boost economy</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99640652/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Calderon-and-Stern-Fight-climate-change-boost-economy/</Link>
        <Description>Taking decisive action to protect environment could bring multi-trillion dollar growth.</Description>
        <MainBody>Calderon and Stern: Fight climate change, boost economy
Taking decisive action to protect environment could bring multi-trillion dollar growth.
Post to Facebook
Calderon and Stern: Fight climate change, boost economy Taking decisive action to protect environment could bring multi-trillion dollar growth. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1M92PoZ
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
7
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Calderon and Stern: Fight climate change, boost economy
Felipe Caldern and Nicholas Stern 7:54 p.m. EDT July 6, 2015
Taking decisive action to protect environment could bring multi-trillion dollar growth.
Workers, union members and other supporters rally to provide a financial incentive for nuclear power and low-carbon emissions at the Illinois Capitol in Springfield on May 6, 2015.
(Photo: Sara Burnett, AP)
12 CONNECT 115 TWEET LINKEDIN 7 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Taking strong climate action is a multitrillion dollar opportunity for better economic growth.
Recent trends in the global economy  such as the falling cost of clean energy, the spread of carbon pricing and the continuing volatility of oil prices  are building momentum for low-carbon growth and development.
To meet the goals of raising living standards, tackling poverty and reducing climate risk together, the scale and speed of change must accelerate, spurred on by cooperation both internationally and between the public and private sectors. With the help of international partnerships, it is possible through 10 key areas of action to generate better economic growth while achieving nearly all of the emissions reductions needed in the next 15 years to avoid dangerous climate change.
These partnerships go beyond just national governments to include cities and companies. They can stimulate growth by expanding markets, reducing costs, spreading best practices and alleviating concerns about international competitiveness.
What climate change deniers and believers share: Column
We can start by accelerating low-carbon development already underway in the world's cities. Almost 80 cities have already committed to reducing emissions through low-carbon development strategies and tracking their progress through the Compact of Mayors . Key measures such as investing in mass transit and making new buildings energy-efficient could cut emissions strongly while generating $17 trillion in savings by 2050. As an added bonus, making cities more compact, connected and coordinated can also improve quality of life by lowering pollution, congestion and traffic fatalities.
Governments can also lead by pricing carbon emissions. Forty countries and 20 sub-national governments have adopted or are planning carbon pricing , and 28 countries are undertaking energy subsidy reform.
Taking these measures reduces emissions and improves economic efficiency, while increasing the amount of government funds available for other priorities such as health, education and innovation.
Of course, governments cannot do it alone. The private sector must be committed as well  indeed, it is businesses that will likely provide most of the investment. Encouragingly, many businesses are already embracing the low-carbon economy, recognizing that it is better for growth and profitability than the high-carbon alternative. For instance, a group of more than half of the Fortune 100 companies have indicated that they are together saving $1.1 billion annually from emissions reduction initiatives. Major corporations responsible for more than 90% of the palm oil trade have committed to eliminate deforestation from their supply chains. And over 1,000 major companies and investors have explicitly signaled their support for carbon pricing.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:35:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek, other euro leaders set for new round of talks</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99498000/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Greek-other-euro-leaders-set-for-new-round-of-talks/</Link>
        <Description>FM Yanis Varoufakis resigns. Germany's Merkel stresses Greece to take responsibility.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Greek, other euro leaders set for new round of talks
Greece's unorthodox Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis resigned Monday, less than 24 hours after he successfully helped Athens win a divisive referendum on its creditors' bailout terms that increases anxiety that Greece could spectacularly crash out of the eurozone currency bloc.
Post to Facebook
Greek, other euro leaders set for new round of talks Greece's unorthodox Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis resigned Monday, less than 24 hours after he successfully helped Athens win a divisive referendum on its creditors' bailout terms that increases anxiety that Greece could spectacularly crash out of the eurozone currency bloc. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IDQcTX
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
86
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Greek, other euro leaders set for new round of talks
Kim Hjelmgaard , USA TODAY 5:35 p.m. EDT July 6, 2015
July 6 -- Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis said he was quitting hours after his government triumphed in a referendum rejecting further austerity, saying his presence would hamper aid talks. Hans Nichols and Caroline Hyde report on Bloomberg's Bloomberg
Greece Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis speaks at the Finance Ministry after the results of referendum in Athens on July 5, 2015.
(Photo: AP)
691 CONNECT 490 TWEET 18 LINKEDIN 86 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Backed by Greek voters and opposition leaders, Prime Minister Alex Tsipras meets Tuesday with other eurozone leaders to see it they can resurrect debt relief negotiations.
Following Sunday's referendum in which 61% of voters rejected stringent bailout terms set by Greece's international creditors, Tsipras hoped to go to the meeting in Brussels with a strenghtened hand. On Monday, Greek party  leaders rallied around his call for new talks.
However, the lenders gave no immediate indication they were ready to compromise on new loans to keep Greece afloat.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel, who on Monday talked with Tsipras and met with French President Francois Hollande in Paris, stressed that Greece needs to take "responsibility" for reforming its economy. Hollande said Europe needs to show "solidarity" with Greece. The two leaders run the eurozone's largest economies.
Both leaders also said they respect the referendum results, and the door remains open to negotiations to find a way to keep Greece in the 19-country eurozone.
As the outlook for the talks remain unclear, the European Central Bank decided Monday to leave the level of emergency credit to Greek banks unchanged to prevent their collapse. But it raised its collateral requirements.
Banks have been closed for a week, with strict limits on daily ATM withdrawals, and are expected to stay shut at least through mid-week.
Tsipras wins at home, but debt problems remain
In one concession to the creditors, Tsipras replaced his outspoken finance minister, Yanis Varoufakis, who had alienated eurozone leaders by assailing the onerous terms they demanded for new loans.
"I shall wear the creditors' loathing with pride," Varoufakis said in a defiant but characteristically colorful announcement about his resignation on his blog.
He said he was resigning because Tsipras believed his departure might help pave the way for Greece to "achieve a deal."
The Greek government later named lower-keyed economist Euclid Tsakalotos, 55, as the new finance minister. He was the prime minister's lead bailout negotiator in talks that halted last month before Tsipras called the referendum.
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis arrives May 12, 2015, for an Economic and Financial Affairs Council meeting at the European Council in Brussels.
(Photo: Emmanuel Dunland, AFP/Getty Images)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis leaves the polling booth as he prepares to cast his ballot during the Greek referendum in Athens on July 5, 2015.
(Photo: Aris Messinia,  AFP/Getty Images)
Outgoing Greek Finance minister Yanis Varoufakis leaves on his motorcycle with his wife, Danae, after his resignation at the ministry of Finance in downtown Athens on July 6, 2015.
(Photo: Louisa Gouliamaki, AFP/Getty Images)
Fullscreen
A bottle of vodka lemon Grexit by creator Uwe Dalhoff who registered the label taken from a widely used term coined from combining the words "Greece" and "exit." The label shows Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras and Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis smiling.
(Photo: Ina Fassbender, AFP/Getty Images)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis and his wife Danae attend an address by the Greek prime minister in Athens July 3, 2015.
(Photo: Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis is greeted as he arrives with his father, Giorgos, at a polling station in Athens on July 5, 2015.
(Photo: Aris Messinia, AFP/Getty Images)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis gestures as he leaves a press conference  in Athens on July 5, 2015.
(Photo: Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images)
Greece's Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis during a debate at the European Business Summit in Brussels on May, 7 2015.
(Photo: Geert Vanden Wijngaert, AP)
Greece's Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis and his wife, Danae, attend a concert in Athens on June 11, 2015.
(Photo: Thanassis Stavrakis, AP)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis makes statements at the Finance Ministry after the results of referendum in Athens on July 5, 2015.
(Photo: Angelos Christofilopoulos, AP)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis arrives at the start of a special Eurogroup Finance ministers meeting on Greece in Brussels, Belgium, on June 27,  2015.
(Photo: Oliver Hoslet, epa)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis leaves a press conference in Athens on July 5, 2015.
(Photo: Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis waits for the start of a special Eurogroup Finance ministers meeting on the Greek crisis at the EU Council headquarters in Brussels, Belgium, on June 27,  2015.
(Photo: Oliver Hoslet, epa)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis   during a debate on the referendum at the Greek Parliament in Athens on June 27, 2015.
(Photo: Alexandros Vlachos, epa)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis at a meeting with his Italian counterpart Pier Carlo Padoan in Rome on May 6 2015.
(Photo: Angelo Caroni, epa)
A woman holds a candle with the photo of Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis in a shop in Thessaloniki, Greece, on April 9, 2015.
(Photo: Nikos Arvanidis, epa)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis during a Parliament session in Athens on June 5,  2015.
(Photo: Yannis Kolesidis, epa)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis arrives on his motorcycle for a Cabinet meeting in Athens on June 21, 2015.
(Photo: Angelos Tzortzinia, AFP/Getty Images)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis attends a party meeting in the Greek Parliament in Athens on June 26, 2015.
(Photo: Simela Pantzartzi, epa)
A protester points his finger at Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis during the May Day rally in Athens on May 1, 2015.
(Photo: Yannis Kolesidis, epa)
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis  at the start of the European Stability Mechanism Board of Governors meeting in Luxembourg on June 18,  2015.
(Photo: Julien Warnand, epa)
Greek Finance  Minister Yanis Varoufakis speaks to the press after placing his vote in the austerity referendum in Athens on July 5, 2015.
(Photo: Milos Bicanski, Getty Images)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:33:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama says anti-ISIL fight making progress</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99590742/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Obama-says-antiISIL-fight-making-progress/</Link>
        <Description>Obama to meet with Pentagon leaders about ISIL.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Obama says anti-ISIL fight making progress
President Obama will meet with the top military brass at the Pentagon on Monday after setbacks in the effort to fight the Islamic State in Iraq and Syria have prompted critics to call for a more robust U.S. response.
Post to Facebook
Obama says anti-ISIL fight making progress President Obama will meet with the top military brass at the Pentagon on Monday after setbacks in the effort to fight the Islamic State in Iraq and Syria have prompted critics to call for a more robust U.S. response. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1M81pec
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
110
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Obama says anti-ISIL fight making progress
Tom Vanden Brook and David Jackson, USA TODAY 5:33 p.m. EDT July 6, 2015
President Obama addressed the progress the U.S. military has made against the Islamic State in Iraq and Syria. VPC
President Obama speaks at the Pentagon alongside Defense Secretary Ashton Carter following a meeting with top military officials about the military campaign against the Islamic State on July 6, 2015.
(Photo: Saul Loeb, AFP/Getty Images)
136 CONNECT 142 TWEET LINKEDIN 110 COMMENTEMAILMORE
WASHINGTON  The U.S. military is making progress against the Islamic State in Iraq and Syria, but more work remains to be done, President Obama said Monday.
"This will not be quick  this is a long-term campaign," Obama said at the Pentagon after meeting top military brass in the wake of setbacks that have prompted critics to call for a more robust U.S. response against the Islamic State.
Obama and his military aides discussed "what's working, and what we can do better," the president said.
In his review of the campaign, Obama stressed that the United States is working with a 60-nation coalition, and that local forces must take the initiative. Military force alone will not "degrade" and "destroy" the Islamic State, he said, citing diplomatic and economic efforts that include efforts to cut off terrorists' money.
The United States and other countries must remain vigilant against "lone wolves" who might be inspired by the Islamic State to launch terrorist attacks, Obama said. That includes projects to counter an extremist ideology that seeks to attract adherents, including young Muslim men.
"Ideologies are not defeated with guns," Obama said. "They're defeated by better ideas, more attractive and more compelling vision."
He added: "We will never be at war with Islam while fighting terrorists who distort Islam and whose victims are mostly Muslims."
Defense Secretary Ashton Carter, President Obama and Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Gen. Martin Dempsey attend a meeting with members of the president's national security team at the Pentagon on July 6, 2015.
(Photo: Pool, Getty Images)
Not everyone was persuaded by the president's claims of progress.
Sen. John McCain, R-Ariz,, said the Islamic State continues to gain land in Iraq and Syria, and to expand its influence throughout the region. McCain said Obama's comments "reveal the disturbing degree of self-delusion that characterizes the Administration's campaign against ISIL."
The U.S.-led air war against the Islamic State, also known as ISIL or ISIS, began last August after its fighters overran Mosul and seized tracts of land in Syria as well. It continues with daily airstrikes. The heart of the strategy, however, involves training and equipping local troops to battle ISIL.
The results have been dismal: Iraqi troops fled the provincial capital of Ramadi in May without a fight despite outnumbering ISIL by at least 10 to 1; a touted effort to train and equip Syrian moderates has had a stumbling start, with fewer than 100 having been vetted and receiving training.
McCain, who chairs the Armed Services Committee, has been a persistent critic of the strategy, saying that the deployment of additional trainers last month is "disconnected from any coherent strategy to defeat ISIL."
Obama's day: Islamic State update
He wants U.S. troops to deploy outside training bases with Iraqi troops to advise them in battle and to call in airstrikes. Military leaders have resisted deploying airstrike spotters, saying they will require a larger troop commitment than the spotters alone.
On Tuesday, Defense Secretary Ash Carter and Army Gen. Martin Dempsey, chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, are scheduled to testify before McCain's committee on the Pentagon's counter-ISIL strategy. Last week, Dempsey described the strategy as building a network of local forces stretching from Africa to Afghanistan to address regional threats.
In Iraq, Carter pointed to the recent deployment of 450 U.S. troops to a base near Ramadi called Taqaddum. Troops there will train 500 Sunni fighters per month to take on ISIL, a Sunni-based movement. Overall, he noted that 10,500 Iraqi security forces have been advised and equipped by U.S. troops.
Risk outweighs reward in deploying airstrike spotters, officials say
Meanwhile, Obama also called on Senate Republicans to confirm a Treasury Department official responsible for blocking the flow of money to potential terrorists.
The Republican-run Senate has not even scheduled a hearing for Adam Szubin for undersecretary of the Treasury responsible for interdicting terrorist funds and sanctioning businesses and nations that supply the money, Obama said. If Congress was serious about helping, it would confirm Szubin.
Szubin would replace David Cohen, who is now deputy director of the CIA.
136 CONNECT 142 TWEET LINKEDIN 110 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1M81pec
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:54:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Analysis: Greece's 'game of chicken' with creditors continues</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99557208/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Analysis-Greeces-game-of-chicken-with-creditors-continues/</Link>
        <Description>Greece's financial situation deteriorates as both sides stand firm.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Analysis: Greece's 'game of chicken' with creditors continues
Greece's international creditors took a hard line against Athens' insistence that it needs better terms to escape a deepening financial abyss.
Post to Facebook
Analysis: Greece's 'game of chicken' with creditors continues Greece's international creditors took a hard line against Athens' insistence that it needs better terms to escape a deepening financial abyss. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1M7seiW
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
43
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Analysis: Greece's 'game of chicken' with creditors continues
On "Morning Must Read," Tom Keene recaps the op-ed pieces and analyst notes that provide insight into today's headlines. Kissinger Associates Vice Chairman Robert Hormats also speaks on "Bloomberg Surveillance." Bloomberg
Kim Hjelmgaard , USA TODAY 4:54 p.m. EDT July 6, 2015
A person holds a banner that reads, "I am a Greek, stop (the) blackmail creditors" during a rally in support of the people of Greece  in Paris on July 5, 2015.
(Photo: AFP)
58 CONNECT 176 TWEET 1 LINKEDIN 43 COMMENTEMAILMORE
As the standoff between Greece and its international creditors continues, the only thing certain is that the country's financial situation will continue to worsen as each side sticks to its hard-line stance.
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras said Greeks made a "brave choice" Sunday in voting by more than 61% to reject harsh bailout conditions demanded by the International Monetary Fund, European Central Bank and European Commission (eurozone governments).
It's up to the creditors to decide whether to soften their demands or stick to their tough terms for massive new lending.
In the interim, Greece's five-year debt crisis appears to be going from bad to worse. The creditors' strategy "has been counterproductive," said Sean Egan, chief executive of Egan-Jones, a ratings firm.
"The hard line they have taken has resulted in a run on Greece's banks, a closing of its banks, a closing of the stock market and a paralysis of Greece's economy," Egan said. Last week, Greece missed a $1.8 billion loan repayment to the IMF.
Greece votes 'no': Now what?
In the wake of Greece's resounding "no" vote, German Chancellor Angela Merkel and French President Francois Hollande, leaders of the eurozone's two largest economies, conferred in Paris but were at odds about what to do next.
Both said they are open to negotiations with Greece. Merkel, Europe's leading advocate for austerity, stressed the importance of Greece taking "responsibility" for reforming its economy, while Hollande adopted a softer tone, saying Europe needs to show "solidarity" with Greece.
Tuesday, representatives of the 19-nation eurozone, where the euro is the official currency, will hold an emergency summit in Brussels to discuss the next steps. Mujtaba Rahman, an analyst at Eurasia Group, said the summit is likely to prove decisive for Greece's membership in the group.
Greek, other euro leaders set for new round of talks
Angelos Chryssogelos, an expert on Greek politics at the London-based think-tank Chatham House, said the strength of Sunday's mandate handed to Tsipras means it will be almost impossible for the prime minister's leftist Syriza party to make a deal with European creditors.
"The Europeans made it pretty clear where they stand, and they have been consistent," Chryssogelos said, adding that the creditors also are unlikely to back down. "Right now, voters across the eurozone largely support the tough stance taken by the eurozone."
Chryssogelos said Greek voters may have underestimated the resolve of the creditors to reach an accord on their terms. "If someone is seen getting preferential treatment, then someone else will want that treatment," he said, referring to other eurozone debtors such as Ireland and Portugal.
Kevin Featherstone, a professor of Greek studies and director of the Hellenic Observatory at the London School of Economics, said it remains in the interest of both sides to reach a compromise because the costs of concessions would be far less than a scenario that sees Greece ejected from the eurozone.
"We've had five years of strategic mistakes on both sides," Featherstone said. "What we now have is the epitome of those mistakes. In the next few days we're going to see who is going to blink first in this dramatic game of chicken."
58 CONNECT 176 TWEET 1 LINKEDIN 43 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1M7seiW
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:02:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Who is the Dalai Lama? 8 facts to celebrate his 80th birthday</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99601140/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Who-is-the-Dalai-Lama-facts-to-celebrate-his-th-birthday/</Link>
        <Description>To celebrate his 80th birthday, check out these eight facts about the Dalai Lama.</Description>
        <MainBody>Who is the Dalai Lama? 8 facts to celebrate his 80th birthday
He posts to Instagram, Facebook and Twitter, and celebrated his 80th birthday Monday in California.
Post to Facebook
Who is the Dalai Lama? 8 facts to celebrate his 80th birthday He posts to Instagram, Facebook and Twitter, and celebrated his 80th birthday Monday in California. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IFir4J
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
2
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Who is the Dalai Lama? 8 facts to celebrate his 80th birthday
Christine Rushton , USA TODAY 4:02 p.m. EDT July 6, 2015
Singer Patti Smith was joined onstage by the Dalai Lama during her performance at the Glastonbury Festival.
(Photo: OLI SCARFF, AFP/Getty Images)
3093 CONNECT 122 TWEET 1 LINKEDIN 2 COMMENTEMAILMORE
He posts to Instagram , Facebook and Twitter , and celebrated his 80th birthday Monday in California. This spiritual and social icon  His Holiness the 14th Dalai Lama  travels worldwide to spread messages of peace  and compassion.
Facebook
Dalai Lama - Timeline Photos | Facebook
But, who was the Dalai Lama before his celebrity debut on social media?
1. Named Dalai Lama at age 2.
Born on July 6, 1935, as Lhamo Dhondup, he lived with a barley-, buckwheat- and potato-farming family in Tibet. Leaders identified him as the reincarnation of the 13th Dalai Lama at age 2 and named him Tenzin Gyatso.
2. Entered the monastery at 6.
At age 6, he started studying the Buddhist philosophy as well as curriculum for his divine role. He learned 10 subjects, including Tibetan art and culture, medicine, monastic discipline canon, logic and metaphysics. He passed exams with honors at age 23, according to dalailama.com .
3. Fled Tibet after a Chinese invasion.
A Chinese invasion of Tibet in 1949 brought the then-15 year old to assume full power over Tibetan leadership in 1950. He attempted peace talks with Chinese leaders but was forced to escape into exile from the country in 1959. The night he left his country for India, he disguised himself as a common soldier to move through crowds unnoticed.
This is an undated photo of the future Dalai Lama of Tibetan Buddhism, born Lhamo Dhondrub on July 6, 1935, in the village of Takster in northeastern Tibet. The 14th Dalai Lama was enthroned Feb. 22, 1940, and renamed Tenzin Gyatso.
(Photo: AP)
The Dalai Lama, 15-year-old ruler of Tibet, smiles from his Throne in Lhasa on Nov. 9, 1950. He wears a gold peaked cap that is his crown.
(Photo: Lowell Thomas, AP)
Pope John Paul II on Feb. 2, 1986, in New Delhi checks a book entitled "Opening The Eye Of New Awareness", which was written by the first Dalai Lama.
(Photo: AFP/Getty Images)
The Dalai Lama appears onstage during a celebration of his 80th birthday at the Global Compassion Summit in Anaheim, Calif., on June 5, 2015.
(Photo: Mindy Schauer, AP)
Fullscreen
Tibetan spiritual leader the Dalai Lama wears a Nyingma -- one of the five traditional schools of Tibetan Buddhism -- hat during an event to celebrate his 80th birthday at Tsuglakhang Temple in McLeod Ganj, India, on June 22, 2015. The Dalai Lama held his official 80th birthday celebration June 21.
(Photo: Narinder Nanu, AFP/Getty Images)
The Dalai Lama takes to the stage to address an audience at Aldershot, Britain, June 29, 2015.
(Photo: Will Oliver, European Pressphoto Agency)
Fullscreen
Tibetan spiritual leader Dalai Lama eats a piece of his birthday cake to celebrate his 80th Birthday at the Global Compassion Summit at the Honda Centre in Anaheim, Calif., on July 5, 2015. The Dalai Lama is on a U.S. tour and will spend three days in Southern California participating in discussions and meetings.
(Photo: Mike Nelson, European Pressphoto Agency)
Exiled Tibetan school children wearing traditional costumes carry a portrait of the Dalai Lama as they sing at a gathering to celebrate their spiritual leader's 80th birthday in Dharmsala, India, on July 6, 2015.
(Photo: Ashwini Bhatia, AP)
Fullscreen
Tibetans living in exile in India stand next to a birthday cake as they celebrate the Dalai Lama's 80th birthday in Dharmsala, India, on July 6, 2015. The Dalai Lama settled at Dharamsala after fleeing Tibet in 1959 after a failed uprising against Chinese rule.
(Photo: Sanjay Baid, European Pressphoto Agency)
Fullscreen
Young Tibetans perform dance during the 80th birthday celebration of the Dalai Lama at Namgyal School in Kathmandu, Nepal, on July 6, 2015. About 1,000 monks and other Tibetans gathered at the school compound to celebrate their spiritual leader's birthday. Exiled Tibetans allowed celebrating the Dalai Lama's birthday only inside school compounds and refugee camps as long as the facilities do not contain slogans or banners protesting against China.
(Photo: Narendra Shrestha, European Pressphoto Agency)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:07:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Running of the bulls festival starts; crowd doused in wine</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99609810/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Running-of-the-bulls-festival-starts-crowd-doused-in-wine/</Link>
        <Description>The festival started with the traditional launching of the fireworks rocket "Chupinazo"</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Running of the bulls festival starts; crowd doused in wine
PAMPLONA, Spain (AP)  Thousands of revelers doused each other with wine Monday to celebrate the start of the famed San Fermin running of the bulls festival in this northern Spanish city. The festival started
Post to Facebook
Running of the bulls festival starts; crowd doused in wine PAMPLONA, Spain (AP)  Thousands of revelers doused each other with wine Monday to celebrate the start of the famed San Fermin running of the bulls festival in this northern Spanish city. The festival started Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IFr6E6
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Running of the bulls festival starts; crowd doused in wine
Andres Kudacki and Ciaran Giles , Associated Press 4:07 p.m. EDT July 6, 2015
Revelers open their mouths as they wait to cool off with water thrown from a balcony to celebrate the official opening of the 2015 San Fermin Fiestas, in Pamplona, northern Spain, Monday, July 6, 2015.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
19 CONNECT 24 TWEET LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
PAMPLONA, Spain (AP)  Thousands of revelers doused each other with wine Monday to celebrate the start of the famed San Fermin running of the bulls festival in this northern Spanish city.
The festival started with the traditional launching of a fireworks rocket  known as the "Chupinazo" from the town hall balcony. The heaving crowd packed the square down below, jumping and screaming "Viva San Fermin!"
Most in the crowd waved red neckerchiefs, which along with white shirts and trousers form the traditional festival clothing.
The Chupinazo takes place a day before the first of eight 8 a.m. bull runs. Thousands of people at the festival test their speed and bravery by racing ahead of six fighting bulls along a 930-yard (850-meter) course from a holding pen to the city's bull ring. The bulls are then killed by professional matadors in bullfights each afternoon.
People watch as Jandilla fighting bulls and revelers run during the running of the bulls at the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
A reveler falls while others run with a Jandilla's ranch fighting bull during the running of the bulls of the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
A reveler is tossed by a cow with dull horns during a celebration held at the bullring after the running of the bulls of the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
Revelers wearing a local traditional outfit march during the San Fermin procession in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
Revelers gather to watch Jandilla fighting bulls running at the San Fermin festival, in Pamplona, Spain, on Tuesday.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
Fullscreen
Revelers run with fighting bulls during the running of the bulls at the Fiestas de San Fermin in Pamplona, Spain, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The festival, locally known as Sanfermines, is held annually from July 6-14 in commemoration of the city's patron saint.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
People from around the world gather for the event.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
The 'Toro de Fuego' (flaming bull) chases revelers through the streets during the opening day.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez)
Revelers gathered on City Hall Square celebrate after the firing of the txupinazo rocket, which marks the official beginning of the festival.
(Photo: Daniel Fernandez, EPA)
Fullscreen
A band performs during the opening day or 'Chupinazo.' Hundreds of thousands of visitors from all over the world attend the nine-day fiesta. Many of them participate in the highlight event: The running of the bulls - or encierro - where they attempt to outrun the bulls along an approximately half-mile-long route through the narrow streets of the old city.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Revelers hold their red scarves as mark the kickoff at noon sharp of the San Fermin Festival.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Not for the claustrophobic! Revelers squeeze through Pamplona's City Hall Square.
(Photo: Ander Gillenea, AFP/Getty Images)
A man gets some air as he's tossed about during the  launch of the chupinazo rocket.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
A reveler wearing a bull earring enjoys the atmosphere during the opening day of the Running of the Bulls fiesta.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Festival goers soak each other with wine.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Ivy Mix from Brooklyn, N.Y., is given a drink of sangria.
(Photo: Jim Hollander, EPA)
Revelers throw a bucket of water from a balcony onto the crowd.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
And below the balcony, the water lands on party goers.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
A red-and-white-clad sea of revelers soaked each other with wine in a packed Pamplona square Monday.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Revelers from around the world kick off the festival. Tuesday is the first of eight days of the running of the bulls.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
A woman is sprayed with water as she celebrates.
(Photo: Ander Gillenea, AFP/Getty Images)
A sea of participants hold red scarves as they celebrate.
(Photo: MIGUEL RIOPA, AFP/Getty Images)
A reveler jumps from a fountain onto the crowd below.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
A  reveler drinks wine during San Fermin Fiestas. Many others wore it, as their formerly white T shirts attest.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
People enjoy the atmosphere during the opening day of the Running of the Bulls festival.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Streets too much? Some people choose to witness the celebration from balconies.
(Photo: Miguel Riopa, AFP/Getty Images)
Sangria is the drink of choice, taken from a plastic bottle as partying continues.
(Photo: Jim Hollander, EPA)
People-surfing/people-tossing is just part of the atmosphere.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
As long as you wear red and white, anything goes.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
Last Slide Next Slide
The nine-day, street-partying fiesta was immortalized in Ernest Hemingway's 1926 novel The Sun Also Risesand attracts thousands of foreign tourists.
Bull runs, or "encierros," as they are called in Spanish, are a traditional part of summer festivals across Spain. Dozens are injured each year in the runs, most of them in falls.
Two men have died being gored by bulls in Spanish festivals in recent weeks  one Saturday in the eastern town of Grao de Castellon and another June 24 in the southwestern town of Coria.
Five Spaniards, two Australians and one American were gored in last year's festival in Pamplona. In all, 15 people have died from gorings in San Fermin since record-keeping began in 1924.
Check out images from last year's event:
A bull gores a runner, on July 14, during the eighth bull run at the San Fermin fiesta  in Pamplona, Spain. Two runners were gored and another five injured after being knocked over during the last race of the nine-day long running-with-the-bulls.
(Photo: Villar Lopez, epa)
Spanish bullfighter Luis Bolivar is gored by a bull during.
(Photo: Jesus Diges, epa)
Spanish bullfighter Diego Urdiales adjusts his capote before doing the "paseillo" or ritual entrance to the arena, before a bullfight of the San Fermin fiesta on July 13.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
A bull runs over a runner during the San Fermin fiesta in Pamplona.
(Photo: Jesus Diges, epa)
Fullscreen
Jandilla fighting bulls run in between revelers during the running of the bulls at the San Fermin festival in Pamplona, Spain, July 11. Revelers from around the world arrive every year to take part in the eight days of the running of the bulls.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
Spanish bullfighter Alejandro Talavante enters the arena during a bullfight at the San Fermin fiesta July 10.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
Spanish bullfighter El Juli kills a bull in the ring July 10.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
Spanish bullfighter Alejandro Talavante is trampled by a bull.
(Photo: Jim Holllander, epa)
Spanish bullfighter Alejandro Talavante is gored July 10 in Pamplona during the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: Jesus Diges, epa)
Revelers dressed as bullfighters wait for the start of the running of the bulls in Pamplona, Spain.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
Revelers run with the bulls. The running of the bulls was glorified by Ernest Hemingway's 1926 novel "The Sun Also Rises."
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
People watch the runners from balconies at the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: Javier Lizon, European Pressphoto Agency)
Runners fall to the ground.
(Photo: Javier Lizon, epa)
Fullscreen
Author and bull runner Bill Hillman, of Chicago, poses in bed recovering from a bull's goring in Pamplona, Spain, on July 10. Hillman, a regular runner at the fiesta in Pamplona, wrote the guide "Fiesta: How to Survive the Bulls of Pamplona."
(Photo: Jim Hollander, epa)
Bill Hillmann, from Chicago, is carried on a stretcher after being gored in his right leg during the running of the bulls of the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: M.J. Arranz, AP)
Spanish bullfighter Juan del Alamo fights against his second bull in Pamplona, on July 9.
(Photo: Javier Lizon, epa)
Spanish bullfighter Juan del Alamo kills a bull with his sword during a bullfight at the San Fermin fiesta, on July 9.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
Spanish bullfighter Ivan Fandno fights a bull in Pamplona.
(Photo: Javier Lizon, epa)
A fighting bull gets a horn through the pants of Spanish bullfighter Ivan Fandino during a bullfight.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
Spanish bullfighter Ivan Fandino is gored by a bull during a bullfight.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
Boys and girls take part in the bullfighting classes at the San Fermine fiesta.
(Photo: Javier Lizon, epa)
People watch from balconies as police controlEstafeta Streeta few minutes beforethe start of the running of the bulls on July 9 in Pamplona, Spain.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos AP)
Revelers run on Estafeta Street July 9.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
A bull pushes a reveler during the running of the bulls.The annual nine-day, running-with-the-bulls festival commemorates St. Fermin, Pamplona's patron saint.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
A bull throws a reveler in the bullring during the San Fermin fiesta in Pamplona.
(Photo: JIm Hollander, epa)
People dance and sing during the San Fermin fiesta on July 8.
(Photo: Pedro Armestre, AFP/Getty Images)
Francisco Marco covers his eyes as he prepares for a bullfight at the San Fermin fiesta, in Pamplona, Spain.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
Jose Ignacio Uceda Leal performs with a Dolores Aguirre ranch fighting bull at the San Fermin fiesta, on July 8.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
Spanish bullfighter Uceda Leal performs a a chest pass, on a bull from the Dolores Aguirre ranch, during a bullfight.
(Photo: Jim Hollander, epa)
A young boy catches bubbles in a Pamplona street.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
People and children are chased by a Toro del Fuego (flaming bull) as it is runs through the streets of Pamplona during the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: Christopher Furlong, Getty Images)
Fullscreen
Runners and bulls round a corner during a run in Pamplona, Spain on July 8.Revelers from around the world arrive in Pamplona every year to take part in the eight days of the running of the bulls glorified by Ernest Hemingway's 1926 novel "The Sun Also Rises."
(Photo: Jesus Digez, epa)
Children take part in a traditional folk dance during the third day of the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
A bull jumps over revelers into the bull ring in Pamplona.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
Young runners touch a statue of San Fermin before running ahead of toy bulls at the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
Children run ahead of toy bulls at the San Fermin fiest, in Pamplona.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
Nerea Sorondo saws a tree trunk with a "tronza" (traditional Basque saw) during a Basque rural sports' championship in Pamplona. It is part of the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: Ander Gillenea, AFP/Getty Images)
A woman  takes part in a traditional Espadrille Dance in the Casino Principal Club in Pamplona.
(Photo: Christopher Furlong, Getty Images)
Bulls chase runners during the first bull run of the San Fermin fiesta in Pamplona, Spain, on July 7.
(Photo: Jesus Diges, epa)
A bull jumps over a runner on the ground.
(Photo: Daniel Fernandez, epa)
Revelers run with bulls along the Plaza Consistorial during the third day of the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Participants run with bulls during the second bull-run of the San Fermin fiesta in Pamplona, Spain, on July 8.
(Photo: Pedro Armestre, AFP/Getty Images)
Runners and bulls enter the bull ring at the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
Two revelers pose for photographs with a statue representing a bull run in Pamplona.
(Photo: Javier Lizon, epa)
Fullscreen
Revelers run with the bulls during the San Fermin fiesta. Revelers from around the world arrive in Pamplona every year to take part in the eight days of the running of the bulls glorified by Ernest Hemingway's 1926 novel "The Sun Also Rises."
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
Revelers run ahead of the bulls at the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
Revelers attend the San Fermin fiesta at Consistorio square in Pamplona.
(Photo: Javier Lizon, epa)
Two runners fall to the ground during the first bull run of the fiesta.
(Photo: Jesus Diges, epa)
Bulls and runners race down a street during the first bull run.
(Photo: Josu Santesteban, epa)
A reveler is struck by a bull in the bull ring  in Pamplona.
(Photo: Jim Hollander, epa)
Revelers run with the bulls along the Calle Estafeta.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
Revelers run with the bulls along the Curva de Estafeta.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
An injured runner is carried away after running with the bulls.
(Photo: Pablo Blazquez Dominguez, Getty Images)
A bull gives chase inside the Pamplona bull ring.
(Photo: Christopher Furlong, Getty Images)
Runners avoid a bull inside the Pamplona bull ring.
(Photo: Christopher Furlong, Getty Images)
Fullscreen
Spanish mounted bullfighter Roberto Armendariz leads a bull during a horseback bullfight at the San Fermin fiesta in Pamplona, Spain, on July 6. The festival involves the daily running of the bulls through the historic heart of Pamplona to the bull ring.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
People sit in the rain watching a bullfight at San Fermin fiesta in Pamplona, Spain. The annual Fiesta de San Fermin was made famous by the 1926 novel "The Sun Also Rises" by Ernest Hemingway.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
Spanish mounted bullfighter Pablo Hermoso de Mendoza kneels in front of the bull during his horseback bullfight at the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
Spanish mounted bullfighter Roberto Armendariz attacks the bull during his horseback bullfight at the San Fermin fiesta.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos. AP)
The body of a bull is pulled from the ring after a horseback bullfight.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
Participants hold red scarves as they celebrate the start of the San Fermin fiestas in Pamplona, Spain, on July 6.
(Photo: Ander Gilenea, AFP/Getty Images)
Participants celebrate the start of the San Fermin fiestas in front of the Town Hall. A red-and-white sea of people soaked each other with red wine to kick off the event.
(Photo: Rafa Rivas, AFP/Getty Images)
A reveler jumps from a fountain onto the crowd below, after the launch of the "Chupinazo" rocket, marking the official opening of the 2014 San Fermin fiestas.
(Photo: Andres Kudacki, AP)
A man celebrates the start of the fiestas. The annual Fiesta de San Fermin was made famous by the 1926 novel "The Sun Also Rises," by Ernest Hemingway.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
Revelers celebrate during the opening of the 2014 San Fermin fiestas. The festival involves the daily running of the bulls through the historic heart of Pamplona to the bull ring.
(Photo: Alvaro Barrientos, AP)
Revelers pack the town hall square to start the fiestas.Revelers wearing traditional white outfits trimmed with red neckerchiefs and cummerbunds gathered for the noontime launching of a fireworks rocket, which signals the beginning of the nine-day festival.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
A  reveler drinks wine during the launch of the San Fermin fiestas.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
Thousands of revelers hold up their red scarves at the start of the San Fermin fiestas at Consistorio Square in Pamplona, Spain.
(Photo: Jesus Diges, epa)
Revelers hold up their red scarves.
(Photo: Daniel Fernandez, epa)
The band plays music after the launch of the "Chupinazo" rocket.
(Photo: Daniel Ochoa de Olza, AP)
The band plays during the opening and the firing of the "Chupinazo" rocket.
(Photo: Christopher Furlong, Getty Images)
A man drinks red wine while awaiting the start of the San Fermin fiestas.
(Photo: Christopher Furlong, Getty Images)
Revelers cheer and throw red wine as they prepare for the opening of the fiestas.
(Photo: Christopher Furlong, Getty Images)
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:16:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>We need to know: Did Saudis help fund 9/11 attacks? Column</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99592710/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~We-need-to-know-Did-Saudis-help-fund-attacks-Column/</Link>
        <Description>We'll never know until classified 28 pages of report are made public.</Description>
        <MainBody>We need to know: Did Saudis help fund 9/11 attacks? Column
Classified 28 pages of 9/11 report need to be released.
Post to Facebook
We need to know: Did Saudis help fund 9/11 attacks? Column Classified 28 pages of 9/11 report need to be released. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1M83V4i
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
30
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
We need to know: Did Saudis help fund 9/11 attacks? Column
James Bovard 2:16 p.m. EDT July 6, 2015
Classified 28 pages of 9/11 report need to be released.
President Obama and Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Nayef after meeting with Gulf Cooperation Council leaders at Camp David in Maryland on May 14, 2015.
(Photo: Pablo Martinez, AP)
813 CONNECT 138 TWEET 2 LINKEDIN 30 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Do Americans have the right to learn whether a foreign government helped finance the 9/11 attacks? A growing number of congressmen and senators are demanding that a 28-page portion of a 2002 congressional report finally be declassified. The Obama administration appears to be resisting, and the stakes are huge. What is contained in those pages  could radically change Americans' perspective of the War on Terror.
The congressional Joint Inquiry Into Intelligence Community Activities Before and After the Terrorist Attacks of September 11, 2001, completed its investigation in December 2002. But the Bush administration stonewalled the release of the 838-page report until mid-2003  after its invasion of Iraq was a fait accompli  and totally suppressed a key portion. Former senator Bob Graham, D-Fla., chairman of the investigation, declared that "there is compelling evidence in the 28 pages that one or more foreign governments was involved in assisting some of the hijackers in their preparation for 9/11." Graham later indicated that the Saudis were the guilty party. But disclosing Saudi links to 9/11 could have undermined efforts by some Bush administration officials to tie Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein to the 9/11 attacks.
Why we didn't close our beach: Opposing view
Suppressing the 28 pages was intensely controversial at the time. Sen. Richard Shelby, R-Ala., the vice chairman of the joint inquiry, urged declassification of almost all of the 28 pages because "the American people are crying out to know more about who funds, aids and abets terrorist activities in the world." Forty-six senators , spearheaded by Sen. Chuck Schumer, D-N.Y., and including almost all the Democratic members, signed a letter to President Bush urging the release of the 28 pages.
Rep. Walter Jones, R-N.C., revived the push to declassify those pages in 2013. Jones is a conservative stalwart best known for coining the phrase " freedom fries " in 2003 when France opposed  invading Iraq. He has since become one of the most outspoken opponents of reckless U.S. intervention abroad. Jones explained that he introduced a resolution because "the American people deserve the truth. Releasing these pages will enhance our national security, not harm it."
Last month, Sen. Rand Paul, R-Ky., fresh from a bracing filibuster against the renewal of the Patriot Act, joined the 28-page fight.  Paul introduced the Transparency for the Families of 9/11 Victims and Survivors Act , co-sponsored by Sens. Ron Wyden, D-Ore., and Kirsten Gillibrand, D-N.Y.  The suppressed pages are another wedge between Paul and other Republican presidential candidates; New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie rejects declassification, instead urging deference to the president's judgment on the issue.
Members of Congress can read the still-classified pages in a special secure room on Capitol Hill if they get prior permission from the House or Senate Intelligence Committee.
When sharks attack and beaches stay open: Our view
Rep. Thomas Massie, R-Ky., one of the few members to go read the report, was shocked : "I had to stop every couple of pages and just sort of absorb and try to rearrange my understanding of history for the past 13 years and the years leading up to that. It challenges you to rethink everything." Massie is one of 18 co-sponsors ofJones' resolution in the House.
Why is the Obama administration continuing to suppress a report completed more than a dozen years ago?  It is not as if the White House's credibility would be damaged by revelations of Saudi bankrolling the worst attack on American soil since Pearl Harbor ( 15 of the 19 hijackers were Saudis).
And it is not as if the Saudis became squeaky-clean Boy Scouts after 9/11.  Saudi sources are widely reported to be bankrolling Islamic State terrorists throughout the Middle East; Gen. Martin Dempsey, the chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, told a Senate committee last September that "I know major Arab allies who fund" ISIS.
President Obama just ordered more U.S. troops to Iraq to seek to rebuff the ISIS onslaught.  If the Saudis are helping sow fresh chaos in the Middle East, that is another reason to disclose their role in an attack that helped launch conflicts that have already cost thousands of American lives and more than $1.6 trillion , according to the Congressional Research Service.
"Don't confuse me with the facts" should not be the motto of the War on Terror. Self-government is an illusion if politicians can shroud the most important details driving federal policy.  If Americans have learned anything since 9/11, it should be the folly of deferring to Washington secrecy.
James Bovard is the author of Public Policy Hooligan and a member of USA TODAY's Board of Contributors.
In addition to its own editorials, USA TODAY publishes diverse opinions from outside writers, including our Board of Contributors . To read more columns like this, go to the Opinion front page .
813 CONNECT 138 TWEET 2 LINKEDIN 30 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1M83V4i
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:55:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The day in pictures</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/95533850/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~The-day-in-pictures/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Cyclists compete in the third stage of the Tour de France in Huy, Belgium.
Post to Facebook
The day in pictures Cyclists compete in the third stage of the Tour de France in Huy, Belgium. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1SbnRa4
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
1
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
The day in pictures
Cyclists compete in the third stage of the Tour de France in Huy, Belgium.
Laurent Cipriani, AP
Revelers gathered on City Hall Square celebrate after the firing of the txupinazo rocket, which marked the official beginning of the Fiestas de San Fermn in Pamplona, Spain. The week-long festival culminates in the running of the bulls.
Daniel Fernandez, epa
Members of a local music group perform next to revelers gathered on City Hall Square shortly before the firing of the txupinazo rocket marking the Fiestas de San Fermin in Pamplona.
Jesus Diges, epa
Iraqi security forces search for survivors after a bombing in the eastern neighborhood of New Baghdad.
Hadi Mizban, AP
Exiled Tibetan monks attend a procession carrying a portrait of their spiritual leader, the Dalai Lama, during a celebration in Kathmandu, Nepal, to mark his 80th birthday.
Narendra Shrestha, European Pressphoto Agency
Greece's former Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis and his wife, Danae Stratou, exit the Finance Ministry in Athens July 5,2015. Varoufakis announced in a tweet and on his personal webpages on July 6 that  he is resigning.
Fotis Plegas, epa
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:29:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek  'suicidal' referendum was still a good idea: Column</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99587072/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Greek-suicidal-referendum-was-still-a-good-idea-Column/</Link>
        <Description>Greece's 'suicidal' referendum won't save economy, but might save the country.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greek  'suicidal' referendum was still a good idea: Column
While the Greek vote won't save the economy, it might save the country.
Post to Facebook
Greek  'suicidal' referendum was still a good idea: Column While the Greek vote won't save the economy, it might save the country. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1IF0p2h
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
14
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Greek 'suicidal' referendum was still a good idea: Column
Mike Edwards and Daniel Oppenheimer 1:29 p.m. EDT July 6, 2015
While the Greek vote won't save the economy, it might save the country.
Anti-debt protester in Berlin on July 3, 2015.
(Photo: Kay Nietfeld, epa)
9 CONNECT 51 TWEET LINKEDIN 14 COMMENTEMAILMORE
After Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras called for yesterday's vote on whether Greece should accept the austerity measures its creditors are demanding, the international reaction was nearly universally negative, with the leftist Greek leader accused of engaging in demagoguery at the expense of his nation. The criticism has even made its way to Urban Dictionary:
Greek Referendum
Noun. An act of intense self-destruction. A suicidal act. Usually harms many people, not just the person committing the act. Often causes those witnessing the act to facepalm or exclaim in a loud voice, "Why?"
The average Greek citizen is not a political economist or an expert in international finance, which means most eligible voters weren't nearly knowledgeable enough on the technical financial issues involved to make an informed decision  certainly not as informed as the government they elected to make these decisions. Nevertheless, the mere fact that Greek citizens were given a choice means that the Greek referendum might actually be good for the country in the long run.
Pick your poison
Going into the vote, Greece faced two very bad options. On the one hand, it could turn down Europe's bailout proposal, reject the attached austerity measures, and face the wrath of its creditors. This would destroy Greece's credit rating for years and probably lead to the country's exit from the European Union, which would in all likelihood trigger massive capital flight, inflation, and all sorts of other economic horrors. On the other hand, Prime Minister Tsipras and his team could accept yet another round of unpopular austerity measures, further cutting salaries and pensions and raising taxes, under the hope that this austerity package (unlike the last several) would finally lead to an improvement in the Greek economy. But with unemployment already at record highs, this would put severe financial strain on Greek families, and potentially cause the economy to collapse further.
In other words, it didn't matter which decision the Greeks made; the ramifications were going to be pretty bad. It was pick-your-poison time.
The biggest threat
One might say that the biggest threat to Greece right now, however, wasn't austerity, nor is it the now very real possibility of leaving the Euro. The biggest threat to Greece right now may be the political instability that could result from citizens' frustrations regarding the inevitable fallout from either of those two unenviable paths. Disruptive protests, rioting, constitutional change, or (at worst) an unconstitutional change in government or regime would only make Greece's economic situation worseand could have ripple effects on every aspect of Greek life for years to come.
The people's say
So how does the government in Athens prevent unrest? Bringing its citizens into the decision-making process may make them more likely to accept the ultimate outcome, whatever that outcome may be. As we discussed in our book, Democracy Despite Itself, there is a strong psychological principle that people are much more at peace with a decision  even one they disagree with  if they are given a voice in the decision-making process. This so-called "procedural justice" also reduces corruption and makes people more willing to follow rules and get along.
Research captures these effects. During the 1991 California drought, the amount of water residents rationed wasn't influenced by their beliefs about the drought's severity, but instead was driven by how fair they thought water pricing and allocating polices were. Studies show that people are more likely to pay taxes when they get to vote on where the tax money goes, even when they aren't on the winning side of the vote.
The referendum result isn't likely to help Greece make better decisions about its future,  but it very well could help Greece nonetheless. The mere fact that the voters themselves are deciding could make all the difference in the world.
Mike Edwards is a writer and political analyst. Daniel Oppenheimer is a professor of psychology and marketing at the UCLA Anderson School of Management. They are the co-authors of Democracy Despite Itself: Why a System that Shouldn't Work at All Works so Well . They wrote this for Zocalo Public Square .
In addition to its own editorials, USA TODAY publishes diverse opinions from outside writers, including our Board of Contributors . To read more columns like this, go to the Opinion front page .
9 CONNECT 51 TWEET LINKEDIN 14 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1IF0p2h
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:43:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tsipras wins at home, but debt problems remain</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/99573190/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Tsipras-wins-at-home-but-debt-problems-remain/</Link>
        <Description>Despite his political victory, Greek's prime minister faces a daunting financial challenge.</Description>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Tsipras wins at home, but debt problems remain
ATHENS  When Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras went to vote in the referendum Sunday morning, he was smiling and confident, saying he was "very optimistic" over the outcome of the polls. And even though
Post to Facebook
Tsipras wins at home, but debt problems remain ATHENS  When Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras went to vote in the referendum Sunday morning, he was smiling and confident, saying he was "very optimistic" over the outcome of the polls. And even though Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1M7J555
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
14
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Tsipras wins at home, but debt problems remain
Nick Roumpis and Thodoris Skoulis, Special for USA TODAY 1:43 p.m. EDT July 6, 2015
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras addresses the nation after the results of the bailout referendum from his office in Athens on July 5, 2015.
(Photo: Andrea Bonetti/ Greek government handout, EPA)
40 CONNECT 97 TWEET 3 LINKEDIN 14 COMMENTEMAILMORE
ATHENS  The  unexpectedly strong "no" vote Greeks cast against a new international bailout plan was a great political victory for Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras. Yet his personal triumph may soon be overshadowed by a worsening financial crisis.
"Nothing changes," said Elena Roumba, 35, an unemployed Athens resident, echoing the sentiment of many in Greece and around Europe. "The crisis remains."
Indeed, Sunday's vote does not change the economic crisis the country faces: banks are nearly out of money, and unless international creditors agree to soften their terms for new loans, Greece remains on the verge of financial collapse.
Analysis: Greece's 'game of chicken' with creditors continues
Some political analysts say the mandate from voters will strengthen the hand of Tsipras and his left wing Syriza party to negotiate with the International Monetary Fund, European Central Bank and European Commission for debt relief with less severe demands for spending cuts.
And by taking a tough stand against unpopular austerity measures as the price for a bailout, Tsipras appears stronger at home, too, since taking office early this year.
On Monday, opposition party leaders rallied around Tsipras in pursuing new bailout negotiations.
"We have a man who has won two electoral battles in six months. Such a man should feel very happy," said Christos Xanthakis, a political analyst in Athens and columnist at the news website newspost.gr.
"Each time he was publicly addressing Greeks, the 'no' vote gained ground," Xanthakis added. "This clearly suggests that his personal image has not been damaged at all but on the contrary, it has been strengthened."
Still, other analysts say, Greece's rapidly deteriorating financial situation could threaten his political future and trigger elections in the not so-distant future.
"The disaster will begin," said Dimitris Charlambis, professor of political science at the University of Athens. "Greece will face a banking crisisdevaluation and hyperinflationthen default."
Since 2010, Greece has borrowed $266 billion, the biggest loan given to a country in history. Despite austerity policies adopted by the government, Greece's public debt has risen to nearly double its annual economic activity and unemployment has skyrocketed to 26%.
Tsipras, who sacked his brash finance minister, Yianis Varoufakis, on Monday, said last week after calling for the referendum that creditors are now offering a "decent" deal to Greece. But some believe he and his government miscalculated.
Greek, other euro leaders set for new round of talks
"Tsipras has overplayed his hand," said Carsten Brzeski, chief economist at ING financial group's Frankfurt office. "The Euro group is so fed up with his political style and the damage it has caused. They have lost trust in the current Greek government."
At the same time, Greek voters, weary after so many years in economic distress, have lost trust in the creditors' ever-demanding calls for more austerity.
Voters elected Tsipras' fringe party into the mainstream in January because they were fed up with the establishment parties that ran Greece for decades and agreed to the tough measures imposed by the creditors.
"I will give Mr. Tsipras the power to negotiate for our better future," said Kostas Petratos, 20, a mathematics student in Patras in western Greece. "This situation was created by the previous prime ministers. Mr. Tsipras is fighting and I will fight with him."
After the vote results were announced Sunday, thousands of  "no" supporters gathered at Athens' main Syntagma Square and erupted in cheers and song to celebrate their victory.
For the moment, no one here was thinking about the government's uncertain future or their own.
Contributing: Marina Rigou, Nikolia Apostolou in Athens, Mihret Yohannes in Berlin.
40 CONNECT 97 TWEET 3 LINKEDIN 14 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1M7J555
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Tue May 26 17:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Battling Islamic State militants</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/87524922/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Battling-Islamic-State-militants/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Battling Islamic State militants
Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq.
Post to Facebook
Battling Islamic State militants Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1ChmkJu
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
5
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Battling Islamic State militants
Iraqi fighters from a Shiite mobilization unit fire at Islamic State militants on May 25 near the Baiji refinery in Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters fire at Islamic State positions during a battle near the Baiji oil refinery.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters advance near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Shiite fighters hold a position near the Baiji oil refinery.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi fighters hold a position against Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Sunni fighters battle Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Shiite fighters from the Popular Mobilization Units display an Iraqi national flag in front of an Islamic State mural on April 1 outside a presidential palace in Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government security forces celebrate in Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government soldiers battle Islamic State militants in Tikrit.
European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi counterterrorism forces patrol a street.
Ahmad Al-rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces deploy in the city.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi soldier guards a checkpoint.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi army tank advances in Tikrit on March 31 during a battle against Islamic State militants.  Iraqi Prime Minister Haider al-Abadi announced that Iraqi troops, supported by U.S.-led airstrikes, have recaptured most of the town from the Islamic State.
European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke rises during fighting in Tikrit.
European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi security forces conduct a house-to-house search for Islamic State militants on March 30 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces attack Islamic State extremists in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government troops watch an area outside the city. Islamic State militants have booby trapped streets and buildings in Tikrit with explosives.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi officer shouts orders.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces launch a rocket at Islamic State extremists.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security force soldiers run to a position as they surround Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi forces fire rockets at Islamic State positions in Tikrit on March 28.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government vehicles are positioned outside western Tikrit on March 27 during a military operation to retake the city from Islamic State militants.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke billows from an air strike as Iraqi government troops hold a position outside Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government vehicles maneuver outside the city.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Explosions rock Tikrit as Iraqi security forces fire rockets against Islamic State militants.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi government vehicle drives to a position.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi security troops fire a mortar at positions held by Islamic State militants.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Smoke rises from buildings during a bombardment in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces fire a rocket at Islamic State militants on March 26 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi helicopter attacks Islamic State positions in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
A member of the Iraqi Shiite militant group the Imam Ali Brigades patrols in Tikrit on March 25.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
A volunteer fighter with the Shiite militant group Jihad Brigades fires his weapon at Islamic State militants on March 21 outside Tikrit, Iraq.
AP
Iraqi fighters with the Saraya al-Salam Brigade, a group formed by Iraqi Shiite Muslim cleric Moqtada al-Sadr, wave their weapons as they leave Najaf to join the fight against Islamic State militants on March 20.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi police leave Najaf to join government and coalition forces battling Islamic State militants in Tikrit.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A U.S. Navy jet takes off on March 19 from the aircraft carrier Carl Vinson on March 19 in the Persian Gulf. The Carl Vinson and French military jets from the French aircraft carrier Charles de Gaulle are flying missions over Iraq against Islamic State militants.
Hasan Jamali, AP
Iraqi security forces and allied Shiite militiamen battle Islamic State fighters in the Qadisiyah neighborhood in Tikrit on March 15.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Members of the group Soldiers of Imam Ali Brigade launch rockets against Islamic State extremists on March 15 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi army armored vehicle prepares to attack Islamic State positions on March 12 in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi government security forces patrol in Tikrit
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Iraqi security forces and allied Shiite militiamen prepare to attack Islamic State extremists at Camp Speicher.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Shiite militiamen prepare to attack Islamic State extremists at Camp Speicher.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
Shiite militiamen prepare to fire a mortar at Islamic State extremists in Tikrit.
Khalid Mohammed, AP
An Iraqi government soldier fires at Islamic State militants on March 11 in Tikrit.
AP
Iraqi government soldiers attack Islamic State militants as they attempt to recapture Tikrit. Iraqi soldiers and Shiite militiamen have entered Tikrit, the largest city controlled by the extremists.
AP
Iraqi government forces deploy during a military operation against Islamic State militants near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi government vehicle fires at Islamic State positions near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi pro-government fighters celebrate as they advance into Tikrit. Government forces are conducting a major military operation against Islamic State militants to recapture the city from the jihadist group.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi medics treat wounded fighters at a field hospital.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi fighter from the Popular Mobilization Unit holds a position as pro-government forces advance into Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
A member of a tribal group fighting alongside Iraqi government forces fires at Islamic State militants during a battle in the Hosh district in Ramadi.
Azhar Shallal, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi police officer aims a rocket-propelled grenade during clashes with Islamic State militants in the Hosh district of Ramadi.
Azhar Shallal, AFP/Getty Images
Members of the Popular Mobilization Unit celebrate with a captured Islamic State flag on March 9 after recapturing Albu Ajil village near Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces advance on Tikrit.
Ahmad Al Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government troops conduct a military operation against Islamic State militants in Albu Ajil village near Tikrit.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi government forces drive toward Al-Alam village on March 8.
Younis Al-Bayati, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi soldier fires at Islamic State positions near Tikrit on March 4.
Iraqi Ministry of Defense via AP
Volunteer pro-government Shiite fighters with the Popular Mobilization Unit fire a howitzer at Islamic State militants on Feb. 28 at Awaynat near Tikrit, Iraq.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
An Egyptian military jet takes off from an undisclosed base on Feb. 16 to strike Islamic State targets in Libya. Egyptian warplanes bombed Islamic State positions in retaliation for the beheading of 21 Egyptian Coptic Christian hostages.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
A video image from an Egyptian warplane shows an airstrike on an Islamic State target in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
A video image shows a bomb hit on an Islamic State position in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AP
An image from Egypt's television station Al-Masriya shows a Egyptian F-16 fighter jet preparing to take off from an undisclosed location to conduct an airstrike on Islamic State targets in Libya.
Egyptian Defense Ministry via AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A United Arab Emirates pilot prepares to take off in an F-16 on Feb. 10 at a base in Jordan. The United Arab Emirates launched airstrikes against Islamic State militants, marking the nation's return to combat operations after it halted flights in late 2014.
WAM via AP
A United Arab Emirates F-16 jet prepares for an airstrike against Islamic State targets at a base in Jordan.
WAM via AP
A Jordanian air force pilot writes a message to Islamic State militants on a missile at Mowafak Al-Salti airbase in Azraq on Feb. 6.
Roya TV via AP
Kayla Mueller speaks to a group on May 30, 2013, in Prescott, Ariz. The White House and her family confirmed the death of Mueller, who was being held by Islamic State militants, on Feb. 10.
Matt Hinshaw, The Daily Courier, via AP
Fullscreen
An image posted by the Islamic State on jihadist forums on Feb. 6 shows a heavily damaged building in Raqa, Syria, after it was allegedly targeted by a coalition airstrike. In a statement posted on jihadist websites the Islamic State group claims a female American hostage had been killed in a raid by coalition warplanes.
AFP/Getty Images
Thousands of people participate in a mass demonstration after Friday prayers near Al Hussein Mosque in Amman, Jordan, to express their solidarity with a Jordanian pilot murdered by the Islamic State group.
Jordan Pix, Getty Images
An image from the Jordanian television on Feb. 5 shows flames erupting from a building hit by an airstrike against Islamic State militants.
AFP/Getty Images
A Jordanian fighter jet takes off from an airbase.
Jordan News Agency via European Pressphoto Agency
A miltary officer writes a message on a missile. The Arabic words reads, "Will show them hell, from the Jordanian air force."
Jordan News Agency via European Pressphoto Agency
Fullscreen
Members of the Kurdish peshmerga forces and the Iraqi security forces patrol on a road as smoke billows from the Khubbaz oil field, some 15 miles west of the northern city of Kirkuk a few days after peshmerga forces and police retook the area from Islamic State group. 
Marwan Ibrahim, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
Members of the Yazidi minority search for clues that might lead them to missing relatives among the remains of those killed by the Islamic State jihadi group, a day after Kurdish forces discovered a mass grave near the Iraqi village of Sinuni, in the northwestern Sinjar area.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
Iraqi Shiite fighters celebrate in al-Mansuriya, in Iraq's Diyala province, after government forces retook the area from Islamic State group's control. Iraqi forces have "liberated" Diyala province from the Islamic State jihadist group, retaking all populated areas of the eastern region.
Ahmad Al-Rubaye, AFP/Getty Images
Fullscreen
A Syrian Kurdish sniper sits among the rubble in the Syrian city of Ain al-Arab, also known as Kobani, Syria. The Islamic State group has acknowledged for the first time that its fighters were defeated there, but vowed to attack the town again.
AP
Fullscreen
A Syrian Kurdish sniper sits among the rubble in the Syrian city of Ain al-Arab, also known as Kobani, Syria. The Islamic State group has acknowledged for the first time that its fighters were defeated there, but vowed to attack the town again.
AP
Kurdish peshmerga fighters surround extremists inside a hotel near police headquarters in the oil-rich city of  Kirkuk, 180 miles north of Baghdad. 
AP
A Syrian Kurdish man walks among the rubble in Kobani.
AP
Rubble and damaged buildings are seen in the devastated Syrian city of Kobani.
AP
Fullscreen
Members of the Yazidi minority search for clues that might lead them to missing relatives among the remains of those killed by the Islamic State jihadi group, a day after Kurdish forces discovered a mass grave near the Iraqi village of Sinuni, in the northwestern Sinjar area.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
Members of the Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units stand on the back of a homemade armored vehicle as they patrol Kobani, Syria.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A member of Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units walks through rubble on a street in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A member of Syrian Kurdish People's Defense Units walks through rubble in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A Kurdish peshmerga fighter aims his weapon as other fighters cross a bridge on Nov. 30 near Kirkuk, Iraq.
Marwan Ibrahim, AFP/Getty Images
An Iraqi soldier inspects destroyed trucks used by Islamic State militants near Amerli.
Ali Mohammed, European Pressphoto Agency
Iraqi army soldiers deploy in front of a court building run by the Islamic State militants in Sadiyah on Nov. 24.
AP
A Kurdish People's Protection Units fighter looks at damage from a Nov. 19 truck bomb attack in Kobani, Syria.
Jake Simkin, AP
Islamic State militants stand on Tilsehir Hill near the Turkish border before an Oct. 23 airstrike in Yumurtalik village.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A bomb explodes on Tilsehir Hill.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
People in Turkey watch an explosion following an airstrike carried out by coalition forces.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A Kurdish refugee woman from Kobani, Syria, holds a child in a camp in Suruc.
Kutluhan Cucel, Getty Images
People warm themselves on a hilltop outside Suruc, Turkey. They've gathered to watch fighting across the border in Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises from an airstrike in Kobani, Syria. Kobani and its surrounding areas have been under assault by extremists of the Islamic State group since mid-September and are being defended by Kurdish fighters.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
U.S.-led coalition aircraft strike at Islamic State targets on Oct. 20 in Kobani, Syria.
AP
Kurdish people observe smoke rising from the Syrian town of Kobani following an explosion as seen from the southeastern Turkish village of Mursitpinar in the Sanliurfa province on Oct. 20.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A explosion during an allied airstrike rocks Kobani.
AP
People watch from a hill in Turkey as Syrian Kurdish fighters battle militants from the Islamic State in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Allied warplanes strike Islamic State positions.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
Shiite fighters loyal to Grand Ayatollah Ali al-Sistani fire missiles at Islamic State militants on Oct. 19 in Karbala, Iraq.
Mohammed Swaf, AFP/Getty Images
People gather on a hill outside Suruc, Turkey, to watch fighting between Syrian Kurds and Islamic State militants in Kobane, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
U.S. Navy Aviation Boatswain Mate Jessica Brown directs an aircraft on the flight deck of the aircraft carrier USS Carl Vinson as the ship conducts strike operations in Iraq and Syria.
U.S. Navy via European Pressphoto Agency
Syrian refugees walk through a camp in Suruc, Turkey.
Bulent Kilic, AFP/Getty Images
A man uses the scope from a sniper rifle to watch fighting in Kobani, Syria, on Oct. 19.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty Images
Islamic State militants fight in Kobani on Oct. 19.
Aamaq News Agency via AFP/Getty Images
Kurdish fighters detonate an Islamic State land mine in Gwer district, northern Iraq.
Safin Hamed, AFP/Getty Images
A bomb explodes during an Oct. 18 allied airstrike on Islamic State targets in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
A U.S. Air Force B1-B bomber flies above Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Iraqi Shiite volunteers participate in a training session in Hillah.
Haidar Hamdani, AFP/Getty Images
An explosion rocks Kobani, Syria, on Oct. 18 during an allied strike on Islamic State militants.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
An Islamic State fighter fires a heavy machine gun in Kobani on Oct. 17.
Aamaq News Agency via AFP/Getty Images
Thick smoke rises following an airstrike by the US-led coalition in Kobani, Syria as fighting continued between Syrian Kurds and the militants of Islamic State.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Iraqi federal policemen search a car at a checkpoint in Baghdad.
Karim Kadim, AP
A woman in Mursitpinar, Turkey, reacts as smoke rises from explosions after an Oct. 13 allied airstrike on Islamic State targets in Kobani, Syria.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Coalition aircraft bomb Islamic State positions in Kobani, Syria.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
Heavy smoke rises following an airstrike by allied aircraft.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty images
A vendor sells bread to people watching the ongoing bombing campaign in Kobani, Syria, on a hilltop outside Suruc, Turkey.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
People watch fighting between YPG Kurdish fighters and Islamic State militants in Kobani.
Tolga Bozoglu, European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke rises from the Syrian town of Kobani after airstrikes on Islamic State fighters.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty Images
Rabia Ali mourns at the grave of her son, Seydo Mehmud, a Kurdish fighter, who was killed during a battle with Islamic State militants.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Civilians and Turkish military personnel watch fighting between Kurds and militants from the Islamic State group.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish Kurds watch fighting in Kobani.
Gokhan Sahin, Getty images
Smoke rises from Kobani near the Turkish-Syrian border.
Stringer, Getty images
Turkish armored vehicles hold a position on a hill above Kobani on Oct. 9.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
A Kurdish man watches fighting in Kobani, Syria, from a hill in Turkey.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke rises from an allied airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
A Turkish Kurd watches an airstrike in Kobani on Oct. 8.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Personnel on a Turkish army tank watch allied warplanes attack Islamic State targets in Kobani, Syria.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
A  plume of smoke rises after an airstrike in eastern Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish Kurds watch an airstrike in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises after an allied airstrike against an Islamic State target in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Turkish Kurds in Mursitpinar, Turkey, watch fighting between Kurdish forces and Islamic State militants in Kobani, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
An allied airstrike hits Islamic State targets in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Turkish armored vehicles patrol the Turkish-Syrian border in Sanliurfa province.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Smoke rises after an airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Turkish Kurds in Turkey watch fighting in Kobani, Syria.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Turkish troops watch the results of an airstrike in Kobani.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Fullscreen
Smoke rises after an airstrike by allied forces against Islamic State targets on Oct. 7 in the Syrian town of Kobani near Suruc district, Turkey. Airstrikes targeted three groups of Islamic State militants in the first daytime action in Syria by U.S.-led coalition forces.
Sedat Suna, European Pressphoto Agency
Smoke from an explosion after an allied airstrike in Kobani.
Aris Messinis, AFP/Getty Images
Turkish soldiers stand near their armored vehicles as they hold a position outside Suruc, near the Turkey-Syria border.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
Smoke rises from an explosion in Kobani.
Lefteris Pitarakis, AP
An Iraqi military vehicle burns after an Islamic State attack in western Anbar province on Oct. 5.
AP
A photograph from the British Ministry of Defense shows the result of a Brimstone missile strike on an armed Islamic State truck on Sept. 30 in Iraq. The Brimstone missile is circled in red moments before impact.
Ministry of Defense via AP
A British Ministry of Defense photograph shows the result of a missile attack on an Islamic State truck in Iraq.
Ministry of Defense via AP
A British Royal Air Force Tornado GR4 aircraft lands after a mission over Iraq at the Akrotiri airbase in Cyprus.
Cpl. Neil Bryden, Royal Air Force, via AP
Iraqi Shiite militiamen battle Islamic State militants on Sept. 29 in Jurf al-Sakhar.
AP
A Department of Defense photograph released on Sept. 29 shows a pair of U.S. Air Force F-15E Strike Eagles flying over northern Iraq on Sept. 23.
Matthew Brusch, U.S. Air Force, via European Pressphoto Agency
A Sept. 26 photograph released by the U.S. Air Force shows a KC-10 Extender refueling an F-22 Raptor fighter aircraft before a strike operation against Islamic State targets in Syria.
Tech. Sgt. Russ Scalf, U.S. Air Force, via AP
Two photographs provided by the Pentagon on Sept. 25 shows before and after images of an airstrike on the Jerible Modular oil refinery in Syria.
Department of Defense via AP
Two photographs provided by the Pentagon shows before and after images of an allied airstrike on the Gbiebi Modular oil refinery.
Department of Defense via AP
A U.S. Navy F-18E Super Hornet receives fuel from a U.S. Air Force KC-135 Stratotanker over northern Iraq after conducting airstrikes on Islamic State targets in Syria.
Staff Sgt. Shawn Nickel, U.S. Air Force, via AP
A formation of U.S. Navy F-18E Super Hornets leaves after receiving fuel from a U.S. Air Force KC-135 Stratotanker over northern Iraq.
Staff Sgt. Shawn Nickel, U.S. Air Force, via AP
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Sat May 23 21:24:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ireland legalizes gay marriage</title>
        <Link>http://rssfeeds.usatoday.com/~/92962503/0/usatodaycomworld-topstories~Ireland-legalizes-gay-marriage/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Ireland legalizes gay marriage
Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum.
Post to Facebook
Ireland legalizes gay marriage Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Stu56b
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
9
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Ireland legalizes gay marriage
Drag queen and gay rights activist Rory O'Neill, also known by the stage name Panti, raises her arms on May 23 beside supporters for same-sex marriage at Dublin Castle as they waited for the result of the referendum.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Irish Sen. Katherine Zappone, left, kisses her partner, Ann Louise Gilligan, as supporters for same-sex marriage wait for the result of the referendum at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
A man blows bubbles as supporters for same-sex marriage waited for the result of the referendum at Dublin Castle.
Paul Faith, AFP/Getty Images
Supporters wait for the final result in the Irish referendum at Dublin Castle.
Peter Morrison, AP
Supporters wait for the final result in the Irish referendum at Dublin Castle.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Supporters for same-sex marriage cheer at Dublin Castle.
Peter Morrison, AP
Michael Barron, right, and Jamie Nanci, who were married in Cape Town, South Africa, kiss at the RDS count center in Dublin.
Charles McQuillan, Getty Images
Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries:
Replay
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
