<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Washington Post">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:00:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The U.S. air war against the Islamic State, in numbers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47e6a374/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cthe0Eu0Es0Eair0Ewar0Eagainst0Ethe0Eislamic0Estate0Ein0Enumbers0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>"This will not be quick," President Obama told reporters at a Monday briefing in the Pentagon, referring to the ongoing U.S. air war against the Islamic State. "This is a long-term campaign. ISIL is opportunistic and it is nimble. . . . It will take time to root them out." Obama was referring to the acronym used by [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor July 7 at 5:00 AM Follow @ishaantharoor
President Obama (L) is flanked by military leaders as he delivers remarks after a briefing on U.S. efforts against the Islamic State (ISIS), at the Pentagon in Arlington, Va., July 6, 2015. REUTERS/Jonathan Ernst
"This will not be quick," President Obama told reporters at a Monday briefing in the Pentagon, referring to the ongoing U.S. air waragainst the Islamic State. "This is a long-term campaign. ISIL is opportunistic and it is nimble. . . . It will take time to root them out."
Obama was referring to the acronym used by his administration for the jihadist organization that still controls swaths of territory in Iraq and Syria.
As my colleague Missy Ryan reports , Obama pointed to notablevictories enabled by American air strikes:
Obama highlighted battles in which U.S.-aligned fighters have prevailed against the group, including combat in the Syrian cities of Kobane and Tal Abyad and the Iraqi city of Tikrit. He said Islamic State fighters have lost more of than a quarter of the populated territory they had captured in Iraq.
But the jihadists, despite having no state support, remain an entrenched, dogged foe.This a reflection of the particular complexity of the fight. The Obama administration is justifiably keen to limit itsrole in a yet another conflict Middle East, especially one thathas crossed borders and involves coordinating with a mess of factions and state actors on the ground. It's also wary of inflicting civilian casualties.
Micah Zenko, a senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations, crunches the numbers of the U.S. air campaign, and sets it against other recent missions. Despite the U.S. air war against the Islamic State now entering a second year, it has conducted far fewer sorties and dropped fewer bombs than during the shock-and-awe campaign in Iraq in 2003 or NATO'soperationsagainst Serbian forces in 1999.
How the airwar against ISIS compares with history. http://t.co/vsmfQMXxLf pic.twitter.com/CSuuhI2PgO
 Micah Zenko (@MicahZenko) July 6, 2015
Zenko qualifies the uses of the comparison:
Understand that these are all distinct military operations with their own objectives, combination of coalition partners, and rules of engagement, and that this data is challenging to compile. However, for a military campaign that allegedly intends to inflict a lasting defeat on the dispersed and large militant army that is the Islamic State, there is a relatively limited  though understandable given the concern of civilian casualties  number of bombs being dropped each day.
Still, according to U.S. estimates , the American bombingcampaign has hit nearly 8,000 Islamic State targets and killedsome12,500 Islamic Statefighters. It's important to note, as Zenko does , that civilians have still died amid the U.S. air strikes. The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights claim s that the U.S.-ledcoalition is responsible for the deathsof 162 civilians, including 51 children and 35 women.
Ishaan Tharoor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. He previously was a senior editor at TIME, based first in Hong Kong and later in New York.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:30:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Germany has defaulted on its debts, too</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47e5f6bf/sc/24/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cgermany0Ehas0Edefaulted0Eon0Eits0Edebts0Etoo0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Greek debt crisis is often portrayed as a dispute between two actors with two very different economic visions: a German government that seeks austerity over anything else and a Greek government desperate to escape its debts without suffering the pain that austerity would bring. That is not necessarily an inaccurate vision. It does, however, miss out on an important [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Adam Taylor July 7 at 3:30 AM Follow @mradamtaylor
Russian soldiers are pictured next to the Reichstag building in Berlin in this undated photo from May 1945. (Georgiy Samsonov/MHM via Reuters)
The Greek debt crisis is often portrayedas adispute between two actors with two very different economic visions: a German government that seeks austerity over anything else and a Greek government desperate toescape its debts withoutsuffering the pain that austerity would bring.
That isnot necessarily an inaccurate vision. It does, however, miss out on an important historical element: that Germany's own strong position was possible only because it has escaped its debts in the past.
This point was hammered home during an interview between Thomas Piketty, the rock star anti-inequality economist, and Die Zeit , a German newspaper, that went viral online over the past few days. Germany is the country that has never repaid its debts," Piketty said . "It has no standing to lecture other nations.
Piketty is talking specifically about the aftermath of World War II , when West Germany owed a number of creditors about $7 billion, or $62 billion in today's dollars. In 1953, these creditors agreed to reduce the debt by about half, hoping that an economically stable Germany would be good for the rest of Europe and acknowledging the role that reparation payments had in fermenting the Nazi movement.
This isn't a new theory. Albrecht Ritschl, an economic historian, has calculated that Germany had truly been exceptional when it came to escaping its debts."Germany is king when it comes to debt," Ritschl told Der Spiegel in 2011."Calculated based on the amount of losses compared to economic performance, Germany was the biggest debt transgressor of the 20th century." Notably, Ritschl's research at the London School of Economics has concluded that debt cancellation for the euro zone's troubled economies (including Greece but also Italy, Ireland, Portugal and Spain) would be roughly equal to the debts canceled by the Allied powers after World War II.
You can go back even further intoGermany's debt issues. As the Economist has pointed out ,Germany defaulted on its debts during the 1930s, and the German states that predated a unified Germany defaulted at least three times in the 19th century. Modern-day Germany, the economic powerhouse of Europe, isa product of all thesedefaults.
Perhaps it is not fair to compare the current situation in Greece to what Germany found itself in during the Weimar years and after the end of World War II:The economic and political context at work nowis certainly very different .But it is hard to deny that the grand ideaof the European Union  an idea that Germany is trying to protect  was created at least partly in response to such financial problems.
And in Greece  a country that was owed money by Germany in 1953  history still matters.Under the leadership of the current Syriza government, Greece has pushed for Germany to pay reparations for its conduct during World War II, a sum that could be as high as $340 billion by some estimates and includesestimates of the structural damage that Axis occupation did to Greece.
More on WorldViews
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:33:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Afghans outraged again as a court overturns death sentences in woman’s mob killing</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47e2198b/sc/3/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A60Cafghans0Eoutraged0Eagain0Eas0Ea0Ecourt0Eoverturns0Edeath0Esentences0Ein0Ewomans0Emob0Ekilling0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Her brutal killing galvanized Afghanistan in March. Thousands protested, demanding punishment for those involved in Farkhunda's mob lynching. The 27-year-old had been falsely accused of burning a Koran and her death, captured on video, ended with her body being burned and thrown into the Kabul River. Four men were sentenced to death in May after a televised [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Elahe Izadi July 6 at 4:33 PM Follow @ElaheIzadi
A woman chants slogans during a protest held by the Solidarity Party of Afghanistan for Farkhunda on Monday at the site of the attack in Kabul. (Massoud Hossaini/AP)
Herbrutal killing galvanized Afghanistan in March. Thousands protested, demanding punishment for those involved in Farkhunda's mob lynching. The 27-year-oldhad been falsely accused of burning a Koran and her death, captured on video, ended with her body being burned and thrown into the Kabul River.
Four men were sentenced to death in May after a televised trial, unusual in the country. Then, last week, an appeals court quietlyoverturned those sentences behind closed-doors, the Associated Press reported . Three men will now serve 20 years and the fourth will serve 10 years,Appeals Court Judge Abdul Nasir Murid told the wire service.
Her family heard the development first from local news reports. Her brother told BBC Persian: Its not a court, its just a show. The media should have been there, we should [have] been there, the lawyers should have been there."
[ How a slain Afghan woman became an unlikely champion for womens rights ]
On Monday, dozens of demonstrators assembled outside the shrine where the mob killed Farkhunda, shouting slogans such as "We want justice," AP reported . The red paint on their bodies was a homage to the images of the bloodied 27-year-old.
Activists from the Solidarity Party of Afghanistan protest Monday against a court's recent decision over the case of Farkhunda. (Ahmad Masood/Reuters)
Farkhunda,an Islamic law student, had reportedly come to the shrine in March to preach against what she deemed as un-Islamic practices, the New York Times reported . An accusation levied against her -- that she burned the Koran -- eventually led to a mob of men descending upon her, attacking her with rocks and stones in broad daylight.
As The Post reported earlier this year :
Although details are unclear, some witnesses suggested that the attack was sparked by a dispute Farkhunda had with the mosques imam. Whatever the case, the mob was bent on killing her in the most horrific manner. They dragged her body with a car, then burned it and threw it into the Kabul River.
It took two hours to murder her, the brutality unfolding as hundreds of people and armed policemen watched, doing nothing to save Farkhunda from her assailants. The neighborhood police headquarters was about a five-minute walk from the mosque. Many witnesses shot photos and videos with their smartphones.
Her death marked a pivotal moment for many Afghans, who were horrified by the manner in which Farkhunda died. Thousands protested in thespring, marching in front of the Supreme Court and chanting "Punish the murderers."
Following the trial,Farkhunda's brotherNajibullah Malikzadah told The Post hundreds "were involved in my sisters brutal killing and only four of them are sentenced to death. This is not justice at all."
A man chants slogans during a Monday protest held by the Solidarity Party of Afghanistan forFarkhunda.(Massoud Hossaini/AP)
Eventually, 49 people were convicted in Farkhunda's death, 37 of whom were released last month, AP reported. Of those convicted, 19 were policemen.
Murid's announcement about the appeals court decision did not include further details as to why the sentences were reduced, AFP reported . The service reported that the appeals were heard in a closed courtroom.
Protests on Monday, reportedly organized by the Solidarity Party, included demonstrators covered in red paint and holding images of Farkhunda as she pleaded with her attackers.
Some activists had met with Afghan President Ashraf Ghani over the weekend regarding the court's decision. Ghani'soffice released a statement Sunday that "the constitution prohibits him from interfering" in the appeals decision, Reuters reported .
Afghan women hold placards of Farkhunda on July 6. (ShahMarai/AFP/Getty)
Afghan women shout slogans during a Monday protest against the verdict of the court. (Hedayatullah Amid/EPA)
Elahe Izadi is a general assignment national reporter for The Washington Post.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:24:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kenyan lawmakers say Obama shouldn’t be allowed to talk about gay rights during his visit</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47e15a5b/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A60Ckenyan0Elawmakers0Esay0Eobama0Eshouldnt0Ebe0Eallowed0Eto0Etalk0Eabout0Egay0Erights0Eduring0Ehis0Evisit0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In just a few weeks, President Obama will visit Kenya. It's an important visit for many reasons, not least because many Kenyans hope that his familial link to the country can lead to a better relationship between the United States and East Africa. Yet there's one subject than some Kenyans do not want brought up: [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Adam Taylor July 6 at 2:24 PM Follow @mradamtaylor
Protesters chant slogans against the lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender community as they march along the streets of Kenya's capital, Nairobi, on Monday. The demonstration is aimed at President Obama, who is set to visit the country later this month. (Thomas Mukoya/Reuters)
In just a few weeks, President Obama will visit Kenya. It's an important visit for many reasons , not least because many Kenyans hope that his familial link to the country can lead to a better relationship between the United States and East Africa.
Yet there's one subject than some Kenyans do not want brought up: gay rights.
On Sunday, Justin Muturi, the speaker of Kenya's National Assembly, warned that parliament has the ability to "sanction any advances perceived to encroach on our social fabric," according to the Star , a local newspaper."As an individual and a Christian, I am opposed to homosexuality and cannot condone gay practices."
Muturi was one of five Kenyan lawmakers at a cathedral fundraising event on Sunday whotold the audience thatObama should not be allowed to bring up the issue of gay rights during his visit. Another,Charles Njagagua, said Obama should be ejected from the Kenyan parliament if he mentions gay rights, the Nation newspaper reported , whileRose Mitaru said the country was ready to reject any aid if it is tied to gay marriage.
In Kenya, where gay sex is punishable by up to 14 years in prison, such an opinion is not unusual. On Monday, a handful of people in Nairobi gathered for a protest against homosexuality.When Obama comes, we are asking him to respect the morals of the Kenyans, respect the faith of the Kenyans, Bishop Mark Kariuki, a leader of theEvangelical Alliance of Kenya, which called for the protest, told the Associated Press .
Video shot by the Star shows the protesters chanting slogans that included "Obama, no gay."
Online, some Kenyan social media users echoed the statement, using thehashtag #KenyansMessageToObama to push an anti-homosexual message.
#KenyansMessageToObama We have very beautiful, amazing and lovely women... why should we be gay pic.twitter.com/32mBhctKxQ
 Nicky Mwathi (@nickythebrand) July 6, 2015
#KenyansMessageToObama @POTUS the homo agenda is not of interest to Kenyans. Try security and trade.
 Dennis Nthumbi (@NNthumbi) July 6, 2015
#KenyansMessageToObama That gay vibe should remain in America.God made Adam and Eve not Steve.
 Arselona! (@D_Atang_a) July 6, 2015
Whether Obama will mention gay rights during his trip is unclear. In the aftermath of a decision by the U.S. Supreme Court, however, gay marriage is being perceived as one of thekey successes of his two terms in office. He also has a history here: Before a trip to Africa in 2013, Obama made a statement in support of gay rights, prompting the president of Senegal to say that his country was"still not ready to decriminalize homosexuality."
Asked about the Kenyan lawmakers' comments on Monday, White House spokesperson Josh Earnest said there would be no constraints on what Obama would discuss during his trip to Kenya."We have been clear that when the president travels around the world he does not hesitate to raise concerns about human rights," Earnest said.
Some critics have argued that Obama's Kenya visit is ill-timed, but the presidenthas recently shown a willingness to seek dialogue with many governments at odds with Washington. Homosexuality is a tricky subject in much of the African continent, however, partly because of colonial-era laws and the work of Westernevangelical preachers. More than half of the countries on the continent have laws criminalizing homosexuality, and it is punishable by death in some places.
A 2013 poll by the Pew Research Center found that Kenya was one of a number of countries where the majority of people rejected gay rights: Just 1 percent said the country should accept homosexuals.
David Nakamura contributed reporting to this story
Adam Taylor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. Originally from London, he studied at the University of Manchester and Columbia University.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:07:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Egypt to foreign journalists: Don’t call them ‘ISIS’ fighters, call them ‘eradicators’</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47e07509/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A60Cegypt0Eto0Eforeign0Ejournalists0Edont0Ecall0Ethem0Eisis0Efighters0Ecall0Ethem0Eeradicators0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Over the weekend, the Egyptian foreign ministry issued a guide to foreign journalists, asking them to reconsider how they refer to certain groups that carry out terror attacks in the country. Alex Ortiz, a producer for CBS News based in Cairo, tweeted one page of the memo that caught his eye: Egypt&amp;#39;s Foreign Ministry issues foreign press [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Adam Taylor July 6 at 11:07 AM Follow @mradamtaylor
Over the weekend, the Egyptian foreign ministry issued a guide to foreign journalists, asking themto reconsider how they refer to certain groups that carry out terror attacks in the country.Alex Ortiz, a producer for CBS News based in Cairo, tweeted one page of the memo that caught his eye:
Egypt's Foreign Ministry issues foreign press corps a style guide for how we should describe terrorist groups. pic.twitter.com/AAn9MNcLxC
 Alex Ortiz (@azortiz) July 4, 2015
The memo appears to be designed to stop foreign news media describing terror attacks in a way that shows any link to Islam  a line of reasoning many others follow around the world. For example, critics have long suggested that the referring to the extremist group based in Syria and Iraq as the "Islamic State" defers on them a religious legitimacy that they don't deserve. This is a mainstream, global debate:Just late last month, British Prime Minister David Cameron asked the BBC to stop referring to the group as the "Islamic State" (the BBC refused).
However, the local context of Egypt's suggestionhas some journalists worried. The memo was handed out at a news conference on Saturday, just a few days after a wave of Islamic State-linked attacks in Sinai that left an unclear number of Egyptian soldiers dead.
According to CNN's Sarah Sirgany , the Egyptian foreign ministry used the press conference topass on "observations" of the foreign ministry's coverage of the Sinai attacks.One clear issue appears to have been the death toll, with the military saying that at least 17 soldiers had died, while the international press, including The Washington Post , reporting numbers as high as 70.
A newly drafted anti-terrorism law , drawn upafter the Sinai attacks and awaiting the approval of Egyptian President Abdel Fatah al-Sissi, may actually make reporting figures that contradict official statements a crime if "intent" or "malice" can be proven. The law stipulates a minimum two-year sentence for the crime.
To critics, the law and the memo are examples of how restrictive it's becoming to report objectively in Egypt. We are faced with an article that pushes the media towards Goebbels media  the media of one opinion and one narrative, Gamal Eid, the executive director of the Arab Network for Human Rights Information (ANHRI), told the Guardian .It is against the freedom of press, especially press that is critical and professional.
More on WorldViews
Why the BBC said no when David Cameron asked it to stop using the term Islamic State

Adam Taylor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. Originally from London, he studied at the University of Manchester and Columbia University.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:01:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The terrible, sexist tweet that shows how far women’s soccer still has to go</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47dfb83e/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A60Cthe0Eterrible0Esexist0Etweet0Ethat0Eshows0Ehow0Efar0Ewomens0Esoccer0Estill0Ehas0Eto0Ego0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Here's one way the official Twitter feed of U.S. soccer celebrated the American victory at the Women's World Cup in Canada. We&amp;#39;ve got an idea for a new $10 &amp;#38; $1 @federalreserve. How about the best Women&amp;#39;s Player and Goalkeeper in the World. pic.twitter.com/gJ2aRc36Yz &amp;#8212; U.S. Soccer WNT (@ussoccer_wnt) July 6, 2015 No wonder. The stars [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor July 6 at 10:01 AM Follow @ishaantharoor
Here's one waythe official Twitter feed of U.S. soccer celebrated the American victory at the Women's World Cup in Canada.
We've got an idea for a new $10 &amp; $1 @federalreserve . How about the best Women's Player and Goalkeeper in the World. pic.twitter.com/gJ2aRc36Yz
 U.S. Soccer WNT (@ussoccer_wnt) July 6, 2015
No wonder. The stars of the U.S. women's team are world-beaters, far more accomplished than their male counterparts and a perennial reminder of the awesomeness offemale athletes .Yet, for most of the time, they have tocompete in the shadow of the men's game -- paid a minuscule fraction of what their male equivalents earn and forced to play in conditions that soccer's male superstars would never accept.
[ 20 World Cup goals that changed history ]
The United States has a rich history of success in women's soccer, and so perhaps understands how to properly celebrate its team.You would hopeAmerican soccer authoritieswould never tweet what the official account of the English national team did on Monday morning:
This is a screengrab of anow-deleted tweet . Its tone-deafness is staggering. You would never see the @england account issue the parallel message for its men's team, even though British tabloids spend way too much time obsessing over the personal relationships of the country's incredibly overpaid , perpetually underwhelmingmen's side.
1 of 30
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 12:00:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The amazing story of a tsunami survivor who turned into a soccer star</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47d3ba6c/sc/38/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A40Cthe0Eamazing0Estory0Eof0Ea0Etsunami0Esurvivor0Ewho0Eturned0Einto0Ea0Esoccer0Estar0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>More than a decade ago, Martunis, a young Indonesian boy, was lucky to be alive. Now, he's the subject of a really unlikely feel-good story. On Dec. 26, 2004, an earthquake triggered an epic tsunami in the Indian Ocean that crashed against the shores of 14 countries. Some 230,000 people were killed by the merciless wave. [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody> traveltheroad (@traveltheroad) March 7, 2015
One of the hardest-hit spots was Banda Aceh, a city on the northern tip of the Indonesian island of Sumatra. Amid scenes of utter devastation and ruin , Martunis, then 6, was stranded and alone. His mother and siblings had perished in the disaster. He survived for nearly three weeks, drinking polluted rain water and scavenging packs of dry noodles.
The Daily Mail has moreabout his ordeal:
When found by a group of journalists wandering the beaches of the Indonesian city, Martunis needed a saline drip due to the dehydration he had suffered, while he was also said to be frail and badly bitten after the 21-day ordeal.
A member of the Save the Children team who delivered him to hospital said that had he been found a day later he may not have survived.
When his story reached international airwaves, it caught the attention of viewers in Portugal. The frail child, you see,had clung to life amid death while wearing a Portuguese soccer jersey, with the number 10 of the national team's then captain Manuel Rui Costa .
This was not unusual. All across Asia, Africa and other parts of the world, kidswear the jerseys of Europe's best players, the stars who give flight to their own soccer dreams.
"I was not afraid at all," Martunis, who is known only by one name, was quoted as saying to reporters at the time, "because I wanted to be alive to meet my family and become a football player."
 Martunis Ronaldo (@MartunisCR8) March 15, 2015
With President Fifa Sebletter 2005,Portugal vs Slovakia #EstadioDaLuz pic.twitter.com/35F6D1DOfy
 Martunis Ronaldo (@MartunisCR8) March 20, 2015
Moved by the child's plight,Portugal's soccer federation donated some 40,000 euros to build Martunis and his surviving family a new house. Cristiano Ronaldo, now aglobal superstar but then still a rising talent, paid Martunis a visit in 2005 and met him a few instances thereafter. He was given an audience by the Portuguese national team and even FIFA President Sepp Blatter .
Cristiano Ronaldo and Martunis. What a story! pic.twitter.com/7oiutEuXfK
 Cristiano Ronaldo (@Cr7Prince4ever) July 2, 2015
Now something of a local celebrity, Martunis stuck to his ambitions.
"I let him play football in the afternoon," his father Sarbini said in a 2008 interview. "I ask him to go to school, learn to read the Koran and attend an English course."
Fast forward to this week, and now a truly happy moment. On July 2, Sporting Lisbon, the team that first nurtured ayoung Ronaldo, announced that it had signed Martunis to a contract with its youth team.
Sobrevivente ao tsunami da Indonsia, @MartunisCR8 vai viver e crescer na Academia @Sporting_CP . #MartunisSporting pic.twitter.com/AqMsNgAdCS
 Sporting CP (@Sporting_CP) July 2, 2015
"I am very happy to have joined Sporting. It is a dream come true," Martunis said in a statement that appeared on Sporting's Web site.
"Martunis will work at the academy," said Sportings president, Bruno de Carvalho. "We will work with him also in his development as a human being and as a man."
But perhaps it's worth remembering what the Indonesian youth's idol, Ronaldo, said about him in the aftermath of the tsunami.
"I believe that many adults would not even be able to deal with what he has gone through," said the Real Madrid winger. "We must respect him. His was an act of strength and maturity. He's a special kid."
Ishaan Tharoor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. He previously was a senior editor at TIME, based first in Hong Kong and later in New York.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 20:27:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State destroys priceless statues in ancient city of Palmyra</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47d0efbe/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cislamic0Estate0Edestroys0Epriceless0Estatues0Ein0Eancient0Ecity0Eof0Epalmyra0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Separate reports this week indicated that Islamic State fighters were smashing cultural relics in the ancient city of Palmyra, once one of Syria's most crowded tourist destinations, but now in the grips of the extremist organization. The jihadists consider representations of divinity, especially those from pre-Islamic times, to be heretical and worthy of destruction. According to Syria's director [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor July 3 Follow @ishaantharoor
The ancient Syrian city of Palmyra on May 18, a day after Islamic State group jihadists fired rockets into the city. (AFP/Getty Images)
Separate reports this week indicated that Islamic State fighters weresmashing cultural relics in the ancient city of Palmyra, once one of Syria's mostcrowded tourist destinations, but now in the grips of the extremist organization.
The jihadists consider representations of divinity, especially those from pre-Islamic times, to be heretical and worthyof destruction. According to Syria's director of antiquities, Maamoun Abdelkarim, the militants this week hacked apart the famous Lion of al-Lat , a limestonestatue dating back to the first century B.C. that had been placed outside Palmyra museum.
"Its the most serious crime they have committed against Palmyras heritage," said Abdelkarim in an interview with Agence France-Presse. In May, as anIslamic State offensive neared the historic ruins, he had warned that Palmyra's capture would be "an international catastrophe."
IS destroys iconic lion statue at Syrias Palmyra museum http://t.co/NzT7Epc73L
 The Times of Israel (@TimesofIsrael) July 2, 2015
As WorldViews discussed around the time of its fall , Palmyra was once one of the ancient world's great crossroads  a desert oasis under Rome's sphere of influence connected via trade to the great empires and civilizations further east. A UNESCO World Heritage Site, Palmyra boasts some of the most stunning, intact Roman-era structures still in existence.
The Islamic State's control over the ruins is seen as a tragedy for global patrimony, given the group's track record in nearby Iraq, where it has razed and pillaged a whole series of ancient Mesopotamian sites.
Reports this week suggested that the Sunni extremists had also smashed six busts seized from a smuggler attempting to bring them out of Palmyra.Photos of the pieces were uploaded onto a Web site affiliated with the Islamic Statebutcould not be independently verified. The militants also released images of black-scarved fighters pounding the busts with sledgehammers.
 IBTimes UK (@IBTimesUK) July 2, 2015
Speaking at an event in London, Irina Bokova, the headof the United Nations' cultural agency, decried what the Islamic State was doing to the region's rich archaeological and architectural heritage.
"This deliberate destruction is not only continuing, it is happening on a systematic basis," said Bokova. "The looting of archaeological sites and museums, in Iraq particularly, has reached an industrial scale of destruction."
Bokova said the Islamic State'sbarbaric obliteration and theft of Mesopotamianantiquities was part of alarger "tactic of war, to terrify populations, to finance criminal activities."
She deemed the Islamic State's activitiesas a form of "cultural cleansing" that has "reached unprecedented levels in contemporary history."
Related on WorldViews
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 12:00:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The war over Benghazi is still happening in Benghazi</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47cd5cf1/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cthe0Ewar0Eover0Ebenghazi0Eis0Estill0Ehappening0Ein0Ebenghazi0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A bit more than a year ago, I wrote a post on WorldViews with this headline: The war over Benghazi is actually happening in Benghazi. It charted the violence rocking the Libyan coastal city at a time when politicos in Washington were feuding over that other Benghazi: an overheated, polarizing scandal that had become totally divorced from the city which gave it [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor July 3 Follow @ishaantharoor
Astreet is filled with debris and abandoned houses in the city of Benghazi, Libya, on April 4, 2015. Destruction has permeated the North African country since the civil war ousted Moammar Gaddafi four years ago. For Benghazi, the past year was the worst. (AP Photo/Mohamed Salama)
A bit more than a year ago, I wrote a post on WorldViews with this headline: The war overBenghazi is actually happening in Benghazi .
It charted the violence rocking the Libyan coastal city ata time whenpoliticosin Washington were feuding overthat otherBenghazi: an overheated, polarizing scandal that had become totally divorced from the city which gave it its name.
Fast forward 13 months, and the story is more or less exactly the same, only with a deeper, more tragictrail of death and suffering. Republicans and Democrats are still sparring overtheir Benghazi--the acrimonious aftermath of a 2012 terror attack in the city that led to the deaths of four Americans. But, meanwhile, Benghazi, Libya's second city, increasingly appears to be a ruin, hollowed out by an intractable civil war that has wrecked the country over the past year.
IAtank stands amongst damaged buildings in Benghazi, Libya, on March 3, 2015. (AP Photo/Mohamed Salama)
According to a recent account from Rami Musa, a reporter for theAssociated Press, more than a fifth of the city's roughly 630,000 people have been forced from their homes. Whole swathes of the Old City, renowned for its blend of Moorish and Italian architectural styles, have been destroyed. Musa goes on:
Now charred and wrecked cars, piles of twisted metal and debris act as front-line demarcations between warring factions. In many neighborhoods, Libyan soldiers have blown up entire buildings to clear snipers nests or in search of underground tunnels used for smuggling weapons.
Schools have closed, few hospitals remain open, and wheat and fuel shortages force residents to line up for hours every day outside bakeries and gas stations. Many neighborhoods have been emptied out by fleeing residents, only to be looted and torched by marauding militias.
Libya is divided between an Islamist-dominated faction that holds sway in the capital Tripoli and a feeble, officially recognized government that was compelled to relocate to the eastern city of Tobruk, on the border with Egypt.Benghazi has been a key battleground between a host of rival militias, which range fromthe Islamist outfit linked to the 2012 attacks togroups once loyal tothe late Libyan dictator Moammar Gaddafi, whose ouster and death in 2011 has not yielded thestable democracy so many Libyans sought.
Aman looks on at the destruction on a street of Benghazi, Libya, on April 4, 2015.(AP Photo/Mohamed Salama)
Burned-out cars lie in the open in a damaged street of Benghazi, Libya, on April 11, 2015. (AP Photo/Mohamed Salama)
U.N.-backed peace talks in Morocco between the rival camps stalled this week. It's hard to see how any agreement will be able to adequately redressthe unraveling that has taken place over the past year. Libya's economy has been devastated; its oil output, the country's lifeblood, is only a third of what it was before the 2011 anti-Gaddafi uprising, according to Bloomberg .
Essam al-Hamali, a relief worker in Benghazi, told the AP's Musa that there were 140,000 displaced people in the city alone, many of whom were struggling to find food. His organization has only received a fraction of the outside aid promised to it.
"We have declared Benghazi a disaster zone,"he said . "But it seems that no one cares."
Ishaan Tharoor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. He previously was a senior editor at TIME, based first in Hong Kong and later in New York.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 10:30:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Islamic State routinely shares gruesome images of those it kills. But governments do it, too.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47cd01d9/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A30Cthe0Eislamic0Estate0Eroutinely0Eshares0Egruesome0Eimages0Eof0Ethose0Eit0Ekills0Ebut0Egovernments0Edo0Eit0Etoo0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Islamic State has shown time and time again that it is willing to both document its acts of extreme violence and then share these acts on social media. This tactic appears to serve a dual purpose: While these gruesome images anger and disgust much of the world, they also excite and entice the extremist group's [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Adam Taylor July 3 Follow @mradamtaylor
An Egyptian military officer watches at a post in Egypt's northern Sinai Peninsula, as seen from the Israel-Egypt border, in Kerem Shalom village, southern Israel, onJuly 1. (Ariel Schalit/AP)
The Islamic State has shown time and time again that it is willing to both document its acts of extreme violence and then share these acts on social media. This tactic appears to serve a dual purpose: While these gruesome images anger and disgust much of the world, theyalso excite and entice the extremist group's online "fanboys" to action.
However, the Islamic State does not have a monopoly on using social media to share scenes of violence. Right now, there's plenty of violence going on in the world, and anyone with a) a smart phone or camera, b) Internet access and c) a social media account can share it.
That extends togovernmentforces too.
On Thursday, a day after a major Islamic State assault in Egypt'sSinai Peninsula that left as many as 70 dead , the Egyptian military took to Facebook to rally support. On the page of the Army spokesperson, the military shared images of what it said were fallen militants, describing them as despicable terrorists.
You can click to see the images below, but please bear in mind they are very graphic.
             1 / 7 / 2015 ... ...
Posted by         on Thursday, July 2, 2015
Egyptisn't an isolated example of government forces sharing violent images in the fight against extremists online.
In Nigeria, for example, many thousands of miles away from Egypt, the military hasshared incredibly horrific images of dead and mutilated bodies that it said belonged to fighters with Boko Haram.However, following online criticism, Nigeria backed off this policy this year. The Nigerian military "will no longer show dead bodies henceforth," Gen. Chris Olukolade tweeted in January , while at the same time sharing incredibly graphic images of blown-apart bodies.
Things get more complicated in Iraq, where pro-government Shiite militias have been sharing a variety of violent images for some time. Philip Smyth,aresearcher with the University of Maryland who tracks these militias online, says that some of these groups have shared images that rival the brutality of the Islamic State on social media, including images of a man being roasted alive over a fire and beheading groups.
In an e-mail, Smyth says that while the Iraqi government doesn'tshare these images itself, it is less clear whetherIraqi soldiers have been involved in the violence shared by militias. "It's often easier to ID militia groups doing it than regular Iraqi government forces," Smyth writes. "Why? Well, anyone can buy Iraq gov. patches/gear. Many militias operate alongside Iraq gov. forces too."
So far, in the battle for hearts and minds against the Islamic State, the U.S. has avoided showing off dead bodies of fallen militants.In fact, Washington has balked at even showing violence committed by the Islamic State, with one notorious video showing Islamic State atrocities  Welcome to ISIS Land  seen as gettingfar too close to emulating the extremist organization'sown gratuitous tactics.
Such concerns are legitimate, and there's a good argument that resorting to violent propaganda imageswill help erode the moral superiority real states have over the so-called Islamic State. However, it seems in the short term that these extremely violent images work to rally support in the face of an extremely violent enemy: At the time of writing, the Egyptian army's gruesome photos have been liked more than68,000 times and shared more than 20,000 times.
Adam Taylor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. Originally from London, he studied at the University of Manchester and Columbia University.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jul 02 22:53:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The world’s most anti-Russia country? Canada, says Moscow lawmaker</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47c996b2/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A20Cthe0Eworlds0Emost0Eanti0Erussia0Ecountry0Ecanada0Esays0Emoscow0Elawmaker0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MOSCOW — America, you can rejoice, at least for a while, because the Kremlin has found a new object for its vitriol: Canada. That’s right. The United States’ Mountie-loving, maple-syrup-toting neighbor to the north —the one whose flag Americans love to pin on their backpacks when they travel abroad so as to look innocuous — [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Karoun Demirjian July 2 Follow @karoun
Alexei Pushkov, chairman of the State Duma Committee on International Affairs, shown here in 2012, this week called Canada "now the most ant-Russian state." (Maxim Shemetov/Reuters)
MOSCOW  America, you can rejoice, at least for a while, because the Kremlin has found a new object for its vitriol: Canada.
Thats right. The United States Mountie-loving, maple-syrup-toting neighbor to the north the one whose flag Americans love to pin on their backpacks when they travel abroad so as to look innocuous  is a bigger thorn in Russia's side than Moscows former Cold War rival, according to Alexei Pushkov, the lawmaker who chairs the International Affairs Committee of the Duma, parliament's lower house.
It seems Canada is now the most anti-Russian state, Pushkov said this week, urging the Duma to elaborate a package of measures regarding Canada, in comments carried by the Russian news service Interfax.
Pushkov spoke a day after Canadian Prime Minister Stephen Harper announced additional economic sanctions against 14 Russian entities and Crimea, plus a personal travel ban against three Russians.
Those moves, which would upset Russian authorities coming from anybody, appeared to strike Pushkov as especially uppity coming from Canada.
The government of that country is trying to bolster its rather low profile in international affairs and the objective shortage of weight and authority through high activity in the field of the sanctions, Pushkovsaid.
Ouch.
Apparently the bad blood has been boiling up for a while. In his excoriation of Canada, Pushkov recalled comments Harper made in early June about how Russia would never be allowed back in the Group of 7, a consortium of major economic powers that ejected Russia after it annexed Crimea last year.
Pushkov warned that Russia would respond to this ill-treatment and that Canadas sanctions will not pass unanswered.
Canada is already subject to the counter-sanctions through which Russia has banned the import of fresh produce, meat, fish and dairy products from it, the United States, the European Union, Australia and Norway. Pushkov didnt spell out what the new counter-measures would be, though Russia in the past has made a point of responding tit-for-tat when it comes to individual sanctions.
It is worth noting, as well, that Canada and Russia are natural rivals when it comes to exploration of the Arctic, an area into which Russia has been pushing militarily, attempting to claimexpanded national boundaries.
But not everything Pushkov said appeared intended to deepen the East-West divide. He also suggested that both sides lift sanctions imposed on lawmakers, as a good first step toward resolving the standoff.
In the United States, members of Congress who have been sanctioned by Russia since the annexation of Crimea have mostly taken the designation as a badge of honor . The list includes Sen. John McCain (R-Ariz.), House Speaker John Boehner (R-Ohio) and Senate Minority Leader Harry Reid (D-Nev.), among others. Sen. Mitch McConnell (R-Ky.) doesn't seem to have made the list since he became majority leader in January.
In Russia, many lawmakers have also reacted with pride at being sanctionedbythe West, despite it being more common for Russian lawmakers to take vacations or own property in Europe or, say, Miami than it is for U.S. lawmakers to summer in Russia.
Pushkov is currently under both U.S. and Canadian sanctions.
Karoun Demirjian is a reporting fellow in The Post's Moscow bureau. She previously served as the Washington Correspondent for the Las Vegas Sun, and reported for the Associated Press in Jerusalem and the Chicago Tribune in Chicago.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jul 02 22:18:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why Ted Cruz thinks a U.S. Embassy in Havana is ‘a slap in the face’ of Israel</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47c9a3b5/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A20Cwhy0Eted0Ecruz0Ethinks0Ea0Eu0Es0Eembassy0Ein0Ehavana0Eis0Ea0Eslap0Ein0Ethe0Eface0Eof0Eisrael0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>On Wednesday, President Obama hailed his administration's historic opening to Cuba as "another demonstration that we do not have to be imprisoned by the past." Formal ties have been reestablished after more than a half-century-long deep freeze. Many of his critics, though, are angry. A slew of Republican presidential candidates panned the move as premature [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor July 2 Follow @ishaantharoor
Sen. Ted Cruz (R-Tex.), who is running for president, addresses a legislative luncheon held as part of the Road to Majority conference in Washington on June 18, 2015. (Carlos Barria/Reuters)
On Wednesday, President Obama hailed his administration's historic opening to Cuba as "another demonstration that we do not have to be imprisoned by the past." Formal ties have been reestablished after more than a half-century-long deep freeze.
Many of his critics, though, are angry. A slew of Republican presidential candidates panned the move as premature and playing into the hands of the authoritarian Castro regime. The most conspicuous ire was exhibited by Sen. Ted Cruz (R-Tex.).
But the argument he deployed communicated something particular about his own brand of politics.
Cruz said the administration's decision to "have an embassy in Havana before one in Jerusalem" was "a slap in the face" of Israel.
As WorldViews explained earlier , Jerusalem remains a disputed territory in the eyes of the international community, including the United States, which hasits embassy in Israel in the city of Tel Aviv. This has been the consistent policy of every White House since President Harry S. Truman signaled the U.S. recognition of Israel as an independent state.
From November:
The issue of sovereignty over this ancient city isa very delicate matter. Israel considers Jerusalem its eternal capital and has controlled the cityin its entirety since the 1967 Arab-Israeli war, which saw Israel also seize the Gaza Strip and the West Bank.The United States, on the other hand, let alone other countries less well disposed to Israel, does not recognize Jerusalem as the Israeli capital.
The United States, the main proponent of a two-state solution for the Israelis and Palestinians, views East Jerusalem as making up a future Palestinian capital. The facts on the ground, as WorldViews has reported at length, suggest that a separate, viable Palestinian state is a very distant prospect.
That policy of not recognizing Jerusalem as Israel's capital was challenged recently in the Supreme Court by U.S. citizens born in the city who were petitioning for the right to list their place of birth as Israel. Earlier this month, as my colleague Robert Barnes reported , "amajority of the court came down decisively on the side of the executive branch when the question is the recognition of foreign countries and their territorial boundaries."
That hardly satisfies Cruz, who is an ardent supporter of Israel and has conducted serious agitprop for the Jewish state in the past. He proposed legislation earlier this year to have the U.S. Embassy moved from Tel Aviv to Jerusalem. It had no chance of passing, but it was an indication of how some American conservatives will want to challenge Washington's long-held position in the years to come.
Ishaan Tharoor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. He previously was a senior editor at TIME, based first in Hong Kong and later in New York.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jul 02 19:26:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why the BBC said no when David Cameron asked it to stop using the term Islamic State</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47c7b931/sc/32/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A20Cwhy0Ethe0Ebbc0Esaid0Eno0Ewhen0Edavid0Ecameron0Easked0Eit0Eto0Estop0Eusing0Ethe0Eterm0Eislamic0Estate0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The debate over what to call the Islamist extremist group that controls parts of Iraq and Syria has been raging for well over a year now. The Washington Post, among others, now refers to it as the Islamic State, a name the group itself has used. However, others prefer to call it by its old name and [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Adam Taylor July 2 Follow @mradamtaylor
A member of the Islamic State group holds the IS flag as he dismantles a cross on the top of a church in Mosul, Iraq. (Militant website via AP)
The debate over what to call the Islamist extremist group that controls parts of Iraq and Syria has been raging for well over a year now. The Washington Post, among others, nowrefers to it as the Islamic State, a name the group itself has used. However, others prefer tocall it by its old name and its acronym,theIslamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS). The U.S. government, meanwhile, uses a different translation from the Arabic original , andrefers to it as theIslamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL).
It may seem like much ado about nothing, but many people feel that the symbolism of what the group is called is vitally important. This week, British Prime Minister David Cameron let it be known he was one of those peopleduring an interview with the BBC's "Today" program.
"I wish the BBC would stop calling it 'Islamic State' because it is not an Islamic state, Cameron said during an interview aboutthe deadly attack in Tunisia last week."'So-called' or ISILis better."
[ Militants linked to Islamic State launch major assault in Egypts Sinai ]
British Prime Minister David Cameron leaves 10 Downing Street on June 29, 2015 in London, England. (Photo by Rob Stothard/Getty Images)
Cameron's logic is simple: Calling the group "Islamic State" defers upon it a religious legitimacy and sense of statehood that should be denied. Given the widespread, if wrongheaded, debate over whether the groups' vile brutality can or should be linked to a wider Islamic history and community, it's a powerful argument.
The British prime minister isn't the first person to argue this. Last year,Egypt'sleading Islamic authority,Dar al-Ifta, called on the world's media to stop using the term, instead suggesting a new term:Al-Qaeda Separatists in Iraq and Syria or QSIS. Around the same time, agroup of British imams called on Cameron himself to stop calling the group "Islamic State," and instead refer to them as the"Un-Islamic State" instead.
Perhaps themost popular alternative name for the group has been 'Daesh,' a transliteration of thean Arabic word (), which is anacronym foral-Dawla al-Islamiya fi al-Iraq wa al-Sham (itself atransliteration of the group's Arabic name:    ) and widely used in the Middle East. The use of this name has one big thing going for it: The group is said to hate it (perhaps due to similarity toanother Arabic word,, or Das, which means to trample down). The French government makes a point of using this name , and Secretary of State John Kerry has used it frequently.
Cameron's suggestionput the BBC in an uneasy position. While the news organization is independent from the British government, it is also a public-service broadcaster, funded largely by a television license fee that is set by politicians. The BBC has come under pressure from the British government during times of conflict before, notably during the Suez Canal crisis in 1956 and during the Falklands war of 1982.
Things became more complicatedon Monday when more than 120 British MPs signed a letter that asked the BBC and other broadcasters to stop using the term "the Islamic State" and refer to the group as "Daesh." The letter, authored by Conservative Party MP Rehman Chishti , said that the BBC "has the opportunity to lead on this issue and call this organization what it really is rather than allowing it to be linked by religion."In a column in the Dundee Courier , one of the signatories of the letter, former Scottish National Party leader Alex Salmond, expanded upon this.We should start by understanding that in a propaganda war language is crucial," Salmond wrote.
This all was a stepfurther than Cameron had suggested,and Chishti wrote separately to the prime minister to ask that the British government use Daesh as well. In parliament on Monday, Cameron demurred and suggested that he thought ISIL was far enough.
The BBC pledged to review how it referred to the group andultimately decided it wouldn't budge.On Wednesday the Times of London reported that the BBCplanned tostick with the "Islamic State," with director general Lord Hall quoted as saying that some of the names suggested were "pejorative." Hall added that the broadcaster needed to "preserve the BBC's impartiality" and stick with the name that the group itself used. It would, however, refer to them as the "Islamic State group" to make clear it was not a true state, the Times reported.
The BBC's Mark Mardell expanded upon this in an article published online. "It seems to me, once we start passing comment on the accuracy of the names people call their organisations, we will constantly be expected to make value judgements," Mardell wrote, before asking if China was really a "People's Republic" as an example.
Not everyone was pleased with the decision. In parliament on Thursday,Chishti said the response was "not worth the paper it's written on," while MP Chris Grayling compared it to being impartial to the Nazis. But others offered their support:Remarkably, the BBC won praise from the generally BBC-bashing Daily Mail newspaper, who gave it "full marks" for resisting political pressure. "Will MPs stop fussing irrelevantly about what to call them  and turn their minds to defeating them?" the newspaper wrote in an editorial on Thursday .
Perhaps the naming of the group really is irrelevant, but the debate does reflect the shifting concerns about it in Britain. While much attention has been paid to the propaganda battle against the group, at points Cameron's own rhetoric has been criticized .
And in the aftermath of the attack in Tunisia that left scores of British tourists dead, there are manyin Britain feel as if their country isn't taking enough practical military action to defeat the group.
More on WorldViews
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jul 02 19:23:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A robot killed a factory worker in Germany. So who should go on trial?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47c7b939/sc/3/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A20Ca0Erobot0Ekilled0Ea0Efactory0Eworker0Ein0Egermany0Eso0Ewho0Eshould0Ego0Eon0Etrial0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BERLIN — Prosecutors are leading an unusual investigation after a robot killed a contractor at a Volkswagen production plant in western Germany on Monday. According to Germany's DPA news agency, the victim was in the process of installing the stationary robot when it suddenly struck and crushed the young man. According to the Financial Times, the [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Rick Noack July 2 Follow @rick_n
A man walks past a screen displaying a logo of Volkswagen at an event in New Delhi on June 23. (Anindito Mukherjee/Reuters)
BERLIN  Prosecutors are leading an unusual investigation after a robot killed a contractor at a Volkswagen production plant in western Germany on Monday.
According to Germany's DPA news agency, the victim was in the process of installing the stationary robot when it suddenly struckand crushed the young man. According to the Financial Times , the contractor died in a hospital.
German prosecutors said Wednesday that they are investigating the cause of the accident. "We will then decide whether to bring charges, and, if so, against whom," the prosecutor's office of the city of Kassel said in a statement.
According to prosecutors,the accident is the first of its kind in Germany. Despite the increasing ubiquityof robots in manufacturing plants in Germany, they had not been involvedin a workplace death  until now.
Volkswagen  one of the world's biggest auto manufacturers said a technical defect was unlikely to have caused the victim's death. According to the Financial Times , most robots are not considered to pose any risk to human workers:
Robot-related fatalities are rare in Western production plants as robots are kept behind safety cages to prevent accidental contact with humans. In this instance the contractor was standing inside the safety cage when the accident occurred. (...)
A Volkswagen spokesman stressed that the robot was not one of the new generation of lightweight collaborative robots that work side-by-side with workers on the production line and forgo safety cages.
Nevertheless,robots seem to have been involved in several workplace accidents, as the New York Times reported last year. The paper referenced many lethal accidents in U.S. factories involving robots, dating to 2001, 2006, and 2011.
In Britain alone, authorities documented77 robot-related accidents in 2005, according to t he Economist . "Over the years people have been crushed, hit on the head, welded and even had molten aluminium poured over them by robots," the paper said .
According to the U.S. Labor Department, "Studies indicate that many robot accidents occur during non-routine operating conditions, such as programming, maintenance, testing, setup, or adjustment."
"During many of these operations the worker may temporarily be within the robot's working envelope where unintended operations could result in injuries," according to the department's Web site .
According to German news reports , the contractor had been standing inside the safety cage when the accident occurred.
On Twitter, several users pointed out that the German robot had violated Asimov's first law of robotics .
Goes again Issac Asimov's first "law of robotics" - A robot may not injure a human being or............. https://t.co/dyQ4p74ldM
 Omar Abdullah (@abdullah_omar) July 2, 2015
Please note this: A robot may not injure a human being or, through inaction, allow a human being to come to harm. (Asimov's law)
 Gene Luckman (@koreyome) July 1, 2015
Those tweets referred to a short story published by science fiction author Isaac Asimov in 1942 that described three laws that should restrainthe actions of robots. The first law stated:
1. A robot may not injure a human being or, through inaction, allow a human being to come to harm.
Despite its origins in science fiction literature, the law is discussed in academia . Most often, however, it has been associated with war robots developed to kill enemies, rather than car-manufacturing machines.
Rick Noack writes about foreign affairs and is based in Europe.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jul 02 18:41:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Does Israel actually occupy the Gaza strip?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47c7c377/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A20Cdoes0Eisrael0Eactually0Eoccupy0Ethe0Egaza0Estrip0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>JERUSALEM — It’s often described as a war of narratives. And few things highlight the intractability of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict more than discussions over the status of the Gaza Strip. One of the main points of contention: Is the coastal Palestinian territory occupied by Israel? We asked two Israelis and two Palestinians to lay out their views on [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ruth Eglash July 2 Follow @reglash
Palestinians in Gaza City's seaport wave their national flag as they ride boats during a June 28 rally in support of activists aboard a ship aimed at defying Israel's blockade of Gaza. Israeli naval commandos later intercepted the ship and diverted it toward a port in Israel. (Mahmud Hams/AFP via Getty Images)
JERUSALEM  Its often described as a war of narratives. Andfew things highlight the intractability of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict more than discussions over the status of the Gaza Strip.
One of the main points of contention:Is the coastalPalestinian territory occupied by Israel?
We asked two Israelis and two Palestinians to lay out their views on that question. Their responses, below, have been edited for length and clarity.
First, a little background:
MostPalestinians see Gaza as part of the territories occupied by Israel. They also saythe coastal enclave is under siege, with Israel controlling who and what goes in and out. The United Nations also calls Gaza occupied territory, most recently in a report commissioned by the U.N. Human Rights Council that concluded that both Israel and armed Palestinian factions in Gaza may have committed war crimes. The United Nations says it does not matter that Israeli soldiers are not based inside the strip;they have effective control.
Israelis, however, argue that their withdrawalfromGaza 10 years ago means that the enclave is not occupied  unlike the West Bank.
In 2005, Israel dismantled 21 Jewish settlements and pulled troops out of the strip.Then-Israeli Prime Minister Ariel Sharonsaid the "disengagement"was intended to increase security for residents of Israel, relieve pressure on the Israeli army and reduce friction between Israelis and Palestinians.
Israel handed the area over to the Palestinian Authority. Then, after the militant Palestinian faction Hamas won a majority of seats in Palestinian elections held in 2006, it took over Gazaby oustingits rivals by force in 2007.
Today, Israel maintains a complete air and sea blockade of Gaza and a partial blockade of goods and people through two land crossings. Israel also greatly restricts theability of Gazans to enter Israel.
Israel says that tight border control isessential because of threats from Hamas, which is seen as a terrorist organization by Israel, theUnited States and the European Union.Egypt also tightly controls its border with Gaza.
Late last month, international pro-Palestinian activists attempted to sail into Israeli-controlled waters off the Mediterranean coast to protest what they called Israels illegal siege against occupied Gaza. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu wrote them a letter asserting that there is no blockade.
Here is what people on each side have to say:
1) Raji Sourani, human rights lawyer for the Palestinian Center for Human Rights in Gaza.
Q: Does Israel still occupy Gaza?
A: Gaza is definitely still occupied, and Israel is still the belligerent occupying force, and they have no right to enforce this illegal, inhuman collective punishment. It is entirely against the Geneva Convention.
The people who came on the flotilla are the creme de la creme of international civil society who want to challenge eight years of a criminal siege that has suffocated the people of Gaza. They are trying to highlight the gravity of the situation [in Gaza], where 65 percent of the people are unemployed, 90 percent live under the poverty line, 85 percent depend on [the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East], and we are facing the biggest man-made disaster, which is the occupation.
Q: Israel says it withdrew from Gaza, so how can you say it's still occupied?
A: This is a very well-known trick. Whenever they want to, they can occupy Gaza again. The siege means they control what we eat, what medicines we receive. This claim is ridiculous.
Gaza has not been rebuilt since the [Israel-Gaza war]of 2008/09, and it is not rebuilt after three wars because Israel does not want to do that.
I cannot travel to the International Criminal Court in Geneva because I am not allowed to leave. Fishermen cannot go and fish because of the buffer zone. Because of the Israelis, we cannot bring the goods we want in and out. This is part of the Israeli occupation and is part of our lives.
Israel can decide to kill anyone anywhere in Gaza. They can do what they want in Gaza they are the secret power.
If there is no occupation power, then why is there a siege on Gaza?

2) Israel Ziv, former commander of the Israel Defense Forces' Gaza Division, who headed the armys Operations Directorate during the disengagement from Gaza.
Q: Does Israel still occupy Gaza?
A: No, of course Israel does not still occupy Gaza, at least no more than the Egyptians are occupying Gaza.
The issue here is that Israel does not have any involvement at all in the day-to-day running of Gaza. Unfortunately, until the ruling party there, Hamas, changes its policy of acting as both a government and a terror organization, Israel will insist on controlling everything that goes into or out of Gaza.
Q: So why do Palestinians, and many in the international community, continue saying Gaza is occupied?
A: Palestinians like to ride on that narrative because it is a very catchy narrative, and since part of this warfare is about the narrative and justification of the narrative, using that narrative  even though it is not what happens in the field  is still useful. And, unfortunately, many people in the world still like to buy this narrative.
Another narrative that is more correct is that Gaza is under blockade. This is partly true, but that is due to the fact that there is no other supervision arrangement, no satisfying international supervision that would allow Israel to open the gates for everything to flow into Gaza.
I would like to mention that although there is no formal arrangement, Israel opens the border every day, allowing the flow of raw materials, humanitarian aid, food and anything that cannot be used for military purposes. Other than materials that might be used for dual purposes, which are supervised, Israel does not have full control of how it will be used.
3) Ghassan Khatib, a Palestinian lecturer of political science at Birzeit University in Ramallah, West Bank, and a former Palestinian minister.
Q: Does Israel still occupy Gaza?
A: Yes, it does, and this is not only the view held by Palestinians. It is also seen this way by experts in international law, who confirm the Palestinian understanding that Israel did not withdraw from Gaza but merely redeployed from inside Gaza to around it.
The presence of the Israeli army inside Gaza was removed, but the Israeli military still controls the borders of Gaza, meaning the Gazans do not have control over their borders and, consequently, their movement and movement of goods going into and out of Gaza.
I am not a legal expert, but I would say that Israels control over the borders is a continuity of the occupation.
Q: Israel says it has relaxed restrictions on goods and people going in and out of Gaza, and figures from international organizations show the numbers of bothare up in 2015.
A: Israel increasing its restrictions or relaxing its constrictions confirms the idea that Israel is controlling the border. When it is in Israels interest, they relax restrictions. This means that Gaza is under Israeli control.
Q: Israel says it controls the crossings because of Hamas rocket fire.
A: The Israeli restrictions, Hamas rockets and all other aspects of the conflict all take place within the framework of an illegal occupation of the Palestinian territories. We have resistance and rockets; sometimes it's legitimate and sometimes it's an illegitimate means of resistance, but it's all because of the occupation. Evacuating part of Palestinian territory, changing the form of control from inside to outside, does not mean the Palestinians should give up on their efforts to get complete freedom.
4) Dani Dayan, formerchairman of the Yesha Council, the main advocacy group for settlements in the West Bank and, previously, in Gaza.
Q: Does Israel still occupy Gaza?
A: I am not going to refer to the legal perspective because I am not a lawyer, but in a common-sense perspective, Israel withdrew from every square inch of the Gaza strip in 2005. Israel ethnically cleansed the Jewish presence, both military and civilians, so common sense dictates that we are not occupying. I think if you ask Israelis, 95 percent of the people will be of that opinion.
In 2005, a Palestinian state was established in Gaza, and it became an independent state free to take any course that its leaders and its people chose. I think the Gazans were given a historical choice that is seldom given to a group of people, and they could have become a Middle Eastern Singapore or a Middle Eastern Somalia. They decided they did not want to be Singapore but wanted to be Somalia, because they want to continue the effort to exterminate Israel. That is what happened in 2005 and ever since.
Q: Is it possible that Gaza is under siege by Israel instead  a claim made by many Palestinians and their supporters?
A: We have to remember that Gaza has twoborders, one with Israel and one with Egypt. I dont see any reason to single out Israel and not to mention Egypt. If it is just Israel, that is one thing. But the second thing, more important: The moment Gazans made a decision they want to continue war with Israel, Israel had no other choice than to take the necessary precautions on its border.
The border could be completely open for goods, financial tools and for cooperation. But, unfortunately, Gazans decided instead to make it for rockets, and Israel has to decide to defend itself. This is not an Israeli decision, this is a Gazan decision.
The minute the Gazans make a decision not to fire rockets into Israel, the border will be opened. They call the shots and make the rules, and Israel reacts.
Ruth Eglash is a reporter for The Washington Post based in Jerusalem. She was formerly a reporter and senior editor at the Jerusalem Post and freelanced for international media.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jul 02 17:25:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In China, hostile foreign forces blamed for bursting stock market bubble</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47c7172a/sc/24/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A20Cin0Echina0Ehostile0Eforeign0Eforces0Eblamed0Efor0Ebursting0Estock0Emarket0Ebubble0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>There are now officially more stock market investors in China than there are Communist Party members, Bloomberg reported this week. But if capitalists now definitively rule China, they have had a very rough few days. China’s stock market slumped again Thursday, despite fresh moves by regulators to arrest a decline that has seen the benchmark [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Simon Denyer and Xu Jing July 2 Follow @simondenyer
A stock investor gestures as he looks at a screen displaying share prices at a security firm in Hangzhou, in east China's Zhejiang province, on June 26. (STR/AFP/Getty Images)
There are now officially more stock market investors in China than there are Communist Party members, Bloomberg reported this week. But if capitalists now definitively rule China, they have had a very rough few days.
Chinas stock market slumped again Thursday, despite fresh moves by regulators to arrest a decline that has seen the benchmark index in Shanghai lose 24 percent since June 12 and $2.4 trillion wiped off equity valuations.
Reuters said the decline raised questions about how much more firepower Beijing can bring to bear before a full-scale panic sets in.
The latest weapon appears to be a good old-fashioned dose of nationalism, as opinion leaders took to social media to urge investors to hold onto shares for the glory of the Chinese nation.
Believe in my country, Cao Zenghui, deputy general manager of Sina Weibo, whose company runs Chinas main microblogging service and who personally has more than100,000 followers, posting a national flag as his profile image. It is not just a stock market issue any more. I will fight with forces who short Chinas economy. No eggs can remain unbroken when the nest is upset.
The Shanghai Composite index fell 3.5 percent Thursday, closing below the psychologically important level of 4,000, one that many investors had believed the authorities would defend by buying shares.
The market had surged 150 percent in the year to June 12, most of those gains recorded in the past eight months. Some saw the authorities hand in that feverish bull market, in an attempt to boost personal wealth and consumer spending at a time when economic growth is slowing and the property market has been weak.
But if so, it is in danger of backfiring.
In the past few days, Chinese authorities have eased monetary policy, suggested more pension funds would invest in stocks, cut trading fees and even relaxed rules on using borrowed money to speculate in the markets. But none of it has provided more than short-lived relief.
Retail investors dominate the market, and many are believed to have borrowed heavily to reap quick profits when the market was rising, Reuters says. Now, some are being forced to withdraw to avoid losing money they dont have.
In the past few days, rumors have circulated on the Wechat messaging service that international capital  or simply capitalism itself  was attacking China. Goldman Sachs and the Hong Kong office of China Southern Asset Management were supposed to be profiting from short-selling the market  rumors that were later rubbished by the China Securities Regulatory Commission . On Thursday, Chinese media also implied that George Soros or Morgan Stanley might be to blame.
Fan Shaoxuan, a senior executive at Weibo TV who has more than 12,000 followers on Sina Weibo, posted a photograph showing the slogans: Hold stocks with confidence. Win glory for the country even if you lose the last penny.
Hostile foreign forces often get blamed for trying to undermine China, and were said by the government to be behind pro-democracy demonstrations in Hong Kong last year.
Columnist Liao Baoping wrote that rumors of an attack by international capital often arise when the market falls sharply, because people want to combine speculative behavior with national security and hope the Chinese government will introduce more policies to save the market.
People useinternational conspiracy theories as excuses, he argued, because they dont want to admit to losing money becauseof their own misjudgment.
Experts say more action by the authorities, like the suspension of Initial Public Offerings (IPOs) or the outright buying of shares by state-owned companies, are possible.
"The government has more tools it could use to support equities, but these moves could be short-lived if investors remain negative," wrote Oliver Barron of NSBO in a research note cited by Reuters.
"Retail investors account for about 85 percent of turnover, and the recent correction has greatly endangered their belief in the capital market opening up and reform, and might even cause social unrest."
In a research note cited by the Financial Times on Monday, Anne Stevenson-Yang of JCap Research said market valuations had nothing to do with financial fundamentals of quoted companies, saying it was more a game of Russian roulette now than a reasoned calculation of future share values.
The Chinese equity market now has more than 90 million individual investors, according to China Securities Depository and Clearing Co., compared to the Communist Party's 87.8 million reported members at the end of last year.
"Ultimately, market participants all understand that the A-share bubble has been engineered to distract the average person from sinking values and illiquidity in the property markets," Stevenson-Yang wrote, predicting that efforts to prop up the market would ultimately fail and the bubble would eventually burst, as indeed now seems to be happening.
"The pools of cash owned by Chinese people are regularly redirected to the asset classes that the government needs to rise and that elites are tapped into, and it behooves the political elite to delay recognition for as long as possible of the drastic losses that are in those assets and would be proven beyond doubt if left to market forces," she wrote, according to the FT.
Simon Denyer is The Posts bureau chief in China. He served previously as bureau chief in India and as a Reuters bureau chief in Washington, India and Pakistan.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jul 02 12:00:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How not to write about Iran</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47c4909e/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A20Chow0Enot0Eto0Ewrite0Eabout0Eiran0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In the Western imagination, Iran has long been a kind of bogeyman. It's the land of hostage crises and headscarves. It was part of the Axis of Evil (whatever that was). Its leaders grouse about defeating Israel, an American ally. Its mullahs, say Iran's critics, plot terror and continental hegemony. Supporters of the ongoing talks in Vienna, where Iranian diplomats and [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor July 2 Follow @ishaantharoor
An Iranian woman walks a street of the capital Tehran, Iran. (Abedin Taherkenareh/EPA)
In the Western imagination, Iran has long been akind of bogeyman. It's the landof hostage crises and headscarves. It was part of the Axis of Evil ( whatever that was ). Its leaders grouse about defeating Israel , an American ally. Its mullahs, say Iran's critics, plot terror and continentalhegemony.
Supportersof the ongoing talks in Vienna, where Iranian diplomatsand their internationalcounterparts are wrangling over a final agreement on Tehran's nuclear program, are in part hoping tochange this overwhelmingnarrative.
Rapprochement between Iran and the U.S., they argue , would signal anew erafor U.S. relations in the Middle East  and, at the very least, put to rest fears of yetanotherAmerican military escalation in the region.
[ Here's what is in the way of a 'good' Iran nuclear deal. ]
But whether that changes the actual Western discourse around Iran is another matter. Everysociety or culture getsstereotyped in some way by others but Iran, evenbefore the riseof the Islamic Republic in 1979, has beena very conspicuous victim.
That's in part a consequence of its history. As the inheritor of Persia's ancientempires, Iran has been the Other  the enemy of the nominal "West"  since classical times and the famouswars with Greek city-states. In the 18th century, some Europeanwriters and thinkers popularized the image of a "decadent" and "despotic" Persia as an allegoricaldevice to critique their own societies. A century later, as Europe's empires gained in power, the Orientalist cliches hardened and served to bolstertheWest'sown sense of racial and moral superiority.
Even in the present day, many of the old tropes have been trotted out during the nuclear talks. While giving testimony to Congress in 2013, Wendy Sherman, a senior State Department official and lead negotiator with Iran,counseled caution when dealing with the Iranian regime because "deception is in their DNA." The remarks, which infuriated Tehran , gestured at much older Western perceptions ofIranians as "wily" swindlerswho cannot be trusted.
Sherman was hardly alone in conjuring up this stereotype:Those opposed toher efforts have also done the same. An editorial in the Wall Street Journal last year warned against "haggling in a Mideast bazaar" and embarking on a "Persian nuclear carpet ride." ThisApril, Michael Oren, Israel's former U.S. ambassador, wenton a cringe-worthyramble about the crafty tricksof Persian rug salesmen.
"The Iranians are not just expert carpet merchants," Oren wrote , stretchingthe ungainly metaphor to its frayed, tasseled edges. "They also deal in terror and endangering American allies."
Other more nuanced assessments fall into similartraps, too. Earlier this week, James Stavridis, a retired U.S. admiral, top NATO official and the dean of the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, painted a picture of the Iranian regime with the broadest brush he could possibly find.
"Tehrans geopolitical strategy," he wrote,"is taken directly from the playbooks of the first three Persian empires, which stretched over a thousand years."
To no great surprise, this view of Iran as a mysterious realm, beholden to its past (and its vast store of carpets), irks someobservers.
"Iran is an ancient civilization with a rich culture that definitely has roots in its old history," Iranian-American journalist Negar Mortazavi tells WorldViews."But to stereotype modern Iran and Iranians based on what happened thousands of years ago is wrong."
Mortazaviargues that you would never see such simplistic, overreaching appraisals of American allies: "Do we viewtoday's Europe throughthe affairs of the Vikings? No.Do we look at Saudi Arabia through the lens of its old Islamic Empire when it was taking over the world? No."
Arash Karami, the Iran editor of the Middle East news site Al-Monitor , dismissesthe idea "that Iran has imperial ambitions in the Middle East simply because of itshistory." He adds that "most Iranians only have a vague understanding" of the long-gone Achaemenid dynasty or the medieval Safavids.
The stereotypes in play seem to support the contention of some hawks that Iran is not a normal, rational state actor . Critics of the Islamic Republic may see nothing wrong with that, but these sorts of characterizations were being madewellbefore the 1979 Islamic Revolution and the collapse of U.S.-Iran ties.
In a write-up published in January 1952 , Time magazine named Iran's democratically-electedPrime Minister Mohammed Mossadegh as "Man of the Year." The recognition was not particularly flattering. It sneeringly described Iran as"a mountainous land between Baghdad and the Sea of Caviar." And it went on to attack both Mossadegh's plan to nationalize Iran's oil  at the expense of British and American energy interests -- and the leader's character.
Time actually called the Iranian politician "a strange old wizard."
A year later, the Ivy League buddies of Time's editors in the C.I.A. helped engineer a coup that ousted Mossadegh, scrapped Iran's fledgling democracy, and re-installed the country's monarchy as an American client. Memory ofthat event still informs the political conversation within Iran, but is rarely recognized in the West.
"In American media, it seems that either those wily Persians are calculating 'chess masters' outwitting the well-meaning Westerner," says Karami, "or they're bumbling idiots" who resent how"the West rules the Middle East."
To be sure, there are many negative things that shouldbe said about Iran's political status quo  wherea repressive theocratic government curbs dissent, jails journalists and actively supports armedproxies elsewhere in the Middle East. But you don't need tostart quoting Xenophon or Morier to get there.
"If youre writing about a country of more than 77 million people," says Kia Makarechi, news editor at Vanity Fair, "and the metaphors or signifiers you draw on come more from 'Aladdin' than a serious understanding of that nations politics and culture, you should probably hand the assignment to someone else."
See also on WorldViews
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jul 02 10:30:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Has the global Jewish population finally rebounded from the Holocaust? Not exactly.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47c39746/sc/28/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A20Chas0Ethe0Eglobal0Ejewish0Epopulation0Efinally0Erebounded0Efrom0Ethe0Eholocaust0Enot0Eexactly0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In 1939, the global population of Jewish people worldwide peaked at around 16.6 million. That population was soon decimated by the Holocaust, which saw Nazi Germany and its collaborators kill approximately 6 million Jews. In just a few horrifying years, the global population of Jews had fallen by more than a third. This week, a new report by the Jerusalem-based think tank Jewish People [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Adam Taylor July 2 Follow @mradamtaylor
In 1939, the global population ofJewish people worldwide peakedat around 16.6 million. That population was soon decimated by theHolocaust, which saw Nazi Germany and its collaboratorskillapproximately6 million Jews. In just a few horrifying years, theglobal population of Jews had fallenby more than a third.
This week, a new report by the Jerusalem-based think tankJewish People Policy Institute (JPPI) made a startling announcement: The world's Jewish population was finally approaching16.6 million again. The announcement sparked headlines around the world, with many observers shocked that it could have taken 70 years for the global Jewish population to return to itspre-Holocaust peak.
The problem is, itwasn't entirely accurate.
Professor Sergio DellaPergola, perhaps the most well-known expert in Jewish demographics in the world today, isamong those who have rebutted the reports. "It is a canard,"DellaPergola told the Times of Israel this week, suggesting that the numbers widely reported were both a result of "misunderstanding" and "journalistic counterfeit."
When you look closely at the JPPI's numbers, DellaPergola's objections make sense. The report makes no bones that the number of self-identifying Jews in the world are around 14.2 million a number DellaPergola had come to in his own work last year , published
It then, however, adds on to this a number of other people, including those with only oneJewish parent or those who identify as partially Jewish due to their family history. Some348,000 Israeli citizens whocame to Israel under the Law of Return but are not recorded as Jews are also included in the higher figure.
Traditionally, Judaism has a comparatively strict definition of who is Jewish, with halakha (Jewish religious law) requiring either that a person's mother was Jewish or that theygo through a formal conversion process. Not all Jews agree with these definitions, however. The Lawof Return, anIsraeli legislation that allows Jews to immigrateto Israel, was amended in 1970 to allow "child and a grandchild of a Jew, the spouse of a Jew, the spouse of a child of a Jew and the spouse of a grandchild of a Jew" to enter the country, leading hundreds of thousands of non-Jews to move to Israel.
In a phone call earlier this week, JPPI presidentAvinoam Bar-Yosef was keen to emphasize that the higher figure included these people, who others might not consider fully Jewish, in order to help with policy discussions (the JPPI report was presented to the Israeli Cabineton Sunday ). The JPPI report arguesthat there werechanging patterns of Jewish identification" in the past few years, hence the use of the larger number. Indeed, a 2013 Pew study on the nature of Jewish Americans found that more and more people could be considered "partially Jewish," in part due to the shifting attitudes to intermarriage and religion.
DellaPergola's own estimates of the world's Jewish population havemade a point of not including these people, noting that if "we add persons who state they are partly Jewish and non-Jews who have Jewish parents, an extended global aggregate population estimate of 17,236,850 is obtained."DellaPergola disagreeswith using these broader definitions,however: "If the United States had 6.7 million holders of a doctorate, and 1 million of these hold a doctorate partly, how many Ph.D.s are there in America?" he asked in the Forward in 2013.
So when will the core Jewish population actually reach its pre-Holocaust heights? Recent estimates by Pew found that the world's Jewish population would rise by15 percent in the next two and a half decades, compared to 35 percent for the overall global population, to reach 16.1 million in 2050.DellaPergola's research has suggested that, had the Holocaust not taken place, the global Jewish population would have been at least 26 million and possibly as much as 32 million today.
Adam Taylor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. Originally from London, he studied at the University of Manchester and Columbia University.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jul 01 19:33:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece, on the brink of collapse, is receiving the largest numbers of refugees in Europe</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47bf22d0/sc/25/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A10Cgreece0Eon0Ethe0Ebrink0Eof0Ecollapse0Eis0Ereceiving0Ethe0Elargest0Enumbers0Eof0Erefugees0Ein0Eeurope0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In the first six months of this year, more refugees arrived in Greece than in any other European country, according to a new report from the U.N. refugee agency. This is at a time when Greece's economy is teetering on the precipice, its politicians desperately wrangling with international creditors over the terms of a new [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor July 1 Follow @ishaantharoor
Syrian migrants wait to be registered in the port of Mytilini on the island of Lesbos on June 18, 2015. (Louisa Gouliamaki/AFP via Getty Images)
In the first six months of this year, more refugees arrived in Greece than in any other European country, according to a new report from the U.N. refugee agency.
This is at a time when Greece's economy is teetering on the precipice , its politicians desperately wrangling with international creditors over the terms of a new bailout package. The country'sbanks are shut, a quarter of the populace is unemployed,and many Greeks once comfortably middle-class see a dystopian future for their homeland.
But for hundreds of thousands of Asian and African migrants, including many asylum seekers fleeing the Syrian civil war, Greece is a gateway to a better life in the European Union.
(UNHCR)
The report, by theU.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, says that the "eastern Mediterranean route," with migrants traveling throughTurkey to enterGreece, "has now surpassed the central Mediterranean route [from North Africa to Italy] as the main source of maritime arrivals."
Over the past year, the world watched in horror as a succession of overcrowded boats boundfor Italy and Greece's islands sank in the Mediterranean  turning the sea, in Pope Francis's words , into "a vast cemetery."
(UNHCR)
According to the U.N. statistics, the largest number of those arriving in Greece are from Syria, having fled their war-ravaged home through Lebanon and Turkey. This year's influx of migrants is rapidly eclipsing levels recorded in 2014.
(UNHCR)
In a lengthy expos , my colleague Anthony Faiola chartedthe escape route of one Syrian family from Aleppo to Austria.After paying money to Ukrainian smugglers, they made their way to the tiny island of Tilos, population 299. Their journey was being replicated on a far larger scale .
More and more desperate Syrians like the Jinaids were pouring into Greece. They were hardly welcome. On the much larger neighboring island of Kos, overwhelmed with more than 7,000 migrants in the first four months of the year, arrivals were being crammed into a fetid husk of a hotel with no working toilet, no electricity and halls piled with rotting food.
These conditions received attention in the European media after admittedly myopic holidaygoers in Greece complained about thesqualid, "disgusting" state of the islands' tourist infrastructure.
The family Faiola followed kept moving. They trekked through hills and forest, evaded wolves and police, until they found sanctuary in northern Europe  after a tangled, harrowing series of events.
Many of the migrants reaching Greece have no intention of remaining there. As UNHCR notes ,of the 68,000 migrants who arrived in Greece, only about 5,100 have applied for asylum.
See alsoon WorldViews
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jul 01 18:53:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>MAP: Greece isn’t the first nation to default on a sovereign debt</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47be7e99/sc/24/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A70C0A10Cmap0Egreece0Eisnt0Ethe0Efirst0Enation0Eto0Edefault0Eon0Ea0Esovereign0Edebt0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>After Greece defaulted on a payment to the International Monetary Fund on Wednesday, Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras signaled that he may accept bailout terms outlined by the country's creditors. It's not the first time that Greece has defaulted on its sovereign debts: In 2012, it did so twice. This time, the repercussions could be much [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Rick Noack July 1 Follow @rick_n
After Greece defaulted on a payment to the International Monetary Fund on Wednesday, Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras signaled that he may accept bailout terms outlined by the country's creditors. It's not the first time that Greece has defaulted on its sovereign debts: In 2012, it did so twice. This time, the repercussions could be much worse as international creditors are unlikely to save thecountry from being forced to leave the euro zone and return to the Greek drachma.
Nobody really knows the consequences of a "Grexit," but since 1998, at least 16 sovereign bond issuershave defaulted, according to ratings agency Moody's . Apart from Greece, there are fourother countries that have defaulted twice in the last 17 years: Ecuador, Jamaica, Belize and Argentina.
The Moody's list only takes into account recently defaulted sovereign bond issuers. Sudan, Somalia and Zimbabwe have been in default to the IMF for several years ordecades, as well,and continue to do so. Sudan started defaulting to the IMF in 1984, according to an extensive database collected by the Bank of Canada, which is why it is not included on the map above that focuses on defaults that started after 1998.
Can Greece learn from previous defaults?
A closer look at recent and more historical incidents of states being unable to fulfill their financial obligations reveals that the Greek case is indeed unique.
Argentinais most frequently brought up in discussions on the potential effects of a Greek default. Asked about the lessons for Greece, Domingo Cavallo, who was Argentina's economics minister when that nation defaulted in 2001, told the BBC :"Defaulting not only on the foreign debts but also on the domestic debts and all foreign contracts at the beginning of 2002 was really a tragedy for Argentina."
In 2014, Argentina became a defaulted sovereign bond issuer for the second time in only 15 years.(Reuters)
The default's repercussions were devastating: More than half of all Argentines lived in poverty in 2003. Inflation and unemployment rose sharply. Despite thedramatic consequences for Argentines, the default appears to have had a limited impact on other economies. "Argentinas sovereign default in 2001 was then the largest ever, and yet even it did not provoke contagion in global markets," the Financial Times concluded last year when Argentina faced yet another default.
But Argentina was not part of a currency union such as the euro zone. Furthermore, Greece is geopolitically significant, given its NATO membership and its proximity to the Middle East.
Somewhat less momentous was Russia's experience in the late 1990s.When oil prices dropped in 1997, Russian exports plummeted and caused a budgetary crisis. Despite an IMF loan, Russia later defaulted on its domestic as well as foreign obligations. It took until 2000 to restructure the Russian debts.
The situation became so dire that Russia had to demand humanitarian aid. Rising oil prices helped the country overcome its crisis soon afterward. Greece, however, only has limited access to valuable natural resources, and its manufacturing sector is weak. Tourism, one of the country's few reliable revenue streams, would likely suffer froma euro zone exit.
Other countries that have recently defaulted on sovereign debt include Pakistan, Ukraine, Ivory Coast, Moldova, Uruguay, Nicaragua, Grenada, the Dominican Republic, the Seychelles and Cyprus.
That sounds like a lot of defaults, but according to research by the Bank of Canada, the share of total sovereign debt in default out of world public debt or world GDP has sunk since reaching a peak in the 1980s.
Since 1800, Germany has defaulted four times
What appears striking is that some of the countries that have been particularly tough on Greek debts havefaced the same fate over the last two centuries. Spain, for instance, has defaulted six times.
And Germany -- Europe's leading economy, which has been especially been keen on enforcing austerity in countries such as Greece, Spain and Portugal -- has defaulted four times over the last two centuries. Perhaps their experience proves countries can come back from a default, given time.
Related:
Greece and Puerto Rico face economic disasters. Here's what you need to know about the defaults and how it will affect the U.S. (Jason Aldag/The Washington Post)
Rick Noack writes about foreign affairs and is based in Europe.
world
Success! Check your inbox for details. You might also like:
Please enter a valid email address
Sign Up
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
