<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Washington Post">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 12:00:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japan has a flag problem, too</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47a04923/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C270Cjapan0Ehas0Ea0Eflag0Eproblem0Etoo0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>As the debate about the use of the Confederate flag raged in the United States this week, many looked abroad for other symbol-based controversies. Germany, which had banned the swastika and other Nazi iconography after World War II, became an especially common reference: If the Germans had banned Nazi symbols, the logic went, why couldn't [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Adam Taylor June 27 Follow @mradamtaylor
An anti-Japan protester tears a Japanese Rising Sun flag during a rally outside the Japanese Consulate General in Hong Kong on Aug. 16, 2012. Protesters were demanding that the Japanese government release Chinese activists arrested in Japan after landing on Uotsuri Island, one of the islands of disputed territory between the two countries. (Kin Cheung/AP)
As the debate about the use of the Confederate flag raged in the United States this week, many looked abroad for other symbol-based controversies. Germany, which had banned the swastika and other Nazi iconography after World War II , became an especially common reference: If the Germans had banned Nazi symbols, the logic went, why couldn't the United Statesban symbols of the Confederacy?
The German example is illuminating, if imperfect, but the swastika isnot the only controversial symbolof World War II worth considering. The most infamous emblemof the horrors of wartimeJapan, the Rising Sun flag, was never banned, and it still flies today.
Much like the Confederate battle flag, which was used by several Confederate army units, the Rising Sun flag was a flag of war. It was first used by warlordsback inthe Edo period between the 17th and 19th centuries and wasofficially made the war flag of the Imperial Japanese Navy in 1870.
Despite its history, the Rising Sun flag remains in use. It is flown by theJapanese Maritime Self-Defense Force, which was formed following the dissolution of the Imperial Japanese Navy.TheJapanese Ground Self-Defense Force uses a modified version, too, and you can spot the flag on cans of Asahi beer or in theflag of the Asahi Shimbun newspaper company. (Japan's official nationalflag since 1999, which shows asun disk and is known as theHinomaru,also has links to Imperial Japan but is generally considered less provocativethan the Rising Sun flag.)
The continued use of the flagcauses significant problems with Japan's neighbors, many of whichlink the Rising Sun symbolto imperial aggression and war crimes that they thinkJapan hasn't fully atoned for, even 70years later.
"Unquestionably, in China and Korea, the use of those flags remains very controversial, as they are associated withJapanese imperialism and specifically with the invasion of China and colonial rule in Korea," DanSneider,associate director at Stanford University's Walter H. Shorenstein Asia-Pacific Research Center, explains in an e-mail. "Japanese were warned not to use the flag during the Olympics in Beijing, for example. I recall being told that one of the obstacles (though not the only one) to Japanese naval vessels making port calls in Korea is the flying of the Rising Sun flag."
In the United Statesor Europe, the controversy surrounding the Rising Sun flag is little known. Sometimes, the flag is even co-opted by Westerners as a kitsch symbol of Japan:In one recent example , Britishrock band Muse prominently used the flag during a rock video shot in Japan. Internet users in Asia were incensed.
"To the people who can't understand why some are mad, I guess you can compare the Rising Sun flag with the Confederate flag," one commentator onYouTube explained. "Some people can go on and on about how the Confederate flag is a symbol of Southern heritage, but come on now, you know that's not what people associate it with. Same with the Rising Sun flag. Both are rife with controversy and history."
Sneider says that althoughthe comparison withthe Confederate flag or Nazi symbols might seemfair, itsJapanese fansdon't see it that way the flag's origins, like othersymbols of Japan's imperial history, goes back long beforeWorld War II and its associated horrors. It's not quite as simple as Germany ignoring the years of 1933 to 1945, or Southerners ignoring the period between 1861 to 1865 when the Confederate flags were used.
Akiko Hashimoto, a sociologist who has studied Japanese attitudes about World War II , says that the flag's popularity seems to befar lower than that of the Confederate flag in the United States. But, she says, she sees a similar message from those who fly bothflags, which she describes as "the aspiration to destigmatize themselves from a tarnished past and the desire to feel better about themselves despite the perceived characterization of them as primitive, backward, uncivilized people who wronged others in the past."
For Japan, this aspiration and the corresponding response from countries such asChina and Korea may prove to become a problem. Unlike Germany, Japanhas struggled to find good relations with its neighbors, and territorial disputes have threatened to spark new conflicts. Prime Minister Shinzo Abe, like other Japanese leaders before him, has visited the YasukuniShrine in Tokyo despite the criticism of those who say it honors war criminals. Under Abe, some analysts say that the country has veered toward a murky return to nationalism.
It's unlikely that a post-World War II banning of the Rising Sun flag or limiting its official use would have solved this problem completely,of course. But the continuing controversy over the flag and other symbols of Imperial Japan are a reminder of how fresh the horrors of the 20th century are in Asia.
"I think there will always be traditional nationalists who are attached to symbols of a heroic past to give them a sense of positive identity and belonging, especially when feeling discounted and devalued," Hashimoto says. "Dealing with these potent resentments is politically important in any era."
More on WorldViews
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 02:00:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Justice Roberts cited the traditions of four cultures in his dissent on gay marriage. Here’s what he didn’t mention.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/479cd907/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C260Cjustice0Eroberts0Ecited0Ethe0Etraditions0Eof0Efour0Ecultures0Ein0Ehis0Edissent0Eon0Egay0Emarriage0Eheres0Ewhat0Ehe0Edidnt0Emention0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In his written dissent to the Supreme Court's decision to effectively legalize gay marriage in all 50 states in the United States, Chief Justice John G. Roberts Jr. made a conspicuous gesture to the rest of the world. He referred to the "social institution" that the majority of the court was "transforming," and anchored its legitimacy [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor June 26 Follow @ishaantharoor
Supreme Court Chief Justice John G. Roberts Jr. greets President Obama on Capitol Hill in Washington, Tuesday, Jan. 24, 2012, prior to the president's State of the Union address. (AP Photo/J. Scott Applewhite)
In his written dissent to the Supreme Court's decision to effectively legalize gay marriage in all 50 states in the United States,Chief Justice John G. Roberts Jr. made a conspicuous gesture to the rest of the world. He referred to the "social institution" that the majority of the court was "transforming," and anchored its legitimacy in the currents of history.
...the Court invalidates the marriage laws of more than half the States andorders the transformation of a social institution that has formed the basis of human society for millennia, for the Kalahari Bushmen and the Han Chinese, the Carthaginians and the Aztecs. Just who do we think we are?
It's not quite clear to WorldViews why Roberts decided to implicate these four particularcultures in his opposition to the legalizing of gay marriage. But we can suggest reasons why they are hardly exemplars of "traditional" unions between men and women.
The Kalahari Bushmen
These hunter-gatherers in sub-Saharan Africa have long been the world's stock image of "primitive man," and presumably that's why Roberts referenced them -- as the stereotype of an atavistic people, whether it'sfair or not. (It's not, but let's move on.) The Kalahari Bushmen don't have very strong wedding practices , and don't pay muchattention to ceremonies around mating.
Early European accounts of tribes and kingdoms encounteredin southern Africa included details of warrior women styling themselves as kings (not "queens"), polygamous households where lesbianism was common, and even ancient Bushmen rock paintings depicting explicit homosexual sex.
Han Chinese
Again, it's unclear what exactly Robertsis invoking by mentioning the largest ethnic group in China. Gay marriage is not legal in China, but activists are working to change that . A whole set of other "traditional" wedding practices -- including the grisly custom of "corpse brides" -- are banned.
During the Han dynasty,the ancient lineage of kings that gives the Han their name, homosexuality was rife . Almost all the emperors -- you know, the lawgivers of the land -- of the Western Han dynasty apparently had same-sex lovers .
The Carthaginians
For centuries, the Carthaginians were Rome's greatest rival, and sparred for preeminence in the ancient Mediterranean. The great Hannibal, general of Carthage's legions, famously crossed the Alps with war elephants in 218 B.C. and almost snuffed out the world-conquering empire before it bloomed. Sadly for him, things went the other way.
Now, some right-wing Italian scholars of Roman history see in Carthage the seeds of Rome's eventual fall. Why? Well, according toRoberto De Mattei , formerly the deputyhead of Italy's National Research Council, Carthage "was a paradise for homosexuals." After it was conquered by Rome, said De Mattei in 2011, "the abhorrent presence of a few [Carthaginian] gays infected a good part of the [Roman] people."
De Mattei's remarks led to a heated backlash, but one imagines Roberts was not that aware of the debate.
The Aztecs
Here's an excerpt from a discussion of Aztec customary law on the Web site of the University of Texas at Austin. It hardly presents a picture-perfect snapshot of conservative family values:
Marriage was conditional in that the parties could decide to separate or stay together after they had their first son. Marriages could also be unconditional and last for an indefinite period of time. Polygamy and concubines were permitted, though this was more common in noble households and marriage rites were only observed with the first, or principal, wife. Aztec families could live in single family homes, though many opted to live in joint family households for economic reasons.
Then you have to factor in the whole human sacrifice thing . Children, meanwhile, needed to behave: "Parents were permitted to physically punish their children, and would beat them using maguey spines or force them to inhale chili smoke," notes UT-Austin's site.
The Supreme Court ruled, 5 to 4, that same-sex marriage bans are unconstitutional. Here's what you need to know. (Gillian Brockell/The Washington Post)
Ishaan Tharoor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. He previously was a senior editor at TIME, based first in Hong Kong and later in New York.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 22:07:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In Kuwait, a man paused to gaze at worshipers. Then he blew them up.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/479bdaef/sc/3/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C260Cin0Ekuwait0Ea0Eman0Epaused0Eto0Egaze0Eat0Eworshipers0Ethen0Ehe0Eblew0Ethem0Eup0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A ghastly day of terror attacks on three continents began with a suicide bombing of a mosque in Kuwait. The attacker entered the Imam Sadiq mosque, one of the oldest Shiite mosques in Kuwait City, and detonated the explosives strapped to his body, killing at least 25 people and wounding hundreds. The Islamic State, an extremist [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor June 26 Follow @ishaantharoor
National security correspondent Greg Miller discusses the impact of three terrorist attacks in France, Tunisia and Kuwait after an Islamic State leader called to make the month of Ramadan a time of "calamity for the infidels." (McKenna Ewen/The Washington Post)
Aghastly day of terror attacks on three continents began with a suicide bombing of a mosque in Kuwait. The attacker entered the Imam Sadiq mosque, one of the oldest Shiite mosques in Kuwait City, and detonated the explosives strapped to his body, killing at least 25 people and wounding hundreds.
The Islamic State, an extremist Sunni organization that views Shiites as apostate enemies,claimed responsibility for the attack, one of a spate of recent bombings of Shiite sites in the region. Footage of the suspected attacker approaching the mosque appeared on social media.
CCTV footage of suicide attacker entering mosque today shortly after killing 24 worshippers in Kuwait #_ pic.twitter.com/AcKAn6KRGP
 Ala'a Shehabi (@alaashehabi) June 26, 2015
Other image-captures showed the attacker approaching the inner chamber of the mosque, where hundreds were gathered for Friday prayers.
According to accounts , he stood at the threshold of the room, and apparently shouted "God is great!" over the prayer service, as well as a declaration thatthat he woulddine with the Prophet Muhammad in the evening.
          pic.twitter.com/MpnnjvESKv
   (@alsoultah_5) June 26, 2015
Hassan Hassan, a Middle East scholar, summed up the barbarism of the act in this tweet:
An unsparing ideology. Extremely telling photo: during Ramadan, they're prostrating &amp; he looks at them. Sums up evil. pic.twitter.com/aYXixVyNXd
 Hassan Hassan (@hxhassan) June 26, 2015
Ishaan Tharoor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. He previously was a senior editor at TIME, based first in Hong Kong and later in New York.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:57:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bangladesh might exile Rohingya refugees to a remote, flood-prone island</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/479c5535/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C260Cbangladesh0Emight0Eexile0Erohingya0Erefugees0Eto0Ea0Eremote0Eflood0Eprone0Eisland0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Mohammed Islam is a Rohingya Muslim who has lived in a refugee camp in Bangladesh since age 9, after his family fled religious tension in his home country of Burma, also known as Myanmar. His life is one of uncertainty coupled with despair, which has deepened in recent weeks because of  a  Bangladesh government proposal to move 32,000 [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Annie Gowen June 26 Follow @anniegowen
Rohingya migrants drift in Thai waters off the southern island of Koh Lipe in the Andaman in May. (Christophe Archambault/AFP/Getty Images)
Mohammed Islam is a Rohingya Muslim who has lived in a refugee camp in Bangladesh since age9, after his family fled religious tension in his home country of Burma, also known as Myanmar.
His life is one of uncertainty coupled with despair, which has deepened in recent weeks because of a Bangladesh government proposal to move 32,000 Rohingya refugees to a remote island that swamps at high tide .
We dont want to die, he said in an interview. We are already persecuted; we dont want to suffer more.
Islam, now 29, is an activist at the Nayapara camp, a fetid assemblage of tarp-roofed huts in the touristy Coxs Bazar beachfront area in southern Bangladesh. He said he and other refugees dont want to leave to move to a barren, 15.6-square-mile island in the Bay of Bengal, a two-hour speedboat ride away.
The refugees are deeply concerned, he said of the island, which completely floodswhen the tide rolls in. We are not willing to move from this place until they find a solution.
The remote island, Thengar Char, disappears completely under several feet of water at high tide, and has no roads or barriers to flooding, according to an AFP report . Accounts from locals and a forest department official who oversaw the planting of mangroves on Thengar Char in 2011 gave an indication of the challenges, according to AFP.
"At high tide the entire island is under three to four feet of water," said the official, speaking on condition of anonymity."It is impossible to live there."
About 32,000 Rohingya Muslims live in two government-run camps in the Coxs Bazar area, according to the United Nations, but the government estimates that hundreds of thousands of other Rohingyas live illegally in Bangladesh, a country of more than 155 million.
[ New concerns rise over Burmese treatment of Rohingya Muslims ]
The stateless Rohingya Muslims have long been victims of persecution in Burma. Their situation worsened during violent ethnic clashes in 2012 between Buddhists and Rohingya Muslims in Burmas Rakhine state that resulted in more than 100,000 Rohingya being confined to displacement camps.
Women and children wait in line for medical care at the makeshift Aung Clinic in Sittwe, Burma, which serves many Rohingya, with a few dedicated staff giving free medical care. (Paula Bronsteinfor The Washington Post )
An estimated 25,000 Rohingya and others have fled both Bangladesh and the Burma camps since January, according to the United Nations, precipitating an international crisis after thousands became stranded at sea attempting to enter Malaysia and Thailand.
Bangladeshs prime minister, Sheikh Hasina, criticized those fleeing by boat in remarks last month , saying they were mentally sick for wanting to leave Bangladesh, adding, they are tainting the image of the country along with pushing their life into danger."
Hasina had reportedly visited Coxs Bazar in the fall and decided that the grimy Rohingya camps were an impediment to tourism, officials said. A plan to relocate them was launched.
Gowher Rizvi, an adviser and special representative to Hasina, said that the proposed move was still in the preliminary stages and that no final decision had been made.
There are a large number of Rohingyas, as you know, in Coxs Bazar area, which is not ideal for keeping people there, he said. There have been discussions about whether or not a better or more suitable location can be found.
Annie Gowen is The Posts India bureau chief and has reported for the Post throughout South Asia and the Middle East.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:51:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What was the first country to legalize gay marriage?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/479bc9d9/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C260Cwhat0Ewas0Ethe0Efirst0Ecountry0Eto0Elegalize0Egay0Emarriage0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>With a landmark Supreme Court decision Friday, the United States became the 17th country to legalize same-sex marriage. But what was the first? The Danish were the first to grant same-sex unions almost the exact same rights as marriages, with its Registered Partnerships Act of 1989. However, the law stopped short of calling same-sex unions "marriages," and couples could not be married in the Danish [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Adam Taylor June 26 Follow @mradamtaylor
Guests celebrate the unveiling of a plaque by Amsterdam Mayor Job Cohenon Feb. 14, 2007, commemorating the first same-sex marriage in Amsterdam. (Robin Utrecht/AFP/Getty Images)
With alandmark Supreme Court decision Friday, the United Statesbecame the 17thcountry to legalize same-sex marriage.But what was the first?
The Danish were thefirstto grant same-sex unions almost the exact same rights as marriages, with its Registered Partnerships Act of 1989. However, thelaw stopped short of calling same-sex unions "marriages," andcouples could not be married in the Danish state church or adopt a child. Even so, the law was viewed as an important stepping stone at the time.
''The only way to be able to move anything is to be open about it," Eigil Axgil, 67,who entered a union with his partner on the day the law passed, told the New York Times in 1989. ''You have to say that this is the way I am so society can be open to you. If everyone follows this lead in Denmark, if everyone goes out and says this is the way they are and go out of the closet, this event will also happen in the rest of the world.''
And people did follow Denmark's lead: During the 1990s, a number of other countries and regions introduced laws that granted same-sexunions similar rights to marriages. It wasn't until 2001, however, that a country fully legalized same-sex marriage. That country was the Netherlands.
The Dutch law went further than Denmark's, effectively eliminating any distinction at all between heterosexual and homosexual marriage. When it passed parliament in 2000 (it would not become law until a few months later), The Washington Post's Keith Richburg noted that it seemed to "add to the Netherlands' reputation in Europe and beyond for enacting laws that many hail as signs of tolerance and others decry as laxity."
The vote had been a foregone conclusion, and government officials seemed bemused by the global attention. "The discussion was years ago," a spokeswoman for the Dutch Embassy told The Post. "We are always a bit ahead of other countries. We had those discussions years before other countries even started."
Again, other countries followed the Dutch lead. Belgium legalized same-sex marriage in 2003, and many others have since then (the Danish fully legalized it in 2012). So far in 2015, four countries have legalized same-sex marriage, including the United States.
So how has the Netherlands coped since legalizing gay marriage? Even some of its fiercest Dutch critics now say it was a good move.
"At the time I opposed same-sex marriage, I was led by fear," Hannie van Leeuwen, leader of the Christian Democrat party and opponent to the gay marriage law, was reported to have said just a few years later . "Having seen so many happy gay and lesbian couples getting married, I realize I was wrong. I don't understand anymore what made me treat gays and lesbians differently from other citizens."
And evidence suggests that while discrimination was far fromtotally eradicated by the Netherland's gay marriage law, the institution of marriage has suffered no ill effects at all .
"Heterosexual couples did not turn away from the institution of marriage, nor did the world isolate my country,"Boris Dittrich, a former member of Netherland's parliament, wrote in 2011 . "Civilization as we know it did not end. And, as far as I can tell, God did not punish the Netherlands."
More on WorldViews
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:27:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sousse: The beautiful Tunisian city that became a scene of terror</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/479b984e/sc/10/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C260Csousse0Ethe0Ebeautiful0Etunisian0Ecity0Ethat0Ebecame0Ea0Escene0Eof0Eterror0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Gunmen launched a brazen attack on a resort hotel and a beach full of vacationers in the seaside Tunisian city of Sousse, some 90 miles south of the capital Tunis. According to authorities, at least 28 people were killed and dozens more wounded. The majority of the casualties are said to be tourists. The attack immediately brings to [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor June 26 Follow @ishaantharoor
Tourists enjoythe beach near a hotel in the resort town of Sousse in October 2013. The popular tourist destination 90 miles south of the Tunisian capital was rocked by a terrorist attackJune 26 that left at least 28 dead.several people, the interior ministry said. (Bechir Bettaieb/AFP/Getty Images)
Gunmen launched a brazen attack on a resort hotel and a beach full of vacationersin the seaside Tunisian city of Sousse, some90 miles south of the capital Tunis. According to authorities, at least 28 people were killed and dozens more wounded. The majority of the casualties are said to be tourists.
The attackimmediately brings to mind the March assault on the Bardo museum in Tunis , when militants killed 22 people, again mostlyEuropean tourists. The small Mediterranean nation attracts millions of tourists each year to its gorgeous beaches and ancient, classical ruins.
[ Why Tunisia is so vulnerable to terror attacks. ]
The details of the attack in Sousse are emerging. British, German and Belgian nationals are believed to be among those killed, according to Reuters. Irish media also reported the death of an unnamed Irish woman in her 50s. No group has claimed responsibility for the massacre.
Some reports suggest the attackers landed on the beach in Port El Kantaoui, to the north of Sousse's city center, in an inflatable boat, armed with grenades and automatic weapons. Then, an attacker moved against the Hotel Imperial Marhaba, not far from the shoreline.
An update posted on the Web site of the hotel's parent company indicated that, at the time of the assault, occupancy of the five-star facility was at 77 percent, with 565 guests.
Inside hotel lobby, seemed all guests were out of their rooms- several in tears &amp; shook up. #SousseAttack #tunisia pic.twitter.com/0WNEC6NI1K
 Rana Jawad (@Rana_J01) June 26, 2015
Tunisian authorities have identified one of the gunmen as a man from the city of Kairouan, Tunisia's most important religious center. According to the AP, he "came from the beach hiding his Kalashnikov under an umbrella before opening fire on the tourists. From there, he entered the Hotel Imperial [Marhaba] through the pool, shooting people as he went."
A bloodied sunbed at the scene of attack by gunmen in sousse that killed at least 28 people. #SousseAttack #tunisia pic.twitter.com/pO9hjeRhu7
 Rana Jawad (@Rana_J01) June 26, 2015
MAP: At least 27 killed in attack on beach near Imperial Marhaba hotel in Sousse, #Tunisia http://t.co/ET6C6LqAhD pic.twitter.com/HT9F5wTVqI
 BBC News Graphics (@BBCNewsGraphics) June 26, 2015
Here's the horrifying account of one tourist, who eventually barricaded his room with a mattress.
There has been a shooting on the beach at our hotel it's been going on for 20 mins
 John Yeoman (@johnyeo68) June 26, 2015
We were in the pool when we heard automatic gun fire. People ran past saying there was an armed man on the beach
 John Yeoman (@johnyeo68) June 26, 2015
Hope it's enough pic.twitter.com/XaW4yTpplU
 John Yeoman (@johnyeo68) June 26, 2015
The gunman was shout in our hotel by armed police there a reports of a child amongst the dead. We are all in shock here.
 John Yeoman (@johnyeo68) June 26, 2015
Another tourist, Steve Johnson, related this account to the Guardian :
We were just laying on the beach as usual ... and we heard what at first we thought was fireworks but it was soon pretty obvious that it was not fireworks, it was firearms being discharged, and people screaming and starting to run from along the beach towards us.
Me and my friend said: Thats guns, lets go, and we shouted to everybody around us who joined the sort of mass rush from the beach. People running in all directions around us.
Sousse is one of Tunisia's popular coastal destinations, drawing some 1.2 million tourists a year. It's a historic city that, like ancient Carthage near Tunis, was founded more than 2,000years ago by Phoenician settlers and traders, and remained a prominent port and fortress town in the centuries thereafter.
Its famed medieval Medina, or market, is a UNESCO World Heritage Site that the U.N. cultural agency deems "an outstanding example of Arabo-Muslim and Mediterranean architecture that reflects a particular traditional way of life."
Twitter user Emily Haddad posted images of the city in happier times under the hashtag #LetMeTellYouAboutSousse.
#LetMeTellYouAboutSousse The Kasbah built in AD 859 stands crisply beautiful against the horizon in #Sousse #Tunisia pic.twitter.com/C5rQQmHZlu
 Emily Haddad (@ThinkTwig) June 26, 2015
#LetMeTellYouAboutSousse The Medina area of #Sousse takes pride in a variety of door colors/styles #Tunisia pic.twitter.com/I9XPU0lRH2
 Emily Haddad (@ThinkTwig) June 26, 2015
#LetMeTellYouAboutSousse Inside Kasbah is an archeology museum filled with gorgeous Roman-era mosaics #Tunisia pic.twitter.com/VlrySPusOf
 Emily Haddad (@ThinkTwig) June 26, 2015
#LetMeTellYouAboutSousse As a child, it was a great treat to go to #Sousse for pastries made fresh on the spot. pic.twitter.com/5uwe80dDXe
 Emily Haddad (@ThinkTwig) June 26, 2015
Sadly, there were already reports ofEuropean airlines canceling flights to the city, and turning around other aircraft en route. Another Twitter user posted this image of tourists heading to Sousse's airport.
Des touristes commencent  quitter la ville de #Sousse aprs lattaque terroriste #SousseAttack pic.twitter.com/V8OrGwp0II
National security correspondent Greg Miller discusses the impact of three terrorist attacks in France, Tunisia and Kuwait after an Islamic State leader called to make the month of Ramadan a time of "calamity for the infidels." (McKenna Ewen/The Washington Post)
Related on WorldViews
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:00:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ramadan had brought fears of new Islamic State attacks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/4755fe22/sc/11/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C170Cthe0Estart0Eof0Eramadan0Eis0Ebringing0Enew0Efears0Eof0Ean0Eislamic0Estate0Eattack0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Islamic State claimed responsibility for a bomb attack at a Shiite mosque that was packed for Ramadan on Friday in Kuwait. Sixteen people were killed and 179 were wounded in the attack, according to the Associated Press. Two other deadly attacks on Friday, at a gas plant in France and a mass shooting at a beach [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Adam Taylor June 26 Follow @mradamtaylor
Crowds surround the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a bomb explosion following Friday prayers, in the Sawaber area of Kuwait City. Four people were killed in the suicide attack on Friday on the Shiite Muslim mosque in Kuwait City, the governor of Kuwait City Thabet al-Muhanna said. (Jassim Mohammed/Reuters)
The Islamic State claimed responsibility for a bomb attack at a Shiite mosquethat waspacked for Ramadan on Friday in Kuwait . Sixteen people were killed and 179 were wounded in the attack, according to the Associated Press.
Two other deadly attacks on Friday, at a gas plant in France and a mass shooting at a beach resort in Tunisia , increased concerns of terrorist action during the Islamic holy month of Ramadan, although those attacks have not been directly linked to the Islamic State.
Ramadan, famous for its dawn-to-dusk fasting and evening feasting, is observed by millions of Muslims around the world.It's atime of intense religious importance in the Islamic world, with Muslims encouraged to regularly pray andhelp those less fortunate.
Yet, forthose watchingthe Islamic State, the month of Ramadan has given them reason to worry. Ramadanis seen astime of action for the extremist group,which sees the month's religious importance as anadded imperative for jihad, and its traditions as an opportunity to go on the offensive.
Just earlier this week , IslamicState spokesman Abu Mohammed al-Adnani called on the group's followers to turn Ramadan into a time of "calamity for the infidels ... Shiites and apostate Muslims." We may have witnessed this on Friday.
This image made from video posted on a militant Web site onJuly 5, 2014, purports to show the leader of the Islamic State group, Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi. (Militant video via AP)
The Islamic State has a history of making dramatic movesduring Ramadan. Last year, for example, the group declared its "caliphate" on the first day ofRamadan, with Adnani declaring"a new era of international jihad."
It was a clearescalation of the group's rhetoric, and its timing was unmistakable. Shortly after this announcement , the newly proclaimed caliph, Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi, made his first public appearance, and hewas unequivocal about the importance of Ramadan to the Islamic State.There is no deed in this virtuous month or in any other month better than jihad in the path of Allah, so take advantage of this opportunity and walk the path of your righteous predecessors, Baghdadi told his supporters .
As the terrorism research firm Soufan Group has noted , itwasn't the first time that the Islamic State had made major moves that coincidedwith Ramadan. In 2013, the group, then known as the Islamic State in Iraq and the Levant, broke into Abu Ghraib, an infamous prison in Iraq. Many of the prisoners who escaped during this raid went on to join the group, bolstering its following in both numbers and fervor. "There's no underestimating the boost to morale," analyst Charles Lister told The Post at the time.
And in 2012, the group launched a bombing campaigntargeting security forces and Shiite neighborhoods in Iraq that left many dead. At the time, the Guardian noted that the bombings appeared to be timed to cause maximum carnage around Ramadan's predawn meals."We are starting a new stage,"Baghdadi said in an audio recording released before the bombings.
Some analysts had predicted some kind of similar event in Ramadan in 2015. In its recently released forecast for the Islamic State, the Institute for the Study of War wrote that the Islamic State is "likely preparing a surge of operations to try to achieve important campaign objectives" during Ramadan. The report suggests that the Islamic State may try to seize a historic city or attack a Shiite holy site in a bid to further inflame sectarian tensions, thoughboth would be ambitious tasks.
Some had also pointed out that this the first Ramadan in which the Islamic State's vast social media presence and international support are fully developed. The Soufan Group had notedthat these social media supportershave called for so-called " lone wolf " attacks.
In its primary battlefield of Iraq and Syria, theIslamic Statehas suffered some major defeatsrecently, such as the loss of Tikrit in April , andits recent routing in Tal Abyad , a defeatthat cuts the group off from a key border crossing with Turkey. Yet the group still seemsfar from collapse: This week Islamic State militantsinfiltrated Kobane and carried out suicide attacks that left scores dead. With attacks linked to Ramadan, the Islamic Statemay hope to remind the world that even if it is losing on the battlefield, it can still create pain.
Assailants rammed a car into a gas plant in southeast France on Friday morning, triggering two blasts. A severed head and Islamist flag were found at the scene. (Reuters)
More on WorldViews
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:57:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Watch: Neo-Nazi hooligans disrupt an epic urban downhill bike race</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/479a6fc4/sc/23/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C260Cwatch0Eneo0Enazi0Ehooligans0Edisrupt0Ean0Eepic0Eurban0Edownhill0Ebike0Erace0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Last weekend, hundreds of neo-Nazi hooligans, ostensibly protesting immigration, burst into the path of a downhill urban bike competition in Bratislava, the capital of Slovakia. The footage above was taken from the headcam of Brazilian biker Bernardo Cruz, who zooms down narrow cobbled lanes in the old city and makes stomach-clenching jumps before careening straight into [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor June 26 Follow @ishaantharoor
Last weekend, hundreds of neo-Nazi hooligans, ostensibly protesting immigration, burst into the path of a downhill urban bike competition in Bratislava, the capital of Slovakia.
The footage above was taken from the headcam of Brazilian biker Bernardo Cruz, who zooms downnarrow cobbled lanes in the old city and makes stomach-clenching jumps before careening straight into a mob of angry, masked men.
Cruz uploaded the video to his Facebook page, along with this comment:
"This city is really amazing! In the final meters of the track the neo nazis just ran into the track and destroyed everything, then we had to stop our race. Hope to come back to this race next year!"
According to reports, authorities arrested at least 27 men for disrupting the peace.
Ishaan Tharoor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. He previously was a senior editor at TIME, based first in Hong Kong and later in New York.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:30:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why many Kurds in Turkey are willing to die in Syria’s border towns</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47977866/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C260Cwhy0Emany0Ekurds0Ein0Eturkey0Eare0Ewilling0Eto0Edie0Ein0Esyrias0Eborder0Etowns0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The battle for Kobane raged once more this week after Islamic State fighters launched an assault on the Syrian border town, which had been firmly in the control of Kurdish militias ever since they chased out the jihadist organization in January. Initial reports suggested dozens died in the fighting, including numerous civilians, with Syrian Kurdish militias forces either killing, [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor June 26 Follow @ishaantharoor
Smoke billows in the Syrian town of Kobane as people watch from the Turkish side of the border. Turkey denied "baseless" claims that Islamic State militants reentered Kobane through the Turkish border.(AFP/Getty Images)
The battle for Kobane raged once morethis week after Islamic State fighters launched an assault on the Syrian border town, which had been firmly in the control of Kurdish militias ever since they chased out the jihadist organization in January.Initial reports suggested dozens diedin the fighting, including numerous civilians, with Syrian Kurdish militias forceseither killing, capturing, or cornering most of the Islamic State militants.
Significantly, tensionsalso flared in neighboring Turkey, where roughly 15 million Kurds live. Some Kurdish groups, as they often do, accused the Turkish government of tacitly enabling the Islamic State assault. These conspiratorial claims were angrily dismissed on Thursday by Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan as "slander and black propaganda." But the hostile mood underscores the precariousness of the moment.
The plight of Kobane, a predominantly Kurdish town right on the border with Turkey,is a lightning rod for many Kurds in Turkey. It's adjacent to the Turkish townof Suruc, where many residentshave direct ties of kinship and clan to those living in Kobane.Last year, as Kobane wasbesieged by jihadist forces, hundreds of thousands of Syrian Kurdish refugees sought sanctuary across the border.
Kurds living in Turkey grew impatient with their government, which they believed was, at best, not doing enough to save Kurdish lives and, at worst, actively colluding with the extremist Islamic State in order to quash Kurdish separatism. That led to days of protests and unrestin October,and triggered violence that claimed some 50 lives .
Turkey warily eyes the main Syrian Kurdish militia fighting the Islamic State. Its political parent is directly tiedto the Kurdistan Workers' Party, or PKK, the principal Kurdish separatist organizationthat was locked in a three-decade-long war with the Turkish state . Some 40,000 people died in the conflict, which technically ended in a ceasefire in 2013. The organizationis considered a terrorist group by both Turkey and the United States.
Erdogan hasdone more for Turkey's Kurds than any other leaderin the history of the modern Turkish republic, which for decades refused to recognize the existence of Kurds as a distinct ethnic group and restricted their ability to learn, speak and write their language. But Turkey's ambivalent role in the Syrian conflict , combined withfrustrations over a stalled peace process with the PKK, steadily turned the tide of Kurdish opinion againstthe country's president.
Earlier this month, the shadow of Kobane fell over Turkey's parliamentary elections. Erdogan's ruling Justice and Development Party lost a considerable segment of its Kurdish support to the leftist Peoples' Democratic Party, or HDP, a party that many say is an extension of the PKK and whose candidates included relatives of slain or jailed PKK leaders. Yet the HDPwon 80 seats in the Grand National Assembly in Ankara by pitching itself as a progressive, inclusive party for Turks of all ethnicities and creeds.
That dramatic success ensured that the Erdogan's partydid not win a parliamentary majority, and appears to have scrapped Erdogan's mooted plans to transform Turkey'spolitical structure into a presidential system that would have given him more executive powers. Turkey's four main political parties are currently wrangling over the formation of a coalition government .
TheHDP's gains remain fragile, especially if Turkeyhas to stageearly elections. Their rainbow-nationembrace of Turkey's vast diversityalso to a certain extent belies a real groundswell of Kurdish nationalism that's emerged recently in the region. The election results were celebrated not just by Kurds in Turkey, but their compatriots across the borders in Syria and Iraq as well, areas wheresemi-autonomous Kurdish territories are gaining strength and confidence.
In early June ahead of the elections, I was in Diyarbakir, the center of Kurdish cultural and political life in southeastern Turkey. On a hot week day, I attended the funeral of two young fighters  one still a teenager  from the city who had been killedwhile fighting the Islamic State alongside Syrian Kurdish units. Hundreds gathered, chanting Kurdish nationalist slogans that celebrated the PKK anddenouncedboth the Islamic State and the "fascists," presumably a slur directed at Ankara.
Though they were all Turkish nationals, they considered the fight against the Islamic State in Syria to be their own, inextricably linked from thelong struggle for greater Kurdish rights and freedoms within the Turkish state.
"We have been fighting for 30 yearsfor this time," said Lokman Bakr, father of one of the slain fighters. He was referring to the HDP's surge in the polls.
But he didn't seem to see Kurdish victories in the electoral arena in all thatdifferent a light than those on the battlefield.
His son and the otheryoung "martyr," both local lads, were buried in a cemetery lined with the graves of dozens of other Diyarbakir men who had gone across the border to Kobane and elsewhere to combat the jihadists.
"If my other children want to go," said Bakr, "I will not stop them."
Ishaan Tharoor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. He previously was a senior editor at TIME, based first in Hong Kong and later in New York.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:18:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>An Alabama tractor company wants to set up shop in Cuba, if only Washington will let it</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/4794c5c1/sc/28/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C250Can0Ealabama0Etractor0Ecompany0Ewants0Eto0Eset0Eup0Eshop0Ein0Ecuba0Eif0Eonly0Ewashington0Ewill0Elet0Eit0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Two U.S. businessmen are trying to become the first Americans to set up a manufacturing operation in Cuba in more than half a century, with plans to build inexpensive tractors on the island for sale to local farmers. Horace Clemmons and Saul Berenthal, former IBM engineers and longtime business partners, said they have been working with officials in Cuba and regulators [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Nick Miroff June 25 Follow @nickmiroff
Early in the morning, as the sun rises, Geraldo Carrion, 72, picks cilantro plants that have gone to seed, on a small farm in Santiago, Cuba. (Sarah L. Voisin/The Washington Post)
Two U.S.businessmenare trying to become the first Americans to set up a manufacturing operationin Cuba in more than half a century, with plans to build inexpensive tractors onthe island for sale to local farmers.
Horace Clemmons and Saul Berenthal, former IBM engineersand longtime business partners, saidthey have been working with officials in Cuba and regulators in Washington to turn their seemingly implausible business plan into a trailblazing pilot project for a new era of U.S.-Cuba relations.
Cleber LLC, their Alabama-based company, is seekingto build a smallassembly plant in the Mariel Special Economic Zone , anarea west of Havana with a new $1 billion deepwater port terminal where the Cuban government is trying to attract foreign investment.
Two Mexican companies that plan to set up ameatpacking plantand apaint factory are the only two projectsthat Cuba hasannouncedso far in the Mariel zone. Cleber LLC is believed to bethe first U.S. company to apply.
"I believe we can pull it off," said Clemmons, 71, "and it'll be good for everyone."
Clemmons and Berenthal have never madetractors before-- they're working on their first prototypes-- but that may be the least of their problems.
The U.S. trade embargo onCuba remains firmly in place even asthe two countries are moving to restore diplomatic relations severed by Washington in 1961. It remains a bureaucratic minefield for eventhe most basicforms of U.S.-Cuba commerce -- like charter flights or shipmentsof frozen chicken-- never mind something as complicated as a tractor-assembly operation.
Officialsat the U.S. Treasury Department and Commerce Department have told the men their plan could be approved "as long as we comply with the spirit of the law," said Berenthal. "They're cooperating with us."
Officials in Washington have told them to expect a response within 180 days.
The tractor-making plan would take advantage of loopholes in the trade sanctionsthat allow for agricultural exports and farm equipment, as long as the end users of those products are private farmers and non-government cooperatives.
And Berenthal said they would hire a non-government cooperative to assemble the tractors, a labor arrangement that does not appear to be possible under Cuba's existing investment framework. They would start with five to 10 employees, he said.
The tractor parts will come from Alabama, Berenthal said, but eventually the company would like to source parts from Cuba.
Clemmons and Berenthal have hiredan engineering firm to buildthe first tractors based on the simple designs of the Allis-Chalmers G model that was madein the United Statesfrom 1948 to 1955. It was specially tailoredto the type of small family farms that have mostly disappeared in the United States, but remainthe standard in Cuba.
"These tractors are perfectfor 100-acre farms," said Clemmons.
A similar-sized model made in the United States or Korea might cost $20,000 or so, said Clemmons. He wants theCleber version toretail for half as much. They plan to call it "Oggun," named for the orisha, orAfro-Cuban Santeriaspirit, of metal.
Clemmons and Berenthal are planning to bring their prototype version to the annual Havana trade fair inNovember.
As far-fetched as the plan may seem, thecolorful biographies of the two men suggest they might actually be able to do it.
Berenthal and Clemmonsleft IBM to start their own North Carolina-based software service firm, PSI, which grew to 400 employees before theysold it to Japan's Fujitsu Corp in 1997, for an undisclosed sum. "It was more than enough to retire on," said Clemmons.
He returned home to northern Alabama, where he grew up farming cotton and corn. "My grandfather didn't have a tractor, and I would helphim plow thefields with a mule," he said.
Clemmons bought a 3,000-acreparcelof land, donating most of it to the Nature Conservancy, and then built a 7,000-square-foot house to runmostly on wind and solar power, drawing water from a nearby cave. He ran for commissioner of Jackson County (pop. 53,000) in 2008 and won, serving a four-year term.
Berenthal, 70, grew up in Cuba and left the island with his family in 1960 after Fidel Castro's revolution. After the sale of PSI, he began traveling back to Cuba more often, and then leading Jewish tour groups to visit the island's synagogues.
His grandparents, who settled in Cuba toescapethe Holocaust, are buried at the island's Jewish cemetery. "I still go back every time I visit the island," he said.
Berenthal said both men are motivated, more than anything, by an urge to help small farmers who rely mostly on old Soviet-era tractors and oxen teams. Cubaimports most of its food, despite an abundance of fertile land.
"With a tool like this, these farmers willbe able to increase their output," he said. "We think this willbe a mitzvah-- a good deed."

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:16:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anti-Uber protests in France lead to scenes of chaos and violence</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/479399b5/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C250Canti0Euber0Eprotests0Ein0Efrance0Elead0Eto0Escenes0Eof0Echaos0Eand0Eviolence0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In the past, Uber has faced resistance from abroad, as well as from within the United States. On Thursday, however, French taxi drivers took the fight against the American ride-hailing company to a new level, clashing with riot police and burning tires and cars. At least one cabdriver was injured, according to CNN. And protests and roadblocks were not limited [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Rick Noack June 25 Follow @rick_n
An UberPop vehicle was overturned by French taxi drivers as they clashed with riot police during a demonstration against the app-based transportation network Uber in Paris on June 25. (Ian Langsdon/EPA)
In the past, Uber has faced resistance from abroad, as well as from within the United States. On Thursday, however, French taxidrivers tookthe fight against the American ride-hailing company to a new level, clashing with riot policeandburning tires andcars.
At least one cabdriver was injured, according to CNN . And protests and roadblocks were not limited to Parisian train stations and airports, but also affected Marseille and other southern French cities. According to the BBC , there have been nearly 100 attacks on Uber drivers and their passengers since the protests turned violent for the first time several weeks ago.
"Our first driver sped away as taxi drivers approached us loading his cab. Our second driver agreed to meet us in a back street near Gare du Nord and passed David a baseball bat to hold," one businessman, Hardy Blechman, told CNN . According to Blechman, his UberPop driver was armed with a baseball bat to be able to defend himself against officially registered cabdrivers in case of an attack. UberPop, the service which was targeted by the protesters, isavailable in some European cities and is roughlycomparable toUberX in the United States, butis legally distinct to adapt its terms of use to European legislation.
The chaos forced hundreds of travelers to walk to airports, causing anger among many departing or arriving visitors.
Travelers walk with their luggage on a road near Charles de Gaulle airport as French cabdrivers protest Uber's car-sharing service in Roissy, France, on June 25. (Balint Porneczi/Bloomberg)
Sometravelers took to Twitter to express their discontent.
Today, all Paris taxis are on strike to protest against Uber. So, I had to take an Uber.
 Thomas Moradpour (@TomMoradpour) June 25, 2015
Singer Courtney Love Cobain said she was "held hostage" in a car for an hour. Her comparison to Baghdad attracted criticism and led to a backlash on Twitter.
they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
 Courtney Love Cobain (@Courtney) June 25, 2015
The protestingFrench cabdrivers, however, argue that Uber threatens their very existence. Whereas French law requires official taxidrivers to buy expensive licenses, Uber's position in the gray areas of French law hasenabled the company's drivers to operate withoutpermits. The protesters fear thatUber would destroy the securejobs of experienced taxi drivers and replace them with unregulated "hobby drivers."
"We are faced with permanent provocation [from Uber] to which there can only be one response: total firmness in the systematic seizure of offending vehicles," Serge Metz, the head of a French cabcompany, told French TV station BFM TV, according to Reuters .
Although the French interior minister called for a clampdown on UberPop hours after the violence erupted Thursday, many taxidrivers are likely to be skeptical of their government's efforts to curtail the influence of the U.S.-based transportation app. Last October, French lawmakers bannedunregistered drivers from providing services to passengers. Known as theThevenoud law , the rule has so far not been fully implemented by authorities.
French taxi drivers protesting against the ridesharing service Ube have set fires and clashed with police in Paris. (Reuters)
Uber has appealed the law, andno final decision has been made. A governmental order , adopted Thursday, will nevertheless allow police officers tosanction UberPop drivers as well as their passengers.
But it does not ban the company's app.AlthoughFrench taxi drivers are expected to continue their protests, which will put UberPop drivers and passengers at risk, the company said Thursday that it was planningtocontinue its operations in France.
The company has faced criticism elsewhere in Europe and around the world. Last August , for instance, a German court practically banned Uber nationally, a decision that came after months of protests against it in other countries such as Britain.
Not everyone has been willing to show solidarity with the taxi drivers, however.
"This is not about one company. This debate is about whether Europe will dare to be open to the opportunities of technology and the future," Neelie Kroes, vice president of the European Commission and head of its digital agenda, told the Financial Times last year.
Rick Noack writes about foreign affairs and is based in Europe.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:37:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pakistan’s heat wave is so deadly that morgues are overflowing</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/4793c856/sc/31/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C250Cpakistans0Eheat0Ewave0Eis0Eso0Edeadly0Ethat0Emorgues0Eare0Eoverflowing0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A heat wave in southern Pakistan has caused so much death in the country that morgues are overflowing, local medical workers say. "They are piling bodies one on top of the other," Seemin Jamali, an official at a government hospital in Karachi, said of the city's overflowing morgues in an interview with Al Jazeera. Anwar Kazmi, [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>Scorching temperatures above 113 degrees kill hundreds in Pakistan
View Photos
A deadly heat wave with temperatures over 113 degrees covers southern Pakistans city of Karachi.
Caption
A deadly heat wave with temperatures over 113 degrees covers southern Pakistans city of Karachi.
June 24, 2015 A police officer sprinkles water on a colleague, who collapsed in the heat, in a police van outside Jinnah Postgraduate Medical Center in Karachi, Pakistan. Rain finally broke a four-day heat wave, but hundreds of people died from its effects. Akhtar Soomro/Reuters
Buy Photo
Wait 1 second to continue.
A heat wave in southern Pakistan has caused so much death in the country that morgues are overflowing, local medical workers say.
"They are piling bodies one on top of the other," Seemin Jamali, an official at a government hospital in Karachi, said of the city's overflowing morgues in an interview with Al Jazeera .Anwar Kazmi, an official with the Pakistani charity Edhi Welfare Organisation, told Agence France-Presse that the morgues had "reached capacity."
Pakistan's heat wave has been described as theworst in decades, with temperatures soaring to120 degrees Fahrenheit. The high temperatures hit during the Islamic month of Ramadan, when many Muslims were fasting during daylight hours.As of Thursday, reports in the Pakistani media put the death toll at 1,200 , though temperatures have begun to fall.
Things got so bad that somemorgues have put up signs outside, explaining that they are full.
Photographs taken from inside one morgue show how crowded it has become.
Volunteers try to identify a body amongothers of thosewho have died due to an intense heat wave at the Edhi Foundation morgue in Karachi on June 22. (Akhtar Soomro/Reuters)
A man waits, right, while volunteers search for the body of his deceased relative among the bodies ofheat wave victims at Edhi Foundation morgue in Karachi on June 22. (Akhtar Soomro/Reuters)
The scale of crowding at the morgueshadsome major ill effects, Kazmi told Reuters ."The refrigeration unit was not working properly because there were too many bodies," the official explained.
On Tuesday, the Express Tribune reported that authorities were now attempting to bury unidentified bodies within a day to help deal with the backlog, but gravediggers were taking advantage of the situation and charging double their normal rates.
As horrific as Pakistan's situation is, it's not the first major heat wave of the year to result in deaths in South Asia. A heat wave in India in late May was blamed for the deaths of 2,500, making it one of the deadliest heat waves in history (Pakistan's heat wave would also find a place on that list).
And while infrastructure problems definitely play a role in the death toll (power cuts coincided with the heat wave in Pakistan), an even more difficult factor also plays a major role. As The Post's Wonkblog noted this year, climate change may not always create these extreme weather events , but it certainly makes them worse.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:32:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Assad regime started the #SummerinSyria hashtag. The Internet then took over.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/47920326/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C250Cthe0Eassad0Eregime0Estarted0Ethe0Esummerinsyria0Ehashtag0Ethe0Einternet0Ethen0Etook0Eover0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>It's not a great time for the regime of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad. Resurgent rebel fighters are making steady inroads against Syrian government forces, capturing strategic towns and bases in various pockets of a country that has been tragically hollowed out by war. Earlier this week, Egyptian President Abdel Fatah al-Sissi warned that Assad was about [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor June 25 Follow @ishaantharoor
It's not a great time for the regime of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad. Resurgent rebel fighters are making steady inroads against Syrian government forces, capturing strategic towns and bases in various pockets of acountry that has been tragically hollowed out by war. Earlier this week, Egyptian President Abdel Fatah al-Sissi warned that Assad was about to fall "at any moment."
But, judging from the English-language Twitter account of the regime's statenews agency, all's well in Assad land.
On Monday, it issued thisfarcically tone-deaf tweet, encouraging the use of the hashtag #SummerinSyria .
Now that #summer is upon us, snap us your moments of summer in #Syria using the hashtag #SummerInSyria pic.twitter.com/sutvUuZUoj
 SANA English (@SANA_English) June 22, 2015
The reaction was swift and biting.
@SANA_English Join one of the 'charity fun-run' events this #SummerInSyria pic.twitter.com/IHcNHUTQT0
 Not a spy (@finriswolf) June 23, 2015
https://twitter.com/amaal_dani/status/613339547762601985
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:11:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea unveils a gleaming new airport terminal featuring high-end stores and chocolate fondue</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/479200e1/sc/28/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C250Cnorth0Ekorea0Eunveils0Ea0Egleaming0Enew0Eairport0Eterminal0Efeaturing0Ehigh0Eend0Estores0Eand0Echocolate0Efondue0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un recently visited a shiny new terminal at Pyongyang Sunan International Airport, according to photographs released by state media on Thursday that showcase amenities that — in all honesty — would make many domestic travelers in the United States jealous. A three-page spread in the newspaper Rodong Sinmun showed shops [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>A peek inside North Koreas new airport terminal: Wine bars and chocolate fondue
View Photos
Leader Kim Jong Un toured the new terminal at Pyongyang International Airport, and it features plenty of fancy amenities.
Caption
Leader Kim Jong Un toured the new terminal at Pyongyang International Airport, and it features plenty of fancy amenities.
 North Korean leader Kim Jong Un, right, and his wife, Ri Sol Ju, tour the new terminal of Pyongyang International Airport in this undated photo released by North Koreas Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) on June 25, 2015. KCNA via Reuters
Buy Photo
Wait 1 second to continue.
In one image, Kim is even seen inspecting what appears to be a chocolate fondue set. "He was very satisfied to see the terminal well built as required by modern architectural beauty and national character,"  Rodong Sinmum reported .
(Rodong Sinmun)
North Korea may be under international sanctions and have a reputation as a "hermit kingdom," but in recent years it has attempted to become a tourism mecca. Officials aim to eventually attract 1 million visitors a year , though current numbers are thought to be closer to 100,000, with only about 5,000 to 6,000 Europeans visiting each year, according to some sources.
However, North Korea's grand aspirations have run into hurdles  often of its own creation. The country, a notorious police state, hasarrested a number of Western tourists , for example, and last year it shut down its borders because of the Ebola crisis  a move that many considered an overreaction. In Pyongyang, a symbol of North Korea's failed tourism dreams looms on the horizon: The 105-story Ryugyong Hotel, where construction started in 1987 but was never completed, despite several attempts.
The opening of the airport terminal comes at what might be a difficult time for North Korea. Recently, Pyongyang announced that the country was facing its worst drought in 100 years. It's unclear whether this is a real problemor simply an attempt to gain sympathy from abroad  but either way a new airport terminal with a chocolate fondue station doesn't look so great in these circumstances.
More on WorldViews
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 10:30:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Germans don’t think America stands for freedom anymore</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/478e5519/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C250Cgermans0Edont0Ethink0Eamerica0Estands0Efor0Efreedom0Eanymore0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>To many, America is synonymous with freedom. The country dubbed itself the "land of the free" and, when trying to reclaim sliced and fried potatoes from the French, briefly attempted to rename "French fries" as "freedom fries." Yet America's global reputation for personal freedom has taken a beating over the last couple of years. Data from Pew [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Adam Taylor June 25 Follow @mradamtaylor
A U.S. flag hangs over the U.S. Embassy on Oct. 28, 2013 in Berlin.(Sean Gallup/Getty Images)
To many, America is synonymous with freedom. The countrydubbed itself the "land of the free" and, when trying to reclaim sliced and fried potatoes from the French, briefly attempted to rename"French fries" as " freedom fries. "
Yet America's global reputation for personal freedom has taken a beating over the last couple of years. Data from Pew Global Research suggests adramatic fall in the number of people around the worldwho saythe U.S. government respects the freedom of its people.
The issue may be most stark in Germany. Back in 2013, a whopping 81 percent of Germans polled by Pew thought that the U.S. government respected personal freedom. Then, in 2014 , it was 58 percent. Now, according to figures released by Pew this week , just 43 percent of Germans think the U.S. government respects the freedom of its citizens. Fifty-three percent think it doesn't.
[Americas freedom reputation is on the decline a year after NSA revelations]
There are only three other countries listed by Pew wherethose who think America doesn't respect personal freedom are in the majority, and all have an antagonistic relationship with the United States -- Argentina, Turkey and Russia. Despite being a clear geopolitical ally, Germany's naysayers have a far larger pointslead than any of these nations: It is the only country where more than half of the population says the United States does not respect personal freedom.
In 2014, Pew attributed a global drop in perceptions of U.S. freedom to the NSA revelations and what it dubbed "the Snowden Effect." However, while "the Snowden Effect" appears to have been a worldwide phenomena, in many countries it bounced back or stabilized in 2015. In Germany, pessimism about the personal freedom of Germans reached new nadirs.
Part of this may well be Germany's own place in the scandal the documents released by NSA whistleblower Edward Snowden in 2013 showed that Chancellor Angela Merkel had been targeted by the NSA, and Merkel herself was said to be "livid" over the surveillance. Snowden has become an icon within some circles in Germany a square in Dresden was recently renamed after him, for instance.
One factor may be Germany's own experience with freedom, or the lack thereof. The 20th century saw not only the rise of Nazi Germany and its associated horrors, but also the Stasi surveillance state in East Germany until the Berlin Wall fell.
Whatever the reasoning, Pew suggests "this view has become increasingly common among Europeans over the last two years." And the United States isn't immune to concerns about its own citizens' freedom either: Just 51 percent of Americans said their government respected their freedom in 2015, a drop of 15 percent from 2013.
More on WorldViews
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 10:29:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bobby Jindal’s identity causes a Twitter storm in India</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/478e5520/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C250Cwhy0Eis0Ebobby0Ejindal0Ebeing0Ecalled0Ewhite0Eon0Etwitter0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A day after Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal announced that he will run for U.S. president in 2016, the way he chooses to identify himself has become the subject of a trending hashtag in India. It's called #bobbyjindalissowhite. Jindal’s meteoric rise in the Republican Party as a conservative of color has won him many supporters in the United States. [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Rama Lakshmi June 25 Follow @RamaNewDelhi
Louisiana Governor Bobby Jindal talked the importance of conservatism and faith as he joined the crowded Republican field for the U.S. presidency in 2016. (Reuters)
Aday after Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal announced that he will run for U.S. president in 2016, the way he chooses to identify himselfhas become the subject of a trending hashtag in India.
It's called #bobbyjindalissowhite.
Jindals meteoric rise in the Republican Party as a conservative of color has won him many supporters in the United States. But here in India, Jindal is seen as a man who has spent a lifetime distancing himself from his Indian roots.
Im sick and tired of people dividing Americans, Jindal said on Wednesday. And I am done with all this talk about hyphenated Americans. We are not Indian-Americans, Irish-Americans, African-Americans, rich Americans or poor Americans. We are all Americans.
His remarks fueled a firestorm of jokes on Twitter that he is trying to pass as white despite his Indian roots. Here's just a sample:
Don't miss the powder on Jindal's face in this 'family time' photograph. #BobbyJindalIsSoWhite https://t.co/2636uQVyZr
 Shiv Aroor (@ShivAroor) June 25, 2015

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:10:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In Australia, $325 million will get you a piece of property almost the size of England</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/478b8203/sc/28/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C240Cin0Eaustralia0E3250Emillion0Ewill0Eget0Eyou0Ea0Epiece0Eof0Eproperty0Ealmost0Ethe0Esize0Eof0Eengland0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>One of Australia's largest landholders has put on a vast chunk of real estate nearly the size of England on the market, making it possibly the world's single biggest property sale in modern memory. Estate the size of England has hit the market for $325MILLION http://t.co/Jb8h58jQYl pic.twitter.com/nmY8ngsBTi &amp;#8212; Daily Mail Australia (@DailyMailAU) June 23, 2015 As [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>One ofAustralia's largest landholders has put on a vast chunk of real estate nearly the size of England on the market, making it possibly the world's single biggest property sale in modern memory.
Estate the size of England has hit the market for $325MILLION http://t.co/Jb8h58jQYl pic.twitter.com/nmY8ngsBTi
 Daily Mail Australia (@DailyMailAU) June 23, 2015
As reported by the Daily Mail, the total size of the holdings, which are scattered around parts of Australia's vast interior, amount to about 39,155 square miles. That, reports the newspaper, is "equivalent to the US state of Indiana, and more than three-quarters the size of England." (Theproperties are marked in red below.)
One of The biggest farms in Australia for sale, 11 million hectares, price 223 million dollar http://t.co/Wee6KIyTsT pic.twitter.com/AaynDwgcAK
 John (@AgriHarvest) June 23, 2015
They are part of the vast cattle empire raised by the late Sir Sidney Kidman, who went from being a penniless urchin as a child to one of Australia's leading business magnates in the 1920s. (The actress Nicole Kidman is one of his descendants.)
Now, prospective bidders will have to spend a week flying around on a plane to conduct a thorough inspection of what's on offer. More photos of the stark, dramatic landscape for sale can be seen here .
Ishaan Tharoor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. He previously was a senior editor at TIME, based first in Hong Kong and later in New York.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 21:41:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pakistan targets 3 Catholic nuns as part of campaign against foreigners</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/478acd13/sc/31/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C240Cpakistan0Etargets0E30Ecatholic0Enuns0Eas0Epart0Eof0Ecampaign0Eagainst0Eforeigners0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan — First, Pakistan nearly forced one of the world’s most recognized charities, Save the Children, to stop doing business in the country. Then, it announced that thousands of charities and international aid groups would have to follow strict new licensing procedures. Now, it has canceled the visas of three Philippine nuns, prompting a lawsuit [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Tim Craig June 24 Follow @timcraigpost
A police officer stands guard outside the shuttered office of the international aid group Save the Children in Islamabad, Pakistan, on June 15, 2015. Authorities said the charity was "working against the country." They have since reversed their decision but have now canceled the visas of three Catholic nuns. (Aamir Qureshi/AFP via Getty Images)
ISLAMABAD, Pakistan  First, Pakistan nearly forced one of the worlds most recognized charities, Save the Children, to stop doing business in the country. Then, it announced that thousandsof charities and international aid groups would have to follow strict new licensing procedures. Now, it has canceled the visas of three Philippine nuns, prompting a lawsuit from the Catholic Church.
In a case that highlights thePakistani governments growing suspicion of foreigners, the nuns were ordered last week to leave. They were accused of "engaging in employment in violation of their visa category, the Express Tribune newspaper reported Wednesday .
The nuns, who have been working in Pakistan for about a decade, were told they must leave by the end of the month. One of them is the principal of Islamabad Convent School, one of 42 private schools operated by the Roman Catholic Diocese of Islamabad-Rawalpindi.
But the nuns and church officials are fighting back, a rare public stance by the Catholic Church in this overwhelmingly Muslim country. On Wednesday, the diocese filed a motion asking an Islamabad judge to block the expulsion.
Abid Nazir, an attorney for the church, said in an interview all the three nuns are missionary workers who have devoted their lives to educating and helping impoverished children in Pakistan. Nazir added that he fears Interior Minister Chaudhry Nisar Ali Khan has a personal vendetta against them and the school.
Nazir said Khans wife used to work as a teacher at the school but resigned in 2011 after a dispute with the principal.
More than 4,000 students of Islamabad Convent School, who are Pakistani Nationals are made the scapegoat, just because of (a) personal liking or disliking, the court filing states. If the missionary workers will be sent back then no proper replacement will be available for the proper taking care of the 4,000 children/students of our nation.
The Interior Ministry did not return calls seeking comments. A judge has yet to rule on the case.
Still, the controversy is anotherexample of howPakistan is again taking a more aggressive stance toward some foreigners trying to work here.
Earlier this month, The Washington Post and other news outlets reported that Pakistan was not renewing the permits of nearly two dozen international aid organizations. On June 10, Pakistan announced the expulsion ofSave the Children over what it called anti-Pakistan activities.
The State Department condemned the move, as did many local commentators, who noted that Save the Children employs about2,000 Pakistanis. Last week, the government reversed its decision and said Save the Children could continue its operations.
But Khan announced Monday that thousands of international aid groups had six months to re-register with the government.
He also said that the governments Economic Affairs Division would no longer oversee the groups. Instead, he said, the Interior Ministry would be tasked with it. That will put the charitable organizations under the same umbrella as police, which could result in even more scrutiny of humanitarian efforts.  Aidgroups alsoare prohibited from working in certain areas of the country.
There has also been a sudden, noticeable shift in the governments oversight of Western journalists and other foreign visitors. Its now harder for foreigners to renew visas or get permission slips to travel outside the major cities of Karachi, Lahore and Islamabad.
When The Post recently inquired about a months-old travel request, a communications officer said the matter was being held up by the Interior Ministry.
Over the past decade, there have been other times when Pakistan has adopted a stringent posture towardforeigners. After a U.S. military raid killed al-Qaeda leader Osama bin Laden in the garrison town of Abbottabad in 2011, Pakistan effectively closed its door to American visitors for several months.
But what makes the latest crackdown so surprising is that there has been no known trigger for it.
Over the past year, both Pakistani and U.S. officials have been stressing that relations between their countries have greatly improved. Pakistani political and military leaders also have been touting their countrys relationship with Russia, China and a host of European countries, which they hope to leverage into increased foreign investment to bolster the economy.
And with civilian deaths from terrorist attacks at an eight-year low , this year could have provided Pakistani leaders a real opportunity to pitch the country to outsiders. Instead, many Pakistani analysts worry that the government is harming the countrys reputation by getting into high-profile spats with groups such as Save the Children and the Catholic Church.
All this brings is a bad name to the country, Hasan Askari Rizvi, a Lahore-based political analyst, said in an interview.
Analysts note that Interior Ministry officials never explained what sort of anti-Pakistan activities Save the Children was alleged to have been a part of. But there is speculation that the order may have been linked to accusations  which Save the Children strongly denies  that the group had ties to a Pakistani doctor who helped the CIA track bin Laden in 2011.
As for the three nuns, Nazir said their pending expulsion is particularly alarming because it comes one month after immigration authorities approved a two-year extension of their visas. But when they arrived at the school on June 17, they found a letter with the heading cancellation of visas of Philippines missionary workers," Nazir said.
They were just condemned and no explanation has ever been given, he said. What we are now trying to do is say, No one should ever be condemned unheard... and the church is very concerned by it.
Shaiq Hussain contributed to this report.
Tim Craig is The Posts bureau chief in Pakistan. He has also covered conflicts in Iraq, Afghanistan and within the District of Columbia government.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 21:11:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran’s Ahmadinejad says the U.S. is out to get the Hidden Imam, who, uh, disappeared in the 10th century</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/478a37d6/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C240Cirans0Eahmadinejad0Esays0Ethe0Eu0Es0Eis0Eout0Eto0Eget0Ethe0Ehidden0Eimam0Ewho0Eum0Edisappeared0Ein0Ethe0E10Ath0Ecentury0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>For some time now, Iran's former president, Mahmoud Ahmadinejad, has been back on the country's political scene -- no longer hidden from view, as it were. And so, the world once more has had to hear his strange, inflammatory statements. According to a report by Radio Liberty, the outspoken ex-president directed his ire once more at the United States [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>By Ishaan Tharoor June 24 Follow @ishaantharoor
A handout picture made available by the official Web site of the Iranian supreme leader shows former Iranian president Mahmoud Ahmadinejad, center, attending a ceremony commemorating the 26th anniversary of the death of Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini at the shrine for Khomeini in southern Tehran on June 4. (Web Site of Supreme Leader via EPA)
For some time now, Iran's former president, Mahmoud Ahmadinejad, has been back on the country's political scene --no longer hidden from view, as it were.And so, the world once more has had to hearhis strange, inflammatory statements.
According to a report by Radio Liberty , the outspoken ex-president directed his ire once more at the United States this past weekend.
During a speech to a group of clerics, Ahmadinejad accused Washingtonof seeking the arrest of the Hidden Imam, a messianic figure in Shiite theology who, according to tradition, went into " occultation " -- or hiding -- in the 10th century.
Wait, what?
To be fair, the Hidden Imam -- known also as the Twelfth Imam and the Mahdi, sanctified with the religious and political authority of the prophet Muhammad -- is a big deal.The Islamic Republic's supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, technically rules in his absence as his custodian on Earth until he returns to fill the world with peace and justice.
So it's unclear exactly what U.S. agency, in Ahmadinejad's mind, is out to prevent the Hidden Imam's arrival. In his remarks, Ahmadinejad first pointed the finger at American educational institutions. And then, well, read the RFE/RL report :
"They've done so much research about the Hidden Imam in the human science universities of the United States that I am not exaggerating by saying that it is a thousand times more than all the work done in the seminaries of Qom, Najaf, and Mashhad," [Ahmadinejad] reportedly said, referring to three Shi'ite holy cities.
Ahmadinejad, who is known for his controversial statements and his devotion to the Hidden Imam, added that U.S. universities have debriefed numerous individuals who have been in touch with the disappeared spiritual leader.
"To quote a friend, they've completed a case against the Hidden Imam, and closed it also for his arrest," he was quoted as saying. "The only [evidence] they lack is his picture."
Ahmadinejad suggested that the West -- and particularly the United States -- sees the return of the Hidden Imam as a threat to its "empire," adding that the U.S. administration is "evil."
"It is really a government established by Satan to prevent reaching God and the Hidden Imam," Ahmadinejad was quoted as saying. "  This evil government knows that its end will come if the Hidden Imam reappears."
This is not the first time Ahmadinejad has warned of the supposed American fear of the coming messiah.
In 2009, not long after he returned to power, despiteanelection many thought was rigged and mass street protests quashed by his government, Ahmadinejad framed his struggles in millenarian terms .
"We have documented proof that [the Americans]believe that a descendant of the prophet of Islam will raise in these parts [Middle East] and he will dry the roots of all injustice in the world," Ahmadinejad said at the time. "They have devised all these plans to prevent the coming of the Hidden Imam because they know that the Iranian nation is the one that will prepare the grounds for his coming and will be the supporters of his rule."
What that evidence was is unclear, but it all fits a purpose for Ahmadinejad. His grandstanding on the Hidden Imamis a matter of domestic politics -- a means of snatchingsome of themessianic figure's moral authorityaway from Iran's religious establishment, with which he has feuded in the past. Ahmadinejad'stense political battles with other factions in the Islamic Republic even led to the arrest of a number of his close allies .
As the Iran scholar Abbas Amanat observed a few years ago , the link between political authority and signs of the Mahdi is a relatively new phenomenon, made most prominent in recent decades by the doctrines of theIslamic Republic.
Even then, Amanat notes , the "majority of the more cautious and circumspect members of the clergy seem to be paying only a lip service to [the] idea and treat [Ahmadinejad's] repeated statements about the impending advent of the Mahdi with silent skepticism."
Ishaan Tharoor writes about foreign affairs for The Washington Post. He previously was a senior editor at TIME, based first in Hong Kong and later in New York.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 19:27:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Erdogan’s colossal dinner table inspires a stream of Turkish memes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636535/s/4789780c/sc/31/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cblogs0Cworldviews0Cwp0C20A150C0A60C240Cerdogans0Ecolossal0Edinner0Etable0Einspires0Ea0Estream0Eof0Eturkish0Ememes0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In the photograph above, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan is pictured meeting with former and current officials from his country's Directorate General for Religious Affairs, also known as the Diyanet, for an iftar dinner on Sunday. You may have noticed that the table at which Erdogan and others are eating is large. Very large. In fact, it's hard [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>But perhapsthe most cutting criticism pointed to the far humbleriftar meals enjoyed by President Obama recently or those enjoyed by Erdogan himselfnot so long ago.
Fakir lan bu Amerikanlar! pic.twitter.com/2GMRc0hiaU
 Atilla Ta (@AtillaTasNet) June 23, 2015
Find the one common point between these two pictures. pic.twitter.com/pKDZZjRRIH
 Hakan Berberolu (@hakanberberoglu) June 23, 2015
For his critics, the sheer scale of the table was indicative of Erdogan's grandiose vision of himself. The Turkish president resides in a new palace that has more than 1,000 rooms and covers about 2,150,000 square feet , andsome believe that Erdogan's frequent references to the days of the Ottoman caliphate betray where his intentions lie.
Compounding the issue is the controversy around theDiyanet, which handles the workings of Islam in Turkey. The Diyanet has been criticized for being too close to Erdogan's Justice and Development Party (AKP), and its leader,Mehmet Gormez, recently returned a $435,000 official car he had purchased after a public outcry .
The table sparked further headlines Tuesday aftersuggestions that the table and the chairs cost as much as6.5 million Turkish lira ($2.43 million). Mustafa Varank, an adviser to Erdogan, denied this, however, claiming that the table was worth less than $2,000 and tweeting photographs that appeared to show arelatively humble piece of furniture.
Dnyann en aalk, en kahpe iftiraclaryla mcadele etmekten bktk.Bu masa btn yemeklerde kullanlyor 4600 TL pic.twitter.com/B00qJHL4GP
 Mustafa Varank (@varank) June 23, 2015
In a statement released late Tuesday , the office of the presidency denounced the scandal over the table, dubbing it "black propaganda" against Erdogan. Images were released of Erdogan at another, far more humble, iftar dinner.
Cumhurbakan Erdoan, Orucunu elik Ailesiyle At http://t.co/Lu7ODpii6J pic.twitter.com/Wx7xN8HFQr
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
