<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="whittierdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Money, politics, power struggles -- Pakistan's media scandal has it all</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150526/money-politics-power-struggles-x2014-pakistans-media-scandal-has-it-all</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Money, politics, power struggles  Pakistans media scandal has it all
Pakistan Federal Investigation Agency (FIA) deputy director Kamran Attaullah speaks to media after leaving the Axact in Karachi on May 20, 2015, after conducting an investigation. (RIZWAN TABASSUM/AFP/Getty Images)
By Lawrence Pintak, GlobalPost
# Comments
KARACHI, Pakistan  A government raid on the company that is bankrolling Pakistans newest media conglomerate has highlighted the corruption and infighting within the countrys news industry.
A front-page article in The New York Times early last week accused Karachi-based Axact  which calls itself the worlds leading IT company  of selling fake diplomas in an internet-era scheme on a global scale.
The story broke as BOL, the media company financed by Axact, was preparing its long-delayed launch in mid-summer. The wheels are now coming off the project. Over the weekend, BOLs top two news executives and some staffers resigned.
[T]his is a massive conspiracy by the seths of the Pakistani media industry to defame BOL and Axact and derail the launch of BOL, the company said in a statement on its website after the Times story broke. (Seth is a South Asian term for chief or merchant.) In defiance of the resulting media furor, BOL moved up the TV channels launch date to mid-June. Its English- and Urdu-language newspapers were scheduled to follow in the fall.
The controversy underlines the deep divide in Pakistans media, with corporate owners beholden to powerful forces in the civilian and military wings of the government, which are in a constant struggle for control.
Storm against BOL is war of media moguls, tweeted political analyst Fawad Hussain. #Axact corrupt or innocent. Whatever. But BOLtv gave sleepless nights2 media owners who feared losing monopoly, wrote Rauf Klasra, a journalist at ARY television.
The Express Tribune, which publishes the international edition of The New York Times as an insert, had long known about the allegations against Axact  which calls its employees Axactians  but was prevented from publishing by a court order prompted by an Axact lawsuit, according to media sources in Karachi.
The Times story unleashed an avalanche of articles in the Pakistani media, with headlines like,  Who is the real owner of Axact? ;  Why I left Axact: The Inside Picture ; and  Employees were berated, threatened if they did not meet their targets  (DunyaNews).
But some media houses  with different political allegiances  took a more measured approach. My hats off to newspapers like @dawn_com and the @The_Nation because they kept the banner of fair coverage of #Axact, tweeted Murtaza Solangi, former director general of Radio Pakistan, referring to two of Pakistans largest media companies.
Advertisement
Rumors have long swirled around the impending launch of BOL, many centering on the question of who was really behind the nascent media group. Some in Pakistans media and political circles speculated that the military was using BOL, which recruited many of the top figures in Pakistani journalism, to force other media groups into line. In a nation rife with conspiracy theories, there was even speculation BOL was an elaborate ruse that would never actually launch.
Axact and BOL vehemently denied all those claims.
We will be the first organization where editorial decisions will be made in the newsroom, not at the owners desk, Kamran Khan, president and editor-in-chief of the BOL Media Group, told GlobalPost in a meeting at BOLs partially complete headquarters building last month. At those other media houses, he said, business interests come first.
For us, its a legacy; we want to make a real difference in the paradigm of media thinking, added his colleague Azhar Abbas, president of BOL News.
But over the weekend, Khan and Abbas announced their resignations on Twitter. Previously, both were senior executives at rival GEO TV, which ended up in a major confrontation with the military after it blamed the Armys intelligence wing for the 2014 attempted assassination of one of its anchors.
The resignations came three days after the channel defiantly moved up its launch date and began test transmissions. Screenshots from the BOL website with the faces of high-profile journalists crossed out began making the rounds on social media even as Axact filed suit against a blogger for aggregating the many tweets making fun of the companys travails.
Meanwhile some of the other high profile journalists hired by Axact/BOL stayed on the offensive. Anchor Mubasher Lucman announced he would remain with the channel after issuing a warning to the competition: #Axact #BOL TV story from media houses is sickening, there is a lot beneath the skin &amp; they would wish they had never started this campaign.
The Axact/BOL scandal highlights the murky finances and complicated political relationships that underpin the Pakistani media landscape. Top editors say it is common for media companies to owe millions in unpaid taxes and debts to banks, or to generate profits under the table while saying they lose money. These sources claim that leaves media houses open to pressure from the rival civilian and military wings of the government to shape coverage. The government also ultimately controls a large portion of the countrys advertising expenditures.
They immediately say yes, when the military orders them to report or suppress a story, because the military has their dirty laundry, said Badr Alam, editor of The Herald, a monthly magazine that is part of the rival Dawn media group.
Its so easy to control those organizations because its easy to control the owners, BOLs Khan said in Karachi last month. They are making money but not showing it or paying their taxes. If you are not officially making money for six months, you are making it somewhere else.
But the subsequent scandal, which led Khan to resign, raises the question of whether the man Khan and many others in the Pakistani media elite went to work for was any different. Pakistani newspapers reported last week that Axacts chief executive, Shoaid Shaikh, paid the equivalent of 25 cents in taxes last year. And the government tax office has launched a full investigation into the companys finances.
As for the conspiracy theory that BOL would never launch: its looking more and more credible by the day.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:15:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former LAPD officer turned fugitive arrested in Mexico</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150526/former-lapd-officer-turned-fugitive-arrested-in-mexico</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Mexican authorities working in conjunction with the FBI have arrested former LAPD officer turned fugitive Henry Solis, Mexican authorities confirmed this afternoon.
FBI officials would only to say there have been significant developments in the case.
Solis, 27 of Pomona, who was wanted on a federal warrant, fled the United States into Mexico after the March 13 early morning fatal shooting of Salome Rodriguez Jr., 23, down the street from a Pomona nightclub.
Investigators learned Rodriguez and Solis were engaged in a fist fight before the shooting, police said.
Rodriguez was taken to Los Angeles County-USC Medical Center, where he died.
The next day Solis failed to report for duty at LAPDs Devonshire Division, where he was assigned.
His father, Victor Solis, 53, of Lancaster, was indicted in April for allegedly lying to the FBI after misleading investigators to prevent them from finding his son.
A federal arrest warrant issued for Henry Solis says agents interviewed the elder Solis, but he claimed to not know of his sons whereabouts.
Victor Solis was interviewed by El Paso FBI agents on Monday, March 16, 2015, the warrant says. Victor Solis advised the agents that he drove his son, defendant Solis, to El Paso on Friday March 13, 2015, and dropped him off at a bus station, but he does not know where defendant Solis is.
The indictment also alleges the elder Solis told authorities that he, alone, crossed into Mexico on March 14 despite photographs released by the FBI showing Victor Solis, accompanied by Henry Solis, crossed into Juarez, Mexico, from El Paso at the Paso Del Norte Port of Entry on March 14, 2015, according to a Department of Justice statement.
The elder Solis faces up to five years in federal prison and a maximum $250,000 fine, if hes convicted.
LAPD Chief Charlie Beck fired Solis days after the shooting.
If Henry Solis is watching this ... you have dishonored this police department, your country and your service to the country and your family, Beck said. You should turn yourself in and face the consequences for your action.
Security cameras recorded both father and son walking across the border at the Paso Del Norte international bridge in Downtown El Paso.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:32:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Appeals panel won't lift hold on Obama immigration action</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150526/appeals-panel-wont-lift-hold-on-obama-immigration-action</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Appeals panel wont lift hold on Obama immigration action
By Kevin McGill and Juan A. Lozano, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
NEW ORLEANS &gt;&gt; A federal appeals court refused Tuesday to lift a temporary hold on President Barack Obamas executive action that could shield as many as 5 million immigrants illegally living in the U.S. from deportation.
The 2-1 ruling by a panel of the 5th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeal is far from the final word; more arguments on the merits of the case are tentatively set at the 5th Circuit for early July.
But immigrant advocates decried the continued roadblock on Obamas actions. And, White House spokeswoman Brandi Hoffine said the two-judge majority in Tuesdays ruling chose to misinterpret the facts and the law.
Obama announced the executive action in November, saying lack of action by Congress forced him to make sweeping changes to immigration rules on his own.
Twenty-six states sued to block the plan, led by Texas. They argue that Obama acted outside his authority and that the changes would force them to invest more in law enforcement, health care and education.
U.S. District Judge Andrew Hanen sided with the states and, from his court in Brownsville, Texas, issued a temporary injunction on Feb. 16 to block the plan from taking effect while the lawsuit works its way through the courts.
Justice Department lawyers sought a stay while they appealed the injunction. They argued that keeping the temporary hold interfered with the Homeland Security Departments ability to protect the U.S. and secure the nations borders. They also said immigration policy is a domain of the federal government, not the states.
But 5th Circuit judges Jerry Smith and Jennifer Walker said that the federal government lawyers are unlikely to succeed on the merits of the appeal.
Smith and Elrod rejected the governments argument that it has the discretion to selectively defer legal action against immigrants. The Obama policy, the ruling said, goes beyond simple non-enforcement. It is the affirmative act of conferring lawful presence on a class of unlawfully present aliens, Smith wrote.
Judge Stephen Higginson dissented, saying the administration had not abused its discretion. He also noted congressional inaction on immigration issues.
Smith and Walker were nominated to the court by Republican presidents, Ronald Reagan and George W. Bush; Higginson, by Obama.
The White House said its appeal of the preliminary injunction will proceed on an expedited basis in the 5th Circuit while the Justice Department reviews Tuesdays opinion and contemplates other possible steps.
This decision is a victory for those committed to preserving the rule of law in America, Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton said in a statement.
Advertisement
Marielena Hincapie, executive director of the National Immigration Law Center, said the decision will result in confusion and fear in immigrant communities. But she predicted eventual victory in the courts.
The first of Obamas orders  to expand a program that protects young immigrants from deportation if they were brought to the U.S. illegally as children  was set to take effect Feb. 18. The other major part, extending deportation protections to parents of U.S. citizens and permanent residents who have been in the country for some years, had been scheduled to begin May 19.
Hanen issued his injunction believing that neither action had taken effect. But the Justice Department later told Hanen that more than 108,000 people had already received three-year reprieves from deportation as well as work permits. Hanen said the federal government had been misleading, but he declined to sanction the governments attorneys. Earlier this month, the U.S. government told Hanen it had mistakenly awarded three-year work permits to another 2,000 people.
Along with Texas, the states seeking to block Obamas action are Alabama, Arizona, Arkansas, Florida, Georgia, Idaho, Indiana, Kansas, Louisiana, Maine, Michigan, Mississippi, Montana, Nebraska, Nevada, North Carolina, North Dakota, Ohio, Oklahoma, South Carolina, South Dakota, Tennessee, Utah, West Virginia and Wisconsin.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Uber just found another way to anger Mexico City's taxi drivers</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150526/uber-just-found-another-way-to-anger-mexico-citys-taxi-drivers</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Uber just found another way to anger Mexico Citys taxi drivers
Taxis and a bus ride along the streets of Mexico City. (Omar Torres/AFP/Getty Images)
By Sara Yasin, GlobalPost
# Comments
Taxi drivers in Mexico City are going on strike today, so naturally the people over at Uber decided to offer free rides.
The publicity-hungry company made the announcement on their Mexico City blog  promising their customers that they wouldnt allow a little labor dispute interfere with their services.
Mexicos capital  like some other cities in Latin America  has been considering a ban on the popular service, which has drawn outrage from its taxi drivers.
According to Excelsior, a Mexican daily newspaper, approximately 5,000 taxi drivers are on strike today . According to CNNs Spanish language channel, the taxi drivers are protesting against the car sharing service.
Back in March, the fight between Uber and local taxi drivers turned violent. A group of taxi drivers used baseball bats to attack an Uber drivers car.
The citys 140,000 taxis have been the focus of reforms as a part of a plan to regularize transportation.
Hailing a taxi in Mexico City and elsewhere in Latin America can be dangerous. As GlobalPosts Simeon Tegel explains, in some cases passengers risk crossing paths with violent criminals who carry out what is known as an express kidnappings:
Mexico City is perhaps the world capital of this kind of crime, and no self-respecting guidebook fails to warn of the danger. Passengers are taken at gunpoint on a forced ATM tour.
The battle between taxi drivers and Uber isnt exclusive to Latin America  its a face-off taking place around the world . Well see if Mexico City becomes the next place to crackdown on the ride sharing app.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:14:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Etiwanda High softball player fights for her life after aneurysm on the field</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/sports/20150526/etiwanda-high-softball-player-fights-for-her-life-after-aneurysm-on-the-field</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Softball
Etiwanda High softball player fights for her life after aneurysm on the field
California Thunder softball player Dana Housley, who just finished her freshman year at Etiwanda High School in Rancho Cucamonga, suffered from a brain aneurysm Saturday, May, 22, 2015, while at bat. She has been on life support since then. (Image from the #prayforDana GoFundMe page)
By Michelle Gardner , Inland Valley Daily Bulletin
Posted:
# Comments
Etiwanda High School freshman softball standout Dana Housley continues fighting for her life as friends, teammates and the softball community rally around her.
Dana sustained a brain aneurysm while at the plate to hit in the last inning of a travel ball game for the California Thunder on Saturday. Her condition has not changed.
Dana is in the ICU at Kaiser Hospital in Fontana.
The high school team is scheduled to play a second-round Division 1 playoff game at 3:15 today at Murrieta Valley. Coach Dave Masucci, also the schools athletic director, says the game is still on as of now.
Masucci said Sunday night the game would probably be played if Dana was still on life support but would probably be postponed if that were not the case. But being a holiday weekend, he had not been able to touch base with anyone from the opposing school or the CIF.
Masucci said if the game was moved to Wednesday, then if the Eagles won, he would ask that the next game be moved from Thursday to Friday.
Dana spent much of the season playing on the junior varsity team, but she had seen some time on the varsity and Masucci said he was planning on having her with the varsity for the postseason.
As of Tuesday morning, a GoFundMe account to help Housleys family had already generated more than $43,000 in contributions nationwide. More 1,000 people have donated in the day since the account was set up.
The response has been overwhelming, and we cannot thank everyone enough. There has been so much support, please know that we appreciate every ounce of it, wrote Valerie LeVier on the GoFundMe page.
There has also been an outpouring of support on social media for the family with classmates and players posting messages for Housley.
Todays the day. Pull through baby girl, you have God and the whole softball community on your side, @samanthaareanne tweeted on Tuesday.
And @gowiththeflo005 tweeted Sending love and prayers from #Chicago #PrayForDana #danasmiracle.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:34:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of killing wife in La Mirada arrested, returned to U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150526/man-accused-of-killing-wife-in-la-mirada-arrested-returned-to-us</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of killing wife in La Mirada arrested, returned to U.S.
By Ruby Gonzales , San Gabriel Valley Tribune
Posted:
# Comments
A man charged with the 1992 murder-for-hire of his 17-year-old wife at a La Mirada park was arrested by federal officers in Antigua and Barbuda and transported back to the United States, authorities confirmed Tuesday.
Morrad Ghonim, 42, was living in Antigua and Barbuda where he owns Ayoushe Beauty Supplies and Beyond Ltd. He married a former Miss Dominica.
I would say that Mr. Ghonim was returned to the U.S. on Saturday. He was returned not extradited, said Steadroy Benjamin,  attorney general for Antigua and Barbuda. Benjamin said there was a warrant issued by a superior court in Los Angeles County but didnt have details about the warrant.
Benjamin said officers with the U.S. Marshals Service accompanied Ghonim.
Benjamin declined to confirm media reports that Ghonim didnt have a work permit for Antigua and Barbuda and that his last extension was in 2012.
Its not clear where Ghonim is being held right now. His name doesnt appear in the federal inmate or Los Angeles County Sheriffs online booking system.
Ghonim called his current wife Nadira Lando-Ghonim and told her that he has not been charged with any offence, according to The Daily Observer in Antigua and Barbuda.
He said he was being questioned about the incident but was unaware of any official charges, Lando-Ghonim told the Daily Observer.
But Ricardo Santiago, a spokesman for the Los Angeles County District Attorneys Office, said prosecutors on April 17 charged Ghonim with the July 23, 1992 murder of Victoria Ghonim.
The prosecution also alleged that Ghonim solicited the murder of Victoria Ghonim and that he killed her by means of lying in wait. It is also alleged that a handgun was used to commit the crime.
Santiago said there is currently no date for the arraignment. Ghonim is not in Los Angeles County yet, he added.
Ghonims arrest comes two months after a jury convicted Leon Martinez of Yucaipa for being the hit man in the murder.
Martinez, who will be sentenced Sept. 16, was hired for $500 to kill Victoria Ghonim, said Deputy District Attorney Robert Villa who prosecuted Martinez.
The prosecutor alleged that Ghonim hatched the plan. Ghonim was arrested before for the fatal shooting but was later released.
Advertisement
On July 23, 1992, Ghonim, Victoria Ghonim and their baby were in a car at Creek Park, 12021 Santa Gertrudes Ave. when Martinez walked up to the vehicle, tried to rob them and shot her several times.
Villa said Victoria Ghonim pleaded with Martinez not to kill her baby as shes being shot.
The killing was a cold case until 2009.
Villa said DNA on clothes left behind by the shooter matched that of Martinez, who was in prison on an unrelated case in San Bernardino County.
About the Author
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Egypt's military government has started executing people on overtly political charges</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150526/egypts-military-government-has-started-executing-people-on-overtly-political-charges/1</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Egypts military government has started executing people on overtly political charges
The Muslim Brotherhood's Safwat Hegazy (C) shouts from behind the defendants' cage as a judge reads out the verdict sentencing him and more than 100 other defendants to death on May 16, 2015 at the police academy in Cairo. (KHALED DESOUKI/AFP/Getty Images)
By Laura Dean, GlobalPost
# Comments
CAIRO, Egypt  Next Tuesday, a lawyer will plead for a Cairo court to suspend the execution of six men, arguing that their death sentences were unconstitutional. The only trouble is, the defendants are already dead.
Since the coup that swept Muslim Brotherhood President Mohamed Morsi from power, hundreds of his supporters have been handed death sentences in a rash of mass trials. But until this month, only one had been carried out  against a man convicted of throwing another man off a roof.
A little over a week ago, however, six men sentenced to death by a military court were executed on charges of belonging to militant group Ansar Beit al-Maqdis and attacking security forces.
The day before, a Cairo court sentenced ousted president Morsi and 120 others to death on charges related to a mass prison break during the 2011 uprisings. Some were sentenced in absentia, including Sondos Asem, a young Oxford University student who used to work as a media coordinator for Morsi, and Emad Shahin, a well-known professor at the American University in Cairo.
The six executions of political opponents mark the first overtly political killings ordered under Abdel Fattah el-Sisis leadership. They recall other killings of political opposition figures after violent power shifts  Iran in 1979, Liberia in 1980  but it remains to be seen how deep the similarities will go.
A key question now being debated: Will they really kill Morsi?
The precedent set by the court-ordered killings is already worrying monitors. Now that they have been executed this paves the way for other executions to take place, said Mohamed Elmessiry, Egypt researcher with Amnesty International.
It is a sign that some parts of the state are in a very bloody-minded mood; at times it seems as if there is a vendetta between parts of the state and an increasingly militant opposition, said Nathan Brown, professor of political science and international affairs at George Washington University.
In this case it appears that a serious miscarriage of justice took place. Three of the six convicted men have an alibi  they were already in prison on the dates they allegedly carried out their attacks on the army. Ahmed Helmy, a lawyer who represented the men, said the court seemed unwilling to listen to the evidence. The judge was shown official documents that proved that they were arrested before the crimes allegedly took place, he said. The documents included times and places of arrest and the fact that they were in Azouli prison, a military detention facility known for human rights abuses.
Advertisement
Helmy said the outcome of the trial seemed like a foregone conclusion from the start.
There is a sense that the sentences were already decided. The defendants told me not to bother [defending them]. They said, We know we will get the death penalty, dont trouble yourself. They knew this would happen, he said.
The whole trial was flawed, rights groups say. Elmessiry describes the proceedings as procedurally completely null and void because they were held in enforced disappearance [not official detention] and they were not held in an official place of detention. The civilian defendants were also tried in a military court. The administrative case on June 2 will challenge the sentences on these grounds.
Helmy sees the executions as a warning to those still in jail.
It was a kind of threat  they will apply this sentence to scare the other prisoners into negotiating with them and solving the crisis.
What do Egypts friends have to say?
The United States gave a milquetoast response to Morsis death sentence, saying they were deeply concerned  a sentiment that didnt get in the way of a meeting in Cairo last Wednesday between General Lloyd James Austin, the head of US Central Command, and Sisi. The presidency said the two men were talking about counterterrorism efforts.
I think Western actors  the Europeans and the US  have essentially come to terms with the fact that the new Egyptian regime is following a repressive path, said Brown. He added that it is unlikely to pose a serious barrier to relations.
But if politically motivated death sentences continue  and particularly, if Morsi does end up being executed  the US and other Western governments who have supported the Sisi government will have some explaining to do.
If the Egyptian government actually executed all those who have death sentences passed on them, the bloodletting would be hard to ignore. I think it would lead to a bit of international isolation, Brown said. If instead we see selected executions it will lead to more tension in their relationship but will not completely disrupt it.
Already, Egypts increasingly poor record on human rights is causing Cairo to lose friends in some European capitals. The president of the German parliament canceled a June meeting with Sisi, citing human rights abuses and lack of parliamentary elections in Egypt. Egypt, meanwhile, denied that it had requested a meeting in the first place.
What weve seen from the West is disappointing but expected, said Sarah Leah Whitson, head of the Middle East division at Human Rights Watch. The Obama administration has routinely set aside the rights of Egyptian citizens in favor of its so-called strategic interests in Egypt, she said.
That doesnt mean US officials arent keeping an eye on the Egyptian judiciary, however.
I think a lot of diplomats are waiting to see whether the Court of Cassation [the final line of legal appeal] continues to function as a pressure valve or whether it begins finalizing the hundreds of preliminary death sentences currently before it, Whitson said.
Helmy said it is too soon to tell what will happen in those cases. But he doesnt think the former president will actually be executed.
I dont expect they will carry out Morsis sentence. They want to negotiate with the Muslim Brotherhood and they dont need to kill him now, he said.
What will happen in Egypts courts is increasingly difficult to predict. Under former president Hosni Mubarak there were sometimes faulty sentences, but usually not in cases carrying the death penalty, Helmy said.
Now you have the feeling that the whole system is lost, that the sentences comes from above and are already decided.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Egypt's military government has started executing people on overtly political charges</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150526/egypts-military-government-has-started-executing-people-on-overtly-political-charges</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Egypts military government has started executing people on overtly political charges
The Muslim Brotherhood's Safwat Hegazy (C) shouts from behind the defendants' cage as a judge reads out the verdict sentencing him and more than 100 other defendants to death on May 16, 2015 at the police academy in Cairo. (KHALED DESOUKI/AFP/Getty Images)
By Laura Dean, GlobalPost
# Comments
CAIRO, Egypt  Next Tuesday, a lawyer will plead for a Cairo court to suspend the execution of six men, arguing that their death sentences were unconstitutional. The only trouble is, the defendants are already dead.
Since the coup that swept Muslim Brotherhood President Mohamed Morsi from power, hundreds of his supporters have been handed death sentences in a rash of mass trials. But until this month, only one had been carried out  against a man convicted of throwing another man off a roof.
A little over a week ago, however, six men sentenced to death by a military court were executed on charges of belonging to militant group Ansar Beit al-Maqdis and attacking security forces.
The day before, a Cairo court sentenced ousted president Morsi and 120 others to death on charges related to a mass prison break during the 2011 uprisings. Some were sentenced in absentia, including Sondos Asem, a young Oxford University student who used to work as a media coordinator for Morsi, and Emad Shahin, a well-known professor at the American University in Cairo.
The six executions of political opponents mark the first overtly political killings ordered under Abdel Fattah el-Sisis leadership. They recall other killings of political opposition figures after violent power shifts  Iran in 1979, Liberia in 1980  but it remains to be seen how deep the similarities will go.
A key question now being debated: Will they really kill Morsi?
The precedent set by the court-ordered killings is already worrying monitors. Now that they have been executed this paves the way for other executions to take place, said Mohamed Elmessiry, Egypt researcher with Amnesty International.
It is a sign that some parts of the state are in a very bloody-minded mood; at times it seems as if there is a vendetta between parts of the state and an increasingly militant opposition, said Nathan Brown, professor of political science and international affairs at George Washington University.
In this case it appears that a serious miscarriage of justice took place. Three of the six convicted men have an alibi  they were already in prison on the dates they allegedly carried out their attacks on the army. Ahmed Helmy, a lawyer who represented the men, said the court seemed unwilling to listen to the evidence. The judge was shown official documents that proved that they were arrested before the crimes allegedly took place, he said. The documents included times and places of arrest and the fact that they were in Azouli prison, a military detention facility known for human rights abuses.
Advertisement
Helmy said the outcome of the trial seemed like a foregone conclusion from the start.
There is a sense that the sentences were already decided. The defendants told me not to bother [defending them]. They said, We know we will get the death penalty, dont trouble yourself. They knew this would happen, he said.
The whole trial was flawed, rights groups say. Elmessiry describes the proceedings as procedurally completely null and void because they were held in enforced disappearance [not official detention] and they were not held in an official place of detention. The civilian defendants were also tried in a military court. The administrative case on June 2 will challenge the sentences on these grounds.
Helmy sees the executions as a warning to those still in jail.
It was a kind of threat  they will apply this sentence to scare the other prisoners into negotiating with them and solving the crisis.
What do Egypts friends have to say?
The United States gave a milquetoast response to Morsis death sentence, saying they were deeply concerned  a sentiment that didnt get in the way of a meeting in Cairo last Wednesday between General Lloyd James Austin, the head of US Central Command, and Sisi. The presidency said the two men were talking about counterterrorism efforts.
I think Western actors  the Europeans and the US  have essentially come to terms with the fact that the new Egyptian regime is following a repressive path, said Brown. He added that it is unlikely to pose a serious barrier to relations.
But if politically motivated death sentences continue  and particularly, if Morsi does end up being executed  the US and other Western governments who have supported the Sisi government will have some explaining to do.
If the Egyptian government actually executed all those who have death sentences passed on them, the bloodletting would be hard to ignore. I think it would lead to a bit of international isolation, Brown said. If instead we see selected executions it will lead to more tension in their relationship but will not completely disrupt it.
Already, Egypts increasingly poor record on human rights is causing Cairo to lose friends in some European capitals. The president of the German parliament canceled a June meeting with Sisi, citing human rights abuses and lack of parliamentary elections in Egypt. Egypt, meanwhile, denied that it had requested a meeting in the first place.
What weve seen from the West is disappointing but expected, said Sarah Leah Whitson, head of the Middle East division at Human Rights Watch. The Obama administration has routinely set aside the rights of Egyptian citizens in favor of its so-called strategic interests in Egypt, she said.
That doesnt mean US officials arent keeping an eye on the Egyptian judiciary, however.
I think a lot of diplomats are waiting to see whether the Court of Cassation [the final line of legal appeal] continues to function as a pressure valve or whether it begins finalizing the hundreds of preliminary death sentences currently before it, Whitson said.
Helmy said it is too soon to tell what will happen in those cases. But he doesnt think the former president will actually be executed.
I dont expect they will carry out Morsis sentence. They want to negotiate with the Muslim Brotherhood and they dont need to kill him now, he said.
What will happen in Egypts courts is increasingly difficult to predict. Under former president Hosni Mubarak there were sometimes faulty sentences, but usually not in cases carrying the death penalty, Helmy said.
Now you have the feeling that the whole system is lost, that the sentences comes from above and are already decided.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:15:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Central Basin Water District hires law firm that once employed Charles Calderon</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150526/central-basin-water-district-hires-law-firm-that-once-employed-charles-calderon</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMERCE &gt;&gt; Central Basin Municipal Water Districts Board of Directors voted 3-2 Tuesday to hire the law firm that once employed former state Sen. Charles Calderon.
Nossaman will replace Arnold Alvarez-Glassman, whose firm was hired on an interim basis in May 2014.
Alfred E. Smith, who works for Nossaman of Los Angeles, said that Calderon, who once was a partner for his firm, doesnt work for his company anymore.
Chuck Calderon worked at the firm 12 years ago, Smith said. There is no current relationship with the Calderon family and no intent to re-establish a relationship. That is a thing of the past.
Both of Calderons brothers faces federal charges.
Former Assemblyman Tom Calderon, D-Montebello had a $12,000 a month consulting contract with Central Basin until February 2013 but now faces federal charges of money laundering.
His brother, Ron, a former state senator from Montebello, faces bribery charges in a massive federal corruption case.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:09:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Faulty fan, smoke blamed in brief evacuation of U.S. Capitol</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150526/faulty-fan-smoke-blamed-in-brief-evacuation-of-us-capitol</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Faulty fan, smoke blamed in brief evacuation of U.S. Capitol
By Alan Fram, The Associated Press
Posted:
WASHINGTON &gt;&gt; Police briefly evacuated hundreds of workers and tourists from the U.S. Capitol and its adjacent visitors center on Tuesday in a problem officials tentatively blamed on a faulty exhaust fan in a visitor center kitchen.
Within an hour after alarms sounded, employees returned to the building. Tourists were readmitted shortly after that.
Lawmakers are in recess this week for the weeklong Memorial Day break.
The U.S. Capitol Police told congressional workers in an email that two alarms were triggered in the visitors center, which they said was apparently caused by a known problem with environmental controls with the kitchen exhaust fan. It provided no additional detail.
Kimberly Schneider, a Capitol Police spokeswoman, said there were no signs of smoke or fire. An email sent later to House staff by the chambers sergeant at arms office said the triggering of alarms was most likely caused by smoke in the kitchen; there was no fire.
The evacuation occurred two days after a bomb squad destroyed a pressure cooker found in an unattended, suspicious vehicle on the National Mall near the Capitol and the vehicles Virginia owner was arrested. Almost six weeks earlier, a Florida man was arrested after he flew his gyrocopter through restricted air space and onto the Capitol grounds.
In Tuesdays incident, police cleared the East Lawn and closed First Street between the Capitol and the Library of Congress until the buildings were reopened.
Denise Grandits of Buffalo, New York, said she and 70 eighth-graders were touring the Capitol and heard the alarms. She said the guide escorted them out of the building.
We just walked. It was pretty calm, she said.
According to the police email, officials initially thought one of the two triggered alarms was in the Capitol and they began evacuating that building.
In a moment of confusion, police soon advised people in the Capitol that they could remain inside because the alarms were not coming from that building. They reversed themselves again minutes later and resumed evacuating the Capitol.
The police email said once officials determined both alarms were in the visitor center, they decided to continue emptying the Capitol to ensure staff and members did not receive conflicting information.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:56:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Broken piece of pipeline responsible for Santa Barbara oil spill to be removed, inspected</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150526/broken-piece-of-pipeline-responsible-for-santa-barbara-oil-spill-to-be-removed-inspected</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Oil spills
Broken piece of pipeline responsible for Santa Barbara oil spill to be removed, inspected
Plastic buckets with oil collected from the beach are placed at the side at Refugio State Beach, north of Goleta, Calif., Thursday, May 21, 2015. More than 7,700 gallons of oil has been raked, skimmed and vacuumed from a spill that stretched across 9 miles of California coast, just a fraction of the sticky, stinking goo that escaped from a broken pipeline, officials said. (AP Photo/Jae C. Hong)
By The Associated Press
# Comments
A worker removes oil from the beach at Refugio State Beach, north of Goleta, Calif., Thursday, May 21, 2015. (AP Photo/Jae C. Hong)
GOLETA &gt;&gt; Officials from Plains All American Pipeline say they hope the broken section of a pipeline that spilled oil along the California Coast can be removed for investigation by Tuesday.
The company on Monday downgraded the amount of oil that may have spilled. The new estimate of the worst-case volume of oil released is 101,000 gallons. Thats about 4,200 gallons less than previously thought.
Plains All American is still measuring the spill as it cleans up along the Santa Barbara County coastline and recovers oil from the pipeline.
Oil blackened area beaches and created a 10-square-mile slick in the ocean after the onshore pipeline ruptured May 19.
Officials say one sea lion, nine pelicans and untold numbers of fish have been killed.
Two public beaches are closed until at least June 4.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:43:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hot Topic buying 'Star Wars'-heavy ThinkGeek parent company for $117.3 million</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/business/20150526/hot-topic-buying-star-wars-heavy-thinkgeek-parent-company-for-1173-million</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Mergers and acquisitions
Hot Topic buying Star Wars-heavy ThinkGeek parent company for $117.3 million
Clothing retailer Hot Topic is buying Geeknet, the parent company of ThinkGeek, which sells clothing, toys and gadgets based on such popular media properties and brands as "Star Wars," Minecraft and "The Big Bang Theory." (Image fom the ThinkGeek web site)
By The Associated Press
# Comments
LOS ANGELES &gt;&gt; The retailer Hot Topic is buying the parent company of Think Geek and ThinkGeek Solutions for about $117.3 million.
ThinkGeek sells clothing, toys, gadgets and other products mostly based on popular movies, television shows and brands with geek appeal. That includes Star Trek, The Big Bang Theory, Star Wars and the Marvel brand.
ThinkGeek Solutions is a distributor of video-game themed merchandise through licensed web stores.
Hot Topic Inc. will pay $17.50 per Geeknet share. Thats more than double the companys Friday closing price of $7.90.
The companies put the transactions total value at approximately $122 million.
Shares of Geeknet Inc., which is based in Fairfax, Virginia, more than doubled, rising $9.19 to $17.09 on morning trading Tuesday.
Privately held Hot Topic, based in Los Angeles, has more than 650 stores in the U.S. and Canada. Geeknet will become a Hot Topic subsidiary.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:25:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lee's Sandwiches recalls 213,000 pounds of meat</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/health/20150526/lees-sandwiches-recalls-213000-pounds-of-meat</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Lees Sandwiches recalls 213,000 pounds of meat
By The Associated Press
# Comments
SANTA ANA, Calif.  Fast-food restaurant Lees Sandwiches has recalled 213,000 pounds of meat because it bore unauthorized United States Department of Agriculture marks of inspection, despite having not been inspected properly.
The Orange County Register reports that chicken, beef and pork products were recalled by the Garden Grove-based company from its restaurants in Arizona, California, Nevada, Oklahoma, Oregon and Texas.
There have been no reports of adverse reactions to eating any of the products.
USDA officials say the biggest quantities of recalled meat products were 62,000 pounds of pork pate chaud, 56,000 pounds of chicken pate chaud, 55,000 pounds of banh bao pork and egg steamed bun, 23,000 pounds of sliced oil browned turkey and 15,000 pounds of bahn boa trung cut pork and quail egg steamed bun.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:22:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taco Bell, Pizza Hut: Artificial ingredients getting booted</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/business/20150526/taco-bell-pizza-hut-artificial-ingredients-getting-booted</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Fast food restaurant operators
Taco Bell, Pizza Hut: Artificial ingredients getting booted
Taco Bell and Pizza Hut say theyre getting rid of artificial colors and flavors, making them the latest big food companies scrambling to distance themselves from ingredients people might find unappetizing. Gene J. Puskar  The Associated Press file
By Candice Choi, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; Taco Bell and Pizza Hut say theyre getting rid of artificial colors and flavors, making them the latest big food companies scrambling to distance themselves from ingredients people might find unappetizing.
Instead of black pepper flavor, for instance, Taco Bell will start using actual black pepper in its seasoned beef, says Liz Matthews, the chains chief food innovation officer.
The Mexican-style chain also says the artificial dye Yellow No. 6 will be removed from its nacho cheese, Blue No. 1 will be removed from its avocado ranch dressing and carmine, a bright pigment, will be removed from its red tortilla strips.
Matthews said some of the new recipes are being tested in select markets and should be in stores nationally by the end of the year.
The countrys biggest food makers are facing pressure from smaller rivals that position themselves as more wholesome alternatives. Chipotle in particular has found success in marketing itself as an antidote to traditional fast food. In April, Chipotle announced it had removed genetically modified organisms from its food, even though the Food and Drug Administration says GMOs are safe.
Critics say the purging of chemicals is a response to unfounded fears over ingredients, but companies are nevertheless rushing to ensure their recipes dont become disadvantages. In recent months, restaurant chains including Panera, McDonalds and Subway have said theyre switching recipes for one or more products to use ingredients people can more easily recognize.
John Coupland, a professor of food science at Penn State University, said companies are realizing some ingredients may not be worth the potential harm they might cause to their images, given changing attitudes about additives.
Additionally, he noted that the removal of artificial ingredients can be a way for companies to give their food a healthy glow without making meaningful changes to their nutritional profiles. For instance, Coupland said reducing salt, sugar or portion sizes would have a far bigger impact on public health.
Taco Bell and Pizza Hut are owned by Yum Brands Inc., which had hinted the changes would be on the way. At a conference for investors late last year, Yum CEO Greg Creed referred to the shifting attitudes and the desire for real food as a revolution in the industry.
Advertisement
Representatives at KFC and Yums corporate headquarters in Louisville, Kentucky were not immediately available to comment on whether the fried chicken chain would also be removing artificial ingredients.
Pizza Hut says it will remove artificial flavors and colors by the end of July. It said it will start listing all it ingredients online once the changes are completed.
Taco Bell says it will take out artificial colors, artificial flavors, high-fructose corn syrup and unsustainable palm oil from its food by the end of 2015. It says artificial preservatives will be removed where possible by 2017. The moves do not affect fountain drinks or co-branded products, such as its Doritos-flavored taco shells.
Brian Niccol, the chains CEO, said the company would work to keep its menu affordable.
I do not want to lose any element of being accessible to the masses, Niccol said.
When asked whether the changes would affect taste, a representative for Taco Bell said in an email that It will be the same great tasting Taco Bell that people love.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue May 26 17:12:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charter to buy Time Warner Cable for $55.3 billion in wake of failed Comcast bid</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/business/20150526/charter-to-buy-time-warner-cable-for-553-billion-in-wake-of-failed-comcast-bid</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Mergers and acquisitions
Charter to buy Time Warner Cable for $55.3 billion in wake of failed Comcast bid
Time Warner Cable rejected a $38 billion hostile offer from Charter Communications in early 2014, but now appears poised to accept a $55.3 billion offer. Mark Lennihan  The Associated Press (file)
By Tali Arbel, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
John Malones Liberty Broadcast Corp., which owns more than a quarter of Charter Communicationss stock, is backing the Time Warner Cable acquisition, which puts Charter in the same league as Comcast. Jeff Roberson  The Associated Press (File)
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; As TV watchers increasingly look online for their fix, cable companies are bulking up. In the latest round, Charter Communications is buying Time Warner Cable for $55.33 billion.
And executives say theyre confident regulators will allow the creation of another U.S. TV and Internet giant.
The deal comes a month after Comcast, the countrys largest cable provider and owner of NBCUniversal, walked away from a $45.2 billion bid for Time Warner Cable, the No. 2 cable company, after intense pressure from regulators. The government worried that the company would be able to undermine increasingly popular online video competitors like Netflix because the bigger Comcast would have more than half the countrys high-speed Internet customers.
There has been a wave in consolidation in the cable industry as providers are starting to lose TV subscribers, costs for TV, sports and movies rise and pressure from online video services such as Netflix and Hulu increases. The traditional cable ecosystem is breaking up  for example, you can subscribe to HBO online without having to pay for cable, or pay for a smaller group of channels that you watch via a Sony PlayStation.
Getting bigger is one way to deal with those changes. It gives cable providers more lucrative Internet subscribers and more leverage against entertainment companies providing the channels.
Whether government regulators will approve the Charter deal after quashing Comcasts bid for Time Warner Cable remains to be seen. Charter also announced Tuesday that it is buying Bright House Networks, a smaller cable provider, for $10.4 billion.
In a statement Tuesday, Federal Communications Commission Chairman Tom Wheeler said that the FCC weighs every merger on its own to see if it will be in the public interest, and that an absence of harm is not sufficient. He said the FCC will look to see how American consumers would benefit from the deal.
Charter notes that it will have less than 30 percent of the customers in the U.S. that the FCC defines as broadband: Those downloading at 25 megabit-per-second and faster. Comcast plus Time Warner Cable would have had more than half of those subscribers.
Were a very different company from Comcast and this is a very different transaction, said Charter CEO Tom Rutledge on a conference call Tuesday. Were confident its going to get done, said Time Warner Cable CEO Rob Marcus.
Charter, combined with Time Warner Cable and Bright House, will have nearly 24 million customers, compared with Comcasts 27.2 million. It will also lag AT&amp;T, whose pending deal with DirecTV would give it 26.4 million U.S. TV customers and 16.1 million fixed Internet customers as well as tens of millions of wireless customers.
Advertisement
One has to be sober about genuine risks that this deal could still be rejected, said MoffettNathansons Craig Moffett in a research note Tuesday, given the number of Internet and TV subscribers involved.
But it doesnt raise the same immediate concerns as the Comcast-Time Warner Cable merger, said John Bergmayer of Public Knowledge, a public interest group that had opposed the Comcast deal. The scale is totally different. Its not the No. 1 buying the No. 2, he said.
Another sign of confidence from the companies: The deal comes with a $2 billion break-up fee if it doesnt go through. If regulators dont approve it, Charter would pay Time Warner Cable; if Time Warner Cable kills the deal and goes with another buyer, itll pay.
John Malones Liberty Broadcast Corp., which owns more than a quarter of Charters stock, is backing the acquisition. Liberty Broadband is expected to own about 20 percent of the new Charter.
Charter Communications Inc., based in Stamford, Connecticut, will provide $100 in cash and shares of a new public parent company equal to 0.5409 shares of Charter for each outstanding Time Warner Cable Inc. share. The transaction values each Time Warner Cable share at about $195.71.
The companies on Tuesday valued New York-based Time Warner Cable at a total of $78.7 billion, including debt. They expect to complete the deal by the end of the year.
Time Warner Cable had chosen the Comcast deal and rejected a $38 billion hostile offer from Charter in early 2014.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
