<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="whittierdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:11:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tesla charges into home battery market despite challenges</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/technology/20150501/tesla-charges-into-home-battery-market-despite-challenges</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Technology
Tesla charges into home battery market despite challenges
Elon Musk, CEO of Tesla Motors Inc., unveils the companys newest product, Powerpack in Hawthorne, Calif., Thursday, April 30, 2015.  (AP Photo/Ringo H.W. Chiu)
By Michael Liedtke and Jonathan Fahey, AP Business Writers
Posted:
# Comments
FOSTER CITY, Calif. &gt;&gt; Tesla CEO Elon Musk is trying to steer his electric car companys battery technology into homes and businesses as part of an elaborate plan to reshape the power grid with millions of small power plants made of solar panels on roofs and batteries in garages.
Musk announced Teslas expansion into the home battery market amid a party atmosphere at the companys design studio near Los Angeles International Airport. The festive scene attended by a drink-toting crowd of enthusiasts seemed fitting for a flashy billionaire renowned for pursuing far-out projects. For instance, colonizing Mars is one of Musks goals at Space X, a rocket maker that he also runs.
Now, he is setting out on another ambitious mission. Our goal here is to fundamentally change the way the world uses energy, Musk told reporters gathered in Hawthorne, California.
Although Tesla will make the battery called Powerwall, it will be sold by a variety of other companies. The list of partners includes SolarCity, a solar installer founded by Musks cousins, Lyndon and Peter Rive. Musk is SolarCitys chairman and largest shareholder.
As with Teslas electric cars, which start around $70,000, the battery might be too expensive for most consumers. The system will carry a suggested price of $3,000 to $3,500, depending on the desired capacity. That could discourage widespread adoption, especially for a product that may only have limited use.
I dont believe this product in its first incarnation will be interesting to the average person, conceded Peter Rive, SolarCitys chief technology officer. Rive, though, still expects there to be enough demand to substantially increase the number of batteries in homes.
Musk is so encouraged by the initial demand that he believes Tesla and other future entrants in the market will be able to sell 2 billion battery packs around the world  roughly the same number of vehicles already on roads. Although that may sound like a super crazy goal, Musk insisted it is within the power of humanity to do.
It will take a long time to get there. Tesla hopes to begin shipping a limited number of Powerwall batteries this summer in the U.S. before expanding internationally next year.
The long-term goal is to reduce the worlds reliance on energy generate from fossil fuels while creating regional networks of home batteries that could be controlled as if they were a power plant. That would give utilities another way to ensure that they can provide power at times of peak demand.
For now, the battery primarily serves as an expensive backup system during blackouts for customers like David Cunningham, an aerospace engineer from Foster City, California. He installed a Tesla battery late last year to pair with his solar panels as part of a pilot program run by the California Public Utilities Commission to test home battery performance.
Advertisement
Although Cunninghams home has not endured a blackout in the six months that he has had the battery, its capable of running critical home appliances like lights and refrigeration and can be recharged by solar panels during the day.
As long as a person has solar panels, its just a natural fit for the two to go together, Cunningham, 77, said. I consider it to be a whole power system right here in my home.
Cunningham took advantage of state incentives that sharply reduced the batterys $18,300 sticker price under the pilot program. He still paid $7,500.
The value proposition now is around reliability and backup power more than it is around savings, but over time that may change, said Shayle Kahn, an analyst at GTM Research.
The batteries are likely to become more useful if, as expected, more utilities and regulators allow power prices to change throughout the day based on market conditions. That way, the software that controls the solar and battery system will allow customers to use their home-generated power  and not expensive grid power  when grid prices spike.
Many commercial customers already buy power this way, and Tesla also announced battery systems designed for them, along with bigger battery packs that utilities can use to manage their grids. Analysts say these utility and commercial markets will probably be more promising for Tesla during the next few years than residential customers.
Several businesses, including Amazon.com and Target, plan to use Teslas battery storage system on a limited basis. Southern California Edison is already using Tesla batteries to store energy.
Tesla is building a giant factory in Nevada that will begin churning out batteries in 2017, so Musk needs to begin drumming up customers now. The spotlight may help Musk push policy makers and utilities to consider reshaping regulations so solar and battery storage could be more easily incorporated into the larger electric system, Kahn said.
Teslas ambitions already have intrigued homeowners like Mike Thielen, who installed one of the prototype batteries with SolarCity panels on his Redondo Beach, California, home last year. Although he hasnt needed the backup power yet, he has embraced the concept.
I think its brilliant, he said. I would consider upgrading to a more powerful home battery if they could figure out a way to get me totally off the grid.
___
Fahey reported from New York and Houston. AP Writer Justin Pritchard contributed to this story from Hawthorne, California.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:03:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sherpas face uncertain future following Mount Everest avalanche</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150501/sherpas-face-uncertain-future-following-mount-everest-avalanche</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Earthquakes
Sherpas face uncertain future following Mount Everest avalanche
FILE - In this May 16, 2013 file photo, Nepalese Sherpas rest as they climb Mount Everest. The abrupt ending of the climbing season on Mount Everests north and south sides following a deadly earthquake will be a severe blow to the Sherpas in the region, who will not receive their daily pay or highly-anticipated bonuses for helping people scale the world's tallest peak. (AP Photo/ Pasang Geljen Sherpa, File)
By Martha Bellisle and Binaj Gurubacharya, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
SEATTLE &gt;&gt; Mount Everest is normally buzzing with activity this time of year, with hundreds of hopeful climbers gathering at base camp to attempt to summit the worlds tallest peak during a narrow 10-day window in May before the monsoons arrive.
It is also the most lucrative season for Sherpas, the locals living in the high-altitude regions of the Himalaya who support climbing teams as porters, guides, rope-fixers, cooks and dish-washers.
But Everest is basically closed after a magnitude-7.8 quake triggered a massive avalanche that killed 19 at basecamp and more than 5,800 people throughout the country. China said Wednesday it was ending the climbing season early on the Tibet side, and most major mountaineering companies on the Nepal side canceled their climbs because of logistical challenges and safety concerns.
That leaves Sherpas, who can earn up to $5,000 to $7,000, plus bonuses and tips, during the three-month climbing season, wondering how theyll make up that lost revenue in a country where the per capita income is about $730 annually. Cooks and other support personnel earn about half as much, but still well above the average pay in the country.
Ang Tshering Sherpa, president of Nepal Mountaineering Association, an umbrella body of mountaineering agencies and climbers in Nepal, said Sherpas are worried the season may be over. While many Sherpas sign contracts that will still have to be paid, theyll miss out on day rates and bonuses.
Steve Mock, director a climbing school for Nepali called the Khumbu Climbing Center, said the lower incomes also mean Sherpas now have less money to rebuild their homes.
Insurance for that sort of thing is simply not available in Nepal so rebuilding costs come directly out of pocket, he said. Many save up money from working on Everest for years in order to build a decent house that may well have been destroyed or at least damaged by the quake. So financially, this is simply devastating.
The financial burden could spread beyond just the Sherpas. Everest is a major economic driver for the country, which receives more than $3.5 million from Everest climbing permits annually, said Conrad Anker of Bozeman, Montana, who has climbed Everest three times.
Climbing permits run about $11,000 per person for climbing Everest from the Nepal side and $7,000 per person on the Tibet side, and hundreds are sold each year.
The climbing season runs from March to June.
A few teams are trying to find a way to salvage the season, and some Sherpas would welcome the work.
Kapindra Rai of the Sagarmatha Pollution Control Committee, which is in charge of the route through the treacherous Khumbu Icefall on the Nepal side, said staff descended from base camp because two of their cooks were injured, they lost their equipment and many wanted to be with their families.
Advertisement
But they were ready to return if any expedition asks, Rai said.
Adrian Ballinger, a guide with the California-based Alpenglow Expeditions, said although his Everest team had to call off their summit bid on the Tibet side, they are still paying their 12 Nepali Sherpas.
We are paying full wages minus summit bonuses, and a separate fund for home rebuilding, he said in a text message Thursday. We recognize this is their sole income.
Others in the international climbing community are raising funds to support the communities.
The Seattle-based Alpine Ascents International team is working its way back to Kathmandu and then home but they are leaving their climbing supplies behind for earthquake victims, said Gordon Janow.
The Alex Lowe Charitable Foundation, based in Bozeman, Montana, said on its website that it is accepting donations to be given to climbing communities of Nepal. The American Himalayan Foundation is also collecting donations for earthquake support.
The quake has once again raised questions about whether the mountain, with a storied history of dramatic accidents and high death rates, can be climbed safely. The catastrophe came almost a year after a block of ice triggered an avalanche that struck the Khumbu Icefall just above base camp on April 18, 2014, killing 16 Sherpas.
The bigger question is, what are peoples perspectives of the mountain going to be now? Are people going to want to climb Everest? asked Peter Athans, a Washington state climber who has been on 14 Everest expeditions.
The future is very uncertain.
_______________
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:08:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore gangs agree to truce similar to one during 1992 riots in L.A.</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/social-affairs/20150430/baltimore-gangs-agree-to-truce-similar-to-one-during-1992-riots-in-la</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody># Comments
Protesters look on during a rally in Baltimore, Maryland, on April 25, 2015, against the death of Freddie Gray while in police custody. Organizers anticipated the biggest outpouring of public anger since Gray, 25, was arrested on April 12, only to die in a coma seven days later from severe spinal injuries.   AFP PHOTO / ANDREW CABALLERO-REYNOLDS        (Photo credit should read Andrew Caballero-Reynolds/AFP/Getty Images)
BALTIMORE &gt;&gt; Rival gang members walked side by side down Pennsylvania Avenue to their cars.
Not one menacing glare was exchanged by the dozens of gang members, despite a bloody feud between the crews that has raged for more than 40 years in cities across the country.
In the midst of historic civil unrest, some of Baltimores most violent residents have put aside their long-standing feud, at least for now.
I cant say how long the truce will last, but the church and the community have to continue to do the work to maintain peace, the Rev. Walter Sheppard Jr. of the Gospel Tabernacle Baptist Church in Baltimore said Tuesday.
The Bloods and Crips, gangs whose origins and deadly rivalry stretch back to Southern California, struck a peace accord hours after the death of Freddie Gray was made public. Gray died of injuries suffered in police custody, and after his funeral riots exploded in the streets of Baltimore.
The deal the gangs have struck is simple: no violence between the rival cliques and no members are to take part in looting or rioting.
I believe its very encouraging any time young men can find common ground to form a unified front against police violence, said Najee Ali, a Los Angeles civil rights activist.
The agreement in Baltimore is similar to an accord made the day before Los Angeles erupted in violence in 1992 after a jury acquitted four Los Angeles Police Department officers in the beating of motorist Rodney King.
Despite the promises made by the gangs, a riot still broke out Monday along North Avenue in the heart of Baltimores impoverished west end. Looters set a fire that gutted a CVS drugstore, and when fire crews tried to extinguish the blaze, rioters cut the fire hoses, according to media reports. The looters pilfered goods from the Mondawmin Mall. Rioters clashed with police and vandalized a cruiser.
Its unclear how many gang members heeded the instructions of their leadership.
I believe the looting was done mostly by random youths, most of whom are not part of the gangs, Sheppard said.
Lower-ranking members, or soldiers for the gangs, said that if the gangs had joined the melee in full force, the destruction would have been worse.
People would have gotten hurt, had we come out in full force and rioted, said Gino, a Crips gang member, who would only go by his moniker out of fear of retaliation for talking to the press.
Advertisement
There have been 68 homicides in Baltimore since the beginning of the year. One death was reported in Baltimore on Monday, a 2-year-old girl who died of blunt force trauma.
On Tuesday night, the demonstrations in West Baltimore remained largely peaceful. The Bloods and Crips stood at the intersection of North and Pennsylvania avenues dressed in their respective gang colors, red and blue, forming a unified front against police violence. As the 10 p.m. curfew put in effect to curb violence approached, the rival gangs let out battle cries. But then, instead of violence, the Bloods and Crips made a slow retreat from the protest to their cars.
A fragile peace
West Baltimore is home to more than just the Bloods and Crips. Gangster Disciples and the Black Guerilla Family also populate the neighborhood. The truce was struck among all the gangs and started with meetings held by each respective set or gang on the day Grays death was announced.
We decided a week ago, every set in the city decided to not get involved unless it was for something positive. We decided we werent going to riot, said Shadow, a member of the Gangster Disciples, who works as a recovery counselor at Penn North Supportive Housing, a program based in West Baltimore a block from where the riots erupted.
On Monday, the gangs met at Shiloh Baptist Church also in West Baltimore to formalize the peace agreement. Crips and Bloods gang members stood side by side inside the church vowing not to attack each other.
The gang members came up to Shiloh Baptist Church to sit at the table because they believed the media scapegoated the gangs, Sheppard said, referring to reports on Monday that the gangs were planning an action against the cops.
More than 20 years ago, a similar set of events occurred the day before the  King case verdict. Gang members, anticipating riots, agreed to a truce. Inside Imperial Courts housing project in Watts, home to one of the largest and most lethal gangs in Los Angeles, the P.J. Watts Crips and the rival Bounty Hunter Bloods, from the neighboring Nickerson Gardens projects, agreed to meet. Under the leadership of Hall of Fame football player and activist Jim Brown and activist Aqeela Sherrills, a peace accord was established on April 28, 1992, according to Ali.
But the peace was fragile. The Rollin 60s, the 8-Trey Gangsters, the P-Stone Bloods  large and violent gangs in South Los Angeles  didnt sign the agreement.
People had survived multiple shootings and were angry and wanted to get revenge. But the spirit of unity, the need to get together, won over, Sherrills said.
The next day, April 29, 1992, riots swept across Los Angeles.
As in Baltimore, its unclear whether the agreement kept L.A. gang members out of the chaos that erupted the next day.
The peace between the rival gangs in Los Angeles didnt hold long. After the embers from the burned stores stopped smoldering, the Bloods and Crips resumed their decades-long war, with drive-bys and retaliation killings.
The main factor in ending the truce was economic  a lack of jobs. There was no political will to continue to empower the young men economically. Eventually, they returned to their old ways, Ali said.
Unlike the massive sprawl that defines Los Angeles, Baltimore is a much smaller city, 92 square miles. In West Baltimore, the Bloods and Crips operate only blocks apart. Maintaining peace in such a tightly confined space seems improbable, especially to the gang members on the front lines.
The truce is going to end, but when, I dont know. Itll continue as long as we are united against the cops and police brutality, Gino said.
Opportunity to rebuild
By Wednesday morning Baltimore residents had turned much of their attention to healing the wounds cut open by Grays death. Churches were set up on corners delivering prayers and messages of hope, community groups served meals and gave groceries to West Baltimores poor. And at least some of the anger directed at police began to shift to how West Baltimore can rebuild from the economic and civic tailspin it has been stuck in for decades.
Central to that recovery will be curbing gang violence.
In Baltimore, activists hope the peace established in recent days will offer them an opportunity to not just end gang violence but bring economic development to the community. Economics and gang violence in the city are tethered.
You have to make sure when people come to this neighborhood to shop or live, they dont get knocked upside the head, said Blaize Connelly-Duggan, executive director of Penn North Supporting Housing.
The task is tall.
While Maryland is the countrys richest state as measured by per capita income, West Baltimore suffers from high concentrations of extreme poverty. More than one in three of the residents living in the ZIP codes that make up West Baltimore are poor. One in six lives at or below 50 percent of the poverty line.
How do you rebuild a city that wasnt rebuilt after 1968 (when riots erupted in Baltimore), where there are so many poor people? Connelly-Duggan asked. Theres a lot of talk in Baltimore about the vacant houses that line the streets, but what we also have is vacant lives.
About the Author
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 10:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Clippers force Game 7 with 102-96 win over Spurs</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/sports/20150430/clippers-force-game-7-with-102-96-win-over-spurs</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody># Comments
San Antonio Spurs' Boris Diaw, left, and Los Angeles Clippers' Blake Griffin, right, eye a rebound during the second half of Game 6 in an NBA basketball first-round playoff series, Friday, May 1, 2015, in San Antonio. Los Angeles won 102-96. (AP Photo/Darren Abate)
SAN ANTONIO  Do or die. Win or go home. Wait til next year.
Whatever adage one desires, they were all applicable to the Los Angeles Clippers in Game 6 of their Western Conference first-round series against the San Antonio Spurs on Thursday night at AT&amp;T Center.
The Clippers entered down 3-2, largely because they couldnt finish Games 2 and 5 at Staples Center, where they lost by identical scores.
After a 27-8 run between the second and third quarters erased a 10-point deficit - setting the tone - the Clippers finished this one, defeating the Spurs 102-96, tying the what has been a spectacular series - a classic, if you will - 3-3 and sending it back to Staples Center for a Game 7 Saturday. Each team has won two games on the others court.
There were some clutch baskets that made it possible. One was a 3-pointer by J.J. Redick for a 92-86 lead. Another was a layup by Blake Griffin off an assist from Chris Paul, yet another was an 18-footer by Jamal Crawford. Paul chipped in with a 7-footer with 21 seconds left for a 98-93 lead. Marco Belinelli, who made 7 of 11 from 3-point range for the Spurs, made his final long-distance shot to get the Spurs within 98-96.
But when Crawford made two free throws with 10.1 seconds left, the Clippers led 100-96 and the Spurs were done.
Griffin led the Clippers with 26 points, 12 rebounds and six assists. Paul finished with 19 points and 15 assists. He had only four points at halftime - all on free throws - and had missed all seven of his shots. J.J. Redick also scored 19 and DeAndre Jordan scored 15 points with 14 rebounds. He was again victim of Hack-a-DJ, making 7 of 15 from the free-throw line. Belinelli led the Spurs with 23 points off the bench and Boris Diaw scored 17. Tim Duncan and Kawhi Leonard scored 12 points apiece with Duncan getting a team-high 13 rebounds.
I thought Blake Griffin and Chris Paul took the game over, Spurs coach Gregg Popovich said. We didnt stop them. They were tremendous.
Paul still didnt shoot well overall, finishing 7 of 21. But he made ones that counted.
I knew he didnt have any field goals from just being in the game, Redick said, when asked if he knew Paul had not made a field goal in the first half.
Weve got confidence in Chris, said Crawford, who scored 10 points. Hes one of the best players in the world. As long as he gets the shots he shoots every single night, theyll go in sometimes and sometimes they wont.
Advertisement
But we have confidence that the next one will go in. He does as well.
So, how did Paul get himself back into the game after halftime?
I didnt think about it, he said.
Crawford, who is in his 15th season and fifth postseason, is shaking his head at this series, where homecourt advantage hasnt meant much. He said hes never seen anything like it.
Not like this, this has been unbelievable, he said. Youre seeing high-level basketball right now.
Said Griffin: It has been entertaining.
Clippers coach Doc Rivers said he never could have imagined that after six games, each team would have gathered two victories away from home.
No, I did imagine it being seven (games), he said. The Spurs are probably excited to go to our place now. The way this series has turned out. ... Its a crazy series.
The Clippers shot 47.5 percent from the field, but just 22.2 percent (4 of 18) from 3-point range. The Spurs shot 43.4 percent, 42.9 (12 of 28) from beyond the arc.
The most noteworthy statistic of the game perhaps came from the scoreline of Leonard, who was hounded into a 3-for-15 shooting performance. Matt Barnes, who scored eight for the Clippers, talked about that.
Ive got two fouls in the first quarter every game, Barnes said, just ticky-tack stuff. So tonight the refs let me play. I was able to keep my body on him and be physical and it worked out.
Asked what he took from this game, a glum Leonard said, Just that we lost. Just regroup as a team and get ready for Game 7.
Duncan gave the Clippers all the credit.
They played better than us, he said. We werent consistent enough and they made shots down the stretch when we were trying to get back into it. Hats off to them in that respect. But now we have to go to L.A. and win a game.
Getting back to that aforementioned 27-8 run, it came at a time when it appeared the Spurs could blow out the Clippers. They led 45-35, their fans were going wild and instead of folding and being down by even more at halftime, the Clippers went into the break tied 51-51.
It was, Redick said, a big stretch.
About the Author
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 06:50:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thousands expected to march in May Day rallies in Los Angeles, Inland Empire</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/social-affairs/20150430/thousands-expected-to-march-in-may-day-rallies-in-los-angeles-inland-empire</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thousands expected to march in May Day rallies in Los Angeles, Inland Empire
By Brenda Gazzar , Los Angeles Daily News
Posted:
# Comments
Carolina Gallegos and her daughter Scarlett,4,  put together signs that will be carried during the march. Los Angeles May Day Coalition and volunteers made posters, signs and art as thousands prepare to march through the streets of Los Angeles for International Worker's Day, also known as May Day. Los Angeles, CA 4/30/2015 (Photo by John McCoy Daily News)
Carolina Moran was seven months pregnant when she walked for three days in the desert with two young daughters before sneaking across the U.S. border more than a decade ago in search of a better life.
So the Canoga Park resident was thrilled when she found out late last year that as parents of a U.S. citizen, she and her husband would qualify under an executive order by President Obama to remain in the country and work for three years without being deported. But since a Texas judge placed a temporary hold on Obamas Deferred Action for Parental Accountability (DAPA) in February and with its fate up in the air, Moran says she and her family are still living in limbo.
We are afraid that immigration officials will come one day and grab us and separate the family, the mother of five said in Spanish Thursday.
Moran is one of thousands of immigrants, civil rights activists, laborers and clergy who plan to march Friday on May Day or International Workers Day through the streets of Los Angeles and Murrieta calling for No Justice Delayed. Activists are demanding immediate implementation of Obamas recent executive orders that would temporarily shield from deportation more than 4 million undocumented persons out of some 11 million estimated to be living in the country. The presidents second executive order, which is also on hold by the court injunction, would expand the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) program that temporarily shields from deportation certain undocumented youth and young adults who came to the U.S. as children.
Morans three adult children are currently protected under the DACA program, but she longs to see a path to citizenship for all undocumented immigrants  a permanent solution, she said.
All of us are human beings and we have rights and all of us have to work, Moran, 41, said. Without a work permit here, one cannot advance.
On May Day, activists will also be calling for a $15-an-hour minimum wage for all of the nations workers and an end to police brutality, particularly when it comes to African Americans and immigrants, said Miguel Paredes, membership coordinator for the Coalition for Humane Immigrant Rights of Los Angeles and a member of the Los Angeles May Day Coalition.
The May Day rally in L.A. will begin at 3:15 p.m. at the Dragons Gate in Chinatown with the march beginning about 3:45 p.m. This year, an Immigrant Families Resource Fair will take place at Grand Park on North Spring Street that will offer information on immigration, wage theft, fraud, criminal defense and housing attorneys.
International Workers Day is celebrated around the world and here in Los Angeles, weve celebrated May Day as an immigrant rights effort since 2006, Paredes said.
Massive protests were staged in Los Angeles and around the country on May 1, 2006, to protest a proposed U.S. House of Representatives bill that would have cracked down on undocumented immigrants and penalized those who help them. The bill died in the Senate.
Advertisement
On May Day in 2007, Los Angeles police officers used batons and rubber bullets to disperse a mostly peaceful gathering at an immigrant rights rally at MacArthur Park, which resulted in more than 250 reported injuries. An LAPD Police Commission report faulted inadequate planning and tactical failures for the melee, which authorities said was prompted by a small group of protesters throwing bottles and other objects.
In Murrieta, the Justice for Immigrants Coalition of Inland Southern California is hosting a march and rally from noon to 3 p.m. Friday starting at 1 Town Square and ending at 25762 Madison Ave. The event will support migration and family unity while calling for an end to local cooperation with Immigration and Customs Enforcement and Border Patrol, according to organizers.
But others say they will be placing the emphasis on American citizens this May Day. Robin Hvidston, executive director with the Claremont-based anti-immigration group We the People Rising, said she and members of her organization will be making phone calls Friday to federal elected officials as well as posting on social media to share their message.
Were calling on May Day to elected officials to say put American workers first, she said. They should be the focus of legislation. Not people here illegally. We have our own U.S. population, high unemployment of people looking for jobs as well as homeless. We have our veterans living in poverty.
Some members of her group will also be visiting the offices of their local Congress members, she said.
Maegan Ortiz, executive director of the Institute for Popular Education of Southern California, said she will be marching with day laborers to call attention to seven day labor centers funded by the city, including those in Van Nuys, North Hollywood and Wilmington, that are facing dramatic budget cuts, she said. The office of Los Angeles Mayor Eric Garcetti is proposing $250,000 in funds for the upcoming fiscal year, a steep decline from the $750,000 these day labor centers received this fiscal year, she said.
The city had to draw from its general fund this year to fund the day labor program to replace the loss of Community Development Block Grant federal dollars, a spokeswoman for the mayors office said.
Ortiz said the reduction would result in a significant staffing decrease and could cause some of the centers to close.
The day labor centers act as integration centers for the most vulnerable among immigrant populations, she said. The majority of these workers dont even qualify for DACA/DAPA. They come to these centers not just to get work. They are also offered (English as a Second Language) classes, potential safety and workplace training programs such as OSHA certification. ... They are capacity building centers.
Ahilan Arulanantham, the deputy legal director of the ACLU of Southern California, said he will be marching Friday to call attention to a variety of immigration issues, including the absence of legalization for undocumented immigrants, the overuse of detention of people and families who present no threat to the community or no flight risk and the fact that the government does not provide counsel to children and others who cannot represent themselves in deportation cases.
The movement toward legalization has to come through increased political pressure, and May Day is a manifestation of that, he said. Going back to 2006 ... the May Day rally was against a bill that would have criminalized just being undocumented. That rally really changed everything. People came out and it completely changed the optical discourse in Washington on the subject.
If you go
What: May Day march and rally in L.A.
When: 3:15 p.m. (rally), 3:45 march
Where: Dragons Gate in Chinatown, Cesar Chavez and Broadway
What: May Day march and rally in Murrieta
When: noon to 3 p.m.
Where: Starting at 1 Town Square
About the Author
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:24:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>California state senators' calendars should be released to the public, judge rules</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/social-affairs/20150430/california-state-senators-calendars-should-be-released-to-the-public-judge-rules</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Freedom of the press
California state senators calendars should be released to the public, judge rules
A judge issued a tentative ruling in a lawsuit filed by the Los Angeles News Group and the Bay Area News Group seeking the appointment calendars of state senators that include Ron Calderon, who was indicted by a federal grand jury on multiple political corruption charges, including mail and wire fraud, bribery and money laundering. (File photo by Rich Pedroncelli/Associated Press)
By Dakota Smith , Los Angeles Daily News
Posted:
# Comments
In a groundbreaking victory for open-government advocates, a Sacramento County Superior Court judge on Thursday ordered the state Senate and its leaders to turn over the appointment calendars and other records of two former state senators.
In a sweeping decision, Judge Michael Kenny tentatively ruled that the appointment books, meeting schedules and calendars of former Democratic Sens. Leland Yee and Ron Calderon requested by two news organizations are public records.
The Los Angeles News Group and its sister news organization the Bay Area News Group sued the state Senate last year over its refusal to release portions of the appointment calendars of the senators.
Senate leaders maintained the records were exempt under state open records law.
In his ruling, Kenny wrote that the public interest in the documents outweighs keeping them private.
The allegation of such wrongdoings created by the federal investigation is of a significant interest to the public. To the extent these alleged activities occurred under the guise of the legislators official duties is even more concerning, Kenny wrote.
This ruling, once final, will allow our journalists to more thoroughly investigate exactly with whom Sen. Calderon met on certain days and the nature of those meetings, said Michael A. Anastasi, vice president of news and executive editor of LANG, which includes this publication.
Peter Scheer, executive director at the First Amendment Coalition, a San Francisco-based non-profit dedicated to government accountability and free speech, said the Legislature has long fought to keep its records and calendars private. By contrast, governors and local city officials are expected to comply with public records requests, Scheer said.
Its an important decision, Scheer said of Thursdays ruling. The Legislature, under its own law, has up until now enjoyed complete immunity from public access.
The Senate Rules Committee, under the direction of Senate President Pro Tempore Darrell Steinberg, rejected a request from this news organization asking for the calendar entries of Calderon. The request was an attempt to find out with whom Calderon met on specific dates outlined in an FBI affidavit.
Secretary of the Senate Gregory Schmidt also rejected four requests from the Bay Area News Group to obtain calendar entries for Yee, who was federally charged with public corruption, racketeering and weapons trafficking.
Advertisement
Bob Pratt, counsel for the California State Legislature and the Senate leaders, didnt immediately respond.
LANG and BANG attorney Duffy Carolan predicted the court ruling would finally address the 1991 court ruling, Times Mirror Company v. Superior Court, in which the court blocked a request for five years of governor calendars. Over the years, the California Legislature has leaned on that ruling and rejected numerous news organization requests for records.
Thursdays ruling puts to rest the notion that public officials calendars are off limits, Carolan said.
Terry Francke, general counsel for Californians Aware, a state nonprofit that advocates for open government, cited a recent poll that found overwhelming support for more transparency in the Legislature.
Following Thursdays tentative ruling, Kenny will issue a final ruling. The next hearing is scheduled for this morning, Carolan said.
Calderon has pleaded not guilty to federal charges of accepting nearly $100,000 in cash bribes and other perks in exchange for political favors. He was snared in an FBI sting in which an undercover agent posed as a film executive.
The basis of Yees indictment  which involves his fundraiser Keith Jackson and former Chinatown gang leader Raymond Shrimp Boy Chow, among others  is also a months-long FBI sting operation involving interactions with undercover agents, many of which appear to have been recorded.
Both cases are set to go to trial this year.
About the Author
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:15:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Port of Los Angeles police chief indicted on tax evasion, corruption charges</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150430/port-of-los-angeles-police-chief-indicted-on-tax-evasion-corruption-charges</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Political corruption
Port of Los Angeles police chief indicted on tax evasion, corruption charges
Chief Ronald Boyd in front of the Port of Los Angeles police station. 2011 file photo. (Robert Casillas / Staff Photographer)
By Donna Littlejohn , The Whittier Daily News
and Larry Altman , The Whittier Daily News
Posted:
# Comments
A federal grand jury indicted Port of Los Angeles Police Chief Ronald Jerome Boyd on tax and corruption charges Thursday, alleging he plotted to steer a port contract to a software company developing a smartphone app that would deliver profits to him.
Boyd, 57, faces 16 counts accusing him of corruption, wire fraud, lying to FBI agents, failing to file federal corporate tax returns for his private security company and tax evasion, prosecutors said.
A Torrance resident, Boyd allegedly executed a scheme to defraud the citizens of the City of Los Angeles and the Harbor Department by taking bribes and kickbacks, and not disclosing his financial interest in the company developing the social networking app, the indictment said.
The scheme centered on an app called PortWatch, which was designed to provide information about the port and to allow the public to report crime there.
Prosecutors allege Boyd and two business partners formed BDB Digital Communications in 2011 and entered into an agreement with an unnamed company to develop PortWatch and share the profits.
BDB intended to make money by marketing and selling a similar app called Metrowatch to government agencies. The indictment alleges Boyd was to receive 13.3 percent of the revenue generated by MetroWatch throughout the United States.
At least two cities have learned of my concept and LOVE the idea!!! Boyd wrote in an email on Oct. 27, 2011. Especially the potential revenue split. It is a home run. ... Get a DIAMOND on that ring.
The agreement required Boyds help to secure the PortWatch contract for the unnamed company. For a year beginning in October 2011, Boyd held private meetings with the unnamed companys officials to disclose confidential information, met with the mayor and city attorney in Los Angeles, and monitored the apps development. He also urged the port to quickly issue a press release to announce the PortWatch app, and encouraged port employees to download it, authorities say.
The indictment does not name the company, but Ironroad USA, a social media and mobile marketing company based in Santa Monica and Stockholm, issued a press release on Oct. 12, 2012, announcing that the Port of Los Angeles had released the PortWatch app.
Ironroad won the contract allowing them to build the PortWatch app and analytics system several months ago and delivered the working system recently on all major device platforms, the release said.
In the release, Boyd called the PortWatch app the first of its kind nationally.
Advertisement
Our hope is that it will provide for a better means of disseminating critical information to our constituents and a more meaningful and speedy response to any reported incident, Boyd said.
The app allowed for video and text sharing, including emergency notifications, public relations, and security and public reporting of incidents.
The indictment alleges Boyd lied to FBI investigators in October when he denied having a financial interest in MetroWatch, when he said BDB was created to sell body armor, and when he said he was unaware of the revenue-sharing agreement between the unnamed company and BDB.
Boyd faces charges of making false statements, failing to file tax returns for his security business from 2008 to 2011, and tax evasion for failing to report income substantially greater than the amount stated on the return from 2007 through 2011, the indictment said.
If convicted, Boyd faces up to 124 years in federal prison. He is expected to surrender to federal authorities sometime next week.
The IRS and FBI conducted the investigation.
Port of Los Angeles Executive Director Gene Seroka said in a statement late Thursday that Boyd would be placed on administrative leave until further notice. Deputy Chief of Port Police Thomas Gazsi will assume Boyds responsibilities, Seroka said.
The city and Port of Los Angeles will fully cooperate in the investigation of this matter, Seroka said.
Boyd was appointed chief of the Los Angeles Port Police in November 2004 and was promoted in January to handle a second role as chief of emergency management at the port. He had served on the Port Police Department from 1982 to 1999 and then joined the police force at Los Angeles World Airports, where he became patrol services commander and assistant airport security coordinator.
He was hailed for his leadership qualities and strong law enforcement experience by port officials when he was appointed.
The Los Angeles Port Police Department is dedicated exclusively to port activities, enforcing all federal, state and local laws, including those related to cargo protection, pollution investigation, vessel traffic control and narcotics interdiction.
After the terrorist attacks of 9/11, Boyd was trained in tactical terrorist response with the FBI, U.S. Coast Guard, the Los Angeles Police Department, Los Angeles County Sheriffs Department and the California Highway Patrol.
In 2012, Boyd was one of three port officials named in a federal lawsuit filed by a Port Police officer alleging civil rights violations related to union activity.
About the Authors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 06:13:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jury rules CSU's 2009 tuition hike was proper, rejects class-action lawsuit</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150430/jury-rules-csus-2009-tuition-hike-was-proper-rejects-class-action-lawsuit</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Jury rules CSUs 2009 tuition hike was proper, rejects class-action lawsuit
By City News Service
# Comments
The Long Beach-based California State University system acted properly when it hiked tuition in 2009, despite claims by students that they were unfairly double-billed, a jury ruled Thursday.
A San Francisco Superior Court jury voted 9-3 in favor of the university, rejecting a class-action lawsuit that challenged the validity of the CSU Board of Trustees May 2009 vote to raise tuition by 10 percent in the face of state funding shortfalls.
Todays verdict affirms the California State Universitys commitment to student success and the fiscal stability of the university for future generations of Californians, said Framroze Virjee, CSU executive vice chancellor and general counsel. While raising tuition fees is always a decision of last resort, the CSU acted reasonably and responsibly to preserve academic programs and minimize disruption to students completing degree programs.
With the states reinvestment in the university, tuition fees have remained stable for the past four years, Virjee said. The CSU continues to offer one of the most affordable quality undergraduate degree programs in the nation.
Five students sued the CSU on behalf of about 200,000 students, contending the fall 2009 tuition hike was illegal because they had already paid their tuition for that semester.
The Board of Trustees voted on May 13, 2009 to boost tuition by 10 percent. CSU officials said the system was facing an unprecedented and devastating financial crisis at the time, notably in the face of back-to-back cuts in state funding.
In defending against the lawsuit, attorneys for the CSU argued that students were repeatedly warned that tuition and fees can change at any time.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 06:08:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New businesses, balancing budget among Azusa council's top priorities</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150430/new-businesses-balancing-budget-among-azusa-councils-top-priorities</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>New businesses, balancing budget among Azusa councils top priorities
By Melissa Masatani , San Gabriel Valley Tribune
Posted:
AZUSA&gt;&gt;Attracting new businesses and keeping a balanced budget are top two priorities for the next fiscal year, the City Council decided at its special meeting Monday.
The environment, planning, infrastructure and public services were the other top four objectives set by the council.
Now, staff is going to take those goals and develop objectives to implement those goals and that will help shape the budget for next year, City Manager Troy Butzlaff said.
The city will begin holding study sessions on the 2015-2016 fiscal budget by the end of May, he said.
The council hopes to attract a grocery store as part of business development while establishing a diverse and stable economic base that supports city revenues, goods, services and jobs for residents, the staff report stated.
Other priorities include working with the citys unions to reduce retirement and benefits costs; monitoring Vulcans mining activities and drought conditions; work with Rosedale to complete development obligations; enhance the citys public facilities; and explore a potential police substation on the southern edge of the city.
The citys department leaders also gave a presentation listing each staffs accomplishments from the last year and stated their goals for the next year.
The accomplishments ranged from the finance departments refunding of two bonds, saving the city almost $4 million to the improvement of six miles of aging sewer line from the public works department, while goals included setting up a nonprofit police foundation and finalizing a transit-oriented development plan for the city.
The council will have its next regular meeting at 7 p.m. Monday in council chambers. Agenda items include an agreement for the redesign of the citys website, a contract for a new city auditor and a musical tribute to Mothers Day.
About the Author
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 06:08:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>L.A. Zoo admission prices slated to rise under Mayor Eric Garcetti's budget</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/lifestyle/20150430/la-zoo-admission-prices-slated-to-rise-under-mayor-eric-garcettis-budget</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Zoological parks
L.A. Zoo admission prices slated to rise under Mayor Eric Garcettis budget
This 2010 file photo shows giraffes roaming around their enclosure at the L.A. Zoo. (Photo by John McCoy/Los Angeles Daily News/File)
By Dakota Smith , Los Angeles Daily News
Posted:
# Comments
Los Angeles Zoo admission prices will rise by $1 under Mayor Eric Garcettis proposed budget for the next fiscal year, with entry slated to hit $20 for adults and $15 for children.
Ticket prices have gone up by $1 every year for the last eight years, according to data provided by the City Administrative Office.
The Los Angeles City Council must sign off on Garcettis budget and is in the midst of hearings on the mayors fiscal plan.
At a budget meeting Wednesday, Los Angeles City Councilman Bob Blumenfield questioned raising zoo admission fees again and asked for a report back on how entry prices are affecting visitor numbers.
Were going to see more in revenue because people are paying more per ticket, Blumenfield told budget officials. But we may see a decrease in attendance because of that price.
Based on projected attendance, the $1 increase will bring in $857,000 in additional admissions revenue in 2015-16, budget officials said.
Zoo director John Lewis said in an email Wednesday the fee hike will help balance the facilitys proposed $19.7 million budget.
Mayoral spokeswoman Vicki Curry said the $1 increase was part of an 2013 agreement made between the zoo and the Greater Los Angeles Zoo Association, the nonprofit that fundraises for the facility.
Owned and operated by the city, the L.A. Zoo sits on 133 acres at the base of Griffith Park and receives more than 1.6 million visitors a year, according to facilitys website. Parking is free, but there are also paid preferential spots on select days.
The zoo has long been overshadowed by the popular San Diego Zoo, located 130 miles to the south.
In an effort to boost the L.A. Zoos popularity, the City Council last year signed off on a deal to allow GLAZA to market the zoo.
The San Diego Zoos admission rates are $48 for adults and $38 for children, a price that includes free tram rides and shows, according to the attractions website.
Visiting the Aquarium of the Pacific in Long Beach costs adults $28.95 and kids $14.95, while the Santa Barbara Zoo is $15 for adults and $10 for children.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 06:06:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>No suspects, no motive in fatal shooting of West Covina man</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150430/no-suspects-no-motive-in-fatal-shooting-of-west-covina-man</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>No suspects, no motive in fatal shooting of West Covina man
By Ruby Gonzales , San Gabriel Valley Tribune
Posted:
# Comments
WEST COVINA &gt;&gt; Police have no suspects and are trying to determine why a man was shot and killed in a West Covina parking lot Wednesday night.
Jabarri Rafael Butts, 36, died at the scene of the shooting, Los Angeles County Department of Coroner Lt. R. Hays said. He was listed at the coroners office as transient.
West Covina police Officer Brian Kearns said officers found the victim, later identified as Butts, lying in the parking lot outside a U.S. Social Security Administration building in the 500 block of South Vincent Avenue after a caller reported hearing shots in the 800 block of West Christopher Street at 9:46 p.m.
A scrap of yellow police tape lying next to a tree in the commercial strip was the only indication Thursday that police had been there.
Joel Louis, who lives nearby, was doing his homework and didnt hear gunfire. He said a friend, who is also a neighbor, called asking if he heard the shots then told him to come over.
The police were at my friends house, Louis said, adding that the parking lot is behind his friends backyard.
Louis looked over the wall and described seeing a black man with dreadlocks lying on his side with his legs crossed.
My friend mentioned seeing him a few times at a liquor store. And this guy would go to the liquor store and he would always be short (of money) for whatever he would buy, Louis said.
No one answered the door of the house where Louis friend lives.
Antonia Guerrero said her daughter was watching her house and heard nine gunshots Wednesday night.
I was coming home. My daughter called me. She said, Mom be careful,, Guerrero said. My granddaughter was really scared.
Anyone with information about the case is asked to call West Covina Police at 626 939-8500. Anonymous tipsters can call the WCPD hotline at 626-939-8688
About the Author
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:27:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Industry Mayor David Perez ordered City Hall to hire his company</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150430/former-industry-mayor-david-perez-ordered-city-hall-to-hire-his-company</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Former Industry Mayor David Perez ordered City Hall to hire his company
Dave Perez
By Frank Girardot , Pasadena Star-News
and Steve Scauzillo , San Gabriel Valley Tribune
Posted:
# Comments
Industry Investigation
The latest: Internal memo suggests former City of Industry Mayor David Perez had his company hired to do work without City Council approval. There is a process that we had and that process was not followed, City Manager Kevin Radecki said.
Homestead Museum:  After Perez suggested in 2009 the Workman-Temple Homestead needed to be fixed up, payments to his company for work at the site more than doubled.
Online: To read stories from our ongoing investigation into the City of Industry visit: whittierdailynews.com/topic/Industry-Audit
INDUSTRY &gt;&gt; Former Mayor David Perez and his associates ordered work at a city-owned property without the approval of the City Council and then collected on questionable invoices, according to documents obtained by this news organization.
An internal memo dated Aug. 7, 2014 and sent to City Manager Kevin Radecki by Robert Barron, facilities director of the Workman and Temple Family Homestead Museum, noted that work on the historic adobe began shortly after a March 2009 visit from Perez, who asked when the place was going to be fixed up.
Radecki said the memo highlights a practice that became commonplace during Perezs tenure as mayor of the east San Gabriel Valley city.
The Mayor is authorizing his own company to do that work, Radecki said. There is a process we had and that process was not followed.
A recent audit commissioned by the city, and obtained first by this news organization, found that more than $326 million was paid to companies owned by Perez or members of his family over the past 20 years. Much of the money went to vague or even erroneous invoices that possibly resulted in massive overpayments.
Supervisors Michael D. Antonovich and Hilda Solis have asked the Los Angeles County District Attorneys Office to convene a grand jury investigation.
During the 11 years from 2003 to 2014, city officials paid more than $2 million to Zerep, one of several shell companies set up by Perez and members of his family, for work at the Homestead Museum. About $1.7 million of that went to labor costs, according to the audit. Zerep is Perez spelled backward. A Perez-owned company called Municipal Maintenance also billed for work at the site.
Maintenance costs at the site rose dramatically from just under $100,000 in 2009 to about $377,000 in 2012, according to the audit. Perez was mayor from 2002 to 2012.
A list of the top 10 Zerep projects done for the city puts the Homestead Museum at No. 9, in dollars spent by the city. The city severed its contract with Zerep Management Corporation on Sept. 2.
Prior to that, Zerep submitted on average 681 invoices per year, equivalent to 57 invoices per month, or 13 invoices per week. The invoices submitted consistently lacked sufficient supporting documentation and/or adequate detailed description of the services performed, the KPMG audit found. Without detailed descriptions and supporting documentation, it would not be possible to determine whether the costs of services billed on the invoices are reasonable, accurate and commensurate with the work performed; and whether the services performed were permissible under the Contract and/or authorized by the City.
Advertisement
Barrons memo, not included in the KPMG audit document, notes work was done at the Homestead over a period of five years.
The memo also details how Vince Perez, a nephew of David Perez, was tasked with collecting $70,000 in August. When Vince Perez learned that the museum had no records that could verify a payment was owed, he asked Barron to create documentation validating the charges and request the invoices be paid.
Since I have not seen the billings, it is very difficult for me to validate any billings that have been issued, Barron wrote to Radecki.
Ultimately the city paid the $70,000, Barron said. An outside contractor performed interior work on the home as well, which is now open to the public. Between 2007 and 2011, Industry annually budgeted $1.5 million for upkeep at the site.
The Workman House is listed on both the California and National Register of Historic Places. Work done by Municipal Maintenance was interior renovation, Baron said. The museum also hired another contractor to do additional renovation work on the house.
About the Authors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:08:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First Bird LA Day celebrates Los Angeles' thriving environment for varied species</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/lifestyle/20150430/first-bird-la-day-celebrates-los-angeles-thriving-environment-for-varied-species</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody># Comments
More than 30 events will be held Saturday across the LA Basin in the first-ever Bird LA Day organized by Audobon California. A pair of Canada Geese at Madrona Marsh in Torrance. Chuck Bennett/Staff Photographer
It may seem counterintuitive in a seemingly concrete-encased county of 10 million people and more than 500 miles of freeways, but it turns out greater Los Angeles is literally for the birds.
The greater Los Angeles area is one of the best places for birds in the nation, said Garrison Frost, spokesman for Audubon California and a South Bay native.
You have almost every type of habitat there is all in one county  youve got beaches, wetlands, oak forests, deserts, rivers, streams, he added. Birds that migrate up and down the coast all stop in Los Angeles County. Its spring migration right now, so were seeing some amazing things.
On Saturday, the first Bird LA Day will celebrate those that take flight with a collection of 30 bird-watching events countywide.
A full listing is at www.birdladay.org . Most events are free, although some require preregistration. Participants are urged to submit photos to the Bird LA Facebook page and via tweets on Twitter using the hashtag #birdLADay .
We designed the day so theres something for everyone, said Susan Gottlieb, a board member of Audubon California. Serious birders can connect with like-minded environmentalists, while others might want to join a pop-up picnic or participate in a photo class to learn how to shoot nature and wildlife photography.
For example, you can get a secret National Park Service hand-drawn bird map of Los Angeles from noon to 4 p.m. Saturday at El Pueblo de Los Angeles Historical Monument and then go searching for Elysian Park raptor roosts or the massive colonies of swifts downtown.
Prefer a cocktail or local craft beer while taking in your views of nature?
From 3-7 p.m. Saturday, National Park Service bird experts, equipped with binoculars and a telescope, will be at two downtown bars and Angel City Brewing Co., in the arts district. And since Sunday is a full moon and some birds use stars to migrate at night, its possible to enjoy birds and beer late into the evening, too.
Lila Higgins, manager of citizen science at the Los Angeles County Natural History Museum and a member of an artists collective called Project 51: Play the LA River, will pull double duty Saturday.
That includes coordinating several bird-themed museum tours and an informal afternoon meet-and-greet by its resident rock star ornithologist Kimball Garrett, one of the go-to birders in L.A., she said.
Then at 3 p.m. she hosts a BYOB  Bring Your own Binoculars  Picnic hosted by Project 51 at the Los Angeles River Greenway Trail near Atwater Village.
Advertisement
A lot of people have this misconception that the entire 51 miles (of river) is like the concrete section you see in downtown Los Angeles, but thats not true, Higgins said. There is a huge amount of biodiversity. We have great blue herons and Ive seen osprey catching fish out of the river.
Historically, more than 520 bird species have been seen in the county.
In February, 816 bird enthusiasts submitted checklists identifying 258 species during the Great Backyard Bird Count, Frost said. No other county in the nation came close to that figure.
If you have a high diversity of species, regardless of population numbers, then you know you have a healthy habitat, said Tracy Drake, manager and naturalist at Torrances Madrona Marsh Nature Preserve , a remnant of the vernal marshes that once stretched across much of the Los Angeles Basin.
We experience between 45 and 70 bird species on any given day, she said. When we first started (habitat) restoration about 13 years ago we only experienced between 30 and 40.
The city-owned preserve will host talks and walks beginning at about 8:30 a.m. throughout the day so visitors can see the 30 resident ducklings there and other birds passing through.
Birds are the one thing that ties the entire Earth together, Drake said. There are no boundaries.
Which is just as true in decentralized Los Angeles County and a perfect metaphor for the event, Frost noted.
Los Angeles seems like a sprawling, disunited place, he said. Maybe we can come together over, of all the strange things, birds. Birds are the one form of wildlife everybody sees every day.
Bird LA Day seems to fit the personality of the city.
About the Author
Reporter covering Torrance, Lomita, Rolling Hills Estates and Palos Verdes Estates. Nick also covers soccer as a sports columnist. Reach the author at nick.green@dailybreeze.com or follow Nick on Twitter: @lasoccerblog @NickGreen007 .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 04:44:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Los Angeles County firefighters help rescue teen boy from Nepal earthquake rubble</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/general-news/20150430/los-angeles-county-firefighters-help-rescue-teen-boy-from-nepal-earthquake-rubble</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Earthquakes
Los Angeles County firefighters help rescue teen boy from Nepal earthquake rubble
Krishna Devi Khadka is carried on a stretcher after being rescued from a building that collapsed in Saturdays earthquake in Kathmandu, Nepal, Thursday, April 30, 2015. Police in Kathmandu confirmed that rescuers dug out Khadka, a woman in her 20s from the debris of Saturdays massive quake. (AP Photo/Bikram Rai)
By City News Service
# Comments
Krishna Devi Khadka is carried on a stretcher after being rescued from a building that collapsed in Saturdays earthquake in Kathmandu, Nepal, Thursday, April 30, 2015. Police in Kathmandu confirmed that rescuers dug out Khadka, a woman in her 20s from the debris of Saturdays massive quake. (AP Photo/Bikram Rai)
LOS ANGELES &gt;&gt; A 57-member task force of Los Angeles County firefighters helped rescue a teenage boy found buried in rubble in Nepal several days after a magnitude-7.8 earthquake devastated the Himalayan nation, killing at least 5,500 people.
The Los Angeles County Fire Departments California Task Force 2  known internationally as USA-2 Medium Search and Rescue Team and headquartered in the San Fernando Valley  took off for Nepal around 11:25 p.m. Sunday from March Air Reserve Base in Riverside County and arrived in Nepal on Tuesday.
USA-2 then began working along with a counterpart team from Fairfax County, Virginia, that is known as USA-1, said Los Angeles County fire Inspector Chris Reade.
On Wednesday, USA-1 team members heard voices in a rubble pile, and asked USA-2 personnel to assist, Reade said.
USA-2 members used a specialized camera system to find the teen, and emergency crews slowly and methodically brought him to safety, Reade said. The boys condition was not immediately known, Reade said, noting that communication in the remote area is very difficult.
Rescuers were continuing their efforts to locate any other possible survivors, Reade said.
Scores of people, including Santa Monica-based documentary filmmaker Tom Taplin, were killed in the earthquake, which struck just before noon local time Saturday  just before 11:15 p.m. Friday, California time.
USA-2 was notified Saturday by the United States Agency for International Development to gather its personnel and equipment and prepare for deployment.
Each member of the team has a specific area of expertise, including doctors, structure collapse experts, engineering specialists and dog handlers, but the majority are firefighter-paramedics.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 04:32:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dynamite left on old plane at LAX for 4 days after police training exercise, says official</title>
        <Link>http://www.whittierdailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150430/dynamite-left-on-old-plane-at-lax-for-4-days-after-police-training-exercise-says-official</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Dynamite left on old plane at LAX for 4 days after police training exercise, says official
By Tami Abdollah, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
LOS ANGELES  A law enforcement official at Los Angeles International Airport says a live stick of dynamite was accidentally left on an old plane at an airport museum for four days.
The official, who was briefed on the incident and spoke on the condition of anonymity because the person wasnt authorized to speak publicly, said workers on the tarmac found the dynamite Tuesday when they noticed the bright colors on the stick.
It was left behind after a Saturday evening training exercise for K9 officers and their dogs who work at the airport. Though live, the dynamite would have required a detonator or explosive to be set off.
Sgt. Belinda Joseph, a spokeswoman, said the object was a training aid and there was a certain amount of TNT contained in it but denied that it was a stick of dynamite.
She said airport police are investigating and have notified the Transportation Security Administration.
The stick was checked out from a TSA explosive storage container for training. Such trainings are done nearly daily, the official said.
TSA officials didnt immediately respond to a request for comment.
The stick of dynamite was left in a compartment underneath the Spirit of Seventy Six plane, the official said. The plane is featured at the Flight Path Learning Center and Museum on the airports southern edge.
The plane is outside the museum, which is run by volunteers and hosts school groups and other visitors.
Museum representatives did not immediately respond to a request for comment.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
