<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Yahoo">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:42:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nuke deal remains elusive after deadline, but talks continue</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/diplomatic-process-us-resolve-tested-nuke-deadline-nears-080613056--politics.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nuke deal remains elusive after deadline, but talks continue
By BRADLEY KLAPPER 47 minutes ago

Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears

Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
 Replay video
ShowBiz Minute: Weintraub, Cosby, Box Office

Spain&amp;#39;s Red Cross says one person was gored and six others injured as thousands of daredevils dashed alongside fighting bulls through the streets of Pamplona. The San Fermin Festival began on Tuesday. (July 7)
Load More
VIENNA (AP)  Iran nuclear talks busted through their second deadline in a week Tuesday, casting new questions about the ability of world powers to cut off all Iranian pathways to a bomb through diplomacy. But the parties agreed to continue their talks.
"We knew it would have been difficult, challenging, and sometimes hard," said Federica Mogherini, the European Union's foreign policy chief. Negotiations, she said, will continue for the next couple of days despite hitting some "tense" moments.
As the latest target date arrived for a deal setting a decade of restrictions on Iran's nuclear program, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry, Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif and other top diplomats huddled in Vienna in search of a breakthrough. All had spoken of deep differences remaining even after 11 days of discussions, and there was no public indication they had resolved disputes ranging from inspection rules on suspicious Iranian sites to limits on Tehran's research and development of advanced nuclear technology.
"The last, difficult, political issues, we have to solve," Mogherini said.
Diplomats extended their discussions by a week when they missed their goal of a pact by June 30, after passing previous deadlines in July 2014 and last November. For Kerry and his team, pressure is increasing from skeptical U.S. allies and members of Congress. If the accord isn't sent over to American lawmakers by Thursday, their month-long review period would be doubled to 60 days, hampering the ability of the Obama administration to offer speedy economic benefits to Iran for nuclear concessions.
In Tehran Tuesday, Iran's Atomic Energy Organization declared it had reached a "general understanding" in parallel talks with the U.N. nuclear agency on "joint cooperation." The Iranians have made similar claims previously, and it was unclear if any process was established for the International Atomic Energy Agency's long-stymied investigation of past nuclear weapons work by the Islamic Republic  a demand of Washington and its partners in negotiations in Austria's capital.
View gallery
European Union foreign affairs chief Federica Mogherini (left) and Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad
There, in a baroque, 19th-century palace, Kerry gathered early Tuesday with the foreign ministers of Britain, China, France, Germany and Russia. The larger group was to meet with Zarif at some point later in the day, with the clock ticking. Russia's Sergey Lavrov and China's Wang Yi were expected for a gathering of emerging economies in the Russian city of Ufa on Wednesday, and White House spokesman Josh Earnest said another prolongation of talks was "certainly possible."
The U.S. is in a tough spot. President Barack Obama has expended significant political capital on finalizing an agreement that has prompted suspicion from Iran's regional rival, Saudi Arabia, outright hostility from America's closest Mideast ally, Israel, and deep ambivalence even among Obama's Democratic allies in Congress. They're concerned that the accord would leave Iran's nuclear infrastructure largely intact and compel the West to provide the leading U.S.-designated state sponsor of terrorism with potentially hundreds of billions of dollars' worth of economic relief from international sanctions.
To ease their concerns, Obama and Kerry have vowed to hold out for a "good deal" that verifiably keeps Iran at least a year away from a nuclear weapons capability for at least a decade. Current intelligence estimates put the Iranians only two to three months away from amassing enough material for a nuclear warhead, if they pursued such a course. As part of the guarantee, the administration has repeatedly threatened to abandon negotiations if they prove fruitless or appear as an Iranian stall for time.
On-and-off talks with Tehran have been going on for more than a decade, though this incarnation has come closest to any resolution. The latest effort began in secret a couple of years ago and gained speed after the election of moderate-leaning Iranian President Hassan Rouhani in 2013. By November that year, Iran and the six world powers clinched an interim nuclear agreement and began the process for a comprehensive accord.
Over the weekend, a cautious Kerry told reporters that talks on the final package "could go either way."
View gallery
Workers construct a nuclear power plant in Bushehr, 1215 km (755 miles) south of Tehran, April 3, 20
"If we don't have a deal, if there's absolute intransigence, if there's an unwillingness to move on the things that are important, President Obama has always said we'll be prepared to walk away," Kerry said. "It's not what anybody wants. We want to get an agreement. But I've said from the moment I became involved in this we want a good agreement, only a good agreement, and we're not going to shave anywhere at the margins in order just to get an agreement."
Republicans hostile to compromise with Iran have been urging the U.S. to pull back from the talks. Their refrain for several months has been that Obama and Kerry want a deal more than the Iranians do, and have let red lines erode on Iranian enrichment capacity, inspections and providing limited sanctions relief. The president and his top advisers vehemently reject such claims.
Iran has its own red lines, defiantly outlined in recent weeks by Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, the nation's supreme leader. They include a quick easing of sanctions, and rejection of any inspections of military sites or interviews with Iranian nuclear scientists.
___
Associated Press writer George Jahn contributed.
John Kerry
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 08:25:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lawyers: Cosby's drugs-sex admission could help women's suit</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/lawyers-cosbys-drugs-sex-admission-could-help-womens-051603756.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>A Riverside County woman suing Bill Cosby for sexual battery allegedly tried to extort money in exchange for her silence, the comedian&amp;#39;s attorney says.
Load More
PHILADELPHIA (AP)  Bill Cosby's admission that he obtained quaaludes to give young women he was pursuing for sex could bolster defamation claims lodged by his accusers, the women's lawyers said after The Associated Press reported on newly released court documents.
Cosby in sworn testimony unsealed Monday admitted that he gave the now-banned sedative to at least one of his accusers and to unnamed others. His lawyer interfered before he could answer deposition questions in 2005 about how many women were given drugs and whether they knew about it.
"If today's report is true, Mr. Cosby admitted under oath 10 years ago sedating women for sexual purposes," said Lisa Bloom, attorney for model Janice Dickinson, who contends she was drugged and raped. "Given that, how dare he publicly vilify Ms. Dickinson and accuse her of lying when she tells a very similar story?"
The AP had gone to court to compel the release of a deposition in a sexual abuse lawsuit filed by former Temple University employee Andrea Constand  the first of a cascade of lawsuits against Cosby that have severely damaged his image as doting TV dad Dr. Cliff Huxtable on "The Cosby Show" from 1984 to 1992.
His lawyers objected to the release of the material, arguing it would embarrass him. Ultimately, a judge seized on Cosby's public moralizing as he unsealed portions of the deposition that had been filed in court.
"The stark contrast between Bill Cosby, the public moralist and Bill Cosby, the subject of serious allegations concerning improper (and perhaps criminal) conduct, is a matter as to which the AP  and by extension the public  has a significant interest," U.S. District Judge Eduardo Robreno wrote.
View gallery
Janice Dickinson arrives at the LA Premiere of "Lord of the Freaks" on Monday, June 29, 20
Cosby, 77, has been accused by more than two dozen women of sexual misconduct in episodes dating back more than four decades. He has never been charged with a crime, and the statute of limitations on most of the accusations has expired.
The entertainer settled Constand's lawsuit under confidential terms in 2006. Even the judge never saw the settlement terms, although the documents show that Cosby at one point offered the accuser an "educational trust" fund.
His lawyers in the Philadelphia case did not immediately return telephone and email messages Monday. The AP does not identify victims of sexual assault, but Constand's lawyer said she consented to be identified although she did not want to comment.
Cosby's lawyers insisted during the deposition that two of the accusers knew they were taking quaaludes from the comedian, according to the documents.
Nevertheless, attorneys for some of the numerous women suing Cosby seized on the testimony as powerful corroboration of what they have been saying all along: that he drugged and raped women.
View gallery
This excerpt from a 2005 deposition given by entertainer Bill Cosby, and released Monday, July 6, 20
"The women have been saying they've been drugged and abused, and these documents appear to support the allegations," said lawyer Joe Cammarata, who represents accuser Therese Serignese, one of three women suing Cosby for defamation in Massachusetts. She has also agreed to have her name published.
Celebrity attorney Gloria Allred, representing other women, said she also hopes to use the admission in civil court cases against the comedian.
Cosby, giving sworn testimony in the lawsuit accusing him of sexually assaulting Constand at his home near Philadelphia in 2004, said he obtained seven quaalude prescriptions in the 1970s. Constand's lawyer asked if he had kept the sedatives through the 1990s  after they were banned  but was frustrated by objections from Cosby's attorney.
"When you got the quaaludes, was it in your mind that you were going to use these quaaludes for young women that you wanted to have sex with?" lawyer Dolores M. Troiani asked.
"Yes," Cosby answered.
Attorney Gloria Allred (L) speaks accompanied by Actress Lili Bernard (R) announcing allegations aga
"Did you ever give any of these young women the quaaludes without their knowledge?"
Cosby's lawyer again objected, leading Troiani to petition the federal judge to force Cosby to cooperate.
Cosby later said he gave Constand three half-pills of Benadryl, although Troiani in the documents voices doubt that was the drug involved. Constand thought he was giving her an herbal remedy, she said in her lawsuit. She recalls having him touch her breasts and put her hand on his penis, and woke up to find her clothes askew, according to her lawsuit. Cosby called any sexual contact consensual, according to arguments made by Troiani.
"This evidence shows a pattern in which defendant 'mentored' naive young women and introduced drugs into the relationship, with and without the woman's knowledge, in order for him to achieve sexual satisfaction," Troiani wrote in a motion to compel Cosby to answer deposition questions.
Cosby had fought the AP's efforts to unseal the testimony, with his lawyer arguing that the deposition could reveal details of Cosby's marriage, sex life and prescription drug use.
View gallery
Therese Serignese and her attorney, Joseph Cammarata speak to reporters outside U.S. District Court 
"It would be terribly embarrassing for this material to come out," lawyer George M. Gowen III argued in June. He also said the material would "prejudice him in eyes of the jury pool in Massachusetts," where Cosby is fighting defamation lawsuits brought by the women who say his representatives smeared them by accusing them of lying.
Robreno, the judge, had temporarily sealed some documents in the Constand lawsuit but never ruled on a final seal before the case was settled. Under federal court rules in Pennsylvania, documents must be unsealed after two years unless a party can show specific harm. Robreno ruled that Cosby's potential embarrassment was insufficient.
Robreno asked last month why Cosby was fighting the release of his sworn testimony, given that the accusations in the Constand lawsuit already were public. "Why would he be embarrassed by his own version of the facts?" Robreno said.
Cosby resigned in December from the board of trustees at Temple, where he was the popular face of the Philadelphia school in advertisements, fundraising campaigns and commencement speeches.
Lawyer Gayle Sproul, representing the AP, in court last month called the married Cosby "an icon" who "held himself out as someone who would guide the public in ways of morality."
Troiani, summarizing her evidence, painted a starkly different picture.
Cosby "has evidenced a predilection for sexual contact with women who are unconscious or drugged. His victims are young, 'star struck' and totally trusting of his public persona," Troiani argued.
Bill Cosby
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:47:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece faces last chance to stay in euro as cash runs out</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/germany-france-press-greece-fast-credible-proposals-020951804--business.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Greece faces last chance to stay in euro as cash runs out
By Paul Taylor and Renee Maltezou 1 hour ago

Next video starts in : 7 Play
Emergency euro zone summit
Load More
By Paul Taylor and Renee Maltezou
BRUSSELS (Reuters) - Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras had a final chance to present credible reform proposals to an emergency euro zone summit on Tuesday to persuade skeptical creditors to reopen aid talks before his country's banks run out of money.
With Greek lenders down to their last few days of cash and the European Central Bank tightening the noose on their funding, Tsipras must convince the bloc's other 18 leaders, many of whom are exasperated with five years of crisis, to authorize negotiations fast on a new loan to rescue Greece.
But Greek officials said the leftist premier's proposals would not go far beyond a plan he sent to the euro zone last week before Greek voters overwhelmingly rejected the austerity terms of a bailout in a referendum on Sunday.
The leaders of Germany and France, the currency area's two main powers, said after conferring on Monday that the door was still open to a deal to save Greece from plunging into economic turmoil and ditching the euro.
Chancellor Angela Merkel, under pressure in Germany to cut Greece loose, made clear it was up to Tsipras to come up with convincing proposals after Athens spurned the tax rises, spending cuts and pension and labor reforms that were on the table before its 240 billion euro bailout expired last week.
View gallery
A street vendor reacts as as she sits behind used items for sale in central Athens, Greece, July 7, 
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker, under suspicion from both sides for trying to broker a last-minute deal, told the European Parliament: "There are some in the European Union who openly or secretly are working to exclude Greece from the euro zone."
He did not name names but may have been referring to German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble, who has made no secret of his scepticism about Greece's fitness to stay in the euro and last week suggested a possible "temporary" exit.
From the Greek side, the key to making any deal politically acceptable will be to win a stronger commitment from Merkel and other lenders to reschedule Greece's giant debt burden, which the International Monetary Fund says is unsustainable.
Without some firmer pledge of debt relief, neither Greece nor the IMF is likely to accept a deal. But that may be more than Germany and its northern allies can swallow.
Schaeuble said on arrival for a preparatory meeting of finance ministers that anyone who had read the EU treaty knew debt write-offs were forbidden in the euro zone. He did not rule out other forms of restructuring.
View gallery
Newly appointed Greek Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos (C) is welcomed by Eurogroup President Jero
Asked about reports that Greece was seeking an immediate bridging loan of several billion euros, Italian Finance Minister Pier Carlo Padoan the creditors would listen to Greek requests.
"The door is open to negotiations, but there isn't much time left and the situation is urgent both for Greece and for Europe," French President Francois Hollande said in a joint media appearance with Merkel in Paris on Monday.
At stake at the emergency summit beginning at 6 p.m. in Brussels is more than just the future of Greece, a nation of 11 million that makes up just 2 percent of the euro zone's economic output and population.
If Greek banks run out of money and the country has to print its own currency, it could mean a state leaving the euro for the first time since it was launched in 1999, creating a precedent and fuelling doubts about the long-term viability of an incomplete European monetary union.
"Even if it did not trigger a short-term domino effect, the integrity of the euro zone would come under fresh threat with each episode of political uncertainty within member countries," said Thibault Mercier, an analyst at BNP Paribas.
View gallery
A pensioner leans against the main gate of the national bank of Greece as he waits to withdraw a max
Even in France, the euro zone country most sympathetic to Athens, an opinion poll published on Tuesday showed one in two people want Greece to leave the euro zone.
CONCESSIONS UNCLEAR
Strengthened by the overwhelming 61.3 percent 'No' vote in Sunday's referendum, the leftist Tsipras won the unprecedented support of all other Greek party leaders on Monday and replaced his abrasive Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis with the soft-spoken negotiator Euclid Tsakalotos.
Tsakalotos entered the euro zone finance ministers' meeting without comment. Eurogroup chairman Jeroen Dijsselbloem said it was up to Greece to show a credible way forward.
"The pressure is especially on the Greeks, the banks are closed and the situation is difficult. I guess the Greek government has an interest in coming up with serious and credible solutions soon," Dijsselbloem told reporters.
View gallery
German Chancellor Angela Merkel and French President Francois Hollande want serious proposals from G
In an intensive round of telephone diplomacy, Tsipras spoke to the heads of the ECB, the IMF and the European Commission, as well as Merkel, Russian President Vladimir Putin and U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew.
The United States, China and Japan all called for a solution in which Greece stays in the euro zone.
Tsipras gave little clue of what reform concessions he would make to try to convince deeply skeptical European leaders to lend Athens more money after five months of acrimonious and fruitless negotiations with his leftist administration.
Even with the country on the brink of economic collapse, Greek officials said the government was still seeking exceptions from its reform pledges for special interests.
Athens wants to keep a 30 percent discount on value added tax on Greek islands and delay defense spending from cuts, which rightist junior coalition partners the Independent Greeks have called "red lines". It is also resisting raising VAT on restaurants to 23 percent, and wants to wait until 2019 to phase out an income supplement for poorer pensioners, officials said.
View gallery
A man rubs his head while browsing his smartphone outside a brokerage house in Beijing Tuesday, July
Juncker told EU lawmakers he was working night and day to get negotiations reopened and chided the Greeks for their aggressive approach, saying it was unacceptable to accuse the EU of behaving like "terrorists", as Varoufakis did last week.
"Throwing Greece out of the monetary union or indeed the European Union is not something we want or indeed should want," the EU's chief executive said.
European Central Bank policymaker Ewald Nowotny suggested the bank might be able to provide some sort of bridge funding while Greece negotiated a longer-term conditional loan to see it over a crucial July 20 bond redemption to the ECB.
Greek newspapers dramatized the make-or-break nature of the Brussels showdown.
Centrist daily Ethnos headlined: "Time has run out for a solution before catastrophe," while the center-right Eleftheros Typos said: "Tsipras games finish at today's council: Time of crisis: deal or Grexit."
View gallery
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, center, leaves after a meeting with Greek political part
A clear majority of Greece's 18 partners favor a hard line at the summit, arguing that they too are democracies and that Greeks should not get easier money because they had rejected the austerity terms, casting further doubt on whether they would implement any reforms agreed now.
The ECB left unchanged its emergency liquidity lifeline for Greek banks but raised the discount it charges on collateral they present for funds - a measure banking sources said was largely symbolic since the total they could borrow was capped.
A bank closure in force since the talks collapsed was prolonged until Thursday at least, and cash withdrawals remain limited to 60 euros a day, with 20 euro notes running out.
The Athens stock exchange was also ordered closed for two days in Tuesday and Wednesday to throttle speculation.
(Additional reporting by Costas Pitas, Angeliki Koutantou and George Georgiopoulos in Athens, Julia Fioretti and Alastair Macdonald in Brussels, Paul Carrel in Berlin John O'Donnell in Frankfurt and Mark John in Paris; Writing by Paul Taylor; editing by John Stonestreet and Giles Elgood)
Europe News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:32:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>S.F. sheriff defends prior release of suspect in pier slaying</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/sf-sheriff-defends-prior-release-suspect-pier-slaying-073221388.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>SF sheriff defends prior release of suspect in pier slaying
By JANIE HAR and AMY TAXIN 3 hours ago

Shooting Raises Questions About Sanctuary Policy

Shooting Raises Questions About Sanctuary Policy
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Shooting Raises Questions About Sanctuary Policy
 Replay video
The future of travel? A tube called Hyperloop

A woman was shot dead while taking a walk with her boyfriend in Los Angeles Hollywood area on Sunday night.
Load More
SAN FRANCISCO (AP)  San Francisco Sheriff Ross Mirkarimi has defended his office's decision to release a Mexican man who was in the U.S. illegally and who is now suspected in the killing of a woman at a sightseeing pier.
Mirkarimi said that the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency should earlier have issued an arrest warrant for Francisco Sanchez.
"ICE knew that he had been deported five times," Mirkarimi said. "You would have thought he met a threshold that he required a court order or a warrant. They did not do that."
Prosecutors on Monday charged Sanchez with murder in the death of Kathryn Steinle, who was shot and killed last Wednesday as she and her father took a walk on the popular Pier 14.
Steinle's killing has brought criticism down on this liberal city because Sanchez had been deported repeatedly and was out on the streets after San Francisco officials disregarded a request from immigration authorities to keep him locked up.
San Francisco is one of dozens of cities and counties across the country that do not fully cooperate with federal immigration authorities. The city goes so far as to promote itself as a "sanctuary" for people in the country illegally.
View gallery
San Francisco Sheriff Ross Mirkarimi gestures during an interview Monday, July 6, 2015, in San Franc
In a jailhouse interview with a TV station, Sanchez, a 45-year-old repeat drug offender, appeared to confirm that he came to the city because of its status as a sanctuary.
The case has prompted a flurry of criticism from ICE officials, politicians and commenters on social media, all of whom portrayed the slaying as a preventable tragedy.
"Most of the blame should fall squarely on the shoulders of the San Francisco sheriff, because his department had custody of him and made the choice to let him go without notifying ICE," said Jessica Vaughan, director of policy studies at the Washington-based Center for Immigration Studies, which wants tougher immigration enforcement.
Rep. Bob Goodlatte, the Virginia Republican who chairs the House Judiciary Committee, blamed sanctuary practices and the Obama administration, saying: "The tragic murder of Kate Steinle once again underscores the need to end these reckless policies."
Mayor Ed Lee issued a statement saying city policy was never intended to protect "repeat, serious and violent felons." He asked for federal and local agencies to review what happened.
View gallery
Flowers and a candle lay on the ground following a vigil for Kathryn Steinle, Monday, July 6, 2015, 
California Attorney General Kamala Harris, a former San Francisco district attorney who is running for U.S. Senate, cautioned that when it comes to immigration, "our policy should not be informed by our collective outrage about one man's conduct."
Many other San Francisco politicians stayed quiet as mourners held a vigil at Pier 14 on the downtown waterfront, where the 32-year-old Steinle was gunned down, seemingly at random. She had recently moved to San Francisco.
While many cities have scaled back cooperation with ICE, few have gone as far as San Francisco.
For more than two decades, San Francisco has been considered a sanctuary for people in the U.S. illegally.
The city's sanctuary law prohibits city employees from helping federal authorities with immigration investigations or arrests unless required by law or warrant. That said, the ordinance does not prohibit local law enforcement from informing ICE that they've arrested someone in the country illegally for a felony offense or who has prior felony convictions.
View gallery
This undated photo provided by the San Francisco Police Department shows Francisco Sanchez. The fata
From jail, Sanchez told a KGO-TV reporter in a mix of Spanish and English that he found the gun wrapped in a T-shirt while sitting on a bench at the pier.
"So I picked it up and ... it started to fire on its own," Sanchez said, adding that he heard three shots go off.
Asked if he came to San Francisco because of its sanctuary status, he said yes.
"I only want to say that if the court wants to find me guilty, I wouldn't get mad," Sanchez said during the interview, in which he appeared confused and spoke incoherently at times.
___
Lisa Leff and Paul J. Elias in San Francisco contributed to this report.
San Francisco
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:49:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Carolina Senate expected to vote to remove Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/south-carolina-senate-expected-vote-remove-confederate-flag-094915626.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>South Carolina Senate expected to vote to remove Confederate flag
By Harriet McLeod 3 hours ago

.
View photo
A Confederate flag stands in front of the South Carolina State House in Columbia, South Carolina July
By Harriet McLeod
CHARLESTON, S.C. (Reuters) - South Carolina's Senate is poised to pass legislation Tuesday to remove the Confederate battle flag from the state house, where it has flown for five decades despite being viewed by many as a symbol of slavery.
A bill to banish the flag from the Capitol grounds to a museum is headed on Tuesday for a third and final vote in the Senate, which it is considered virtually certain to pass. Then it will be taken up by the House of Representatives and could become law as early as Thursday.
The legislation, deemed a non-starter only months ago, has garnered strong bipartisan support in the wake of the June 17 killings of nine African-American churchgoers during Bible study at Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church in the port city of Charleston, about two hours south of the state capital Columbia. Photos of the white man charged in the shooting showed him posing with the flag on a website that also carried a racist manifesto.
Support for the flag has evaporated in an emotional wave of sympathy for the victims and their families, who were widely acclaimed for expressing unconditional forgiveness for the shooter at his bond hearing less than 48 hours after the murders.
Several politicians say the shootings opened their eyes to the divisive nature of the flag and what it means to South Carolina's black population.
"The world changed on ... June 17, not only for the victims and their families, but the entire world took notice," said Senator Joel Lourie, a white Democrat.
"Let today be the beginning of a new story about the state of South Carolina ... a story of how we removed a symbol (and)  helped heal a nation and a state in their mourning," he said on the Senate floor on Monday.
While most politicians recognize the flag is part of South Carolina's heritage, honoring those who died for the southern Confederacy in the Civil War, many agree it should not be flown in public places.
The bill passed a Senate reading Monday by a 37-3 margin and could be approved as early as Thursday. South Carolina's Republican Governor Nikki Haley says she will remove the flag immediately if the law is passed.
The flag was raised atop the State House in 1961 in what critics say was a deliberate slap in the face to the black civil rights movement. It was moved in 2000 to a memorial for the Civil War dead that sits only yards from the entrance to the state Capitol.
(Writing by David Adams; Editing by Cynthia Osterman)
South Carolina
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:07:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bill Cosby said in 2005 lawsuit he gave Quaaludes to women for sex</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/bill-cosby-said-2005-lawsuit-gave-quaaludes-women-000126059.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Bill Cosby said in 2005 lawsuit he gave Quaaludes to women for sex
12 hours ago
.
View photo
Comedian Bill Cosby performs at The Temple Buell Theatre in Denver, Colorado January 17, 2015. REUTERS/Barry
LOS ANGELES (Reuters) - Comedian Bill Cosby testified in 2005 that he had obtained Quaaludes with the intent of giving the sedatives to young women in order to have sex with them, according to court documents unsealed on Monday.
Cosby, 77, made the admission during testimony in a civil case brought by a former Temple University employee, Andrea Constand, who alleged that Cosby tricked her into taking drugs before he sexually assaulted her.
The case was settled for an undisclosed sum in 2006 but the documents in the case were unsealed on Monday after the Associated Press went to court.
Cosby's lawyers had argued that the documents would cause severe embarrassment to the comedian-actor, who is best known for playing lovable father figure Dr. Cliff Huxtable on the hit TV comedy series "The Cosby Show" in the 1980s and 1990s.
A representative for Cosby did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Monday.
More than 40 women have come forward in the past year alleging Cosby drugged and sexually assaulted them in incidents dating back decades. His attorneys have consistently denied the allegations.
Cosby has never been criminally charged and most of the allegations exceed the statute of limitations. However, his career has taken a hit in the past year with TV projects and live shows being canceled. He also stepped down from the board of trustees at Temple University, his alma mater.
Cosby testified that in the 1970s he had obtained seven prescriptions for Quaaludes, the brand name for a sedative and muscle relaxant that was widely abused as a recreational drug in the 1970s.
"When you got the Quaaludes, was it in your mind that you were going to use these Quaaludes for young women that you wanted to have sex with?" Cosby was asked in the 2005 deposition.
"Yes," he replied.
Asked whether he ever gave them to young women, his lawyers raised a lengthy series of objections.
Cosby testified later that he gave Constand one and a half pills of the over-the-counter antihistamine drug Benadryl.
Cosby has said little directly about the slew of allegations against him, telling ABC television in an interview in May that he did not wish to discuss them.
"I can't speak; I just don't want to argue; I don't talk about it," Cosby he said.
(Reporting by Piya Sinha-Roy; Editing by Jill Serrjeant, Bill Trott and Lisa Shumaker)
Bill Cosby
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:02:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Clinton says Puerto Rico should have access to U.S. bankruptcy laws</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/clinton-says-puerto-rico-access-u-bankruptcy-laws-110251683.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Clinton says Puerto Rico should have access to U.S. bankruptcy laws
By Amanda Becker 2 hours ago

U.S. Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton   in Fairfax, Virginia, June 26, 2015. REUTERS/Joshua
By Amanda Becker
IOWA CITY, IOWA (Reuters) - U.S. Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton said Tuesday that Puerto Rico's public entities should be able to use U.S. bankruptcy laws to restructure some $72 billion in debt.
Like U.S. states, Puerto Rico, a commonwealth, cannot file for bankruptcy protection. Unlike U.S. states, Puerto Rico's public entities, including municipalities, are not covered by U.S. Chapter 9 bankruptcy laws.
Puerto Rico's non-voting delegate in the U.S. Congress has called for legislation that would allow Puerto Rico to access the same bankruptcy laws available to other municipalities, as has Puerto Rico's Governor Alejandro Garcia Padilla.
The U.S. Court of Appeals for the First Circuit late Monday affirmed a lower court decision to strike down Puerto Rican legislation aimed at granting local municipalities the right to enter bankruptcy, but said excluding the U.S. territory's public entities from federal bankruptcy law was unconstitutional.
"Congress and the Obama administration need to partner with Puerto Rico by providing real support and tools so that Puerto Rico cando the hard work it will taketo get on apath toward stability and prosperity," Clinton said in a statement provided to Reuters.
"As a first step, Congress should providePuerto Rico the same authority that states alreadyhaveto enable severely distressed government entities, including municipalities and public corporations, to restructure their debts under Chapter 9 of the Bankruptcy Code," Clinton added.
The White House said last week that there is "no one in the administration" that is "contemplating a federal bailout of Puerto Rico" but that the U.S. Congress should "take a look at" whether Puerto Rico's government-owned corporations should be able to access Chapter 9 bankruptcy protection.
Congressional Republicans largely oppose such a step. Republican presidential candidate Jeb Bush said in April that he thinks Puerto Rico's public agencies should have the ability to use U.S. bankruptcy laws.
"We're not talking about a bailout, we're talking about a fair shot at success," Clinton said Tuesday.
Clinton said in the statement that the "inconsistent and incoherent" application of U.S. federal law to Puerto Rico contributed to its economic situation, noting high utility rates and unemployment have led to an economy that has shrunk for eight of the last nine years.
"One troubling example of this treatment isthe lack of equity in federal funding for Puerto Rico under Medicaid and Medicare," Clinton said of health insurance programs sponsored by the U.S. government.
Clinton, also a former first lady, is the front runner for the Democratic nomination ahead of the general election in November 2016.
(Reporting by Amanda Becker in Iowa; additional reporting by Megan Davies in New York; Editing by Nick Macfie)
Puerto Rico
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Eric Holder: The Justice Department could strike deal with Edward Snowden</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/eric-holder-the-justice-department-could-strike-123393663066.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:53:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Condemned Boston Marathon bomber files motion for new trial</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/condemned-boston-marathon-bomber-files-motion-trial-185636938.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Condemned Boston Marathon bomber files motion for new trial
17 hours ago
.
View gallery
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev and his defense attorney Judy Clarke (2nd R) are shown in a courtroom sketch after he is sentenced at the federal courthouse in Boston, Massachusetts May 15, 2015. The jury in the Boston Marathon bombing trial on Friday sentenced Tsarnaev to death for helping to carry out the 2013 attack that killed three people and injured 264.    REUTERS/Jane Flavell Collins     NO SALES. NO ARCHIVES. FOR EDITORIAL USE ONLY. NOT FOR SALE FOR MARKETING OR ADVERTISING CAMPAIGNS.
BOSTON (AP)  Lawyers for Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev filed a motion for a new trial Monday, less than two weeks after he was formally sentenced to death for the 2013 attack.
The motion did not contain any details on Tsarnaev's legal arguments, saying only that a new trial is "required in the interests of justice."
Tsarnaev, 21, was convicted of 30 federal charges in the bombing, which killed three people and injured more than 260. The same jury recommended the death penalty, and a federal judge on June 24 sentenced him to death.
Tsarnaev's lawyers call the motion a "placeholder" until they can file a more detailed motion next month.
The defense also filed a request for a judgment notwithstanding the verdict. Both motions are routinely filed by defense lawyers asking a judge to toss out the jury's verdict.
A spokeswoman for U.S. Attorney Carmen Ortiz did not immediately return a call seeking comment.
During his trial, Tsarnaev's lawyers admitted that he and his brother planted two pressure-cooker bombs near the finish line of the marathon. They argued that his older brother, Tamerlan, was the mastermind of the attack and asked the jury to sentence him to life in prison instead of to death.
Tamerlan was killed during an escape attempt several days after the bombings.
Among the arguments expected to be raised in Tsarnaev's appeal is the defense contention that the trial should have been moved out of Massachusetts because of the emotional impact the bombing had here. Judge George O'Toole Jr. rejected numerous requests from Tsarnaev's lawyers to move the trial.
Dzhokhar Tsarnaev
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:36:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deported man charged with murder in San Francisco shooting</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/deported-man-charged-murder-san-francisco-shooting-003632460.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Deported man charged with murder in San Francisco shooting
By Curtis Skinner 12 hours ago

San Francisco Shooter States He Chose City for Sanctuary Policies

San Francisco Shooter States He Chose City for Sanctuary Policies
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
San Francisco Shooter States He Chose City for Sanctuary Policies
 Replay video
Swipe Right for Employment? New App Is Tinder for Job Seekers

Load More
By Curtis Skinner
SAN FRANCISCO (Reuters) - A convicted felon who had been deported from the United States to Mexico five times was charged on Monday with murder in the shooting of a woman last week at a tourist area in San Francisco.
Francisco Sanchez, 45, was arrested for the shooting of Kathryn Steinle, 32, last Wednesday evening. The case drew national attention after Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump during the weekend used the killing to decry U.S.-Mexico border security.
The San Francisco District Attorney's Office said in a statement that Sanchez would be arraigned on Tuesday.
Immigration officials said Sanchez was released from federal prison in March after a felony re-entry conviction. He was transferred to the custody of the San Francisco County Sheriff's Office on a drug arrest warrant and federal officials asked to be notified prior to his release.
The Sheriff's Office said the charges were dismissed and since there was no active warrant or judicial order for Sanchez's removal, the city's policy deemed Sanchez "ineligible for extended detention" and he was freed.
View gallery
Flowers and a candle form a makeshift memorial for shooting victim Kathryn Steinle on Pier 14 in San
Sanchez has a long criminal history including seven felonies and has been deported to Mexico five times, according to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.
Earlier on Monday, San Francisco Mayor Ed Lee expressed concern about Sanchez's release into the community and directed authorities to look at the steps they took with Sanchez leading up to the shooting.
"All agencies involved, federal and local, need to conduct quick, thorough and objective reviews of their own departmental policies and the decisions they made in this case," Lee said in a statement.
He defended his city's so-called sanctuary policy as one that protects immigrant communities and that should not shield criminals.
Dozens of such sanctuary cities across the United States limit the assistance they provide to federal immigration authorities aiming to apprehend or deport individuals.
View gallery
Flowers and a candle form a makeshift memorial for shooting victim Kathryn Steinle on Pier 14 in San
An anonymous law enforcement source told the San Francisco Chronicle newspaper that Sanchez was shooting at sea lions and struck Steinle by accident.
In a jail house interview with broadcaster KGO-TV, Sanchez admitted to the shooting, saying he had just taken several sleeping pills and the gun went off when he picked it up.
Trump, who drew heavy criticism for describing immigrants from Mexico to the United States as drug-runners and rapists during the launch of his presidential bid last month, on Saturday said the shooting was a "totally preventable act of violence committed by an illegal immigrant."

(Editing by Steve Orlofsky and Bill Trott)
SAN FRANCISCO
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:01:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bill Cosby said he obtained drugs to give to women for sex</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/ap-bill-cosby-said-obtained-000930605.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>View photo
Documents: Bill Cosby said he obtained drugs to give to women for sex
Bill Cosby admitted in 2005 that he secured quaaludes with the intent of giving them to young women he wanted to have sex with, and that he gave the sedative to at least one woman and "other people," according to documents obtained Monday by The Associated Press.
Bill Cosby
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:44:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>SC Senate votes to remove flag from Statehouse grounds</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/south-carolina-lawmakers-return-confederate-flag-debate-085829900.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>SC Senate votes to remove flag from Statehouse grounds
By JEFFREY COLLINS 9 hours ago

.
.
COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP)  The South Carolina Senate voted Monday to pull the Confederate flag off the Capitol grounds, clearing the way for a historic measure that could remove the banner more than five decades after it was first flown above the Statehouse to protest integration.
A second vote will be needed Tuesday to send the proposal to the House, where it faces a less certain future. But Monday's 37-3 vote was well over the two-thirds majority needed to advance the bill.
If the House passes the same measure, the flag and flagpole could be removed as soon as Gov. Nikki Haley signs the papers. The flag would be lowered for the last time and shipped off to the state's Confederate Relic Room, near where the last Confederate flag to fly over the Statehouse dome is stored.
The vote came at the end of a day of debate in which several white senators said they had come to understand why their black colleagues felt the flag no longer represented the valor of Southern soldiers but the racism that led the South to separate from the United States more than 150 years ago.
As the senators spoke, the desk of their slain colleague, Clementa Pinckney, was still draped in black cloth. Pinckney and eight other black people were fatally shot June 17 during Bible study at a historic African-American church in Charleston. Authorities have charged a gunman who posed for pictures with the rebel banner. Police say he was driven by racial hatred.
Several senators said the grace shown by the families of the victims willing to forgive the gunman also changed their minds.
"We now have the opportunity, the obligation, to put the exclamation point on an extraordinary narrative of good and evil, of love and mercy that will take its place in the history books," said Sen. Tom Davis, a Republican.
View gallery
State Sen. Lee Bright lets his position be known in the senate chambers July 6, 2015 in Columbia, So
After the vote, Sen. Vincent Sheheen, a Democrat whose suggestion that the flag be taken down while running for governor last year was called a "stunt" by Haley, was given a high-five from a fellow legislator.
"I thought it would happen, but never this fast," Sheheen said.
Republican Sen. Larry Martin, who for decades fought off attempts to remove the flag from Statehouse grounds, said the church shooting drew him to the same conclusion that his black colleague arrived at long ago  that the rebel flag "has more to do with what was going on in the 1960s as opposed to the 1860s."
Martin, who is white, had family who came to South Carolina's then-rugged northern backcountry from Scotland in the early 1800s. That was about the time the enslaved relatives of Sen. Darrell Jackson, a black Democrat, involuntary ended up near Columbia.
Jackson helped write the compromise that took the Confederate flag off the Statehouse dome in 2000 and put it in its current location on a pole on the Capitol's front lawn.
On Monday, he said his great-grandfather's brother fled a plantation and joined the Union army when Gen. William Sherman came storming through Columbia.
View gallery
State Sen. Danny Verdin addresses legislators in the senate chambers July 6, 2015 in Columbia, South
Jackson said he regretted not going further to get rid of the flag completely 15 years ago. But he welcomed the chance now to honor his great-grandfather, Ishmael Jackson, who escaped to freedom.
"You said we lost the war. No we didn't. Not Ishmael Jackson and the 57 percent of people who looked like him. As far as they are concerned, they won the war," Jackson said.
The Senate rejected three amendments. One would have put a different Confederate flag on the pole. A second would fly the flag only on Confederate Memorial Day, and the third would leave the flag's fate up to a popular vote.
State Sen. Lee Bright, who suggested the popular vote, said the Confederate flag has been misused by people like Dylann Roof, who is charged with murder in the church shootings and who posed in pictures with the rebel banner.
"I'm more against taking it down in this environment than any other time just because I believe we're placing the blame of what one deranged lunatic did on the people that hold their Southern heritage high," said Bright, a Republican.
The flag still has at least a few days to fly, even with Haley, business leaders and civil rights proponents wanting it down as soon as possible. There are indications the proposal could have a tougher road in the House. Some powerful Republicans have not said how they will vote, including Speaker Jay Lucas.
Some Republicans want to keep the flagpole and put a different flag on it. Suggestions have included the U.S. flag, the South Carolina flag and a flag that may have been flown by Confederate troops but does not have the same connections as the red banner with the blue cross and white stars.
House Minority Leader Todd Rutherford vowed that no Democrat would vote for a bill that leaves the flagpole up.
The bill is expected to be sent directly to the House floor Wednesday with several amendments offered, said Republican Rep. Greg Delleney, chairman of the Judiciary Committee, which would normally receive the bill before it got to the floor.
If any amendments pass, a conference committee would probably be needed to hash out differences.
___
Follow Jeffrey Collins on Twitter at https://twitter.com/JSCollinsAP .
South Carolina Senate
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:34:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>No evidence of active shooter at Walter Reed, police say</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/walter-reed-shooting-reports-162942837.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>No evidence of active shooter at Walter Reed, police say
Report of a possible gunshot triggered lockdown
By Dylan Stableford 18 hours ago
Yahoo News
.
.
Police say there is no indication there was a shooting at Walter Reed National Military Medical Center on Monday after an unconfirmed report of an active shooter on the hospital's Bethesda, Md., campus triggered a lockdown.
#WalterReed employees were told to shelter in place via a text alert. http://t.co/bwXbv77oFq pic.twitter.com/dYmZiVW2bx
 NBCWashington (@nbcwashington) July 6, 2015
According to police in Montgomery County, a 911 caller reported hearing one shot fired inside Building 1 at approximately 10:48 a.m.
Call received at approx. 10:48 a.m. for report of single shot heard on Walter Reed campus. Officers have not confirmed initial report.
The facility was placed on lockdown while local police and federal agents searched the area.
UPDATE on unconfirmed report of shot fired at #WalterReed / Bethesda. Security searching buildings. No confirmation of incident.
 U.S. Navy (@USNavy) July 6, 2015
Employees were seen being evacuated from a building with their hands raised.
#BreakingNews watching armed personnel escort #WalterReed employees out, report of a gunshot heard pic.twitter.com/HCAPgWBC2q
 Brad Freitas (@NewsChopperBrad) July 6, 2015
Staffers sheltering in place tweeted updates from inside the facility.

Are we sure it wasn't just a car backfiring on/off base? I didn't hear anything on my way in today. https://t.co/fRvRUXtFHV
 Heather (@heather_kopf) July 6, 2015
Others called their family members, who relayed messages via Twitter.
my sister asks me to tweet that she's safe &amp; in lockdown, in complete blackness &amp; someone is passing around candy #walterReed @wusa9
 Allison Baughman (@baughwoman) July 6, 2015
Nearby roads were also closed as a precaution.
Rockville pike shut down near #WalterReed where police search after a report of shooter. @wusa9 pic.twitter.com/vZ6PlaJRDI
 Hank Silverberg (@HankSilverberg) July 6, 2015
At a 1 p.m. press briefing, Montgomery Capt. Paul Starks said officials were close to completing a sweep of Building 1 and there was "no indication of any kind" that there was a shooting, and no injuries reported.
Once the building is cleared, Starks said, it would searched by bomb-sniffing dogs "out of an abundance of caution."
The sweep was completed at 1:30 p.m., police said.
Last week, a report of possible gunshots heard by an employee at the Washington Navy Yard triggered a massive law enforcement response. But a subsequent search found no evidence a shooting had occurred.
That false alarm came two years after a gunman opened fire inside a building at the Navy Yard, killing 12 people and injuring three others.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:57:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World Cup kiss a poignant moment for many</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/us-world-cup-wambach-kiss-wife-135722914.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Abby Wambach kisses wife after World Cup win
A poignant moment that wasn't lost on gay rights supporters
By Dylan Stableford 23 hours ago
Yahoo News
.
.
Abby Wambach celebrated the United States' 5-2 victory over Japan in the Women's World Cup final on Sunday, racing to the stands to kiss her wife, Sarah Huffman.
Coming on the heels of the Supreme Court's historic decision to legalize same-sex marriage, the significance of the moment wasn't lost on gay rights supporters watching on television.
On Twitter, many noted how far American culture has come since the last U.S. Women's World Cup victory in 1999.
Sweet photo, post #USWNT victory: @AbbyWambach kisses her wife, now respected nationwide http://t.co/We2DeD89kt pic.twitter.com/71OrRKE0Ug
 Freedom to Marry (@freedomtomarry) July 6, 2015
This Video Of US World Cup Winner Abby Wambach Rushing To Kiss Her Wife Will Warm Your Heart http://t.co/S3gksew0az #topprog #lgbt #USWNT
 Gay Civil Rights (@gaycivilrights) July 6, 2015
I hope younger people GET how huge it is that @AbbyWambach can kiss her wife in the stands on FOXTV and it's no big thing #Progress 
 Carolyn Hinsey (@CarolynHinsey) July 6, 2015
Wambach kisses wife on national television and camera doesn't cut away. It zooms in. We've come a long way, folks.
 Brigid Black (@brigidblack) July 6, 2015
ABBY WAMBACH KISSING HER WIFE, A UNION NOW RECOGNIZED THROUGHOUT THE USA, IS A PRETTY NICE ENDING TO THIS WORLD CUP https://t.co/1nfhQxGY38
 Ellie Hall (@ellievhall) July 6, 2015
How cool was Abby jumping into the stands to kiss her wife in front of millions on national TV? It's been a good few weeks. #PRIDE
 Abe Asher (@abe_asher) July 6, 2015
Abby Wambach kissed her wife after winning the World Cup and the whole bar went, "awwwwwww". How far we have come!
 Anne-Marije Rook (@amrook) July 6, 2015
ICYMI: That beautiful moment when @AbbyWambach sprints to find her wife after winning the #WWC2015 http://t.co/wyZ1hl6xUs via @sbnation
 Anna Aagenes (@AnnaLinaAagenes) July 6, 2015
Twitter's reaction to the U.S. win over Japan wasn't entirely beautiful, however. As the United States built a 4-0 lead following a flurry of first-half goals, some users mockingly suggested the barrage was payback for Japan's 1941 attack on Pearl Harbor, and the term "Pearl Harbor" soon began trending on Twitter.
That 4th one was for Pearl Harbor. #USA
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:47:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>After vote win, Greece's Tsipras looks to rebuild talks</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/greece-still-cash-starved-decisive-no-bailout-vote-050303610--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>After vote win, Greece's Tsipras looks to rebuild talks
By DEREK GATOPOULOS and ELENA BECATOROS 19 hours ago

Next video starts in : 7 Play
Greece at a standstill
Raw: Greek Leaders, Citizens Vote on Austerity

CNBC&amp;#39;s Rick Santelli reports on May trade balance.
Load More
ATHENS, Greece (AP)  Despite triumphing in a popular vote against austerity, Greece on Monday faced the urgent need to heal its ties with European creditors and reach a financial rescue deal that might prevent it from falling out of the euro  possibly within days.
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras won big in Sunday's referendum, in which 60 percent of Greeks rejected the economic measures creditors had proposed in exchange for loans the country needs to remain afloat. He also received the rare backing of opposition parties to restart bailout negotiations.
But his bolstered mandate to push for better concessions from creditors hit the hard reality of the country's deteriorating finances, with the banks facing the risk of collapse within days unless a rescue deal is reached.
In a sign that he hopes to reach a deal as soon as possible, Tsipras appointed a new mild-mannered finance minister to lead talks with bailout creditors and replace Yanis Varoufakis, the hard-talking professor who clashed regularly with his European counterparts.
Euclid Tsakalotos, a 55-year-old economist, appears more willing to reach a compromise with creditors and will be tested as soon as Tuesday, when he will meet the other 18 eurozone finance ministers in Brussels.
That meeting is meant to seek the basis for a deal that European leaders, including Tsipras, might discuss at an emergency summit later in the day. Ahead of the summit, Tsipras spoke by phone with German Chancellor Angela Merkel.
View gallery
A street vendor reacts as as she sits behind used items for sale in central Athens, Greece, July 7, 
Greece's financial situation is getting more difficult by the day. It had to close the banks last week to prevent their collapse in the face of a run, and imposed limits on cash withdrawals and transfers.
Greek banks remained closed Monday, with only a few branches opening for pensioners to receive emergency assistance. Louka Katseli, head of the Greek Bank Association, said she expected banks to remain closed for at least two more days.
The government is expected to extend the restrictions on withdrawals after the European Central Bank makes a decision later Monday on cash support for Greek banks.
The ECB has frozen the amount of credit it allows Greek banks to draw on, even though their cash requirements are growing as people rush to withdraw what money they can.
Analysts say that if the ECB keeps the amount of credit on hold, Greek banks will come under increasing pressure and the government could have to make the limits on cash withdrawals even tougher.
View gallery
Elderly people argue with a bank worker as they wait to be allowed into the bank to withdraw a maxim
The ongoing Greek drama hurt stocks around the world, particularly in Europe. The losses were not as great as some had feared, however, suggesting investors think that a Greek exit from the euro, while devastating for the country and destabilizing in Europe, would be manageable for the global economy.
"The 'no' vote in Greece's referendum on Sunday dramatically increases the risk of a slide toward a disorderly Greek exit from the eurozone," ratings agency Fitch said.
"An agreement between Greece and its official creditors remains possible, but time is short and the risk of policy missteps, or that the two sides simply cannot agree a deal, is high."
With all ballots counted, 61.3 percent of voters in Sunday's referendum said "no" to the question of whether they would accept creditors' proposed measures.
Tsipras has agreed to imposing more harsh austerity measures, following a six-year recession, but wants eurozone lenders to grant the country better terms for bailout debt repayments.
View gallery
People line up to use ATM machines of a bank after government's decision for limited daily cash 
"The prime minister is ... committed to starting a fundamental debate on dealing with the problem of sustainability of the Greek national debt," a statement signed by the government and three pro-European opposition parties said.
European officials appear to be split on Greece's demand for easier debt repayment.
France's finance minister, Michel Sapin, indicated that discussing Greece's debt is not taboo, saying the country could not recover with its current obligations "in the months and years to come."
Germany, however, remains highly reluctant to discuss debt relief.
Finance Ministry spokesman Martin Jaeger said Germany's "position is well-known ... a debt cut is not an issue for us."
A man walks in central Athens, Monday, July 6, 2015. Greeces finance minister has resigned followin
German Vice Chancellor Sigmar Gabriel said Europe should be preparing to help Greeks with humanitarian assistance.
"The situation that is now being created by the referendum makes me sad, because life for the Greek population is going to get harder in the coming days and weeks," he said.
"After yesterday's celebrations in the streets there's a danger of a rude awakening soon."
___
Demetris Nellas and Menelaos Hadjicostis in Athens, Greece, Lori Hinnant in Paris, Raf Casert in Brussels and Geir Moulson in Berlin contributed.
Alexis Tsipras
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:37:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope puts family first at outdoor Mass in steamy Guayaquil</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/more-1-million-expected-popes-mass-south-america-040722132.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Pope puts family first at outdoor Mass in steamy Guayaquil
By NICOLE WINFIELD and ALLEN PANCHANA 9 hours ago

Raw: Pope Francis Departs for South America

Raw: Pope Francis Departs for South America
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Raw: Pope Francis Departs for South America
 Replay video
Al Shabaab gunmen kill 14 in attack on Kenyan workers

Hollywood star, Jessica Alba enjoys Giambattista Valli&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;exquisite&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;feminine&amp;#39; couture fashion show at Paris Fashion Week. (July 7)
Load More
GUAYAQUIL, Ecuador (AP)  Pope Francis received a hero's welcome in Ecuador's biggest city Monday as he celebrated the first public Mass of his South American tour, telling hundreds of thousands of faithful their families are the bedrock of society but need to be supported better and strengthened.
In his homily, Francis praised families as the nucleus of society, calling them "the nearest hospital, the first school for the young, the best home for the elderly." He said miracles are performed every day inside a family out of love, but sometimes the love and happiness run out.
"How many women, sad and lonely, wonder when love left, when it slipped away from their lives?" he asked. "How many elderly people feel left out of family celebrations, cast aside and longing each day for a little love?"
Firefighters sprayed water from hoses on the crowd to provide relief from a searing sun and high humidity that made the 86 degree Fahrenheit temperature in the Pacific port city of Guayaquil feel at least 10 degrees hotter.
Many pilgrims had spent the night outdoors, and some walked for miles to reach the park on Guayaquil's northern outskirts to catch a glimpse of history's first Latin American pope celebrating Mass on his home turf. They said it was well worth the discomfort.
"I'm tired, I'm hungry, I haven't slept, but I'm also full of emotion and joy in my heart," said Vicente Huilcatoma, a former police officer who walked 25 miles (40 kilometers) to reach Samanes Park.
View gallery
A group of young people wave flags representing the colors of Vatican City as they wait for the arri
The Vatican originally estimated more than 1 million people would turn out for the Mass, and government organizers put the crowd at above that figure in the hour before the service began. But Gabriel Almeida, the government spokesman at the scene, rolled back the estimate to about 550,000 after officials viewed aerial images of the area.
Across the park, flags from Ecuador and more than a half dozen other countries waved above the enormous sea of people, who were divided into quadrants that Francis looped around slowly on his popemobile to cheers of "Francisco! Francisco!"
The pope's homily brought Janeth Valencia Bersosa to tears. The primary school teacher came to the Mass with her older sister Pilar from Cuenca, about 125 miles (200 kilometers) away, spending the night in the park and then baking under the heat of the noontime Mass. She said it was worth it.
"Francis has given us back hope in our families, in those we love the most, the nucleus of society," she said. "I wept at each phrase."
Francis has dedicated the first two years of his pontificate to family issues, giving weekly catechism lessons on different aspects of family life and inviting the entire church to study ways to provide better pastoral care for Catholic families facing difficulties today, including people who are divorced, gays and families in "nontraditional" situations.
View gallery
Pope Francis laughs as he meets the journalists aboard the papal airplane on the occasion of his vis
A preliminary meeting of bishops on these issues ended last year in bitter divisions between liberals and conservatives, particularly over ministering to gays and to Catholics who divorce and remarry outside the church. Church teaching holds that Catholics who enter into a second marriage without having the first one annulled cannot receive Communion.
In his homily Monday, Francis said he hoped the second meeting of bishops on family life, scheduled for October, would come up with "concrete solutions to the many difficult and significant challenges facing families in our time."
"I ask you to pray fervently for this intention, so that Christ can take even what might seem to us impure, scandalous or threatening, and turn it ... into a miracle."
"Families today need miracles!" he added.
The Vatican spokesman, the Rev. Federico Lombardi, said Francis wasn't referring to the gay or divorce issue specifically but was making a more general reference that he hoped the bishops would "help the church chart this path of leaving a situation of sin to one of grace."
View gallery
Ecuador's President Rafael Correa, right, welcomes Pope Francis upon his arrival at Quito Airpor
Upon his arrival in Guayaquil, the pontiff allowed several acolytes on the tarmac to take selfies with him. He then headed to the Shrine of the Divine Mercy, where 2,000 invitees gathered, including young cancer patients, residents of homes for the elderly abandoned by their families and some of Guayaquil's poorest people.
He told those gathered that he would pray for them "and I won't charge you a thing. All I ask, please, is that you pray for me."
After the open-air Mass, Francis had lunch with a group of Jesuits at a nearby high school.
A highlight was his reunion with the Rev. Francisco Cortes, a priest affectionately known as "Padre Paquito," to whom the Argentina-born pope, then the Rev. Jorge Mario Bergoglio, entrusted his seminarians on study trips to Ecuador years ago.
In a recent interview with The Associated Press, Cortes couldn't fathom that Bergoglio remembered him, much less made a point of coming to have lunch. "I don't know what to ask him," the soon-to-be 91-year-old Cortes said. "I'm really just a Mr. Nobody."
View gallery
Pope Francis waves to the crowd as he rides aboard the Popemobile in streets of Quito, Ecuador, Sund
Returning to the capital of Quito at dusk, Francis paid a 50-minute courtesy visit to Rafael Correa at the presidential palace. When it ended, Correa ushered him to reception line of dozens that took a quarter hour to negotiate.
The pope then prayed in Quito's cathedral and went out on the steps to address a crowd, many of whom had waited hours to see him and endured a deluge. But instead of giving the short speech that he had prepared, Francis offered a brief blessing.
Tuesday brings another big public Mass, this time in Quito, as well as a meeting with the country's bishops, a speech at Ecuador's Catholic University and an evening gathering with civil society groups, including indigenous leaders.
Tens of thousands who lined up outside the Quito park where the Mass was to be held got soaked in a punishing rain and hail storm. People grabbed what they could to protect themselves. They tore vinyl advertising placards off the metal fences surrounding the park, which was the city's international airport until two years ago.
Some just shrugged it off. Although her clothes were soaked and she shivered in the cold of Quito's 9,000-foot altitude, 71-year-old Angelica Naranjo said: "This isn't a sacrifice. It's a demonstration of faith."
Quito security chief Juan Zapata said officials would distribute blankets from stocks kept by civil defense authorities.
___
Associated Press writers Jacobo Garcia and Frank Bajak contributed to this report.
Pope Francis
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
