<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Yahoo">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:34:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Terror' attack in France followed by gunfire at Tunisia tourist spot</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/man-decapitated-and-several-hurt-in-suspected-islamist-attack-in-grenoble-factory-092920187.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>More games 
Tunisia Gunfire At Tourist Hotspot As Man Decapitated In French 'Islamist' Attack
Separate attacks see gunman open fire on beach in Tunisian tourist resort, as man is decapitated in 'Islamist attack' near Grenoble
By Chris Parsons 3 hours ago

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:38:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Same-sex marriage among last 5 Supreme Court cases</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/same-sex-marriage-among-last-5-supreme-court-073847423.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>.
View photo
John Becker, 30, of Silver Spring, Md., waves a rainbow flag in support of gay marriage outside of the Supreme Court in Washington, Thursday June 25, 2015. The same-sex marriage ruling is among the remaining to be released before the term ends at the end of June. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)
The right of same-sex couples to marry is the biggest of five cases still to be decided by the Supreme Court.
The justices gave the Obama administration big victories Thursday, in upholding a key part of the health care overhaul and the use of a potent tool to fight housing discrimination. The justices will take the bench again Friday to hand down more opinions. They should finish their work by early next week.
In rare instances, the court will put off decisions and order a case to be argued again in the next term.
This is also the time of the year when a justice could announce a retirement. But no justice, including 82-year-old Ruth Bader Ginsburg, has given any hint that retirement is imminent.
A look at the cases that remain:
Gay marriage: Same-sex couples want the court to declare that gay and lesbian couples can marry anywhere in the United States. Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Tennessee are asking the court to uphold bans on same-sex marriage and allow the political process, not the courts, to handle major societal changes. Same-sex couples can marry in 36 states.
Lethal injection: Death-row inmates in Oklahoma are objecting to the use of the sedative midazolam in lethal-injection executions after the drug was implicated in several botched executions. Their argument is that the drug does not reliably induce a coma-like sleep that would prevent them from experiencing the searing pain of the paralytic and heart-stopping drugs that follow sedation.
Independent redistricting commissions: Roughly a dozen states have adopted independent commissions to reduce partisan politics in drawing congressional districts. The case from Arizona involves a challenge from Republican state lawmakers who complain that they can't be completely cut out of the process without violating the Constitution.
Mercury emissions: Industry groups and Republican-led states assert that environmental regulators overstepped their bounds by coming up with expensive limits on the emissions of mercury and other toxic pollutants from power plants without taking account of the cost of regulation at the start of the process. The first-ever limits on mercury emissions, more than a decade in the making, began to take effect in April.
Repeat offenders: The court is considering whether a catchall provision of the Armed Career Criminal Act, which gives longer prison terms to people with at least three prior violent felony convictions, is so vague that it sweeps in relatively minor crimes.
Ruth Bader Ginsburg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:29:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>9 killed in Alaska sightseeing plane crash</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/missing-plane-carrying-9-found-cliff-side-alaska-003600347.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Recovery efforts resume Friday for 9 killed in Alaska crash
By MARK THIESSEN 3 hours ago

Nine dead in small plane crash in Alaska

Nine dead in small plane crash in Alaska
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Nine dead in small plane crash in Alaska
 Replay video
ShowBiz Minute: Diamond, Swift, Harry Potter

Highlights of this day in history:  President John F. Kennedy rallies West Berlin during the Cold War; The U.N. Charter signed; Scientists complete first rough map of the human genetic code; Charlie Chaplin&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;The Gold Rush&amp;#39; premieres.  (June 26)
Load More
ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP)  Alaska emergency crews will attempt Friday to recover the remains of eight cruise ship passengers and a pilot who were killed when their sightseeing plane crashed in a remote and rugged area of southeastern Alaska.
Wind and rain prevented any recovery after the wreckage of the aircraft was found Thursday against a granite rock face, 800 feet above a lake.
There was no immediate indication of why the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop went down, killing the nine people during the sightseeing excursion. No names have been released.
Clint Johnson, head of the National Transportation Safety Board's Alaska office, said it was too soon to know circumstances of the crash, including whether the plane flew into the cliff.
The NTSB was assembling a high-level team to investigate the crash, including three members from Alaska and at least two people from Washington, D.C.
"The initial rescue crew that went in had a very tough time because of the terrain," Johnson said. "It's a very steep, mountainous area, and weather conditions caused them to stand down."
The Holland America Line cruise ship Westerdam sits in dock in Ketchikan, Alaska, on Thursday, June 
He earlier confirmed the deaths: "''We have nine fatalities."
Coast Guard Petty Officer Lauren Steenson said the agency received a report around 2:15 p.m. that the plane was overdue. Troopers said an emergency locator transmitter activated in the Misty Fjords National Monument, and a helicopter pilot spotted the downed aircraft above Ella Lake, about 800 miles southeast of Anchorage.
Promech Air, an airline based in Ketchikan, operated the shore excursion sold through Holland America Line, the cruise ship company said in a statement. The eight passengers were guests on the Westerdam, which is on a seven-day cruise that departed Seattle on Saturday.
"We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those onboard the plane and their families," the statement said. "Holland America Line is extending its full support to traveling companions of the guests involved."
Promech said that the crash happened about 11:20 a.m., and the plane was one of five Otter aircraft in its fleet.
"There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling," Marcus Sessoms, president of Promech Air, said in a statement. "At this moment, all of us share the pain and anguish of this terrible event.  Our thoughts and our prayers go out to everyone touched by this tragedy."
The Ketchikan Daily News reported the Westerdam had been scheduled to leave the city at 1 p.m., but it remained in port Thursday evening.
The airline's website advertises tours of the 2-million-acre Misty Fjord National Monument in its float planes.
"Towering granite cliffs, 1,000-foot waterfalls, lush and remote valleys and serene crystalline lakes make up this incredible landscape," it says.
___
Associated Press writer Kathy McCarthy in Seattle contributed to this report.
ANCHORAGE, Alaska
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:01:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obamacare ruling puts Supreme Court on hot seat in U.S. presidential race</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/obamacare-ruling-puts-supreme-court-hot-seat-u-050459645.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Obamacare ruling puts Supreme Court on hot seat in U.S. presidential race
By James Oliphant 2 hours ago
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:09:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear talks near deadline</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/iran-nuclear-talks-enter-final-phase-48-hours-084259413.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nuke talks to miss target; Iran foreign minister heads home
By MATTHEW LEE and GEORGE JAHN 1 hour ago

.
.
VIENNA (AP)  A senior U.S. official acknowledged Sunday that Iran nuclear talks will go past their June 30 target date, as Iran's foreign minister prepared to head home Sunday for consultations before returning to push for a breakthrough.
Iranian media said Mohammed Javad Zarif's trip was planned in advance. Still,  the fact that he was leaving the talks so close to the Tuesday deadline reflected his need to get instructions on how to proceed on issues where the sides remain apart  among them how much access Tehran should give to U.N. experts monitoring his country's compliance to any deal.
The United States insists on more intrusive access than Iran is ready to give. With these and other disputes still unresolved the likelihood that the Tuesday target deadline for an Iran nuclear deal could slip was increasingly growing even before the U.S. confirmation.
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry met in Vienna for their third encounter since Saturday.  German Foreign Minister Frank-Walter Steinmeier and French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius are also in Vienna, and their Russian and British counterparts were to join later. China was sending a deputy foreign minister in a building diplomatic effort to wrap up the negotiations.
For weeks, all seven nations at the negotiating table insisted that Tuesday remains the formal deadline for a deal. But with time running out, a senior U.S. official acknowledged that was unrealistic.
"Given the dates, and that we have some work to do ... the parties are planning to remain in Vienna beyond June 30 to continue working," said the official, who demanded anonymity in line with State Department practice.
View gallery
From left, U.S. Secretary of Energy Ernest Moniz, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry and U.S. Under 
Asked about the chances for a deal, Federica Mogherini, the European Union's top diplomat, told reporters: "It's going to be tough ... but not impossible."
Steinmeier avoided reporters but told German media earlier: "I am convinced that if there is no agreement, everyone loses."
"Iran would remain isolated. A new arms race in a region that is already riven by conflict could be the dramatic consequence."
Both sides recognize that there is leeway to extend to July 9. As part of an agreement with the U.S. Congress, lawmakers then have 30 days to review the deal before suspending congressional sanctions.
But postponement beyond that would double the congressional review period to 60 days, giving both Iranian and U.S. critics more time to work on undermining an agreement.
View gallery
From left, U.S. Secretary of Energy Ernest Moniz, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry and U.S. Under 
Arguing for more time to allow the U.S. to drive a harder bargain, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu  a fierce opponent of the talks  weighed in on Sunday against "this bad agreement, which is becoming worse by the day."
"It is still not too late to go back and insist on demands that will genuinely deny Iran the ability to arm itself with nuclear weapons," he said.
The goal of the talks involving Iran and the U.S., Britain, China, France, Germany and Russia is a deal that would crimp Tehran's capacity to make nuclear weapons in exchange for sanctions relief.  Iran insists it does not want such arms but is bargaining in exchange for sanctions relief
On Saturday, diplomats told The Associated Press that Iran was considering a U.S.-backed plan for it to send enriched uranium to another country for sale as reactor fuel, a step that would resolve one of several outstanding issues.
___
Associated Press writer Ali Akbar Dareini in Tehran contributed to this report.
.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:40:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Armed Tunisian police swarm streets of tourist towns</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/armed-tunisian-police-swarm-streets-tourist-towns-attack-100734893.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Armed Tunisian police swarm streets of tourist towns
By Zoubier Souissi 1 hour ago

.
View gallery
Police officers patrol the beach near the Imperial Marhabada resort, which was attacked by a gunman in
By Zoubier Souissi
SOUSSE, Tunisia (Reuters) - Hundreds of armed police patrolled the streets of Tunisia's beach resorts on Sunday and the government said it will deploy hundreds more inside hotels after the Islamist militant attack in Sousse that killed 39 foreigners, mostly Britons.
Thousands of tourists have left Tunisia since Friday's attack, which has shocked the North African country that relies heavily on tourism for jobs and foreign currency revenues.
Britain's Foreign Office warned late on Saturday that Islamist militants may launch further attacks in Tunisia after a gunman opened fire on the Imperial Marhaba resort in the deadliest such attack in Tunisia's modern history.
At least 15 Britons were among the dead and wounded along with German, Irish and Belgian nationals in Sousse. The health ministry says at least 40 people were wounded without giving any details of their nationalities.
"We are going to deploy 1,000 armed police to protect hotels and tourists," Tunisian Interior Minister Najem Gharsalli told reporters late on Saturday night.
Since its 2011 uprising to oust Zine El-Abidine Ben Ali, Tunisia has made a peaceful transition to democracy with a new constitution and free elections. It is seen as a model for the region.
View gallery
A woman attends a protest to condemn an attack by a gunman at the beach of the Imperial Marhabada  h
But its young democracy has also been tested by the rise of  hardline Islamist movements, some of which have turned to violence. The army has been fighting a campaign against pockets of Islamist militants near the Algerian border.
State news agency TAP said gunmen raided houses for food in El Kef, a northeastern city about 160 km (100 miles) from the coast and 40 km from the Algerian border, before heading to the mountains that separate the two countries. TAP gave no further details.
Islamic State has claimed the Sousse attack. But officials say the gunman, named as Saif Rezgui, was not any watchlist of known potential militants. One source said he appeared to have been radicalised over the last six months by recruiters.
It was the second major attack in Tunisia this year, following an Islamist militant assault on the Bardo Museum in Tunis in March when gunmen killed a group of foreign visitors as they arrived by bus.
The tourism minister has described the Sousse attack as a catastrophe for the industry, which accounts for about seven percent of the country's gross domestic product.
"Germans, French and British officials informed us they would not prevent tourists from coming to Tunisia, but they want to participate in the investigation and to see clear security decisions," tourism minister, Salma Loumi, told reporters on Sunday.
"We will receive all ambassadors on Tuesday to inform them of all security measures taken to protect tourists," she said.
Loumi noted that many British tourists had decided to stay in Tunisia until the end of their holidays.
More than 3,000 tourists had already left the country a day after the attack.
"Tunisia is a beautiful country, and we will come back, but right now we need to leave, we need to forget what happened," said Lucy, a young British tourist leaving from a local airport near Sousse. "It's clear it is not safe here at the moment."
Islamist jihadists have attacked North African tourist sites before, seeing them as legitimate targets because they allow for a Western way of life and are tolerant of alcohol. Tunisia is one of the most secular countries in the Arab world.
Prime Minister Habib Essid said his government plans within a week to close down 80 mosques that remain outside state control, for inciting violence, and crack down on financing for certain associations, in order to counter jihadi rectruiters.
(Additional reporting by Tarek Amara; Writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Louise Ireland)
Tunisia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 08:52:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>One injured in shooting at San Francisco gay pride event</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/one-injured-shooting-san-francisco-gay-pride-event-055200259.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>One injured in shooting at San Francisco gay pride event
8 hours ago
.
View photo
People gather in Dallas to celebrate the US Supreme Court decision legalizing same-sex marriage on June 26, 2015 (AFP Photo/Laura Buckman)
San Francisco (AFP) - Shots were fired at a gay pride event in San Francisco, leaving one man injured, city police said.
The incident was believed to have occurred when several groups of men unrelated to the pride event "got in a verbal argument near or inside the venue," the San Francisco Police Department said in a statement.
The pride spectator who was shot was believed to be "unrelated to the dispute", SFPD officer Carlos Manfredi told AFP.
Police said the incident escalated "when one of the subjects pulled out a gun and fired several shots. One shot struck a pride spectator in the arm."
Several suspects have been detained, the statement added.
Police were alerted to the shooting, which occurred in the United Nations Plaza area, just after 6 pm (0100 GMT).
The 64-year-old victim was transported to San Francisco General Hospital where he is in stable condition, police said.
The city's gang task force, crime scene unit and night investigations unit are investigating the incident.
The shooting comes just one day after the US Supreme Court made same-sex marriage legal throughout the nation.
Company Legal &amp; Law Matters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:35:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European tour operators evacuate thousands from Tunisia after attack</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/european-tour-operators-evacuate-thousands-tunisia-attack-031316720--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>European tour operators evacuate thousands from Tunisia after attack
By Tarek Amara 5 hours ago
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f

Tourists flee Tunisia after deadly attack

Tourists flee Tunisia after deadly attack
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Tourists flee Tunisia after deadly attack
 Replay video
Greeks react to referendum green light

Load More
By Tarek Amara
SOUSSE, Tunisia (Reuters) - Tour companies were evacuating thousands of foreign holidaymakers from Tunisia on Saturday, a day after a gunman killed 39 people at a beach hotel in an attack claimed by Islamic State.
Tunisia's Prime Minister Habib Essid said most of the dead were British, and Britain's foreign office said 15 Britons had been confirmed killed in the attack in the resort town of Sousse, 140 km (90 miles) south of the capital Tunis.
A German, a Belgian and an Irish woman have also been identified, foreign and Tunisian officials said.
It was the second major attack in the North African country this year, following an Islamist militant assault on the Bardo Museum in Tunis in March when gunmen killed a group of foreign visitors as they arrived by bus.
Tunisia has undergone a largely peaceful transition to democracy since its 2011 Arab Spring uprising, but its army has been fighting a rise in Islamist militancy.
Tunisia's tourism minister called Friday's attack in one of the country's most popular resorts for Europeans a "catastrophe" and authorities vowed to toughen security, drafting in army reserves and arming tourism police at beaches and hotels.
Saloua Kadri, Sousse tourism commissioner, said more than 3,000 foreign tourists had fled the town on Saturday, including around 2,200 British and nearly 600 Belgians.
Dozens of tourists were waiting to take flights out from the nearby Ennfida airport.
"We don't want to stay any longer, we just want to see our family, parents ... so leaving as soon as possible," said Hannah Russel, an British tourist.
View gallery
<<<<<<< HEAD
A supporter of the Affordable Care Act celebrates after the Supreme Court up held the law in the 6-3
By James Oliphant
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Infuriated by a U.S. Supreme Court ruling that kept President Barack Obamas healthcare program intact, conservative activists and Republican presidential candidates vowed on Thursday to make the role of the high court a central issue in the 2016 presidential election.
Conservative ire was trained particularly on Chief Justice John Roberts, who wrote the majority opinion that preserved the subsidy regime underpinning the Affordable Care Act, even though another Republican appointee, Justice Anthony Kennedy, also voted with the majority.
Roberts, who was appointed to the court by Republican President George W. Bush, has voted with court conservatives on many landmark cases, including ones involving campaign-finance laws and voting rights.  But he also enraged opponents of the Affordable Care Act three years ago when he cast a deciding vote in rejecting a different legal challenge to the law.
Hes let down the [conservative] movement, said Curt Levey of the Committee for Justice, which advocates for conservative judicial nominees. He may feel he has no obligation to the movement.
Some conservatives have been skeptical of Roberts from the start, saying he was maddeningly opaque about his judicial philosophy during his 2005 Senate confirmation hearings. Roberts had spent only about two years  as a federal appeals court judge, which meant a sparse paper trail illuminating his judicial philosophy.
View gallery
Interns with media organizations run with the decision upholding the Affordable Care Act at the Supr
In opening remarks during his confirmation hearing before the U.S. Senate judiciary committee in 2005, Roberts spoke neutrally, noting that "Judges are not politicians who can promise to do certain things in exchange for votes" and vowing to "confront every case with an open mind."
We wanted to be supportive, but there were these nagging doubts, said Carrie Severino, policy director of the conservative Judicial Crisis Network. You cant assume someone is going to go south, but it appears the concerns were warranted. Its what happens when you nominate someone who doesnt have a clear record.
Levey said that the pressure will now fall on Republican presidential hopefuls to spell out in detail their views on court appointments - and simple generalities about being faithful to the letter of the U.S. Constitution wont cut it.
It might have been enough before today for presidential candidates to spout the usual things about appointing someone who interprets rather than writes the law. I think youll have to say more now, he said. Each candidate will have to do something to show the base how they will avoid appointing another Roberts.
Mark Levin, a frequent critic of the court who heads the conservative Landmark Legal Foundation, said Republican senators, too, will need to take their responsibility far more seriously and much more aggressively scrutinize these nominees.
Beyond that, Jay Sekulow, a prominent conservative lawyer who has argued a dozen cases before the high court, suggested that the healthcare ruling will prompt a debate on the presidential campaign trail over the justices proper function. What the court said that is that if legislation is written poorly, we can fix it, he said. Thats very different from the traditional role of the court.
Indeed, some Republican candidates were scathing Thursday in their assessment of the decision. Mike Huckabee, the former Republican governor of Arkansas, termed it an out-of-control act of judicial tyranny. Ted Cruz, the senator from Texas, accused the high court of usurping the role of Congress. Unelected judges have once again become legislators, and bad ones at that, he said.
In that vein, the ruling, along with a decision on the legality of same-sex marriage bans that could come as early as Friday, could hand Republicans a twin-barreled weapon with which to galvanize conservative voters into action. Four years ago, conversely, it was Democrats who made a Supreme Court ruling a centerpiece of their election message, blasting the courts decision in the Citizens United case, which opened the door for massive corporate campaign expenditures.
Obamas successor, whether Republican or Democrat, could play an outsized role in shaping the future of the court, said Severino. The next president could replace Justice [Ruth Bader] Ginsburg or possibly [Justices] Kennedy and Scalia, she said. It would be World War III in terms of the amount of influence that president would have.
(Additional reporting by Alana Wise in New York; Editing by Caren Bohan and Sue Horton)
Chief Justice John Roberts
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:23:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama to deliver eulogy Friday for slain South Carolina pastor</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/obama-deliver-eulogy-friday-slain-south-carolina-pastor-091039658.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Obama to deliver eulogy Friday for slain South Carolina pastor
By David Adams 3 hours ago

U.S. President Barack Obama  at the White House in Washington June 25, 2015.   REUTERS/Jonathan Erns
By David Adams
CHARLESTON, S.C. (Reuters) - South Carolina will take a step forward in healing the wounds of last week's mass shooting when President Barack Obama arrives on Friday to deliver the eulogy for the pastor of the historic church where the attack took place.
Reverend Clementa Pinckney, a widely admired state senator and pastor of Charleston's Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church, was among the nine people who died when a gunman opened fire during Bible study.
The massacre has sparked an intense dialogue across the southern United States over the legacy of slavery and its symbols, centering on the Civil War-era battle flag of the Confederacy.
Addressing the shooting last week, Obama said it raised questions "about a dark part of our history."
Nicknamed "Mother Emanuel," the Gothic Revival-style house of worship is the oldest A.M.E. church in the southeastern United States, and was founded by slaves.
View gallery
Louise Brown walks in the "March for Black Lives" after passing by the Emanuel African Met
In an unusual step, Obama will be accompanied by both First Lady Michele Obama and Vice President Joe Biden for the funeral in a Charleston college arena. All three knew Pinckney personally.
During his presidency, Obama has spoken at half a dozen memorial services for victims of mass shootings in Texas, Arizona, Colorado and Connecticut.
"Ive had to make statements like this too many times," a visibly upset Obama said from the White House last week. "Communities like this have had to endure tragedies like this too many times."
Obama repeated previous calls he has made for tougher gun laws, a politically thorny issue in the United States where the constitution guarantees the right to own guns.
"At some point, we as a country will have to reckon with the fact that this type of mass violence does not happen in other advanced countries. It doesnt happen in other places with this kind of frequency," he said.
View gallery
Gary Washington stands over the casket of his mother, Ethel Lance, as she is buried at the Emanuel A
Married with two children, Pinckney was a talented orator with a baritone voice and began preaching at 13. A Democrat, at 23 he became the youngest African-American in South Carolina history to be elected to the state legislature.
Several thousand turned out on Thursday evening for Pinckney's wake at Emanuel, the line of mourners stretching for three blocks, including 200 college fraternity brothers, friends, politicians and members of the public, both black and white.
"I cried when I got here," said Katharine Moseley, a Texas bus driver who drove 20 hours from Austin. "I was raised in the A.M.E. church."
Lutheran bishop Mike Rhyne also drove down with his wife and three children from central Pennsylvania to pay tribute to his friend and fellow seminary student. "He was one of the best men I have ever met," he said.
Pinckney's high school friends Kevin Riley, 41, and Lachandra Colbert, 42, traveled from Maryland for the funeral. "We wouldn't miss this. He was our classmate," said Riley. "He was on track to be someone really important," Riley added.
View gallery
Police lead suspected shooter Dylann Roof, 21, into the courthouse in Shelby, North Carolina, June 1
Mourners universally echoed the words of forgiveness by relatives of their slain churchgoers for the white man, Dylann Roof, accused of the murders.
"We are not the ones to judge, we leave that to God," said Maxine Frasier Riley, 65, a retired school guidance counselor.
The Department of Justice has opened a hate crime investigation into the shooting.
Roof posed with the Confederate flag in photos posted online and allegedly made racist remarks to his victims as he opened fire.
In the aftermath of the slayings, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley and other Republicans have called for the flag's removal from the State House grounds, saying it is divisive.
The controversy has spread across the country, with politicians adding to voices clamoring for the removal of Confederate symbols and names, and major retailers removing merchandise with Confederate images from stores and websites.
(Additonal reporting by Roberta Rampton in Washington and Harriet McLeod in Charleston; Editing by Nick Macfie)
Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:43:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. top court backs Obamacare, president says it's here to stay</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/supreme-court-upholds-key-obamacare-insurance-subsidies-141618866--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>U.S. top court backs Obamacare, president says it's here to stay
By Lawrence Hurley 15 hours ago
=======
A boy holds a candle and flowers as he attends a protest to condemn the attack by a gunman at the be
Sarah Maeson, another Briton flying back to Manchester, said: "We don't feel safe. Constantly hearing sirens and helicopters is not really helping your nerves."
EXTRA FLIGHTS
Tunisian authorities named the gunman as Saif Rezgui, a student who they say was not known to them. Dressed in shorts and T-shirt, Rezgui opened fire on the beach of the Imperial Marhaba hotel on Friday, picking out foreigners and leaving Tunisians alive.
Witnesses said he made his way to the pool and hotel, his killing spree ending only when he was shot dead by police.
Tour operators Thomson and First Choice, which are owned by German travel group TUI, said they had about 6,400 customers across Tunisia at the time of the attack, including several of the people killed and injured.
They sent 10 planes to evacuate tourists and said 1,000 had already been repatriated. They also said they would cancel all their holiday packages to Tunisia for at least the next week.
TUI's German tour operator TUI also organized flights for tourists wishing to return home and TUI's Belgian airline, Jetairfly, sent six empty planes to bring tourists back from the island of Djerba and from Ennfida airport on Saturday.
German Foreign Minister Frank-Walter Steinmeier confirmed one German had been killed, but said there may be others.
Tobias Ellwood, a junior minister at Britain's foreign office, told reporters in London the British death toll could rise as there were several who had been seriously wounded.
"This is the most significant terrorist attack on British people since 7/7," he said, referring to attacks on the London transport system on July 7, 2005, that killed 52 people.
NOT ON WATCHLIST
Tunisian authorities said the gunman was not on any watchlist of known potential militants. But one source said Rezgui appeared to have been radicalized over the last six months by Islamist militant recruiters.
As one countermeasure, Prime Minister Essid said that Tunisia planned within a week to close down 80 mosques that remain outside state control for inciting violence.
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have gone to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighboring Libya, where some have set up training camps and vowed to return to attack their homeland.
The attack took place during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan and was one of three linked to Islamist militants on three different continents on Friday.
In France, a decapitated body daubed with Arabic writing was found, and in Kuwait a suicide bomber killed two dozen people at a mosque in Kuwait.
(Additional reporting by Estelle Shirbon in London and Erik Kirschbaum in Berlin; Writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Susan Fenton and Raissa Kasolowsky)
Tunisia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 07:02:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>GOP White House hopefuls deride gay marriage ruling</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/court-decisions-highlight-political-challenges-facing-gop-070343735--election.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>GOP WH hopefuls deride gay marriage ruling
By KRISTEN WYATT 10 hours ago

View gallery
.
DENVER (AP)  Republican presidential candidate Mike Huckabee told conservatives Saturday that the Supreme Court tried to "unwrite the laws of nature and the laws of nature's God" when it legalized gay marriage across the nation.
The former Arkansas governor suggested that people in the United States flout the ruling, as President Abraham Lincoln did in the wake of the justices' 1857 decision that blacks could not be citizens. Huckabee also pointed out that President Barack Obama opposed gay marriage until 2012.
"He was either lying in 2008, or he's lying now, or God has rewritten the Bible and only Barack Obama has gotten the new edition," Huckabee told the crowd at the Western Conservative Summit.
Huckabee was among the GOP presidential hopefuls at the gathering, which followed a week in which the high court also upheld Obama's signature health care law. The Republicans offered few suggestions on what to do about the gay marriage ruling, highlighting the party's challenges on social issues ahead of the 2016 elections.
Joining Huckabee at the conference was Republican hopeful Carly Fiorina, who said she supports civil unions. She said opponents of the ruling should now focus efforts on religious freedom in public accommodations, such as cases of bakers facing penalties for refusing to serve gay couples.
Former Texas Gov. Rick Perry derided the ruling but didn't suggest a next step.
View gallery
Republican presidential candidate, Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal speaks to students and area business 
"These decisions need to be made in the states," said Perry, who noted that his states' rights plank extends even to Colorado legalizing recreational marijuana in defiance of federal drug law.
"I defend the right of Colorado to be wrong on that issue," Perry said. The crowd chuckled.
Wisconsin Gov. Scott Walker, who has called for a constitutional amendment to undo the marriage ruling, did not mention the ruling in his remarks late Saturday. He did talk broadly about judicial appointments when asked afterward by a moderator.
"The sole role of the judiciary ... is to uphold the Constitution of the United States and those laws duly enacted, no more, no less," Walker said to applause.
On Friday, former Pennsylvania Sen. Rick Santorum said the gay marriage ruling was "based on a lie" that gay-marriage opponents are motivated by discrimination.
"We have a Supreme Court that says the only reason that you could possibly oppose changing marriage laws in America is because you hate people who want to marry people of the same sex. That is not true," Santorum said.
Mike Huckabee
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:59:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Witnesses describe 'hell' of Taiwan water park blast</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/number-injured-taiwan-water-park-blast-rises-509-022510078.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Witnesses describe 'hell' of Taiwan water park blast
By Benjamin Yeh 4 hours ago
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f

.
.
Taipei (AFP) - Witnesses described the scene at a Taiwan water park as "hell" after a ball of fire ripped through a crowd, with authorities putting the injured at more than 500 on Sunday, almost 200 of them seriously hurt.
The injury toll in the blast late Saturday, which came as coloured powder being sprayed on the partygoers ignited, more than doubled as officials began to track down victims who had taken themselves to hospital or been ferried there by others.
Horrifying amateur video footage showed crowds of young revellers dancing in front of a stage and cheering as clouds of green and yellow powder covered them at the "colour party".
But their joy turned to terror when the powder suddenly erupted into flames engulfing them in an inferno as they ran screaming for their lives.
Some were dressed only in swimwear and images from the scene show many with severe burns being tended by those who escaped.
One male student who sustained minor injuries described the scene as "hell".
View gallery
People tend to an injured woman at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in the Pa
"There was blood everywhere, including in the pool where lots of the injured were soaking themselves for relief from the pain," he told reporters.
His visibly shaken girlfriend added: "I saw lots of people whose skin was gone."
Ambulances had struggled to reach the scene, and victims were carried away on rubber rings and inflatable dinghies as friends desperately tried to get them out.
Bystanders poured bottles of water on the scorched skin of the injured. Trails of bloody footprints leading away from the stage remained.
Around 1,000 spectators had been at the Color Play Asia event at the Formosa Fun Coast water park, just outside the capital Taipei, according to officials.
View gallery
<<<<<<< HEAD
Supporters of the Affordable Care Act celebrate after the Supreme Court up held the law in the 6-3 vote
By Lawrence Hurley
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The U.S. Supreme Court on Thursday rejected a conservative legal challenge that could have doomed President Barack Obama's healthcare law, upholding nationwide tax subsidies crucial to his signature domestic policy achievement.
Obama strode into the White House Rose Garden after the ruling to declare that the law known as Obamacare is working, helping millions of Americans afford health insurance who otherwise would have none, and that it is "here to stay."
Chief Justice John Roberts, a conservative appointed by Republican President George W. Bush, wrote in the 6-3 ruling that Congress clearly intended for the tax subsidies that help millions of low- and moderate-income people afford private health insurance to be available in all 50 states.
The court decided that the law did not restrict the subsidies to states that establish their own online health insurance exchanges, as the challengers in the case contended.
"Congress passed the Affordable Care Act to improve health insurance markets, not to destroy them," Roberts wrote, adding nationwide availability of the credits is required to "avoid the type of calamitous result that Congress plainly meant to avoid."
View gallery
U.S. President Barack Obama delivers remarks after the Supreme Court ruled 6-3 to uphold the nationw
Roberts was joined by fellow conservative Justice Anthony Kennedy and the court's four liberal members in a ruling that may ensure Obamacare becomes a lasting element of the nation's social programs.
The ruling means the current system will remain in place, with subsidies available nationwide. If the challengers had won, at least 6.4 million people in at least 34 states would have lost subsidies worth an average of $272 per month.
It marked the second time in three years the high court ruled against a major challenge to the law brought by conservatives. Both rulings were written by Roberts. Unlike the 2012 case, in which the court was split 5-4, Kennedy joined Roberts in the majority this time.
The law was passed by Obama's fellow Democrats in Congress in 2010 over the unified opposition of Republicans, who have fought it since its inception.
Republicans will keep attacking Obamacare in Congress and on the 2016 presidential election campaign trail to energize right-wing voters and raise money, but little chance exists of the law being rolled back before the end of Obama's presidency in January 2017, political analysts said.
Supporters of the Affordable Care Act celebrate after the Supreme Court up held the law in the 6-3 v
Obama said the law has been "woven into the fabric of America."
"After more than 50 votes in Congress to repeal or weaken this law, after a presidential election based in part on preserving or repealing this law, after multiple challenges to this law before the Supreme Court, the Affordable Care Act is here to stay," Obama added.
The question before the justices was whether a four-word phrase in the expansive law saying subsidies are available to those buying insurance on exchanges "established by the state" has been correctly interpreted by the administration to allow subsidies to be available nationwide.
The exchanges are online marketplaces that allow consumers to shop among competing insurance plans.
Roberts wrote that although the conservative challengers' arguments about the plain meaning of the statute were "strong,' the "context and structure of the act compel us to depart from what would otherwise be the most natural reading of the pertinent statutory phrase."
Supporters of the Affordable Care Act celebrate after the Supreme Court up held the law in the 6-3 v
SCALIA DISSENTS
After Chief Justice Roberts announced the decision from the bench, Justice Antonin Scalia read for 11 minutes from his dissenting opinion inside the court's white marble and crimson-draped setting.
Scalia said the statute's words were clear, that Congress wanted to limit the credits to the state exchanges. Scalia recalled the court's 2012 decision upholding the law, again over his dissent.
"We really should start calling the law SCOTUScare," Scalia said. SCOTUS is the acronym for the Supreme Court of the United States.
"This court has no free-floating power to rescue Congress from its drafting mistakes," Scalia added.
View gallery
Interns with media organizations run with the decision upholding the Affordable Care Act at the Supr
Roberts, sitting next to him on the bench, sat stone-faced. He smiled slightly at the SCOTUScare line, but otherwise betrayed no emotion.
Conservative Justices Clarence Thomas and Samuel Alito joined Scalia's dissent.
The Obama administration said 16.4 million previously uninsured people have gained health insurance since the law was enacted. There are currently around 26 million Americans without health insurance, according to government figures.
"This is not about the Affordable Care Act as legislation, or Obamacare as a political football. This is healthcare in America," Obama said.
Congressional Republicans vowed to continue efforts to repeal Obamacare despite appeals from Democrats for them to stop.
The top two congressional Republicans denounced the law on Thursday. Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnnell said it makes life "miserable" for many people it purports to help. House of Representatives Speaker John Boehner called it "fundamentally broken."
The U.S. hospital industry breathed a collective sigh of relief on Thursday and investors cheered that the growing number of paying customers created by Obamacare would not disappear.
The ruling sparked a broad rally in shares of health insurers with an especially heavy stampede into hospital operators, which were seen as being at particular risk of facing steep losses had the subsidies been struck down.
Shares of hospital chain Tenet Healthcare surged 12.2 percent to rank as the biggest gainer for the day in the S&amp;P 500. Four other hospital operators' shares hit lifetime highs: Community Health Systems, HCA Holdings, Universal Health Services and Lifepoint Health, with gains ranging from 7.6 percent to nearly 13 percent.
Conservatives have called Obamacare a government overreach and "socialized medicine" and launched a series of legal challenges.
The current case started as a long-shot by conservative lawyers opposed to law. Financed by a libertarian Washington group called the Competitive Enterprise Institute, the lawyers recruited four people from Virginia as plaintiffs. The lead plaintiff was a self-employed limousine driver named David King.
The plaintiffs said they were "deeply disappointed" with the ruling. The law "unfairly restricts the health insurance choices of millions of people, and it threatens their jobs as well," they added.
The case is King v. Burwell, U.S. Supreme Court, No. 14-114.
(Additional reporting by Joan Biskupic and Susan Cornwell in Washington and Dan Burns in New York; Editing by Will Dunham)
Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>2015 NBA draft winners and losers</title>
        <Link>http://sports.yahoo.com/news/2015-nba-draft-winners-and-losers-062658169.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>LOSER: JAHLIL OKAFOR
Former Duke center Jahlil Okafor appeared to be the biggest competition for Kentucky forward Karl-Anthony Towns for the top pick in the draft. It was projected that if Okafor wasn't selected by Minnesota, that the Los Angeles Lakers would take him with the second overall pick.
Minnesota took Towns as expected. Lakers general manager Mitch Kupchak, however, never made Okafor a draft promise for good reason. Kupchak was quietly enamored with Ohio State guard D'Angelo Russell and selected him second.
Okafor ended up with the rebuilding Sixers with the third pick. Okafor was the best talent on the board and a surprise option for Philadelphia. Even so, the Sixers have drafted a center for the third year in a row after taking Nerlens Noel and still-injured Joel Embiid the past two seasons.
When asked how the Sixers can make it work with three young centers, Okafor said: "I don't know. It's not my job to figure out. I'll go there and work as hard as I can."
WINNER: MINNESOTA TIMBERWOLVES
The T'wolves filled their biggest roster need by taking Towns with the first overall pick. He joins an intriguing group of young teammates that includes 2015 Rookie of the Year Andrew Wiggins , 2015 dunk champion Zach LaVine , injury-plagued guard Ricky Rubio , center Gorgui Dieng and forward Shabazz Muhammad . Minnesota also acquired the draft rights to Duke point guard Tyus Jones , a Minneapolis native who was the 2015 NCAA Final Four Most Outstanding Player.
Towns should be the next great power forward in T'wolves history after Kevin Garnett and Kevin Love . He also has the challenge of trying to get Minnesota to the postseason for the first time since 2004.
"That's going to be the main goal of the season for me, making the playoffs," Towns said.
View gallery
DeMarcus Cousins remains with the Kings, for now. (Getty Images)
LOSER: SACRAMENTO KINGS
The Sacramento Kings have had one of the least memorable weeks in franchise history, which is very hard to accomplish. Yahoo Sports' Adrian Wojnarowski reported that coach George Karl would like All-Star center DeMarcus Cousins to be traded. New general manager Vlade Divac and owner Vivek Ranadive maintain they don't want to trade Cousins. A disgruntled Cousins was not dealt on draft night but could be later, a source said. The Lakers had talks with the Kings leading up to the draft.
The biggest need in recent years for the Kings has been a point guard. Sacramento passed on All-Rookie Team point guard Elfrid Payton a year ago in the draft. On Thursday, the Kings had a chance to select perhaps the best true point guard in the draft in Emmanuel Mudiay with the sixth pick. Sacramento, however, passed because Divac said Mudiay refused to work out for the Kings. The Kings took Kentucky forward-center Willie Cauley-Stein instead.
Mudiay "refused to come here and work out and I just felt I didn't know him enough to make that very important decision," Divac told reporters in Sacramento.
Back in 2009, there was a talented point guard prospect who refused to work out for the Warriors, but former general manager Larry Harris drafted him seventh overall anyway. The point guard's name was Stephen Curry.
WINNER: PORTLAND TRAIL BLAZERS
It appears that Blazers free agent LaMarcus Aldridge has played his last game in Portland. The San Antonio Spurs and Los Angeles Lakers are the front-runners to land the All-Star, a source told Yahoo Sports. The Dallas native is also expected to have interest from the Dallas Mavericks.
That's not good news for the Blazers. But in preparation for the expected departure, they acquired two forwards in trades: Mason Plumlee from the Brooklyn Nets; and Noah Vonleh from the Charlotte Hornets.
The Blazers acquired Plumlee and the draft rights to Notre Dame guard Pat Connaughton for the draft rights of Rondae Hollis-Jefferson and guard Steve Blake. Plumlee averaged 11.8 points and 7.6 rebounds in 45 games as a starter last season. Vonleh, acquired on Wednesday, was the ninth pick of last year's draft and was limited to 25 games primarily because of injury. Plumlee and Vonleh don't combine to be Aldridge by any means, but at least Blazers general manager Neil Olshey is being proactive.
LOSER: KEVON LOONEY
Former UCLA forward Kevon Looney entered the draft with two major red flags: a hip injury and sports asthma. While Looney was projected to be middle to late first-round pick, it's inevitable that such issues would hurt one's status. Even so, Looney was one of 20 prospects selected for the draft's green room with a late invitation from the NBA.
Late in the first round, however, Looney, his family and his agent Todd Ramasar abruptly departed from the room for the depths of the Barclays Center when the forward's prospects looked in doubt. But once Looney and his family received word that the champion Golden State Warriors were selecting him with the 30th and final pick of the first round, they rushed back to the green room to sit down and enjoy the once-in-a-lifetime moment in front of the TV cameras. After the Warriors' pick was announced, Looney hugged his family but turned his back on his agent who reached out to him.
Chalk this up to a tough and emotional night for the 19-year-old, who has a reputation as a good person.
WINNER: SATNAM SINGH BHAMARA
Satnam Singh Bhamara became the first Indian-born player to be drafted in the NBA when the Dallas Mavericks took him with the 52nd overall pick in the second round. The mammoth 7-foot-2, 290-pounder heard of his selection while sitting in the stands. He is considered a big project who will likely begin his career with the Mavericks' NBA Development League Texas Legends.
More NBA draft coverage:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Timberwolves select Karl-Anthony Towns with No. 1 pick in NBA draft</title>
        <Link>http://sports.yahoo.com/blogs/nba-ball-dont-lie/minnesota-timberwolves-select-karl-anthony-towns-with-no--1-pick-in-2015-nba-draft-214703304.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Content preferences
Done
NEW YORK  There might not have been a promise in place , but there's no longer any question that Flip Saunders sees immense, franchise-changing promise in the 6-foot-11-inch, 250-pound frame of Karl-Anthony Towns . The Minnesota Timberwolves head coach and president of basketball operations removed any lingering doubt on Thursday night, selecting the former University of Kentucky big man with the No. 1 overall pick in the 2015 NBA draft at Barclays Center in Brooklyn.
[ Follow Dunks Don't Lie on Tumblr: The best slams from all of basketball]
"For me, I'm just blessed to be in this opportunity to just show that a boy from Piscataway, N.J., and the Dominican Republic can make it," Towns said during his post-selection press conference. "I'm blessed to be in this situation, to be in this seat talking to all of you. It just means the world that I'm going to be able to show kids around the world that with a little hard work, determination, a little bit of luck and some guidance, you can really make it far in this world."
To be fair, there wasn't very much lingering doubt about Towns. The 19-year-old had long been considered one of the top prospects in the class of 2015. He averaged 10.3 points, 6.7 rebounds, 2.3 blocks and 1.1 assists in 21.1 minutes per game at Kentucky, playing comparatively limited minutes for an insanely deep squad that won its first 38 games before falling to Wisconsin in the Final Four.
Even while surrounded by stars in Lexington, Towns stood out as something special in the making, earning a slew of honors during his lone collegiate season  SEC Freshman of the Year, an All-SEC First Team nod, an All-American Second Team selection  and joining the likes of Duke center Jahlil Okafor and Ohio State guard D'Angelo Russell in the running for the No. 1 spot. As the pre-draft process progressed, though, Towns separated himself from even his future-star peers.
Talent evaluators grew increasingly enamored with Towns' immediate and evident gifts on the defensive end, where he proved capable under John Calipari of stalling pick-and-rolls in space, defending the rim in the paint and cleaning the defensive glass. And as the workouts wore on, the videos kept coming, with Towns comfortably stepping out to the perimeter with a smooth touch that pairs well with the interior game he showed with the Wildcats.
Suddenly, a clearer, more expansive and far more enticing picture began to emerge. When you stepped back and took a look, you saw something that seemed an awful lot like the ideal power forward/center for the state of NBA play in 2015.
Towns topped many mock drafts even before May's draft lottery, which saw the Wolves win the No. 1 pick for the first time in franchise history, their reward for finishing a Western Conference-worst 16-66 in a down and dismal 2014-15 campaign. While Saunders was reportedly enamored of the polished low-post game of Duke's Okafor, he ultimately preferred the opportunity to pair Towns' two-way potential with that of reigning Rookie of the Year Andrew Wiggins , the No. 1 pick in last year's draft , to lead Minnesota into the future alongside playmaking point guard Ricky Rubio , electric skywalking swingman Zach LaVine and a group of young complementary pieces on a Wolves team that could soon be ready to run.
Towns steps into a high-profile frontcourt spot previously occupied by the likes of franchise legend and future Hall of Famer Kevin Garnett , who returned to Minnesota at last year's trade deadline and whose status for next season remains unclear, and former All-Star Kevin Love , whom Saunders traded to the Cleveland Cavaliers last summer in a blockbuster deal that returned Wiggins and 2013 No. 1 pick Anthony Bennett . The young fella's got some pretty big shoes to fill. It's a good thing he's got pretty big feet .
"The craziest thing about those two power forwards, I think you can see some resemblance of me in both of them," Towns recently told Yahoo Sports NBA columnist Marc J. Spears . "They've shown how effective they were in Minnesota. I'm trying to make my own stamp."
One thing's for sure  Towns won't lack for confidence as he sets about the work of giving the Twin Cities faithful a winning team to support after 10 straight sub-.500 seasons, no playoff berths since 2004 and just one trip past the opening round of the playoffs in the franchise's 26-year history.
"It doesn't matter to me where I play," Towns recently told Jon Krawczynski of The Associated Press . "It matters what you do at the place you play at. It doesn't matter how successful or how unsuccessful a team is. It can all change with one pick."
Saunders, the rest of the Timberwolves brass and fans across Minnesota are banking on Towns being that one pick.
"That's going to be the main goal of the season for me, making the playoffs," Towns said Thursday. "[...] We're going to work real hard right now in the summer, get everything straight, and we're going to make sure that we go into the season with the best possible team, with the best mindset, and go out there and try to win and make it to the playoffs."
- - - - - - -
Dan Devine is an editor for Ball Don't Lie on Yahoo Sports. Have a tip? Email him at devine@yahoo-inc.com or follow him on Twitter!
Stay connected with Ball Don't Lie on Twitter @YahooBDL , "Like" BDL on Facebook and follow Dunks Don't Lie on Tumblr for year-round NBA talk, jokes and more.
Minnesota Timberwolves
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:10:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>15 emails missing from Clinton cache</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/state-dept-15-emails-missing-clinton-cache-221215204--politics.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>.
View photo
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Rodham Clinton speaks during a campaign stop at Christ the King United Church of Christ, Tuesday, June 23, 2015, in Florissant, Mo. (AP Photo/Jeff Roberson)
WASHINGTON (AP)  The State Department cannot find in its records all or part of 15 work-related emails from Hillary Rodham Clinton's private server that were released this week by a House panel investigating the 2012 attack in Benghazi, Libya, officials said Thursday.
The emails all predate the Sept. 11 assault on the U.S. diplomatic facility and include scant words written by Clinton herself, the officials said. They consist of more in a series of would-be intelligence reports passed to her by longtime political confidant Sidney Blumenthal, the officials said.
Nevertheless, the fact that the State Department says it can't find them among emails she provided surely will raise new questions about Clinton's use of a personal email account and server while secretary of state and whether she has provided the agency all of her work-related correspondence, as she claims.
Rep. Trey Gowdy, chairman of the Select Committee on Benghazi, released a statement Thursday saying, "This confirms doubts about the completeness of Clinton's self-selected public record and raises serious questions about her decision to erase her personal server  especially before it could be analyzed by an independent, neutral third-party arbiter."
When asked about the discrepancy, Nick Merrill, a Clinton campaign spokesman, said, "She has turned over 55,000 pages of materials to the State Department, including all emails in her possession from Mr. Blumenthal."
Clinton is running for the 2016 Democratic presidential nomination.
Clinton's use of the non-governmental email while in office was not publicly disclosed until earlier this year, after the committee sought her correspondence related to the Benghazi attack. She says the single account for personal and professional purposes was a matter of convenience, and says all her work emails were included in the 55,000 pages of documents she later handed over to the State Department. Emails of a personal nature were destroyed, she says.
The State Department informed the Select Benghazi Committee on Thursday that they are no longer certain that's the case, according to officials who spoke on condition of anonymity because they weren't authorized to speak publicly on the matter. The officials said Julia Frifield, the assistant secretary of state for legislative affairs, confirmed that nine emails and parts of six others that the committee made public Monday couldn't be located in the department's records.
As for 46 other, previously unreleased Libya-related Blumenthal emails published by the committee, officials said all are in the department's records. They weren't handed over to congressional investigators because they had no relevance to events in Benghazi and did not correspond to the committee's request, the officials said. The officials added that they are willing to provide emails outside the committee's initial request, but warned that doing so would require more time.
The emails missing from the State Department's records include missives from Blumenthal in which he sends media accounts about the killing of one of Libyan dictator Moammar Gadhafi's sons, various reports on internal politics among Libya's rebels and news of the assassination of a former Gadhafi minister in Vienna. The last email was sent Aug. 28, 2012, two weeks before the Benghazi attack, and none focus particularly on the eastern Libyan city.
Clinton's responses are brief. In one from August 2011, she tells Blumenthal she will be in Paris the next day to meet rebel leaders and says she had "to resort to new iPad" because she didn't have electricity or Blackberry coverage after Hurricane Irene.
In another from March 2012, she passes on an adviser's skepticism regarding one of Blumenthal's reports about political intrigue in post-Gadhafi Libya, saying: "This strain credulity based on what I know. Any other info about it?"
And after a long August 2012 note from Blumenthal about Libya's new interim President Mohamed Yousef el-Magariaf, Clinton writes: "Another keeper  thanks and please keep 'em coming." Four days later, she responds to a follow-up reports about el-Magariaf, saying: "Fascinating. I had a very good call w him."
Clinton's critics are likely to focus less on the substance of the emails than on the fact that they weren't shared with the State Department.
Gowdy, a South Carolina Republican, has pressed for an explanation of why Blumenthal gave the committee emails not previously shared by the State Department. The suggestion has been that either the department or Clinton was hiding something.
Gowdy said Thursday that the emails show Clinton "was soliciting and regularly corresponding with Sidney Blumenthal  who was passing unvetted intelligence information about Libya from a source with a financial interest in the country. It just so happens these emails directly contradict her public statement that the messages from Blumenthal were unsolicited."
Clinton aides say her submission to the department included all emails from Blumenthal and a dozen more exchanges that weren't in the records he provided the House committee. They said some from Blumenthal's record, which was provided as a Microsoft Word document, couldn't be confirmed as having been sent as emails.
State Department officials also questioned the provenance of some exchanges because they weren't formatted as emails.
___
This story corrects the breakdown of missing emails to nine full emails and parts of six others.
Hillary Rodham Clinton
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>SCOTUS Obamacare ruling: 2016 presidential candidates weigh in</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/scotus-obamacare-2016-candidates-react-122431771361.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Skrillex: The making of a superstar</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/katie-couric-exclusive-edm-superstar-skrillex-152210272.html?soc_src=mail&amp;soc_trk=ma</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Complete interview
By Katie Brinn and Andrew Rothschild
He introduces himself as Sonny Moore, but to his millions of young fans, hes Skrillex  one of the biggest names in electronic dance music (EDM). Since he first found success as an EDM DJ and producer in 2011, Skrillex has collected six Grammys, 19 million Facebook fans and an estimated $20 million  all while giving away most of his music for free.
And at just 27 years old  an age he characterizes as not young  he says he has no plans of slowing down. The EDM prodigy is churning out new collaborations with superstars both inside and outside his genre, testing the limits of his craft  and his fan base  with every new innovation.
One of his boldest, and perhaps most polarizing new partners: pop heartthrob Justin Bieber. Moore and fellow EDM DJ Diplo, under the moniker Jack , teamed up with the Biebs in early 2015 to produce the single Where Are  Now. The track quickly shot to the top of mainstream charts, drawing the ire of some EDM fans who were vocal with their criticism that Skrillex was selling out.
Yahoo global news anchor Katie Couric met up with Moore at his studio in downtown L.A. to give him a chance to respond to the criticism and to take a rare, intimate look into the life and career of one of EDMs biggest stars.
Working with Bieber
He was super-polite, Moore says of his first encounter with Justin Bieber at a party at New York Fashion Week earlier this year. The rest was history. Teaming up as Jack , Skrillex and Diplo worked on Biebers a cappella vocal track to make a hit that few of his fans saw coming.
Childhood of music and Scientology
Sporting a hardcore look from an early age, Moore says he is no stranger to being misunderstood. Youre always bullied if youre an emo kid, he admits. But he says his parents were always supportive of his alternative style and his unconventional ambitions.
The family hit a rough patch when Moore learned at age 16 that his parents had adopted him. He says his music helped him get through that period and has helped as he deals with another trial his family is now facing: the recent death of his mother. He talks about his relationship with her, how his family has come together to mourn and how Scientology has long helped his family cope with hardship.
EDM, drugs and that hairdo
Of course, its impossible to ignore the drug culture that goes hand in hand with EDMs rave scene, a scene Skrillex has so helped to define. Some critics, in fact, have linked the rise of Molly to Skrillexs ascent. Though he emphasizes that he would never want to be telling kids how to run their lives, Skrillex insists that he never uses drugs. I wouldnt be able to do 300 shows a year if I was doing drugs, he says.
Amid their conversation, Couric and Skrillex take a phone call from a special guest star, Marshmello, a mysterious EDM newcomer whose identity remains top secret. Until now, fans have even been unsure whether the rising star is a man or a woman.
Before wrapping up their chat, Skrillex gets a chance to comment on the origins of his signature haircut and muse about what his life might look like in 10 years.
Skrillex ft. Katie Couric
Not to outdo Justin Bieber, Skrillex and Couric decide there is room for one more unlikely EDM collaboration. Together, they hit the studio to churn out what could be a pretty sweet hit. Check out the final product.
Arts &amp; Entertainment
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 14:19:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Obama legacy on race</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/the-obama-legacy-on-race-president-barack-obama-122362581601.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:43:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French anti-Uber protests turn violent</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/french-cabbies-angry-uber-block-paris-airports-roads-103556123.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>The paternoster is a doorless, conveyor-belt-style elevator that is largely extinct, except in Germany, where enthusiasts have kept the lifts running. Photo: Ellen Jervell/The Wall Street Journal
Load More
Paris (AFP) - Protests against ride-booking app Uber turned violent in France on Thursday as taxi drivers set fire to vehicles and blocked major roads.
American rocker Courtney Love was caught up in the demonstrations when a vehicle she was travelling in outside Paris was attacked.
Around 3,000 cabbies took part in the strike, blocking access to the capital's Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports, and preventing cars reaching train stations around the country.
Ten people were arrested, seven police officers were injured and 70 vehicles were damaged in clashes between Uber drivers and taxi drivers.
The service, known as UberPOP, has been illegal in France since January, but the law has proved difficult to enforce and it continues to operate.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said after meeting taxi drivers' unions following a fraught day: "UberPOP is an illegal service, it must be closed down."
Until that was done, "the vehicles of UberPOP drivers should be systematically impounded when they are openly breaking the law", the minister said.
"Governing the country will never be done by the law of the jungle," Cazeneuve added.
One of the taxi drivers' representatives, Ibrahima Sylla, described the minister's words as "promises, again" and said the drivers were considering continuing the demonstrations.
Love, Kurt Cobain's widow, was caught up in a confrontation near Charles de Gaulle airport.
She tweeted that protesters "ambushed" her vehicle and "were holding our driver hostage".
She appealed to the French president in another message, writing "Francois Hollande where are the fucking police???"
French taxi drivers burn tyres during a protest against taxi app Uber in the southern city of Marsei
"This is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad," she added.
- Two vehicles torched -
In the most serious incident in Paris, one private chauffeur, who said he did not work for Uber "or any other app" was dragged from his van when he reached a blockade in the west of Paris.
Angry taxi drivers slashed the tyres of his vehicle, smashed a window and then set it and a chauffeur-driven van on fire.
Police eventually fired teargas to break up the protest on the western stretch of the ring road around the capital and cleared burning tyres.
Prime Minister Manuel Valls said during a visit to Colombia that the perpetrators of the "unacceptable" violence "can be found in both camps" and they would be found and prosecuted.
Taxi drivers are furious at what they see as unfair competition from Uber, which puts customers in touch with private drivers at prices lower than those of traditional taxis.
Licensed cabbies say the service is endangering their jobs by flooding the market with low-cost drivers.
One driver said the strikers had been driven to desperation.
"Taxi drivers -- alright, they've got big mouths -- but normally they're not aggressive," said Malia, 50, who has driven a taxi for three years.
"But these guys have families to feed, debts. They've been pushed to the brink."
- Illegal in France -
More peaceful protests took place at transport hubs in other major cities including Bordeaux, Marseille and Toulouse.
Cabbies argued that the disruption was justified.
"UberPOP is banned, but it's still here," cabbie Stephane Molla said in Bordeaux, southwest France.
Cabbies in France, like their colleagues in several other countries, have held several protests against the app -- some of which have turned violent.
On at least two occasions in Strasbourg in eastern France last week, taxi drivers posed as customers in order to lure Uber drivers to isolated spots where they were assaulted by cab drivers and their vehicles damaged.
In Paris, the government tried to strengthen its hand on Wednesday by obtaining a court order banning Uber from operating in the capital, but the company dismissed the move.
"We will fight it (in the courts) and we'll see what happens on appeal. For the time being it changes nothing, UberPOP can continue to operate," the head of Uber France, Thibaud Simphal, told the BFM Business channel.
San Francisco-based Uber, which offers several types of ride-sharing services, claims to have 400,000 UberPOP users in France.
However, its drivers do not pay taxes, do not need to undergo the 250 hours of training mandatory for French cabbies and do not require the same insurance as taxis.
Uber
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:21:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds Obamacare subsidies</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/supreme-court-upholds-obamacare-subsidies-122340028541.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:20:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What does SCOTUS Obamacare ruling mean?</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/what-does-scotus-obamacare-ruling-mean--142038782.html</Link>
=======
Bloody footprints are seen on the pavement after an explosion at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement par
One male witness told local news channel CTI: "It started on the left side of the stage. At the beginning I thought it was part of the special effects of the party but then I realised there was something wrong and people started screaming and running."
Lee Lih-jong, deputy chief of the health bureau of the New Taipei City government, said 519 people had been injured with 190 of them seriously hurt.
The severely wounded are being treated in intensive care units at 37 different hospitals.
"The reason why the burns were so severe was that in addition to burns to the skin, there were also injuries caused by burns to the respiratory organs from the large amount of colour powder inhaled," Lee told AFP.
"The next 24 hours will be critical for those severely injured."
View gallery
Local officials walk at the site of an explosion at a water park in Pali district, in New Taipei Cit
Several major hospitals in Taiwan have been asked to donate skin grafts and surgical equipment to help treat the injured, the Ministry of Health and Welfare said.
- Young victims -
One father broke down as he told how his daughter was in intensive care with third degree burns.
"She was attending a music concert... why would there be an explosion?" he wept bewildered.
"More than 80 percent of her body has been scorched," he told reporters.
View gallery
Overturned tables lie on the ground at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in th
The man, who was not named, lashed out at authorities saying they had not contacted him or offered any help.
The water park issued a statement Sunday saying it was "deeply saddened" and would cooperate with the ongoing investigation.
General manager Chen Hui-ying told reporters that all partygoers had been insured but did not say to what amount.
"Throwing coloured corn starch around... we had never heard such an activity could be dangerous," she said.
The health bureau's Lee said details of the ages of the victims were not yet available, "but all looked very young, in their 20s or even younger".
The national news agency CNA reported 13 of the injured were foreign nationals.
Among them were four from Hong Kong, two each from China and Japan, one from Macau, Malaysia and Singapore respectively, with another being identified as from "Europe or America" and the last remained of unknown origin.
"Our initial understanding is this explosion and fire... was caused by the powder spray. It could have been due to the heat of the lights on the stage," said a spokesman for the New Taipei City fire department.
Deputy fire chief Chen Chung-yueh said Sunday the blast may have been caused by "sparks from machinery or lighting equipment".
Five people including event manager Lu Chung-chi were detained by police.
They are being questioned by prosecutors on charges of offences against public safety and negligence of duties that caused severe injuries, a police spokesman said.
Color Play Asia has also run other "colour parties" in Taiwan in the past two years.
Taiwan's premier Mao Chih-kuo, who visited the injured Sunday, ordered that all such events be banned unless their safety could be assured.
Taiwan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 11:58:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Landmark U.S. Supreme Court ruling legalizes gay marriage nationwide</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/supreme-courts-landmark-ruling-legalizes-gay-marriage-nationwide-013612550.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Landmark U.S. Supreme Court ruling legalizes gay marriage nationwide
By Lawrence Hurley June 27, 2015 4:58 AM

Glenda Vieira, (L) Mary Ayers and Tina Vieira celebrate the United States Supreme Court's landmark
By Lawrence Hurley
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The Supreme Court ruled on Friday that the U.S. Constitution provides same-sex couples the right to marry, handing a historic triumph to the American gay rights movement.
The court ruled 5-4 that the Constitution's guarantees of due process and equal protection under the law mean that states cannot ban same-sex marriages. With the landmark ruling, gay marriage becomes legal in all 50 states.
Immediately after the decision, same-sex couples in many of the states where gay marriage had been banned headed to county clerks' offices for marriage licenses as officials in several states said they would respect the ruling.
President Barack Obama, appearing in the White House Rose Garden, hailed the ruling as a milestone in American justice that arrived "like a thunderbolt."
"This ruling is a victory for America," said Obama, the first sitting president to support gay marriage. "This decision affirms what millions of Americans already believe in their hearts. When all Americans are treated as equal, we are all more free."
View gallery
Dakota Greene, 24, (top) and Dillon Field, 29, celebrate at a rally in West Hollywood, California, U
As night fell, the White House was lit in rainbow colors - a symbol of gay pride - to mark the high court's decision.
The ruling, the culmination of a long legal fight by gay rights advocates, follows steady gains in public approval in recent years for same-sex marriage. In 2004 Massachusetts became the first state to legalize gay marriage. But the decision may provoke fresh legal fights in some conservative, Republican-governed states.
Justice Anthony Kennedy, writing on behalf of the court, said the hope of gay people intending to marry "is not to be condemned to live in loneliness, excluded from one of civilization's oldest institutions. They ask for equal dignity in the eyes of the law. The Constitution grants them that right."
"Without the recognition, stability and predictability marriage offers, their children suffer the stigma of knowing their families are somehow lesser," Kennedy wrote.
Kennedy, a conservative who often casts the deciding vote in close cases, was joined in the majority by the court's four liberal justices.
View gallery
Stacy Wood, (L) and her wife Michele Barr leave San Francisco City Hall after getting married in San
Appointed by Republican President Ronald Reagan in 1988, Kennedy has now authored all four of the court's major gay rights rulings, with the first in 1996.
The ruling is the Supreme Court's most important expansion of marriage rights in the United States since its landmark 1967 ruling in the case Loving v. Virginia that struck down state laws barring interracial marriages.
At least two states, Louisiana and Mississippi, said they would not immediately issue marriage licenses to same-sex couples while awaiting legal formalities. Supreme Court rulings generally take 25 days to go into effect.
"THREAT TO AMERICAN DEMOCRACY"
In a blistering dissenting opinion, conservative Justice Antonin Scalia said the decision shows the court is a "threat to American democracy." The ruling "says that my ruler and the ruler of 320 million Americans coast-to-coast is a majority of the nine lawyers on the Supreme Court," Scalia added.
View gallery
Hundreds of people celebrate the United States Supreme Court's landmark decision that legalized 
Conservative Chief Justice John Roberts read a summary of his dissent from the bench, the first time he has done so in his 10 years on the court. Roberts said although there are strong policy arguments in same-sex marriage, it was not the court's role to force states to change their marriage laws.
"Five lawyers have closed the debate and enacted their own vision of marriage as a matter of constitutional law," Roberts wrote.
The dissenters raised concerns about the impact of the case on people opposed to same-sex marriage on religious grounds.
While the ruling only affects state laws and religious institutions can still choose whether to marry same-sex couples, Roberts predicted future legal conflicts.
"Hard questions arise when people of faith exercise religion in ways that may be seen to conflict with the new right to same-sex marriage," Roberts said.
View gallery
Gay rights supporters celebrate after the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that the U.S. Constitution provid
There were 13 state bans in place, while another state, Alabama, had contested a court ruling that lifted the ban there.
The ruling is the latest milestone in the gay rights movement. In 2010, Obama signed a law allowing gays to serve openly in the U.S. military. In 2013, the high court ruled unconstitutional a 1996 U.S. law that declared for the purposes of federal benefits marriage was defined as between one man and one woman.
Reaction came swiftly. James Obergefell, the Ohio man who was the lead plaintiff in the case, told a cheering crowd outside the Supreme Court, "Today's ruling from the Supreme Court affirms what millions across this country already know to be true in our hearts - our love is equal, that the four words etched onto the front of the Supreme Court - equal justice under law - apply to us, too."
Obama telephoned Obergefell to offer congratulations.
Hundreds of gay rights supporters celebrated outside the courthouse with whoops and cries of "U-S-A!" and "Love is love" as the decision came down.
View gallery
Rodrigo Zamora (L) and Ashby Hardesty pose together for friends at the New York City clerks office a
In Ann Arbor, Michigan, another of the plaintiffs, April DeBeor, told cheering supporters, "To my beautiful children, we did this for you," referring to her adopted children.
"Love won," added popular comedian and talk show host Ellen DeGeneres, who is gay.
"JUDICIAL TYRANNY"
Conservatives denounced the ruling. Republican presidential candidate Mike Huckabee called it "an out-of-control act of unconstitutional judicial tyranny."
Wisconsin Republican Governor Scott Walker, who is expected to run for president, called for amending the U.S. Constitution to allow states to again ban same-sex marriage. Texas Republican Governor Greg Abbott said, "Marriage was defined by God. No man can redefine it."
View gallery
Gay rights supporters celebrate after the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that the U.S. Constitution provid
Archbishop Joseph Kurtz of Louisville, Kentucky, president of the U.S. Conference of Catholic Bishops, said, "It is profoundly immoral and unjust for the government to declare that two people of the same sex can constitute a marriage."
Opponents say same-sex marriage's legality should be decided by states, not judges. Some opponents argue it is an affront to traditional marriage between a man and a woman and that the Bible condemns homosexuality.
Gay marriage is also gaining acceptance in other Western countries. Last month in Ireland, voters backed same-sex marriage by a landslide in a referendum that marked a dramatic social shift in the traditionally Roman Catholic country.
Ireland followed several Western European countries including Britain, France and Spain in allowing gay marriage, which is also legal in South Africa, Brazil and Canada. But homosexuality remains taboo and often illegal in many parts of Africa and Asia.
The Supreme Court's ruling came in a consolidated case pulling together challenges filed by same-sex couples to gay marriage bans in Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Tennessee.
The Obama administration argued on the side of the same-sex marriage advocates.
(Additional reporting by Joan Biskupic, Megan Cassella, Bill Trott, Fiona Ortiz, Mary Wisniewski, Ben Klayman, Ayesha Rascoe, Jon Herskovitz, Lindsay Dunsmuir, Any Sullivan and Roberta Rampton; Editing by Will Dunham and Leslie Adler)
Supreme Court
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 04:02:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Manhunt for remaining New York prison escapee intensifies</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/manhunt-remaining-york-prison-escapee-intensifies-010201932.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Manhunt for remaining New York prison escapee intensifies
By Pete DeMola 13 hours ago

.
View photo
Law enforcement officers stand along County Route 41 during a search for an escaped prisoner south of
By Pete DeMola
MALONE, N.Y. (Reuters) - A manhunt for a convicted murderer who escaped from a New York state maximum security prison focused on a rural area near the Canadian border on Saturday, a day after his fellow escapee was killed.
David Sweat, 35, remained at large three weeks after taking flight from the Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, New York. His accomplice on Friday was shot dead by authorities near Malone, New York.
After Richard Matt was killed by U.S. Border Patrol officers, a tight security perimeter was set up in the area,  where Sweat was believed to be holed up.
About 1,200 federal, state and local law enforcement officers, were searching through a 22 square-mile (57 sq km) area along a highway between the towns of Malone and Duane in northern New York, New York State Police said in a statement.
At checkpoints on the zone's perimeter, rifle-carrying officers stopped vehicles. As darkness approached, halogen lights illuminated makeshift checkpoints.
Police in vehicle caravans spent the day passing over roads, as officers with dogs combed the ground and helicopters patrolled overhead.
Franklin County Sheriff Kevin Mulverhill spoke hopefully about finding Sweat, who was sentenced to life without parole in 2003 for killing a New York sheriff's deputy.
"After three weeks, he would have to be fatigued, Mulverhill said. "Hes not getting regular meals, not getting good sleep."
Authorities declined to say why they thought Sweat was still in the general area where Matt was killed. Malone is 27 miles (43 km) northwest of the Clinton prison where the convicts were discovered missing on June 6.
Police tracked Matt to the Malone area, just south of the Canadian border, when two burglaries were reported this week at backwoods cabins.
On Friday, after Matt apparently fired a shot at a passing camping trailer, officers spotted and confronted him outside a cabin, New York State Police Superintendent Joseph D'Amico told reporters.
Border Patrol agents warned Matt to drop the shotgun he was holding, and shot and killed him when he failed to comply, police said.
Matt was convicted in the 1997 torture, murder and dismemberment of his boss in Tonawanda, New York.
To stage their elaborate prison break, Matt and Sweat cut through the walls of their adjoining cells and slithered through a steam pipe beneath the prison before popping out through a manhole.
Two prison workers have been charged with aiding them. Gene Palmer, 57, a corrections officer for 27 years, was suspended without pay, the New York State Department of Corrections and Community Supervision said.
He is accused of bringing hacksaw blades and a screwdriver bit to the inmates, hidden in frozen hamburger meat supplied by Joyce Mitchell, 51, a training supervisor in the prison tailor shop.
Mitchell, who also was charged in connection with the escape, told investigators the inmates expected her to pick them up outside the prison walls and drive a getaway car.
When she instead checked into a local hospital with a panic attack, the escapees were apparently forced to take off on foot through rugged, mountainous terrain.
(Additional reporting by Laila Kearney in New York, Alex Dobuzinskis and Victoria Cavaliere in Los Angeles; Editing by Steve Orlofsky and Tom Brown)
Richard Matt
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 04:15:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Activist takes down Confederate flag outside South Carolina capitol</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/activist-takes-down-confederate-flag-outside-south-carolina-011513901.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Activist takes down Confederate flag outside South Carolina capitol
By David Adams 12 hours ago

.
View gallery
Bree Newsome takes down the Confederate Flag from a pole at the Statehouse in Columbia, South Carolina,
By David Adams
CHARLESTON, S.C. (Reuters) - An activist climbed a flagpole outside the South Carolina state capitol early on Saturday and took down the Confederate flag, state officials said, a day after U.S. President Barack Obama called the banner a symbol of racial oppression.
Two people were arrested and charged with defacing a monument, the South Carolina Department of Public Safety said in a statement. The banner was replaced within an hour, it said.
Brittany Newsome climbed the flag pole and James Ian Tyson stood inside a fence and assisted her, police said. They are both 30 years old and from North Carolina.
Both were released on $3,000 bail and allowed to leave the state ahead of a scheduled July 27 court appearance, local television station WIS reported.
The Civil War-era flag has been a focal point in the United States after the fatal shooting last week of nine African Americans during a Bible study session at the historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston.
View gallery
Bree Newsome is arrested after taking down the Confederate Flag from a pole at the Statehouse in Col
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley, who has attended all four of the funerals so far for the victims, on Monday called for the flag's removal saying that while it was an important part of South Carolina's past, it "does not represent the future of our great state."
The suspect in the shootings, Dylann Roof, 21, had posed with a Confederate flag in photos posted on a website that also displayed a racist manifesto.
A group of local activists said they organized the removal of the flag, which by law flies at a memorial on the Statehouse grounds in what supporters of the display says honors soldiers who fought on the side of the pro-slavery Confederacy during the 1860-65 American Civil War.
"We could not sit by and watch the victims of the Charleston Massacre be laid to rest while the inspiration for their deaths continues to fly above their caskets," an activist group organized under the Twitter tag #KeepItDown said in a statement.
Supporters took to social media under the Twitter tag #FreeBree, and a crowdfunding campaign on website Indiegogo raised about $80,000 in nine hours for the protesters' bail and legal defense.
At a funeral for the slain Emanuel church pastor in Charleston on Friday, Obama called the banner "a reminder of systemic oppression and racial subjugation".
The South Carolina Legislature is expected to begin debate next week on removing the flag from the memorial.
(Reporting by David Adams in Charleston, Additional reporting by Alex Dobuzinskis in Los Angeles and Laila Kearney in New York; Writing by Doina Chiacu; Editing by Digby Lidstone and Franklin Paul)
President Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:48:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Terror on the beach: Tourists recount Tunisia attack horrors</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/terror-beach-tourists-recount-tunisia-attack-horrors-195530217.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Authorities say a fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 400 people, many seriously. (June 28)
Load More
SOUSSE, Tunisia (AP)  Tunisia's postcard destination for tourists is reeling from the terror that blighted another day of play at the Mediterranean seaside resort of Sousse. A man armed with a Kalashnikov and grenades gunned down tourists on a private beach, and then moved methodically through the grounds of a luxury hotel  to the swimming pool, reception area and offices.
At least 38 people were killed and dozens of others wounded in Friday's deadly noon rampage by a young Tunisian disguised as a tourist ready for fun in the sun.
From accounts of the attack by shocked survivors, tourists who stayed on, lifeguards and beach employees who helped at the site of the massacre emerge stories of love and horror.
No one grasped what was happening at first in what became Tunisia's worst terrorist attack. Were the popping sounds and explosions fireworks for yet another celebration?
On Saturday, the private beach of the 370-room Imperial Marhaba Hotel was immaculate with chairs lined up under straw umbrellas  and police tape sealing it off. Only the emptiness and an overturned lounge chair with flowers accumulating hinted at the horror. "Why? Warum?" read a note on one bouquet. "Warum" is German for "why." Sousse is a popular destination for Germans and at least one German was killed in the attack.
Some people cried as they placed their offerings.
Tunisian army soldiers guard the street near the attacked Imperial Marhaba hotel in Sousse, Tunisia,
Then there are the horrific recollections of the living  many of whom quickly fled Sousse.
___
Tony Callaghan of Norfolk, England, was near the pool around midday when he heard what many others thought were fireworks. With his 23 years in the Royal Air Force, Callaghan knew better.
"I knew it was gunfire ... The hotel was being attacked."
Callaghan, 63, suffered a gunshot wound to his leg and his wife, Christine, 62, had her femur shattered. Both were among those being treated at Sahloul Hospital, the largest in Sousse.
View gallery
Flowers at the scene of the shooting in Sousse, Tunisia, Saturday, June 27, 2015. The morning after 
Along with what he said were some 40 people, they had taken refuge in the hotel's administrative offices, not far from the reception area. They climbed to the first floor, "but then we were trapped." Callaghan said he told people to hide because the gunman was following "and shooting coming up the stairs."
His wife stumbled in the corridor and "was screaming 'Help me! Help me!'" Callaghan said shortly before heading for surgery. Another woman had been shot four times, he said, and "was lying in a pool of blood."
The gunfire appeared endless. For Callaghan, it lasted about 40 minutes. "It was, like, incessant."
But no one really counted as they looked to save their lives. Some others suggested it lasted about 20 minutes.
The attacker "took time to go to the beach, to the pool, the reception, the administration, climbing the stairs," said Imen Belfekih, an employee for seven years at the hotel. She was among those hiding in the administration offices, along with a fellow employee, who was wounded in the attack.
View gallery
A couple of tourists lay flowers at the scene of Friday's shooting attack in the coastal town of
Belfekih said that the attacker threw a grenade as he climbed the stairs to the rooms where the group was hiding, apparently following the screams of fear. Her colleague was hospitalized with shrapnel wounds.
"We saw only black. It was smoky. Everyone was hiding in offices .... I hid under a desk," she said.
A police officer who was called to the scene told The Associated Press that the gunman threw three grenades  but one failed to explode. He wasn't authorized to speak publicly about the case and asked not to be identified by name.
Belfekih said she was on the beach when she first heard the gunfire. She and her wounded friend only left their hideout "when we heard silence."
The varying accounts of the ordeal made it difficult to understand exactly where the gunman was killed by police. However, he apparently went back downstairs to make an escape. Several accounts put the location outside. And no one who spoke with the AP could clearly describe him.
Tunisian police officers guard the street near the attacked Imperial Marhaba hotel in Sousse, Tunisi
"I never saw him because we were running for our lives," Callaghan said.
___
The hotel manager, Mohamed Becheur, said he had no details about the tragedy that befell his establishment, arriving later when notified and after the attack.
He has not officially closed the hotel, though concedes that everyone will shortly be gone.
"We may have zero clients today but we will keep our staff," Becheur said.
View gallery
Tourists walk at the Nfidha airport near Sousse, Tunisia, Saturday June 27, 2015. Tunisias prime mi
His hotel was a scene of chaos for hours, with people hiding out in halls, offices and bathrooms.
Marian King, from the Dublin suburb of Lucan, was in her final few hours before departure when chaos struck. Then a British woman ran into the lobby screaming that her husband had been shot and was "lying on a sunbed in a pool of blood."
King immediately returned with her son to her room, hiding for two hours in the bathroom as sounds of gunfire continued for what she said was an hour. Others from the hotel joined them.
"There were footsteps in the corridor and people running back and forth, shouting in all languages, every language," she told Irish radio station RTE.
Travel agents were calling with rides out of town, and with a 10-minute warning "we chucked everything into bags and went."
___
On Saturday, a pall hung over sunny Sousse. Scattered sunbathers who said they weren't afraid waded in the water. An occasional police patrol boat skimmed the water, and police on horseback worked the sand. But there was little sign of the violence a day earlier.
But there was lots of praise from tourists for employees of their respective hotels who may soon be out of work if Tunisia's prime industry, tourism, is gutted by the attack.
Employees at nearby hotels or those with outlets on the beach joined in the rescue operation, running to the massacre site to lend a hand.
"You hear the gunfire. You can't count the number of times," said Haytham, a lifeguard at the nearby Royal Kenz Hotel. He and others cleared the beach and moved some wounded into ambulances. Visibly shaken, he and a group of tourists laid a bouquet at the doomed beach.
Faycal Mhoub, who from his post at the beach offers camel rides, rushed from his circuit when he heard the news, putting tourists in the family home, then went to help moved the wounded.
"I live with the tourists more than with my family," he said. "I don't know how many months or years tourists won't come, but I'll be at my spot."
___
Shawn Pogatchnik contributed to this report from Dublin, Ireland.
Tunisia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:17:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran, US warn of 'hard work' at tough nuclear talks</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/us-iran-hard-ahead-seal-nuclear-deal-105736723.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Iran, US warn of 'hard work' at tough nuclear talks
By Simon Sturdee and Jo Biddle 17 hours ago

Key differences remain in Iran nuclear talks

Key differences remain in Iran nuclear talks
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Key differences remain in Iran nuclear talks
 Replay video
Greeks react to referendum green light

More than 500 people were injured in a fire and explosion at an amusement park in Taiwan on Saturday.
Load More
Vienna (AFP) - Iran and the US showed little sign Saturday of an early breakthrough in last-ditch nuclear talks with both sides warning of "hard work" ahead and France stressing key issues remain unresolved.
US Secretary of State John Kerry and Iran's Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif met twice during the day for what is set to be the final push to seal an accord curtailing Tehran's nuclear programme after almost two years of negotiations.
Kerry told reporters that although he remained "hopeful" ahead of Tuesday's deadline "we've a lot of hard work to do".
Zarif agreed negotiators "need to work really hard in order to be able to make progress and move forward".
But his deputy Abbas Araghchi suggested parts of a framework deal reached in April in Lausanne could no longer be applied because other countries had changed their positions.
"In Lausanne we found solutions to many things, but some issues remained unresolved," he told an Arabic-language Iranian television channel Al-Alam.
View gallery
US Secretary of State John Kerry (L) talks to reporters next to US Under Secretary for Political Aff
"And now some of the solutions found in Lausanne no longer work, because after Lausanne certain countries within the P5+1 made declarations... and we see a change in their position which complicates the task."
Officials have acknowledged the June 30 deadline may slip by a few days.
Other foreign ministers from the so-called P5+1 -- Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States -- are due to arrive in the coming days, with EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini expected on Sunday.
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius, who flew in Saturday, said at least three "indispensable" demands remained unresolved.
"We want a robust accord that recognises Iran's right to a civilian nuclear programme, but which guarantees that Iran renounces definitively nuclear weapons," he said.
View gallery
Iran's Minister of Foreign Affairs Mohammad Javad Zarif (R) attends a meeting at the Palais Cobu
Fabius, who met separately with both Zarif and Kerry, stressed there must be "a lasting limitation of Iran's nuclear capacities in research and production" as well as rigorous inspection of military sites, and a mechanism to quickly reimpose sanctions.
It is hoped a deal would end a standoff dating back to 2002 which has threatened to escalate into war and poisoned the Islamic republic's relations with the outside world.
Any deal faces close scrutiny by hardliners in Iran and the United States, as well as Iran's regional rivals Israel, widely assumed to have nuclear weapons itself, and Saudi Arabia.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:36:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore police open probe into new shooting of unarmed black man</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/baltimore-police-open-probe-shooting-unarmed-black-man-183624085.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Baltimore police open probe into new shooting of unarmed black man
By John Clarke 19 hours ago

Done
By John Clarke
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Police have opened an investigation into the killing of an unarmed black man by law enforcement officers outside Baltimore, authorities said on Saturday, two months after the city was rocked by protests over the death of another African-American who was taken into custody.
The latest incident unfolded in the Baltimore suburb of Owing Mills, where three officers fired at least 19 rounds and killed Spencer Lee McCain, 41, during a domestic disturbance on Thursday. The Baltimore County police's homicide unit is investigating, police said in a statement Saturday.
Police will conduct an internal review to determine compliance with departmental policy, rules and regulations, the department said.It will send the findings to the Baltimore County States Attorneys Office for review.
The investigation comes at time when U.S. law enforcement is under close scrutiny over the use of lethal force, especially in confrontations with African-American men.
In April, 25-year-old Freddie Gray died from a spinal injury suffered in custody of Baltimore police. His death triggered protests and rioting on the day of his funeral, drawing national attention to the city. Six Baltimore police officers are now facing criminal charges in his death.
A statement by the Baltimore County police identified the officers involved in the latest incident as Wilkes, Besaw and Stargel, providing only their last names.
A police spokesman would not provide first names or ages, saying he was prohibited from doing so by union rules.
Baltimore County Police Department salary records show Shenell Wilkes, Jonathan Besaw and Shannon Stargel as the only employees with those last names.
Wilkes is a six year veteran, Besaw an eight year veteran, and Stargel is a five year veteran, police said.
Officers were called to a home in Owings Mills just after 1 a.m. on Thursday. They forced their way inside when they heard a disturbance, police said.
Three officers shot McCain, fearing he had a weapon, but no firearms were found. Investigators found 19 shell casings, but the exact number of rounds fired was unknown, police said.
McCain was taken to a hospital, where he was pronounced dead. The officers have been placed on administrative leave.
A woman and two children were also in the home and the woman was injured, the police statement said. McCain was under a protective order barring him from having contact with the woman and the children and from going to the home.
Police had been called to the address about 17 times since January 2012, police said.

(Editing By Frank McGurty and Tom Brown)
RELATED VIDEO:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 07:22:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than 500 injured as fire hits Taiwan water park party</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/fire-injures-scores-attending-party-taiwan-water-park-163921242.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>More than 500 injured as fire hits Taiwan water park party
By RALPH JENNINGS 9 hours ago

Raw: Fire Injured Hundreds at Taiwan Water Park

Raw: Fire Injured Hundreds at Taiwan Water Park
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Raw: Fire Injured Hundreds at Taiwan Water Park
 Replay video
President Obama sings "Amazing Grace during Rev. Clementa Pinckney's funeral service in South Carolina

Now watching Up next
Load More
TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP)  A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a Saturday night party at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 500 people, including eight in critical condition, authorities said Sunday.
The fire was sparked by an accidental explosion of a colored theatrical powder thrown from the stage in front of about 1,000 people, the fire agency and local media said. The powder for the one-time event called "Color Play Asia" ignited along the ground, mainly burning people's lower bodies, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command center.
Taiwan's Central News Agency reported witnesses as saying the fire at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City spread quickly after powder was blown into the air.
Taiwan Premier Mao Chih-kuo announced a ban Sunday on parties that use flammable colored powder.
A total of 516 people were reported to have burn injuries as of about 11 a.m. Sunday, Wang said.
The official injury toll had risen from slightly more than 200 at midnight, because about 300 people had made their own way to hospitals. Eight people had life-threatening injuries, according to Taiwan's Central News Agency.
The victims included four mainland Chinese and two foreigners. An 18-year-old from Taiwan was burned on 90 percent of her body.
Central News Agency said that police were questioning two park workers who had launched the powder as well as the party's on-site organizer and two technicians. They may face charges of professional negligence causing serious injuries and endangering the public, it said.
The exact cause of the fire is still being investigated.
Video showed rescue workers and bystanders carrying burned and injured people on their backs, in inflatable boats and on stretchers to get medical treatment.
TAIPEI, Taiwan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 00:20:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French terror suspect took selfie with beheaded victim</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/police-release-1-4-suspects-held-over-france-095800029.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>French terror suspect took selfie with beheaded victim
By PHILIPPE SOTTO and JAMEY KEATEN 16 hours ago

France factory attack suspect in custody

France factory attack suspect in custody
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
France factory attack suspect in custody
 Replay video
Hear Bubba Watson discuss his approach at the Travelers Championship as he prepares for the final round on Sunday.
Load More
FONTAINES-SUR-SAONE, France (AP)  The top suspect in the beheading of a businessman that French authorities are calling a terrorist attack took a "selfie" photo with the slain victim and sent the image via WhatsApp to a Canadian mobile phone number, officials said Saturday.
French investigators were working to determine the recipient's identity, but weren't able to immediately confirm media reports that it was an unspecified person now in Syria, where the radical Islamic State group has seized territory, the security officials said.
The revelation added a macabre twist to an investigation that has not turned up a solid link to radical or foreign groups, but has revived concerns about terrorism in France less than six months after deadly attacks in the Paris area.
Top suspect Yassine Salhi, a truck driver with a history of radical Islamic ties, as well as his sister and wife remained in police custody in the city of Lyon, a day after he allegedly crashed a truck into a U.S.-owned chemical warehouse and hung his employer's severed head on a factory gate, officials said.
One of the officials said the selfie was forwarded via WhatsApp, the globally popular instant messaging system owned by Facebook, to a phone number in Canada. The officials spoke on condition of anonymity because the investigation was ongoing.
Jean-Christophe de Le Rue, a spokesman for Canada's Public Safety Minister, confirmed that Canadian authorities are involved in the case.
View gallery
Police officers guard the road leading to a plant in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon, Fra
"While I cannot comment on operational matters of national security, we are assisting the French authorities with their investigation," he said.
He declined to comment further on details of the investigation.
No group immediately claimed responsibility. The severed head appeared to mimic Islamic State's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see, and came days after the militants urged attacks during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan. French authorities say Salhi had links to radical Salafists in the past.
Paris prosecutor's office spokeswoman Agnes Thibault-Lecuivre said the leading suspect began speaking with investigators after first refusing to do so. She declined to provide details, but said investigators haven't found any foreign connection.
The site of the beheading wasn't yet known to investigators, and the victim had been strangled beforehand, she said.
View gallery
Police officers guard a road leading to a plant which was attacked on Friday in Saint-Quentin-Fallav
A fourth person arrested Friday was released without being charged. Under French anti-terrorism laws, Salhi and the women can be held up to four days before either being released or handed preliminary charges and locked up.
President Francois Hollande's office said he will convene a meeting with top parliamentary leaders about the matter on Tuesday.
Separately on Saturday, hundreds of people turned out in the region to honor slain businessman Herve Cornara and denounce the violence. Dozens turned out for a minute of silence in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, the town southeast of Lyon where Friday's attack took place at an Air Products chemicals warehouse.
Several hundred people also gathered outside a housing project in the town of Fontaines-sur-Saone to honor Cornara, 54, the manager of a transportation company that had employed Salhi since March. They recalled a kind, humble man who was active in the community of the Lyon suburb.
"He lived on the fifth floor, me on the fourth. He spoke with all the young people in the neighborhood. He didn't differentiate between (non-Muslim) French and Muslims," said Leila Bouri, a 24-year-old cafeteria cashier. "If you ever had a problem, you would go see him."
"When I heard this, I was shocked. It's shameful," she said. "I am a Muslim, but you can't kill like this. It's not who we are. In Islam, we're not told to slit throats. We only slit the throats of sheep. You don't slit the throats of people."
The suspected killer, she added, "isn't a Muslim in my opinion."
___
Jamey Keaten reported from Paris. Michel Euler in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier contributed to this report.
Yassine Salhi
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 04:08:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Parliament approves referendum; Greece's future in balance</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/greeks-face-uncertainty-vote-called-bailout-101948918--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Parliament approves referendum; Greece's future in balance
By RAF CASERT and ELENA BECATOROS 13 hours ago

EU finance ministers in emergency meeting after Greece rejects bailout deal

EU finance ministers in emergency meeting after Greece rejects bailout deal
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
EU finance ministers in emergency meeting after Greece rejects bailout deal
 Replay video
Manhunt for prison escapee David Sweat intensifies

Greek lawmakers vote in favour of holding a referedum on July 5, where Greek voters will decide on whether to accept bailout terms. Yiming Woo reports.
Load More
ATHENS, Greece (AP)  Greece's parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans, with the country's future in the eurozone looking increasingly shaky.
Tsipras' surprise call stunned Greece's international debt negotiators, and the country took a big step closer to falling out of the euro currency union after fellow eurozone member states refused to extend its bailout program past its expiry date on Tuesday, leaving Greece on the brink of financial chaos.
In the streets of Greece, worried people queued outside banks for cash from dawn to dusk after Tsipras' announcement in the early hours of Saturday, after billions of euros had already been emptied in the preceding weeks.
Greece has a 1.6 billion euro ($1.8 billion) debt due to the International Monetary Fund on Tuesday and its bailout program expires the same day, after which it is unclear how the country might survive financially.
The referendum is set for next Sunday with the question on whether to accept proposed reforms needed to get bailout loans from other eurozone countries and the IMF. The government is advocating a rejection of the proposals.
The radical left-wing leader accused the creditors of using blackmail and ultimatums against his proud but struggling people. European officials and all Greek opposition parties except the extremist far-right Golden Dawn party called his move for a vote a foolish and rash gambit that effectively ended negotiations to keep Greece financially afloat.
View gallery
Dutch Finance Minister and chair of the eurogroup Jeroen Dijsselbloem speaks during a media conferen
The sudden move comes after five months of stalemated negotiations, with Tsipras accusing creditors of trying to strong-arm his country into taking harsh austerity measures he says would hammer an economy already on its knees after months of creditor-demanded spending cuts and tax hikes.
"They didn't ask us to agree, they asked us to surrender our political dignity," Tsipras said during a tumultuous and nearly 13-hour parliamentary session that cumulated in a vote just before 3 a.m. Sunday. Out of parliament's 300 lawmakers, 178 voted in favor and 120 against, with two people absent.
He insisted the Greek side had "exhausted every limit" of concessions so there could be an agreement, adding that "perhaps some saw that as a weakness."
The referendum move further crumbled already strained relations between Greece and its European partners.
Tsipras said the Greek people would vote against a deal next Sunday.
View gallery
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis listens to questions during a media conference after a meeti
"This no will also be a big yes, a big yes to the decision of the Greek government to reject an ultimatum that insults the Greek people."
Tsipras dismissed harsh criticism from other European countries on his decision.
"The referendum will take place as scheduled, next Sunday, whether our partners want it or not," he said.
Eurozone finance ministers earlier rejected Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis' request for a one-month extension to the bailout program, with Varoufakis then leaving the meeting.
"It's a sad day for Europe, but we will overcome it," he said.
View gallery
People stand in a queue outside a bank which operates on Saturday but eventually didn't open, in
The other 18 finance ministers then huddled without him to assess how to minimize the damage from the Greek crisis on their currency.
"Our institutions are and will be prepared to take any action if needed," said top eurozone official Jeroen Dijsselbloem of fears that financial turbulence might extend to the rest of the currency bloc. Fellow ministers spoke candidly about the risks of a Greek exit from the euro in a way that would have been inconceivable only weeks ago.
The ministers stressed Greece remained in the eurozone for now, and Dijsselbloem said "the eurogroup stands ready to reconvene to take appropriate decisions where needed, in the interest of Greece as euro area member."
Without a bailout program extension or more loans from creditors, Greece is likely to be in arrears on a debt payment due the same day. Its banks face the risk of collapse.
"The Greek authorities have asked for a month extension. But in that month there can be no disbursements," Dijsselbloem said. "How does the Greek government think that it will survive and deal with its problems in that period? I do not know."
View gallery
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis, second left, shakes hands with Dutch Finance Minister and c
France's finance minister, Michel Sapin, stressed a deal was still possible and that he was ready to act as a go-between among Greece and the creditors after relations neared a breaking point.
Dijsselbloem refused to slam the door full shut. "The door is open. It was not the institutions that walked away from the last talks last night."
Now much will depend on whether the European Central Bank will accept to continue to prop up Greek banks even after the country's bailout program expires. It would be under huge pressure to stop using eurozone taxpayer money to keep alive the banks if there is no prospect for a deal.
The eurozone finance ministers suggested Greece should take steps to stabilize its financial system  code for putting limits on cash withdrawals and money transfers.
If Greece's banks collapse, the government would have to support them itself. Penniless, it would have to revert to printing a new currency, effectively drawing the country out of the euro union.
View gallery
Dutch Finance Minister Jeroen Dijsselbloem gestures as he arrives for a meeting of eurogroup finance
The ECB's governing council will meet "in due course" to assess the situation, most likely this Sunday, officials said.
While Greece's government is recommending a "no" vote on the referendum, Varoufakis noted "the high possibility that the Greek people will vote against the advice of the Greek government."
What would happen in that case  whether Greece would have to leave the euro or try to renegotiate with creditors  is unclear.
An exit from the euro would put Greece through a new era of economic pain. With the new currency less valuable than the euro, the government would have to write off a chunk of its foreign loans  mainly owed to eurozone countries  and many companies and households would go bankrupt. Experts predict a long and deep recession in a country that has already been through five years economic depression.
The uncertainties of all this would roil European and global markets, though experts are divided on the extent. Some say Europe is better equipped to handle a Greek euro exit, but others say it is unclear what might happen. The euro dropped in value slightly on international markets after the referendum was called.
___
Casert reported from Brussels. Demetris Nellas, Thanassis Stavrakis and Paris Ayiomamitis in Athens, Greece, and Derek Gatopoulos and Lorne Cook in Brussels contributed.
Alexis Tsipras
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:33:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charleston suspect's life a troubled road to radicalization</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/charleston-suspects-life-troubled-road-radicalization-153608402.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Charleston suspect's life a troubled road to radicalization
By MITCH WEISS and JOHN MONE 21 hours ago

.
.
CHAPIN, S.C. (AP)  The people who know Dylann Storm Roof  the people who watched his progression from a sweet child to a disturbed man  are struggling with guilt. How could they have missed the signs? Could they have done something to prevent the deaths of nine innocents at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church?
How did it all happen?
Roof himself offers no answers. He sits in North Charleston's Sheriff Al Cannon Detention Center, charged with the murders, his $1 million bail far beyond reach.
But talk to his friends and family, and a portrait emerges of a troubled and confused 21-year-old, often drunk and occasionally threatening violence as he alternated between partying with black friends and spouting white power slogans to white friends. Court documents and nearly two dozen interviews show Roof's early childhood was troubled and confused as well, as he grew up in an unstable, broken home amid allegations of marital abuse and infidelity.
He apparently fell under the thrall of racist websites. But how and why are questions that remain unanswered.
As a 4-year-old, "He was so sweet and bright," recalls Patricia Hastings, who was once his step-grandmother.
Seventeen years later, she is among many who are trying to figure out what happened to Dylann Roof.
___
There is little dispute his childhood was difficult.
Franklin Bennett Roof was a 25-year-old carpenter working for a home construction company, when he met 29-year-old Amelia "Amy" Cowles, a recent divorcee, barely 5-feet tall with blonde hair to her ankles. He was the son of a prominent Columbia attorney; she was a bartender at the Silver Fox. They married in 1988 and had a daughter, Amber, four months later.
They separated in 1990, and divorced a year later. A few years later they briefly reconciled, but split again before Dylann was born on April 3, 1994.
Four years later, Franklin Roof married Paige Hastings.
In an affidavit filed in her 2009 divorce, Paige said she became a surrogate mother for the children: "I raised his kids from a very young age, took them to all of their activities."
Patricia Hastings said her daughter loved Dylann and Amber "unconditionally as her own." She said Amy Roof would leave them in Paige's care with little notice, even though Paige had her own new baby, their half-sister Morgan.
Paige cut Dylann's hair in the bowl cut he still wears; she took Amber to college orientation because "both parents were unavailable," Paige's friend Leslie McArver wrote in an affidavit.
As he grew, Dylann exhibited obsessive compulsive behavior, Hastings said. He would obsess over germs, and insisted on having his hair cut in that same style, Hastings said.
Still, he played video games, interacted with the family, attended church and Bible camp.
But things grew stressful at home. Money was a problem so Paige took a part time job. Franklin Roof was often out of town.
Franklin Roof was verbally abusive, Paige's friend Carol Elliott wrote in an affidavit.
After Paige filed for divorce, Franklin Roof hired a private investigator to shadow her, revealing she was having an affair, according to the court documents.
The divorce was granted in 2009. Hastings recalls that her daughter told her she felt guilty leaving Dylann.
Paige has remarried; her last name is now Mann.
___
Roof began having trouble in school. He failed the ninth grade twice, then dropped out for good in 2010.
People around him worried about his lack of direction. He was spending too much time in his room in front of the computer. They pushed him to get a job, but he was unhappy, his friends said.
Over the past year, Roof became increasingly unhinged.
In February, worried employees at a Columbia shopping mall called the police when Roof, dressed in black, asked them suspicious questions about when stores closed and when they left for the night, according to court records. He was arrested on a misdemeanor charge of possessing the drug Suboxone.
In March, a police officer searched his car and found six empty 40-round magazines for an AR-15 assault rifle, according to a police report. Roof said he was saving up to buy an AR-15, the report said.
In April, he was arrested again on a charge of trespassing at the mall, where he'd been banned.
He had become a recluse. He never responded to an invitation to Amber's wedding  which had been planned for last weekend but was postponed after the massacre. He also appears to have begun a journey into the world of Internet hate sites, according to the Southern Poverty Law Center, which tracks those sites.
"If you don't have much of a social life in the real world, this is a way for you to interact with other individuals and be affirmed and encouraged," said Keegan Hanks, of the Southern Poverty Law Center.
Roof appeared to be "AryanBlood1488," who began posting on the white supremacist site the Daily Stormer in August, Hanks said. Over several months, "AryanBlood1488" described how he typed "black on white crime" into a Google search, found the Council of Conservative Citizens site and descended into radicalism from there.
Kyle Rogers, a member of the Council of Conservative Citizens who lives in Summerville, South Carolina, denied Roof had any direct dealings with the group.
On Feb. 9, according to Internet records, someone using Roof's name, address and phone number registered a new website. On it, were photos of Roof at a Confederate cemetery, brandishing a gun, burning the American flag and spitting on it. The site also contained a manifesto explaining an indoctrination into radical racism.
On his 21st birthday in April, Roof bought himself a present: a .45-caliber Glock semi-automatic handgun with a high-point laser for accuracy.
___
Paige refused to talk to AP, as did Franklin and Amy Roof.
Mann had barely seen her former stepson since her nasty divorce. But last month, when she went to pick up her daughter at her ex-husband's house, he was there.
According to Patricia Hastings, recounting recent conversations with her daughter, Roof was quieter than he used to be; he looked distant, lost. He was no longer the sweet blond kid she helped raise for nearly a decade. As she was getting ready to leave, Roof, not one for affection, hugged her tight.
"It was like he was saying goodbye," Hastings said.
The next time Mann saw him, it was on television as the man accused of the killings.
Roof's friend Joseph Meek said he too is replaying, reinterpreting, his memories of Roof over the last months.
"I just wish he would have talked to me. I wish he would have told me what was bothering him. I would have done something. This will stay with me, with all of us," he said.
___
Associated Press writer Meg Kinnard contributed to this report
RELATED VIDEO:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:18:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia to ramp up security after beach attack</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/claims-tunisian-beach-resort-massacre-statement-001332326.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tunisia to ramp up security after beach attack
By Kaouther Larbi with Camille Bouissou in Tunis 2 hours ago

Tourists flee Tunisia after deadly attack

Tourists flee Tunisia after deadly attack
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Tourists flee Tunisia after deadly attack
 Replay video
US and EU Representatives Meet During Iran Nuclear Talks

Now watching Up next
Load More
Port el Kantaoui (Tunisia) (AFP) - Tunisia weighed new security measures Sunday as it scrambled to secure its vital tourism sector after 38 people were killed at a seaside resort in the worst jihadist attack in its history.
The country's National Security Council was to meet later Sunday after authorities vowed to ramp up security following Friday's attack targeting tourists, which saw at least 15 Britons killed.
After an emergency meeting late on Saturday, Interior Minister Najem Gharsalli promised new steps to ensure the "protection of Tunisia's tourist sites and beaches by armed police units".
"We can no longer refrain from taking difficult measures," Gharsalli said in a statement carried by Mosaique FM radio, adding that at least 1,000 members of security forces would be involved in securing tourist sites.
Authorities had earlier announced plans to deploy armed security officers along the coast and inside hotels from July 1 and to shut down 80 mosques accused of inciting extremism.
The attack saw a Tunisian student disguised as a tourist pull out a Kalashnikov rifle hidden in a parasol and open fire on beachgoers at the Riu Imperial Marhaba hotel in Port El Kantaoui, near Sousse south of the capital Tunis.
View gallery
Tourists leave Tunisia at the Enfidha International airport after a shooting in the resort town of S
Witnesses have described scenes of sheer terror, with the gunman mowing down screaming tourists as many ran for their lives.
One Tunisian witness said the gunman had only targeted tourists, telling locals: "Stay away, I didn't come for you."
Tunisian authorities have so far identified 18 of those killed as 14 Britons, a German, a Belgian, a woman from Ireland and another from Portugal.
- Warning to British tourists -
Health officials have said identification of the bodies is taking time as many of the victims were not carrying ID at the beach.
View gallery
A Tunisian soldier guards in front of the Imperial Hotel in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tou
The attack was Britain's worst loss of life in a jihadist attack since the 2005 London bombings. Britain has said at least 15 of its citizens were confirmed dead and warned that the toll is likely to rise.
The British government cautioned Sunday that other attacks "are possible" in Tunisia, urging visitors to remain vigilant.
The attack was swiftly claimed by the Islamic State group, the extremist organisation that has seized control of large parts of Syria and Iraq and carried out a wave of attacks around the world.
It came just three months after another IS-claimed attack on the Bardo National Museum in Tunis killed 21 tourists and a policeman.
It was carried out on the same day as a suicide bombing that killed 26 people at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait, which was also claimed by IS, and a suspected Islamist murder at a factory in France.
View gallery
Tunisian Assembly President Mohamed Ennaceur (2nd R) visits a Belgian survivor of the mass shooting 
With its hundreds of kilometres (miles) of coastline, turquoise waters, stunning archaeological sites and relatively low prices, Tunisia has long attracted European tourists.
But the tourism industry -- which accounts for seven percent of Tunisia's GDP and almost 400,000 jobs -- has been reeling since the 2011 revolution that ousted dictator Zine El Abidine ben Ali was followed by a rise in jihadist attacks.
Authorities had announced a nearly 26 percent drop in the number of foreign visitors in April compared with the same month last year.
- Exodus of scared tourists -
There has been a huge exodus of shocked tourists since Friday's attack, with British and Belgian tour operators saying they had flown out some 2,400 visitors by late Saturday. Hundreds more were expected to follow on Sunday.
View gallery
Tunisian Prime Minister Habib Essid speaks at a press conference in Tunis, on June 26, 2015, after t
Shops were open early on Sunday in Port El Kantaoui, an AFP reporter said, and about a dozen tourists could be seen lying on the beach near the site of the attack.
Many in Tunisia have questioned the ease with which the gunman entered the resort and how he was able to kill so many before being shot dead.
"What happened is the sign of security failures," said Rached Ghannouchi, who heads the country's second-biggest political party, the Islamist Ennahda.
Analysts say that despite promises from the authorities, it will take a large-scale reform of the country's forces to ensure better security.
Yezid Sayigh of the Carnegie Middle East Centre said the police must face "badly needed professional improvements and organisational reforms" for Tunisia to have "an effective, pro-active and successful strategy against terrorism".
In the past four years, dozens of police and soldiers have been killed in clashes and ambushes attributed to jihadists -- mainly in the western Chaambi Mountains.
While Tunisia has a tradition of secularism and a strong civil society, disillusionment and social exclusion have fuelled radicalism among the country's youth, with the country exporting some 3,000 jihadist fighters to Iraq, Syria and neighbouring Libya.
Airline Industry
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 04:47:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police: Surviving escapee could face a harder time alone</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/1-escaped-murderer-fatally-shot-ny-woods-other-052536640.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Rajasthan CM Vasundhara Raje continues to defend her role in Lalitgate despite TIMES NOW&amp;#39;s relentless exposes. Now, the beleagured politician is giving yet another excuse that she never appeared in the UK court for Lalit Modi. BJP in a complete state of denial and seems to have decided to defend the indefensible.
Load More
MALONE, N.Y. (AP)  With his escape partner killed, the surviving convicted murderer who pulled off an elaborate breakout from a maximum-security prison three weeks ago could have a tougher time eluding the army of searchers scouring miles of thick woods in far northern New York, police said Saturday.
Richard Matt  who once vowed never to be taken alive  was fatally shot Friday during an encounter with border patrol agents about 30 miles west of the prison he escaped from with David Sweat on June 6. Sweat remained on the lam Saturday, and about 1,200 searchers focused intensely on 22 square miles encompassing thick forests and heavy brush around where Matt was killed.
Police hoped the solo escapee would finally succumb to the stress of little sleep, scant food and biting bugs.
"Anyone in the woods and on the run from the law so to speak is not getting a full eight hours sleep, they're not eating well and they have to keep moving," Franklin County Sheriff Kevin Mulverhill said. "He's fatigued, tired, and he's going to make a mistake."
Sweat could have an even tougher time now without someone to take turns resting with and to watch his back, Clinton County Sheriff David Favro said.
"Now it's a one-man show and it makes it more difficult for him," Favro said. "And I'm sure fatigue is setting in for him as well, knowing the guy he was with has already been shot."
Raw: Search for Surviving Escapee in Northern NY Play video
The frustrating manhunt suddenly broke open Friday afternoon when a person towing a camper heard a loud noise and thought a tire had blown. Finding there was no flat, the driver drove eight miles before looking again and finding a bullet hole in the trailer. A tactical team responding to the scene of the shot smelled gunpowder inside a cabin and saw evidence that someone had fled out the back door.
A noise  perhaps a cough  ultimately did Matt in. A border patrol team discovered Matt, who was shot after failing to heed a command to raise his hands.
Matt had a 20-gauge shotgun that was believed to have been taken from another cabin. The pair had apparently been relying on the remote region's many hunting camps and seasonal dwellings for supplies.
Matt  who turned 49 the day before he died  was serving 25 years to life at Clinton Correctional Facility for the killing and dismemberment of his former boss. Local residents were relieved that one killer was no longer roaming the woods, but the constant commotion of speeding police cruisers and helicopters pointed to the continued danger.
"Half the threat is taken care of, but obviously David Sweat is on the loose," said Matt Maguire, who was waiting for a police escort to pick up some clothes from his house inside the search area. Maguire and his fiancee decided a week ago to stay with nearby relatives.
Cuomo: Gunpowder Smell Led To Escaped NY Inmate Play video
Across the state in Buffalo, the man who prosecuted Matt's murder case seven years ago also was relieved  but not surprised  by Matt's violent end. Louis Haremski, the special prosecutor for Matt's 2008 murder conviction, said snitches had told deputies back then that Matt had a plan to break out of the jail he was in at that time. Matt had sworn then that if he escaped, he wouldn't be captured alive.
"I guess maybe it was a self-fulfilling prophecy," Haremski said. "I wasn't looking for him to be killed, but it was not an unpredictable event."
Matt's body was taken to Albany Medical Center for an autopsy.
Sweat, 35, was serving a sentence of life without parole in the killing of a sheriff's deputy in Broome County in 2002. Mulverhill said investigators believe he may be armed.
Matt and Sweat used power tools to saw through a steel cell wall and several steel steam pipes, bashed a hole through a 2-foot-thick brick wall, squirmed through pipes and emerged from a manhole outside the prison.
View gallery
A law enforcement official stands guard on Studley Road where the search for convicted murderer Davi
State troopers continued stopping every car approaching the closed perimeter in the neighboring towns of Malone and Duane while teams within the perimeter performed grid searches. While there have been no confirmed sightings of Sweat, police said investigators saw a second set of tracks near where Matt was shot. Searchers hoped for one last break before heavy rains forecast for Sunday come in.
Ultimately, how the chase ends is up to Sweat, Mulverhill said.
"If he's willing to surrender to law enforcement then we'll place him in handcuffs and we'll bring him back into custody," he said.
"If he chooses to resist or he chooses not to comply, then the results are his."
___
Associated Press writers Jim Fitzgerald in New York City and Michael Hill in Albany, New York, contributed to this report.
Richard Matt
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 01:18:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Escaped N.Y. inmate Richard Matt killed by police, partner on run</title>
        <Link>http://gma.yahoo.com/escaped-york-inmate-richard-matt-shot-killed-police-204947073--abc-news-topstories.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 06:51:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cosby lawyer: Unsealing court docs 'terribly embarrassing'</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/cosby-lawyer-unsealing-court-docs-terribly-embarrassing-024134277.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>.
View photo
FILE - In this Nov. 11, 2014, file photo, comedian and Navy veteran Bill Cosby speaks during a Veterans Day ceremony in Philadelphia. A lawyer for Cosby says it would be "terribly embarrassing" if documents from a 2005 sex-assault lawsuit were unsealed in Philadelphia. Cosby's lawyer on Friday, June 26, 2015, fought efforts by The Associated Press to unseal documents from a lawsuit he settled with a former Temple University employee. (AP Photo/Matt Rourke, File)
PHILADELPHIA (AP)  A lawyer for Bill Cosby argued Friday that it would be "terribly embarrassing" for the comedian if documents from a 2005 sex-assault lawsuit were unsealed.
Cosby is fighting efforts by The Associated Press to unseal motions from a lawsuit he settled with a former Temple University employee.
The lawsuit accused Cosby of drugging and sexually assaulting the woman at Cosby's home. The settlement is confidential.
Cosby's lawyer argued that his client's deposition could reveal details of Cosby's marriage, sex life and prescription drug use.
"It would be terribly embarrassing for this material to come out," lawyer George M. Gowen III argued.
He said the public should not have access to what Cosby was forced to say as he answered questions under oath from the accuser's lawyer nearly a decade ago.
"Frankly, ... it would embarrass him, (and) it would also prejudice him in eyes of the jury pool in Massachusetts," Gowen said.
More than a dozen women have since accused Cosby of sexually assaulting them, and three have a defamation lawsuit pending against him in Massachusetts. They allege that he defamed them when his agents said their accusations were untrue. Cosby is trying to get their case thrown out before discovery. He has never been charged with any related crimes.
U.S. District Judge Eduardo Robreno asked Friday why Cosby would be embarrassed by the release of his sworn testimony, given that the accusations in the Temple woman's lawsuit are already in the public eye.
"Why would he be embarrassed by his own version of the facts?" Robreno asked.
The lawyers also argued over whether Cosby was a public figure entitled to a lesser degree of privacy.
Lawyer Gayle Sproul, representing the AP, called him "an icon" particularly in Philadelphia, who "held himself out as someone who would guide the public in ways of morality."
Robreno had never decided whether the temporary seal on some filings should be made permanent before the case settled in 2006. Under local court rules, Cosby has the burden to show why seals should not be lifted after two years, the AP argued.
Gowen argued that Cosby might not have forged the confidential settlement if he thought his deposition testimony and other motions would someday get out.
The judge did not indicate when he would rule. He could side with Cosby, with the AP, or strike a middle ground and release some of the documents, perhaps with redactions negotiated between Cosby and a lawyer for the ex-Temple employee, Andrea Constand.
"Every case about sex and drugs involves a certain amount of embarrassment," Robreno noted.
Bill Cosby
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 22:09:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jim Obergefell on historic gay marriage ruling</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/katie-couric-interviews-jim-obergefell-following-scotus-gay-marriage-ruling-190957287.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Jim Obergefell on historic gay marriage ruling

Photos
Jim Obergefell finally feels like a real, equal American.
Obergefell was lead plaintiff in the historic Supreme Court ruling in Obergefell v. Hodges that on Friday legalized same sex marriage in the United States. He spoke to Yahoo Global News Anchor Katie Couric ahead of the decision , and again Friday amid celebrations outside the Supreme Court.
As the ruling was read aloud, about two sentences in I started to cry and I cried the whole time, he said.
Obergefell filed his suit after learning his name could not appear on the death certificate of his husband John Arthur, who died of ALS in 2013. The couple traveled to Maryland to get married in the last months of Arthurs life, as their home state of Ohio did not recognize same-sex marriage.
It was an incredible experience to hear a Supreme Court justice talk about how my marriage, my relationship, how John and I matter. How we deserve respect and dignity and I started to feel a lot more like a full, equal American at that moment, he said.
Supreme Court ruling
Katie Couric is Yahoos Global News Anchor, an award-winning journalist and best-selling author.
Follow
Follow Katie to keep up with her latest work on her website , through her newsletter or via her social media channels.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 05:16:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dozens killed in attacks in Tunisia, Kuwait and France</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/report-gunmen-kill-19-attack-tunisian-coastal-resort-123231950.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Dozens killed in attacks in Tunisia, Kuwait and France
By BEN WIACEK and PAUL SCHEMM June 26, 2015 10:16 PM

Gunman storms Tunis resort in deadly attack

Gunman storms Tunis resort in deadly attack
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Gunman storms Tunis resort in deadly attack
 Replay video
President Obama sings "Amazing Grace during Rev. Clementa Pinckney's funeral service in South Carolina

Now watching Up next
Load More
SOUSSE, Tunisia (AP)  A young man pulled a Kalashnikov from a beach umbrella and sprayed gunfire at European sunbathers at a Tunisian resort, killing at least 39 people  one of three deadly attacks Friday from Europe to North Africa to the Middle East that followed a call to violence by Islamic State extremists.
The shootings in the Tunisian resort of Sousse happened at about the same time as a bombing at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait and an attack on a U.S.-owned factory in France that included a beheading. It was unclear if the violence was linked but it came days after the IS militants urged their followers "to make Ramadan a month of calamities for the nonbelievers." In all, the assailants killed at least 65 people.
The SITE Intelligence Group reported later that the IS claimed credit for the Tunisia attack on its Twitter account and identified the gunman as Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani.
The attack in Tunisia, the country's worst ever, comes just months after the March 18 massacre at the national Bardo museum in Tunis that killed 22 people, again mostly tourists, and has called into question the newly elected government's ability to protect the country.
"Once again, cowardly and traitorous hands have struck Tunisia, targeting its security and that of its children and visitors," President Beji Caid Essebsi told reporters at the RIU Imperial Marhaba hotel, near the beach rampage site.
Essebsi promised "painful but necessary" measures, adding: "No country is safe from terrorism, and we need a global strategy of all democratic countries."
View gallery
Bodies are covered on a Tunisian beach, in Sousse, Friday June 26, 2015. A young man unfurled an umb
Rafik Chelli, the secretary of state of the Interior Ministry, told The Associated Press that the attack was carried out by a young student not previously known to authorities. At least 36 people were reported wounded in the shooting spree, which ended when the gunman was shot to death by police.
The Islamic State group claimed responsibility for the suicide bombing at the Shiite mosque in Kuwait City that killed at least 27 people and wounded scores of other worshippers at midday prayers  the first such attack in the mostly quiet and relatively secure Gulf Arab nation in more than two decades.
In southeastern France, a man with ties to Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory, touching off an explosion that injured two people. Authorities arriving at the site made a grisly discovery: the severed head of the driver's employer was found hanging at the plant entrance.
The suspect, Yassine Salhi, was seized by an alert firefighter, authorities said, and French President Francois Hollande said the attacker's intention had been to cause an explosion. A security alert for the southeast region was raised to its highest level for the next three days, and the U.S. Embassy in Paris warned American citizens to be vigilant.
In an audio recording released Tuesday, the Islamic State called on its supporters to increase attacks during Ramadan and "be keen on waging invasion in this eminent month and commit martyrdom."
View gallery
Map locates Sousse, Tunisia, where gunmen killed several people.; 1c x 3 inches; 46.5 mm x 76 mm;
In Britain, police said they were tightening security at major events after the attacks in France, Kuwait and Tunisia, including for the weekend events of Armed Forces Day and the Pride London gay and lesbian festival.
The attacks were condemned by the United Nations, the U.S., Israel and others.
"We stand with these nations as they respond to attacks on their soil today," the White House said. Pentagon spokesman Col. Steve Warren added it was "too soon to tell whether or not these various and far-flung attacks were coordinated centrally or whether they were coincidental."
The carnage in Tunisia began on the beach, where tourists described hearing what sounded like fireworks and then running for their lives when they realized it was gunfire. Video of the aftermath showed medics using beach chairs as stretchers to carry away people in swimsuits.
"He had a parasol in his hand. He went down to put it in the sand and then he took out his Kalashnikov and began shooting wildly," Chelli said of the gunman.
View gallery
Injured people are treated on a Tunisian beach, in Sousse, Friday June 26, 2015. A young man unfurle
He then entered the pool area of the Imperial Marhaba hotel before moving inside, killing people as he went.
British tourist Gary Pine told AP he was on the beach with his wife around noon when heard the shooting. They shouted for their son to get out of the water, grabbed their bag and ran for the hotel. Their son told them he saw someone shot on the beach.
There was "sheer panic" at the hotel, Pine said. "There were a lot of concerned people, a few people in tears with panic and a few people  older guests  they'd turned their ankles or there was a few little minor injuries and nicks and scrapes."
Elizabeth O'Brien, an Irish tourist who was with her two sons, told Irish Radio she was on the beach when the shooting began.
"I thought, 'Oh my God. It sounds like gunfire,' so I just ran to the sea to my children and grabbed our things" before fleeing to their hotel room, she said.
Injured people are treated near the area where an attack took place in Sousse, Tunisia, Friday June 
The Health Ministry said the dead included Tunisians, British, Germans and Belgians, without giving a breakdown.
British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond says at least five Britons were killed but expected to toll to rise because a high proportion of the dead were believed to be British.
Since overthrowing its secular dictator in 2011, Tunisia has been plagued by terrorist attacks, although only recently have they targeted the tourism sector, which makes up nearly 15 percent of GDP.
"The Foreign Office will declare the summer effectively over for Tunisia, and it will destroy  besides the lives taken  the tens of thousands of livelihoods who depend on tourism for a living," said Simon Calder, a London-based travel commentator. Nearly half a million Britons visited Tunisia in 2014.
At a news conference at his office in the capital Tunis, Prime Minister Habib Essid said he would immediately  close mosques outside the control of the ministry of religious affairs and call army reservists into active service and place them around the country.
View gallery
Injured people are treated near the area where an attack took place in Sousse, Tunisia, Friday June 
"No mosque that does not confirm to the law will be tolerated," he said, referring to those that incite to terrorism.
The attacks are also a blow to Tunisia's image as a stable, democratic nation emerging from its revolution in 2011, said Jonathan Hill, a professor of Defense Studies at King's College in London.
"The terrorists are attacking Tunisia's reputation," he said. "Not just as a safe and welcoming destination for Western holidaymakers, but as the one real success story to emerge out of the Arab Spring."
International police agency Interpol offered investigative help in the wake of Friday's violence. Interpol Secretary-General Juergen Stock said the attacks "show the truly global dimension to current terrorist threats."
___
Schemm reported from Rabat, Morocco. Associated Press Writers Bouazza Ben Bouazza in Tunis, Jill Lawless and Greg Katz in London, Shawn Pogatchnik in Dublin and Angela Charlton in Paris contributed to this report.
___
This story has been corrected to reflect that authorities now say there was only one gunman, not two, and that the message from the Islamic State was an audio recording, not a video.
Tunisia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:03:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bitter dissents in gay marriage case reveals deep divide in high court</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/bitter-dissents-in-gay-marriage-case-lays-bare-122528649891.html</Link>
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Content preferences
Done
The U.S. Supreme Court ruled on Thursday to uphold the availability of tax subsidies related to President Barack Obamas signature healthcare law, the 2010 Affordable Care Act better known as Obamacare.
Yahoo global news anchor Katie Couric hosted a special live discussion of the ruling with Yahoo News chief White House correspondent Olivier Knox, Yahoo News national affairs reporter Liz Goodwin, and National Constitution Center President and CEO Jeff Rosen.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:58:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>House completes Obama's trade items as Pacific pact looms</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/senate-house-prepare-complete-obamas-trade-agenda-071045807--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>House completes Obama's trade items as Pacific pact looms
By CHARLES BABINGTON 19 hours ago

.
View photo
Graphic shows Senate vote on Trade Promotion Authority; 1c x 4 inches; 46.5 mm x 101 mm;
WASHINGTON (AP)  The Republican-led Congress completed President Barack Obama's trade package Thursday, overwhelmingly passing a worker training program just weeks after it was stymied.
The House voted 286 to 138 to renew the job retraining program for workers displaced by international trade. Obama had said he wanted to sign that bill alongside the "fast track" negotiating authority that Congress approved a day earlier.
Usually a Democratic priority, the retraining bill briefly became hostage to Democrats' failed efforts to block fast track.
The House measure also renews the African Growth and Opportunity Act.
Obama and his trade opponents are shifting their focus to proposed trade agreements under negotiation for years. The first, the Trans-Pacific Partnership, involves the United States, Japan, Canada and nine other Pacific-rim nations.
The fast-track law allows Congress to ratify or reject such agreements, but not change or filibuster them.
Most House Democrats, along with major labor unions, opposed fast track, saying free-trade pacts send U.S. jobs abroad.
House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi, D-Calif., said Thursday's votes mark "the end of phase one" in the trade debate, but "the fight will continue." The next step, she said, is "to shine a sharp, clear, bright light" on details of the Pacific-rim proposal.
Passage of the trade bills mark a huge win for the president, and one paradoxically spearheaded by Republicans. And it's a defeat for the AFL-CIO and unions and environmental groups that fiercely opposed it. Some have vowed to punish the relatively small number of congressional Democrats who opposed them.
But Obama  much like the last Democratic president, Bill Clinton  portrays expanded trade as crucial in a global, high-tech economy. Most Republicans agree, but most congressional Democrats, especially in the House, do not.
Trade has opened the most striking breach between a Democratic president and the lawmakers who overwhelmingly backed him on health care and other hard-fought issues.
Pelosi and fellow House Democrats dealt Obama a humiliating rebuke on June 12, when they derailed his trade package only hours after he traveled to the Capitol to personally ask for their help. The House voted 302-126 that day to reject the job retraining portion of the package. Nearly half the "no" votes came from Democrats.
Republican leaders, with White House support, restructured the legislative package and passed fast track with big GOP margins, plus modest Democratic support.
On Thursday, only six House Democrats voted against the job retraining program. Among Republicans, 132 voted against the program, and 111 voted for it.
Rep. Paul Ryan, chairman of the House Ways and Means Committee, said some Democrats had questioned Republicans' promises to support the job retraining program even after fast track was secured.
To pass the trade legislation, Ryan, R-Wis., told House colleagues before Thursday's vote, "We needed a little bit of trust. We are here today to keep our word."
Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:39:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds discrimination claims in housing case</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/supreme-court-upholds-broad-discrimination-claims-under-housing-141124553--finance.html</Link>
=======
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 01:04:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'The Reverend President': Obama sings Amazing Grace in eulogy</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/the-reverend-president-obama-sings-amazing-122531605241.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 21:56:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tourists describe scenes of panic in Tunisia attack</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/tourists-flee-panic-tunisia-resort-attack-141651648.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tourists describe scenes of panic in Tunisia attack
By Robin Millard June 26, 2015 2:56 PM

.
.
London (AFP) - British holidaymakers told how they fled in panic from Friday's gun massacre on a Tunisian beach resort, screaming and running for cover when they realised they were under attack.
Five Britons were among the 37 dead in the shootings in Port el Kantaoui outside the town of Sousse.
Survivors told how they were caught by bullets while others were in hysterics as their wounded partners were rushed to hospital.
Frightened tourists hid in their hotel rooms and barricaded themselves in, while a pregnant woman went into labour in the confusion.
British tourists caught up in the attack recounted their ordeal to British media.
One man said he was hit by a bullet.
The Briton, who was not named, appeared to be speaking from a hospital.
"Someone firing a gun, and then I looked at my wife and she got up and ran, and as I turned a bullet just hit me in my arm, and I just ran to the sea," he said, in footage on BBC television.
- Shot in front of wife -
Olivia Leathley, 24, heard "loud bangs" and saw from her hotel room people fleeing the beach, as holiday company representatives blew whistles.
View gallery
Tunisian medics stand next to covered bodies in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destina
Going to the lobby to find out what was happening, she saw a woman whose husband had "been shot in the stomach in front of her".
"She got dragged away by hotel reps trying to get her to safety but she was a complete mess. She was in hysterics.
"All she said was that he'd been shot and that he was there bleeding on the beach and he was just saying, 'I love you, I love you', and then his eyes rolled back into his head."
Leathley said she believed the woman had been taken to hospital to see her injured husband.
"All of a sudden, from the level just below the lobby there was a huge sound of loads of machine gun fire and one of the reps just said 'run'.
"I was crying and we heard the machine gun fire and it was so loud and it seemed like it was just behind us, it seemed so close."
A group of eight people hid in a room with no windows "and just crouched and waited until they said it was OK", she said.
Back in the hotel, she said: "There was a pregnant woman earlier in the lobby who has now gone into labour."
Ellie Makin, from Ripon in northern England, was on the right-hand edge of her hotel's section of beach.
Tourists react at the Riu Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist des
"All I saw was a gun and an umbrella being dropped," she told ITV television.
"Then he started firing to the right hand side of us. If he had fired to the left I don't know what would have happened, but we were very lucky."
She said she ran to her hotel.
"We just saw panic, everyone just got up and fled as soon as we realised it was gunfire.
"A guy ran up into the hotel and started shooting again and everyone fled. He was just below us, if we'd have walked down the stairs we'd have met him halfway.
"I ran to a room upstairs with somebody and their kids and we hid."
- 'Crying and going hysterical' -
Product manager Gary Pine said he heard an estimated 20 to 30 shots before tourists ran to their hotels for cover.
"Only when you could start hearing bullets whizzing around your ear do you realise it was something a lot more serious than firecrackers," he told Sky News television.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach.
"You could see quite quickly the panic that was starting to ensue."
His son told him as they fled: "'I just saw someone get shot'.
"I'm now stood in reception with probably 200 other international guests. Do we leave? Do we stay? Where do we go? What do we do?"
Susan Ricketts told Sky News: "Everybody just started running in and screaming. The whole place just cleared."
She said there were "people crying and going hysterical."
Tomas O Riordain, a UK resident from Cork in Ireland, was in a neighbouring hotel.
"It was all over three or four minutes after it started," he told RTE radio, saying he had two daughters at the beach and "just had to wait and see if they came back".
It was the second time he had been caught up in a terror attack, as he was in Liverpool Street in London during the July 7, 2005 bombings almost a decade ago.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:34:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Terror' attack in France followed by gunfire at Tunisia tourist spot</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/man-decapitated-and-several-hurt-in-suspected-islamist-attack-in-grenoble-factory-092920187.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>More games 
Tunisia Beach Gunfire Kills 'At Least 27' As Man Decapitated In French 'Islamist' Attack
Separate attacks see gunman open fire on beach in Tunisian tourist resort, as man is decapitated in 'Islamist attack' near Grenoble
By Chris Parsons June 26, 2015 5:29 AM

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:00:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Clementa Pinckney eulogy caps a roller-coaster stretch for Obama</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/clementa-pinckney-eulogy-caps-a-roller-coaster-122456191261.html</Link>
        <Description>Barack Obama is experiencing arguably the most pivotal stretch of his tumultuous and consequential two-term presidency as he heads to Charleston Friday to once again take up the unwelcome mantle of comforter in chief.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:29:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>9 killed in Alaska sightseeing plane crash</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/missing-plane-carrying-9-found-cliff-side-alaska-003600347.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Recovery efforts resume Friday for 9 killed in Alaska crash
By MARK THIESSEN June 26, 2015 5:29 AM

Content preferences
Done
ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP)  Alaska emergency crews will attempt Friday to recover the remains of eight cruise ship passengers and a pilot who were killed when their sightseeing plane crashed in a remote and rugged area of southeastern Alaska.
Wind and rain prevented any recovery after the wreckage of the aircraft was found Thursday against a granite rock face, 800 feet above a lake.
There was no immediate indication of why the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop went down, killing the nine people during the sightseeing excursion. No names have been released.
Clint Johnson, head of the National Transportation Safety Board's Alaska office, said it was too soon to know circumstances of the crash, including whether the plane flew into the cliff.
The NTSB was assembling a high-level team to investigate the crash, including three members from Alaska and at least two people from Washington, D.C.
"The initial rescue crew that went in had a very tough time because of the terrain," Johnson said. "It's a very steep, mountainous area, and weather conditions caused them to stand down."
He earlier confirmed the deaths: "''We have nine fatalities."
Coast Guard Petty Officer Lauren Steenson said the agency received a report around 2:15 p.m. that the plane was overdue. Troopers said an emergency locator transmitter activated in the Misty Fjords National Monument, and a helicopter pilot spotted the downed aircraft above Ella Lake, about 800 miles southeast of Anchorage.
Promech Air, an airline based in Ketchikan, operated the shore excursion sold through Holland America Line, the cruise ship company said in a statement. The eight passengers were guests on the Westerdam, which is on a seven-day cruise that departed Seattle on Saturday.
"We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those onboard the plane and their families," the statement said. "Holland America Line is extending its full support to traveling companions of the guests involved."
Promech said that the crash happened about 11:20 a.m., and the plane was one of five Otter aircraft in its fleet.
"There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling," Marcus Sessoms, president of Promech Air, said in a statement. "At this moment, all of us share the pain and anguish of this terrible event. Our thoughts and our prayers go out to everyone touched by this tragedy."
The Ketchikan Daily News reported the Westerdam had been scheduled to leave the city at 1 p.m., but it remained in port Thursday evening.
The airline's website advertises tours of the 2-million-acre Misty Fjord National Monument in its float planes.
"Towering granite cliffs, 1,000-foot waterfalls, lush and remote valleys and serene crystalline lakes make up this incredible landscape," it says.
___
Associated Press writer Kathy McCarthy in Seattle contributed to this report.
ANCHORAGE, Alaska
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:38:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Same-sex marriage among last 5 Supreme Court cases</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/same-sex-marriage-among-last-5-supreme-court-073847423.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>.
View photo
John Becker, 30, of Silver Spring, Md., waves a rainbow flag in support of gay marriage outside of the Supreme Court in Washington, Thursday June 25, 2015. The same-sex marriage ruling is among the remaining to be released before the term ends at the end of June. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)
The right of same-sex couples to marry is the biggest of five cases still to be decided by the Supreme Court.
The justices gave the Obama administration big victories Thursday, in upholding a key part of the health care overhaul and the use of a potent tool to fight housing discrimination. The justices will take the bench again Friday to hand down more opinions. They should finish their work by early next week.
In rare instances, the court will put off decisions and order a case to be argued again in the next term.
This is also the time of the year when a justice could announce a retirement. But no justice, including 82-year-old Ruth Bader Ginsburg, has given any hint that retirement is imminent.
A look at the cases that remain:
Gay marriage: Same-sex couples want the court to declare that gay and lesbian couples can marry anywhere in the United States. Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Tennessee are asking the court to uphold bans on same-sex marriage and allow the political process, not the courts, to handle major societal changes. Same-sex couples can marry in 36 states.
Lethal injection: Death-row inmates in Oklahoma are objecting to the use of the sedative midazolam in lethal-injection executions after the drug was implicated in several botched executions. Their argument is that the drug does not reliably induce a coma-like sleep that would prevent them from experiencing the searing pain of the paralytic and heart-stopping drugs that follow sedation.
Independent redistricting commissions: Roughly a dozen states have adopted independent commissions to reduce partisan politics in drawing congressional districts. The case from Arizona involves a challenge from Republican state lawmakers who complain that they can't be completely cut out of the process without violating the Constitution.
Mercury emissions: Industry groups and Republican-led states assert that environmental regulators overstepped their bounds by coming up with expensive limits on the emissions of mercury and other toxic pollutants from power plants without taking account of the cost of regulation at the start of the process. The first-ever limits on mercury emissions, more than a decade in the making, began to take effect in April.
Repeat offenders: The court is considering whether a catchall provision of the Armed Career Criminal Act, which gives longer prison terms to people with at least three prior violent felony convictions, is so vague that it sweeps in relatively minor crimes.
Ruth Bader Ginsburg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>2015 NBA draft winners and losers</title>
        <Link>http://sports.yahoo.com/news/2015-nba-draft-winners-and-losers-062658169.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>LOSER: JAHLIL OKAFOR
Former Duke center Jahlil Okafor appeared to be the biggest competition for Kentucky forward Karl-Anthony Towns for the top pick in the draft. It was projected that if Okafor wasn't selected by Minnesota, that the Los Angeles Lakers would take him with the second overall pick.
Minnesota took Towns as expected. Lakers general manager Mitch Kupchak, however, never made Okafor a draft promise for good reason. Kupchak was quietly enamored with Ohio State guard D'Angelo Russell and selected him second.
Okafor ended up with the rebuilding Sixers with the third pick. Okafor was the best talent on the board and a surprise option for Philadelphia. Even so, the Sixers have drafted a center for the third year in a row after taking Nerlens Noel and still-injured Joel Embiid the past two seasons.
When asked how the Sixers can make it work with three young centers, Okafor said: "I don't know. It's not my job to figure out. I'll go there and work as hard as I can."
WINNER: MINNESOTA TIMBERWOLVES
The T'wolves filled their biggest roster need by taking Towns with the first overall pick. He joins an intriguing group of young teammates that includes 2015 Rookie of the Year Andrew Wiggins , 2015 dunk champion Zach LaVine , injury-plagued guard Ricky Rubio , center Gorgui Dieng and forward Shabazz Muhammad . Minnesota also acquired the draft rights to Duke point guard Tyus Jones , a Minneapolis native who was the 2015 NCAA Final Four Most Outstanding Player.
Towns should be the next great power forward in T'wolves history after Kevin Garnett and Kevin Love . He also has the challenge of trying to get Minnesota to the postseason for the first time since 2004.
"That's going to be the main goal of the season for me, making the playoffs," Towns said.
View gallery
DeMarcus Cousins remains with the Kings, for now. (Getty Images)
LOSER: SACRAMENTO KINGS
The Sacramento Kings have had one of the least memorable weeks in franchise history, which is very hard to accomplish. Yahoo Sports' Adrian Wojnarowski reported that coach George Karl would like All-Star center DeMarcus Cousins to be traded. New general manager Vlade Divac and owner Vivek Ranadive maintain they don't want to trade Cousins. A disgruntled Cousins was not dealt on draft night but could be later, a source said. The Lakers had talks with the Kings leading up to the draft.
The biggest need in recent years for the Kings has been a point guard. Sacramento passed on All-Rookie Team point guard Elfrid Payton a year ago in the draft. On Thursday, the Kings had a chance to select perhaps the best true point guard in the draft in Emmanuel Mudiay with the sixth pick. Sacramento, however, passed because Divac said Mudiay refused to work out for the Kings. The Kings took Kentucky forward-center Willie Cauley-Stein instead.
Mudiay "refused to come here and work out and I just felt I didn't know him enough to make that very important decision," Divac told reporters in Sacramento.
Back in 2009, there was a talented point guard prospect who refused to work out for the Warriors, but former general manager LarryRiley drafted him seventh overall anyway. The point guard's name was Stephen Curry.
WINNER: PORTLAND TRAIL BLAZERS
It appears that Blazers free agent LaMarcus Aldridge has played his last game in Portland. The San Antonio Spurs and Los Angeles Lakers are the front-runners to land the All-Star, a source told Yahoo Sports. The Dallas native is also expected to have interest from the Dallas Mavericks.
That's not good news for the Blazers. But in preparation for the expected departure, they acquired two forwards in trades: Mason Plumlee from the Brooklyn Nets; and Noah Vonleh from the Charlotte Hornets.
The Blazers acquired Plumlee and the draft rights to Notre Dame guard Pat Connaughton for the draft rights of Rondae Hollis-Jefferson and guard Steve Blake. Plumlee averaged 11.8 points and 7.6 rebounds in 45 games as a starter last season. Vonleh, acquired on Wednesday, was the ninth pick of last year's draft and was limited to 25 games primarily because of injury. Plumlee and Vonleh don't combine to be Aldridge by any means, but at least Blazers general manager Neil Olshey is being proactive.
LOSER: KEVON LOONEY
Former UCLA forward Kevon Looney entered the draft with two major red flags: a hip injury and sports asthma. While Looney was projected to be middle to late first-round pick, it's inevitable that such issues would hurt one's status. Even so, Looney was one of 20 prospects selected for the draft's green room with a late invitation from the NBA.
Late in the first round, however, Looney, his family and his agent Todd Ramasar abruptly departed from the room for the depths of the Barclays Center when the forward's prospects looked in doubt. But once Looney and his family received word that the champion Golden State Warriors were selecting him with the 30th and final pick of the first round, they rushed back to the green room to sit down and enjoy the once-in-a-lifetime moment in front of the TV cameras. After the Warriors' pick was announced, Looney hugged his family but turned his back on his agent who reached out to him.
Chalk this up to a tough and emotional night for the 19-year-old, who has a reputation as a good person.
WINNER: SATNAM SINGH BHAMARA
Satnam Singh Bhamara became the first Indian-born player to be drafted in the NBA when the Dallas Mavericks took him with the 52nd overall pick in the second round. The mammoth 7-foot-2, 290-pounder heard of his selection while sitting in the stands. He is considered a big project who will likely begin his career with the Mavericks' NBA Development League Texas Legends.
More NBA draft coverage:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Timberwolves select Karl-Anthony Towns with No. 1 pick in NBA draft</title>
        <Link>http://sports.yahoo.com/blogs/nba-ball-dont-lie/minnesota-timberwolves-select-karl-anthony-towns-with-no--1-pick-in-2015-nba-draft-214703304.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Minnesota Timberwolves select Karl-Anthony Towns with No. 1 pick in 2015 NBA draft
By Dan Devine June 25, 2015 7:38 PM
Content preferences
Done
NEW YORK  There might not have been a promise in place , but there's no longer any question that Flip Saunders sees immense, franchise-changing promise in the 6-foot-11-inch, 250-pound frame of Karl-Anthony Towns . The Minnesota Timberwolves head coach and president of basketball operations removed any lingering doubt on Thursday night, selecting the former University of Kentucky big man with the No. 1 overall pick in the 2015 NBA draft at Barclays Center in Brooklyn.
[ Follow Dunks Don't Lie on Tumblr: The best slams from all of basketball]
"For me, I'm just blessed to be in this opportunity to just show that a boy from Piscataway, N.J., and the Dominican Republic can make it," Towns said during his post-selection press conference. "I'm blessed to be in this situation, to be in this seat talking to all of you. It just means the world that I'm going to be able to show kids around the world that with a little hard work, determination, a little bit of luck and some guidance, you can really make it far in this world."
To be fair, there wasn't very much lingering doubt about Towns. The 19-year-old had long been considered one of the top prospects in the class of 2015. He averaged 10.3 points, 6.7 rebounds, 2.3 blocks and 1.1 assists in 21.1 minutes per game at Kentucky, playing comparatively limited minutes for an insanely deep squad that won its first 38 games before falling to Wisconsin in the Final Four.
Even while surrounded by stars in Lexington, Towns stood out as something special in the making, earning a slew of honors during his lone collegiate season  SEC Freshman of the Year, an All-SEC First Team nod, an All-American Second Team selection  and joining the likes of Duke center Jahlil Okafor and Ohio State guard D'Angelo Russell in the running for the No. 1 spot. As the pre-draft process progressed, though, Towns separated himself from even his future-star peers.
Talent evaluators grew increasingly enamored with Towns' immediate and evident gifts on the defensive end, where he proved capable under John Calipari of stalling pick-and-rolls in space, defending the rim in the paint and cleaning the defensive glass. And as the workouts wore on, the videos kept coming, with Towns comfortably stepping out to the perimeter with a smooth touch that pairs well with the interior game he showed with the Wildcats.
Suddenly, a clearer, more expansive and far more enticing picture began to emerge. When you stepped back and took a look, you saw something that seemed an awful lot like the ideal power forward/center for the state of NBA play in 2015.
Towns topped many mock drafts even before May's draft lottery, which saw the Wolves win the No. 1 pick for the first time in franchise history, their reward for finishing a Western Conference-worst 16-66 in a down and dismal 2014-15 campaign. While Saunders was reportedly enamored of the polished low-post game of Duke's Okafor, he ultimately preferred the opportunity to pair Towns' two-way potential with that of reigning Rookie of the Year Andrew Wiggins , the No. 1 pick in last year's draft , to lead Minnesota into the future alongside playmaking point guard Ricky Rubio , electric skywalking swingman Zach LaVine and a group of young complementary pieces on a Wolves team that could soon be ready to run.
Towns steps into a high-profile frontcourt spot previously occupied by the likes of franchise legend and future Hall of Famer Kevin Garnett , who returned to Minnesota at last year's trade deadline and whose status for next season remains unclear, and former All-Star Kevin Love , whom Saunders traded to the Cleveland Cavaliers last summer in a blockbuster deal that returned Wiggins and 2013 No. 1 pick Anthony Bennett . The young fella's got some pretty big shoes to fill. It's a good thing he's got pretty big feet .
"The craziest thing about those two power forwards, I think you can see some resemblance of me in both of them," Towns recently told Yahoo Sports NBA columnist Marc J. Spears . "They've shown how effective they were in Minnesota. I'm trying to make my own stamp."
One thing's for sure  Towns won't lack for confidence as he sets about the work of giving the Twin Cities faithful a winning team to support after 10 straight sub-.500 seasons, no playoff berths since 2004 and just one trip past the opening round of the playoffs in the franchise's 26-year history.
"It doesn't matter to me where I play," Towns recently told Jon Krawczynski of The Associated Press . "It matters what you do at the place you play at. It doesn't matter how successful or how unsuccessful a team is. It can all change with one pick."
Saunders, the rest of the Timberwolves brass and fans across Minnesota are banking on Towns being that one pick.
"That's going to be the main goal of the season for me, making the playoffs," Towns said Thursday. "[...] We're going to work real hard right now in the summer, get everything straight, and we're going to make sure that we go into the season with the best possible team, with the best mindset, and go out there and try to win and make it to the playoffs."
- - - - - - -
Dan Devine is an editor for Ball Don't Lie on Yahoo Sports. Have a tip? Email him at devine@yahoo-inc.com or follow him on Twitter!
Stay connected with Ball Don't Lie on Twitter @YahooBDL , "Like" BDL on Facebook and follow Dunks Don't Lie on Tumblr for year-round NBA talk, jokes and more.
Minnesota Timberwolves
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:10:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>15 emails missing from Clinton cache</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/state-dept-15-emails-missing-clinton-cache-221215204--politics.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>President Obama delivered a powerful rendition of &amp;quot;Amazing Grace&amp;quot; at the funeral of slain Rev. Clementa Pinckney, and called on the country to honor those killed in the South Carolina church massacre. Photo: Getty
Load More
WASHINGTON (AP)  The State Department cannot find in its records all or part of 15 work-related emails from Hillary Rodham Clinton's private server that were released this week by a House panel investigating the 2012 attack in Benghazi, Libya, officials said Thursday.
The emails all predate the Sept. 11 assault on the U.S. diplomatic facility and include scant words written by Clinton herself, the officials said. They consist of more in a series of would-be intelligence reports passed to her by longtime political confidant Sidney Blumenthal, the officials said.
Nevertheless, the fact that the State Department says it can't find them among emails she provided surely will raise new questions about Clinton's use of a personal email account and server while secretary of state and whether she has provided the agency all of her work-related correspondence, as she claims.
Rep. Trey Gowdy, chairman of the Select Committee on Benghazi, released a statement Thursday saying, "This confirms doubts about the completeness of Clinton's self-selected public record and raises serious questions about her decision to erase her personal server  especially before it could be analyzed by an independent, neutral third-party arbiter."
When asked about the discrepancy, Nick Merrill, a Clinton campaign spokesman, said, "She has turned over 55,000 pages of materials to the State Department, including all emails in her possession from Mr. Blumenthal."
Clinton is running for the 2016 Democratic presidential nomination.
View gallery
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Rodham Clinton speaks during a campaign stop at Christ the
Clinton's use of the non-governmental email while in office was not publicly disclosed until earlier this year, after the committee sought her correspondence related to the Benghazi attack. She says the single account for personal and professional purposes was a matter of convenience, and says all her work emails were included in the 55,000 pages of documents she later handed over to the State Department. Emails of a personal nature were destroyed, she says.
The State Department informed the Select Benghazi Committee on Thursday that they are no longer certain that's the case, according to officials who spoke on condition of anonymity because they weren't authorized to speak publicly on the matter. The officials said Julia Frifield, the assistant secretary of state for legislative affairs, confirmed that nine emails and parts of six others that the committee made public Monday couldn't be located in the department's records.
As for 46 other, previously unreleased Libya-related Blumenthal emails published by the committee, officials said all are in the department's records. They weren't handed over to congressional investigators because they had no relevance to events in Benghazi and did not correspond to the committee's request, the officials said. The officials added that they are willing to provide emails outside the committee's initial request, but warned that doing so would require more time.
The emails missing from the State Department's records include missives from Blumenthal in which he sends media accounts about the killing of one of Libyan dictator Moammar Gadhafi's sons, various reports on internal politics among Libya's rebels and news of the assassination of a former Gadhafi minister in Vienna. The last email was sent Aug. 28, 2012, two weeks before the Benghazi attack, and none focus particularly on the eastern Libyan city.
Clinton's responses are brief. In one from August 2011, she tells Blumenthal she will be in Paris the next day to meet rebel leaders and says she had "to resort to new iPad" because she didn't have electricity or Blackberry coverage after Hurricane Irene.
View gallery
In this Oct. 18, 2011, file photo, then-Secretary of State Hillary Rodham Clinton checks her Blackbe
In another from March 2012, she passes on an adviser's skepticism regarding one of Blumenthal's reports about political intrigue in post-Gadhafi Libya, saying: "This strain credulity based on what I know. Any other info about it?"
And after a long August 2012 note from Blumenthal about Libya's new interim President Mohamed Yousef el-Magariaf, Clinton writes: "Another keeper  thanks and please keep 'em coming." Four days later, she responds to a follow-up reports about el-Magariaf, saying: "Fascinating. I had a very good call w him."
Clinton's critics are likely to focus less on the substance of the emails than on the fact that they weren't shared with the State Department.
Gowdy, a South Carolina Republican, has pressed for an explanation of why Blumenthal gave the committee emails not previously shared by the State Department. The suggestion has been that either the department or Clinton was hiding something.
Gowdy said Thursday that the emails show Clinton "was soliciting and regularly corresponding with Sidney Blumenthal  who was passing unvetted intelligence information about Libya from a source with a financial interest in the country. It just so happens these emails directly contradict her public statement that the messages from Blumenthal were unsolicited."
Clinton aides say her submission to the department included all emails from Blumenthal and a dozen more exchanges that weren't in the records he provided the House committee. They said some from Blumenthal's record, which was provided as a Microsoft Word document, couldn't be confirmed as having been sent as emails.
State Department officials also questioned the provenance of some exchanges because they weren't formatted as emails.
___
This story corrects the breakdown of missing emails to nine full emails and parts of six others.
Hillary Rodham Clinton
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>SCOTUS Obamacare ruling: 2016 presidential candidates weigh in</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/scotus-obamacare-2016-candidates-react-122431771361.html</Link>
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Supreme Court upholds broad housing discrimination claims
By Lawrence Hurley 16 hours ago

The U.S. Supreme Court in Washington. (Gary Cameron/Reuters)
By Lawrence Hurley
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - A divided U.S. Supreme Court on Thursday embraced a broad interpretation of discrimination claims allowed under the landmark Fair Housing Act, a blow to lenders and insurers that face such lawsuits and had urged the court to curb them.
In a 5-4 decision in a major civil rights case out of Texas, the court preserved a legal tool that has been used for decades to bring bias lawsuits over actions that have a discriminatory effect even with no evidence of discriminatory intent.
The unexpected ruling was a triumph for civil rights activists, who had feared the justices would rein in these lawsuits, and the administration of President Barack Obama, which had asked the justices to allow such claims to continue.
Justice Anthony Kennedy, a conservative who often casts the deciding vote in close cases, joined the court's four liberals in the majority.
"By recognizing that laws, policies and practices with unjustified discriminatory effects are inconsistent with the Fair Housing Act, todays decision lends support to hard-working Americans who are attempting to find good housing opportunities for themselves and their families," U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch said.
The case involved Inclusive Communities Project Inc, a nonprofit group that claimed Texas violated the law by disproportionately awarding low-income housing tax credits to developers owning properties in poor, minority-dominated neighborhoods. The group works to place low-income tenants in the more wealthy, majority white suburbs of Dallas.
The Texas case was closely watched by lenders and insurance companies, which say they are unfairly targeted. Industry groups say companies use neutral criteria when assessing risk. Based on how the law has been interpreted for decades, lawsuits could be filed over legitimate business practices, they argue.
Although a broad win for civil rights advocates on the legal theory, Kennedy, writing for the court, indicated in the ruling that the Texas plaintiffs ultimately could lose when the case returns to lower courts.
 The court was considering whether the 1968 law allows for "disparate impact" claims in which plaintiffs need to show only the discriminatory effect of a particular practice and not evidence of discriminatory intent. There was no dispute over the law's prohibition on openly discriminatory acts in the sale and rental of housing.
 For decades, disparate impact claims have been a way for lawyers representing blacks and other minorities to target policies that do not directly discriminate yet have the effect of putting certain groups at a disadvantage.
Kennedy wrote that Congress indicated in 1988 when it amended the law that it intended disparate impact claims to be available.
"It permits plaintiffs to counteract unconscious prejudices and disguised animus that escape easy classification," Kennedy added.
Kennedy also made clear there are limits to the types of claims allowed, saying "statistical disparity" alone is not enough. Plaintiffs must "point to a defendant's policy or policies causing that disparity," Kennedy added.

'INEFFECTIVE AND UNFAIR'
The disparate impact theory is opposed by business interests because it allows for a broad range of business decisions related to housing to be subject to civil rights litigation.
"Discrimination has no place in the United States, and the government should be equipped to hold accountable those who practice it. However, disparate impact is ineffective and unfair, and will ultimately harm those it is intended to protect," said David Hirschmann, president of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce's Center for Capital Markets Competitiveness.
Hirschmann welcomed what he called "severe limitations" imposed by the court on what kind of claims can be made.
Justice Samuel Alito wrote in a dissenting opinion that the ruling will "have unfortunate consequences for local government, private enterprise, and those living in poverty."
Alito cited an earlier case in which what he called a city's good faith attempt to fix "deplorable housing conditions" for renters was subjected to a legal challenge under the theory.
 National civil rights groups had tried to keep the issue away from the conservative-leaning high court. In the past three years, two other cases that raised the same question about the scope of fair-housing law were taken up by the high court but settled with the help of the rights groups before the justices could rule.
 Under Chief Justice John Roberts leadership, a five-justice conservative majority previously had curtailed remedies for race discrimination in a series of cases involving federal voting rights, promotion tests for firefighters and integration plans designed to balance out whites and blacks throughout a school district and offset segregated housing.
"The way to stop discrimination on the basis of race is to stop discriminating on the basis of race," Roberts wrote in 2007.
 The case is Texas Department of Housing and Community Affairs v. Inclusive Communities Project, U.S. Supreme Court, No. 13-1371.

(Reporting by Lawrence Hurley; Editing by Will Dunham)
Justice Anthony Kennedy
</MainBody>
    </Article>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 13:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Second prison worker arrested in New York escape</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/corrections-officer-gene-palmer-arrested-ny-prison-escape-003817852--abc-news-topstories.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Corrections Officer Gene Palmer Gave Prison Escapees Paint and Tools in Exchange for Art, Documents Say
By DOUG LANTZ, LINZIE JANIS and TOM LIDDY June 25, 2015 6:41 AM

Corrections Officer Charged in NY Prison Escape
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Corrections Officer Charged in NY Prison Escape
 Replay video
NY Prison Escapees May Have Hidden In Hunting Camp

The president responds to the Supreme Court ruling that sided with his administration&amp;#39;s major health care overhaul.
Load More
A veteran New York state corrections officer rolled out the red carpet for two convicted murderers who have made a spectacular prison break -- giving them art supplies, tools and access to the catwalks behind the walls of their cell to do electrical work, stunning court documents say.
Gene Palmer, 57, of Dannemora , was arrested Wednesday and hit with promoting prison contraband and tampering with physical evidence, both felonies, and official misconduct, a misdemeanor in connection with the "Shawshank Redemption"-style June 6 escape of Richard Matt and David Sweat from Clinton Correctional Facility .
The veteran officer, who also allegedly inadvertently passed the inmates tools in frozen hamburger meat, appeared at Plattsburgh Town Court Wednesday and did not enter a plea. He was later released from Clinton County Jail after posting $25,000 bail, the jail confirmed.
He was set to be arraigned Thursday.
According to the court documents, Palmer went shopping for art supplies at Michaels in exchange for "elaborate paintings" done by Matt -- which he burned or buried after their escape -- in addition to information about misconduct for other prisoners. He also allegedly let Sweat alter the electrical box in his cell and provided him access to the catwalk behind it.
Exclusive: Video Offers Glimpse Into Escaped Convict Richard Matt's Past
According to one of the criminal complaints, Palmer, who has 27 years on the force, gave the inmates a flathead screwdriver and needlenose pliers on four occasions between November 2014 to June 6, 2015.
He allegedly gave the inmates the tools in exchange for paintings. Matt, who reportedly painted stunning portraits of celebs , and Sweat were housed in the prison's "Honor Block," which gave well-behaved inmates privileges such as laundry and cooking as well as working as assistants to plumbers and electricians, a source told ABC News .
NY Prison Escapees May Have Hidden In Hunting Camp Play video
"I purchased and then provided paint and paint brushes for Richard Matt on two separate occasions," Palmer allegedly told investigators in a statement date June 20. He also described shopping at Michael's in Plattsburgh approximately two years ago for "white zinc paint" and "white titanium paint" as well as "one large tube of acrylic paint" for Sweat, the statement says.
Then on May 29, he said that he received a package from prison worker Joyce Mitchell, who is also accused of helping the inmates, to give to Matt, the statement said.
According to the documents, the package was a "green-colored, woven cloth bag" approximately 12 inches by 5 inches containing more than a pound of frozen hamburger meat.
The beef was packaged in styrofoam with plastic wrap but no price sticker on it, the statements said. There were also allegedly two tubes of paint and a "small, green cloth item."
The next day, he took the package and delivered it to Matt through his cell.
Did Joyce Mitchell's Husband Know About the NY Play video
"I cannot remember providing him with anything else," he allegedly said.
Palmer also admitted to allowing Sweat to work on the electrical boxes of the cell by accessing the catwalk behind them "because inmate Matt asked me and I was doing him a favor," he allegedly said.
But he denied knowing the men would escape.
"I did not realize at the time, that the assistance provided to Matt or Sweat made their escape easier," he allegedly told investigators.
He said the electrical work was done "to enhance their ability to cook in their cells," according to the statement.
NY Prison Worker's Husband Visits Her In Priso Play video
"Matt provided me with elaborate paintings and information on the illegal acts that inmates were committing within the facility," the statement said. "In turn, I provided him with benefits such as paint, paintbrushes, movement of inmates, hamburger meat, altering of electrical boxes in the catwalk areas."
In the wake of the escape, Palmer allegedly burned some of the paintings in a fire pit at his residence and buried others in the woods.
In an interview, Clinton County DA told ABC News that the pliers were used for the inmates' paintings.
"I'm not attributing those pliers in any manner to the escape," Wylie said.
He also added that bringing Matt and Sweat to the catwalk was "totally inappropriate" unless it was authorized.
Joyce Mitchell Allegedly Passed Tools to NY Prison Play video
Joyce Mitchell, who worked in the prison tailor shop, was accused of putting hacksaw blades, other tools and a screwdriver bit into the meat and then placing it into the shop's freezer, where Palmer would allegedly retrieve it, according to Wylie.
Palmer had been placed on leave, said he didn't know the tools were inside, the DA told ABC News. Mitchell echoed the sentiments, but bringing prisoners food is considered contraband, the DA said.
Matt was serving 25 years to life for kidnapping and beating a man to death in 1997. Sweat was serving life for killing a Broome County Sheriff's deputy.
The men escaped from Clinton Correctional facility, in upstate Dannemora, near the Canadian border, on June 6 in a spectacular breakout akin to that in "Shawshank Redemption."
Sweat and Matt allegedly used power tools to cut through pipes and made their way through a series of catwalks and walls to make it through to the outside where they emerged from a manhole.
They have been on the lam ever since, and despite a series of sightings, police have not been able to catch them.
This week, investigators found prison-issued underwear at a hunting cabin in Owls Head, NY. They also found food and positive DNA samples were confirmed from both suspects.
The time frame was not immediately clear.
Mitchell faces a felony charge of promoting prison contraband and a misdemeanor charge of criminal facilitation.
She has pleaded not guilty.
Before the escape she was investigated for having a suspected relationship with Sweat over the course of the past year but not enough evidence was found to take action.
Investigators were also checking Wednesday whether Mitchell may have had sex with other inmates besides Sweat.
Her lawyer, Steve Johnston, denied the allegations.
"On her behalf all I can say is that she has consistently denied having any sexual relationship with inmate Sweat," her attorney Steve Johnston said today in a statement to ABC News.
Richard Matt
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Obama to Clyburn: Charleston victims 'are my people'</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/obama-to-clyburn-charleston-victims-are-my-122373502106.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
=======
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Skrillex: The making of a superstar</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/katie-couric-exclusive-edm-superstar-skrillex-152210272.html?soc_src=mail&amp;soc_trk=ma</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Complete interview
By Katie Brinn and Andrew Rothschild
He introduces himself as Sonny Moore, but to his millions of young fans, hes Skrillex  one of the biggest names in electronic dance music (EDM). Since he first found success as an EDM DJ and producer in 2011, Skrillex has collected six Grammys, 19 million Facebook fans and an estimated $20 million  all while giving away most of his music for free.
And at just 27 years old  an age he characterizes as not young  he says he has no plans of slowing down. The EDM prodigy is churning out new collaborations with superstars both inside and outside his genre, testing the limits of his craft  and his fan base  with every new innovation.
One of his boldest, and perhaps most polarizing new partners: pop heartthrob Justin Bieber. Moore and fellow EDM DJ Diplo, under the moniker Jack , teamed up with the Biebs in early 2015 to produce the single Where Are  Now. The track quickly shot to the top of mainstream charts, drawing the ire of some EDM fans who were vocal with their criticism that Skrillex was selling out.
Yahoo global news anchor Katie Couric met up with Moore at his studio in downtown L.A. to give him a chance to respond to the criticism and to take a rare, intimate look into the life and career of one of EDMs biggest stars.
Working with Bieber
He was super-polite, Moore says of his first encounter with Justin Bieber at a party at New York Fashion Week earlier this year. The rest was history. Teaming up as Jack , Skrillex and Diplo worked on Biebers a cappella vocal track to make a hit that few of his fans saw coming.
Childhood of music and Scientology
Sporting a hardcore look from an early age, Moore says he is no stranger to being misunderstood. Youre always bullied if youre an emo kid, he admits. But he says his parents were always supportive of his alternative style and his unconventional ambitions.
The family hit a rough patch when Moore learned at age 16 that his parents had adopted him. He says his music helped him get through that period and has helped as he deals with another trial his family is now facing: the recent death of his mother. He talks about his relationship with her, how his family has come together to mourn and how Scientology has long helped his family cope with hardship.
EDM, drugs and that hairdo
Of course, its impossible to ignore the drug culture that goes hand in hand with EDMs rave scene, a scene Skrillex has so helped to define. Some critics, in fact, have linked the rise of Molly to Skrillexs ascent. Though he emphasizes that he would never want to be telling kids how to run their lives, Skrillex insists that he never uses drugs. I wouldnt be able to do 300 shows a year if I was doing drugs, he says.
Amid their conversation, Couric and Skrillex take a phone call from a special guest star, Marshmello, a mysterious EDM newcomer whose identity remains top secret. Until now, fans have even been unsure whether the rising star is a man or a woman.
Before wrapping up their chat, Skrillex gets a chance to comment on the origins of his signature haircut and muse about what his life might look like in 10 years.
Skrillex ft. Katie Couric
Not to outdo Justin Bieber, Skrillex and Couric decide there is room for one more unlikely EDM collaboration. Together, they hit the studio to churn out what could be a pretty sweet hit. Check out the final product.
Arts &amp; Entertainment
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 14:19:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Obama legacy on race</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/the-obama-legacy-on-race-president-barack-obama-122362581601.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:43:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French anti-Uber protests turn violent</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/french-cabbies-angry-uber-block-paris-airports-roads-103556123.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>President Obama delivered a powerful rendition of &amp;quot;Amazing Grace&amp;quot; at the funeral of slain Rev. Clementa Pinckney, and called on the country to honor those killed in the South Carolina church massacre. Photo: Getty
Load More
Paris (AFP) - Protests against ride-booking app Uber turned violent in France on Thursday as taxi drivers set fire to vehicles and blocked major roads.
American rocker Courtney Love was caught up in the demonstrations when a vehicle she was travelling in outside Paris was attacked.
Around 3,000 cabbies took part in the strike, blocking access to the capital's Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports, and preventing cars reaching train stations around the country.
Ten people were arrested, seven police officers were injured and 70 vehicles were damaged in clashes between Uber drivers and taxi drivers.
The service, known as UberPOP, has been illegal in France since January, but the law has proved difficult to enforce and it continues to operate.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said after meeting taxi drivers' unions following a fraught day: "UberPOP is an illegal service, it must be closed down."
Until that was done, "the vehicles of UberPOP drivers should be systematically impounded when they are openly breaking the law", the minister said.
"Governing the country will never be done by the law of the jungle," Cazeneuve added.
One of the taxi drivers' representatives, Ibrahima Sylla, described the minister's words as "promises, again" and said the drivers were considering continuing the demonstrations.
Love, Kurt Cobain's widow, was caught up in a confrontation near Charles de Gaulle airport.
She tweeted that protesters "ambushed" her vehicle and "were holding our driver hostage".
She appealed to the French president in another message, writing "Francois Hollande where are the fucking police???"
French taxi drivers burn tyres during a protest against taxi app Uber in the southern city of Marsei
"This is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad," she added.
- Two vehicles torched -
In the most serious incident in Paris, one private chauffeur, who said he did not work for Uber "or any other app" was dragged from his van when he reached a blockade in the west of Paris.
Angry taxi drivers slashed the tyres of his vehicle, smashed a window and then set it and a chauffeur-driven van on fire.
Police eventually fired teargas to break up the protest on the western stretch of the ring road around the capital and cleared burning tyres.
Prime Minister Manuel Valls said during a visit to Colombia that the perpetrators of the "unacceptable" violence "can be found in both camps" and they would be found and prosecuted.
Taxi drivers are furious at what they see as unfair competition from Uber, which puts customers in touch with private drivers at prices lower than those of traditional taxis.
Licensed cabbies say the service is endangering their jobs by flooding the market with low-cost drivers.
One driver said the strikers had been driven to desperation.
"Taxi drivers -- alright, they've got big mouths -- but normally they're not aggressive," said Malia, 50, who has driven a taxi for three years.
"But these guys have families to feed, debts. They've been pushed to the brink."
- Illegal in France -
More peaceful protests took place at transport hubs in other major cities including Bordeaux, Marseille and Toulouse.
Cabbies argued that the disruption was justified.
"UberPOP is banned, but it's still here," cabbie Stephane Molla said in Bordeaux, southwest France.
Cabbies in France, like their colleagues in several other countries, have held several protests against the app -- some of which have turned violent.
On at least two occasions in Strasbourg in eastern France last week, taxi drivers posed as customers in order to lure Uber drivers to isolated spots where they were assaulted by cab drivers and their vehicles damaged.
In Paris, the government tried to strengthen its hand on Wednesday by obtaining a court order banning Uber from operating in the capital, but the company dismissed the move.
"We will fight it (in the courts) and we'll see what happens on appeal. For the time being it changes nothing, UberPOP can continue to operate," the head of Uber France, Thibaud Simphal, told the BFM Business channel.
San Francisco-based Uber, which offers several types of ride-sharing services, claims to have 400,000 UberPOP users in France.
However, its drivers do not pay taxes, do not need to undergo the 250 hours of training mandatory for French cabbies and do not require the same insurance as taxis.
Uber
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:21:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds Obamacare subsidies</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/supreme-court-upholds-obamacare-subsidies-122340028541.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:20:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What does SCOTUS Obamacare ruling mean?</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/what-does-scotus-obamacare-ruling-mean--142038782.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>What does SCOTUS Obamacare ruling mean?
By Katie Couric June 25, 2015 10:20 AM
Yahoo News
Content preferences
Done
The U.S. Supreme Court ruled on Thursday to uphold the availability of tax subsidies related to President Barack Obamas signature healthcare law, the 2010 Affordable Care Act better known as Obamacare.
Yahoo global news anchor Katie Couric hosted a special live discussion of the ruling with Yahoo News chief White House correspondent Olivier Knox, Yahoo News national affairs reporter Liz Goodwin, and National Constitution Center President and CEO Jeff Rosen.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:58:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>House completes Obama's trade items as Pacific pact looms</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/senate-house-prepare-complete-obamas-trade-agenda-071045807--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>House completes Obama's trade items as Pacific pact looms
By CHARLES BABINGTON June 25, 2015 12:58 PM

.
View photo
Graphic shows Senate vote on Trade Promotion Authority; 1c x 4 inches; 46.5 mm x 101 mm;
WASHINGTON (AP)  The Republican-led Congress completed President Barack Obama's trade package Thursday, overwhelmingly passing a worker training program just weeks after it was stymied.
The House voted 286 to 138 to renew the job retraining program for workers displaced by international trade. Obama had said he wanted to sign that bill alongside the "fast track" negotiating authority that Congress approved a day earlier.
Usually a Democratic priority, the retraining bill briefly became hostage to Democrats' failed efforts to block fast track.
The House measure also renews the African Growth and Opportunity Act.
Obama and his trade opponents are shifting their focus to proposed trade agreements under negotiation for years. The first, the Trans-Pacific Partnership, involves the United States, Japan, Canada and nine other Pacific-rim nations.
The fast-track law allows Congress to ratify or reject such agreements, but not change or filibuster them.
Most House Democrats, along with major labor unions, opposed fast track, saying free-trade pacts send U.S. jobs abroad.
House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi, D-Calif., said Thursday's votes mark "the end of phase one" in the trade debate, but "the fight will continue." The next step, she said, is "to shine a sharp, clear, bright light" on details of the Pacific-rim proposal.
Passage of the trade bills mark a huge win for the president, and one paradoxically spearheaded by Republicans. And it's a defeat for the AFL-CIO and unions and environmental groups that fiercely opposed it. Some have vowed to punish the relatively small number of congressional Democrats who opposed them.
But Obama  much like the last Democratic president, Bill Clinton  portrays expanded trade as crucial in a global, high-tech economy. Most Republicans agree, but most congressional Democrats, especially in the House, do not.
Trade has opened the most striking breach between a Democratic president and the lawmakers who overwhelmingly backed him on health care and other hard-fought issues.
Pelosi and fellow House Democrats dealt Obama a humiliating rebuke on June 12, when they derailed his trade package only hours after he traveled to the Capitol to personally ask for their help. The House voted 302-126 that day to reject the job retraining portion of the package. Nearly half the "no" votes came from Democrats.
Republican leaders, with White House support, restructured the legislative package and passed fast track with big GOP margins, plus modest Democratic support.
On Thursday, only six House Democrats voted against the job retraining program. Among Republicans, 132 voted against the program, and 111 voted for it.
Rep. Paul Ryan, chairman of the House Ways and Means Committee, said some Democrats had questioned Republicans' promises to support the job retraining program even after fast track was secured.
To pass the trade legislation, Ryan, R-Wis., told House colleagues before Thursday's vote, "We needed a little bit of trust. We are here today to keep our word."
Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:39:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds discrimination claims in housing case</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/supreme-court-upholds-broad-discrimination-claims-under-housing-141124553--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Supreme Court upholds broad housing discrimination claims
By Lawrence Hurley June 25, 2015 4:39 PM

The U.S. Supreme Court in Washington. (Gary Cameron/Reuters)
By Lawrence Hurley
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - A divided U.S. Supreme Court on Thursday embraced a broad interpretation of discrimination claims allowed under the landmark Fair Housing Act, a blow to lenders and insurers that face such lawsuits and had urged the court to curb them.
In a 5-4 decision in a major civil rights case out of Texas, the court preserved a legal tool that has been used for decades to bring bias lawsuits over actions that have a discriminatory effect even with no evidence of discriminatory intent.
The unexpected ruling was a triumph for civil rights activists, who had feared the justices would rein in these lawsuits, and the administration of President Barack Obama, which had asked the justices to allow such claims to continue.
Justice Anthony Kennedy, a conservative who often casts the deciding vote in close cases, joined the court's four liberals in the majority.
"By recognizing that laws, policies and practices with unjustified discriminatory effects are inconsistent with the Fair Housing Act, todays decision lends support to hard-working Americans who are attempting to find good housing opportunities for themselves and their families," U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch said.
The case involved Inclusive Communities Project Inc, a nonprofit group that claimed Texas violated the law by disproportionately awarding low-income housing tax credits to developers owning properties in poor, minority-dominated neighborhoods. The group works to place low-income tenants in the more wealthy, majority white suburbs of Dallas.
The Texas case was closely watched by lenders and insurance companies, which say they are unfairly targeted. Industry groups say companies use neutral criteria when assessing risk. Based on how the law has been interpreted for decades, lawsuits could be filed over legitimate business practices, they argue.
Although a broad win for civil rights advocates on the legal theory, Kennedy, writing for the court, indicated in the ruling that the Texas plaintiffs ultimately could lose when the case returns to lower courts.
 The court was considering whether the 1968 law allows for "disparate impact" claims in which plaintiffs need to show only the discriminatory effect of a particular practice and not evidence of discriminatory intent. There was no dispute over the law's prohibition on openly discriminatory acts in the sale and rental of housing.
 For decades, disparate impact claims have been a way for lawyers representing blacks and other minorities to target policies that do not directly discriminate yet have the effect of putting certain groups at a disadvantage.
Kennedy wrote that Congress indicated in 1988 when it amended the law that it intended disparate impact claims to be available.
"It permits plaintiffs to counteract unconscious prejudices and disguised animus that escape easy classification," Kennedy added.
Kennedy also made clear there are limits to the types of claims allowed, saying "statistical disparity" alone is not enough. Plaintiffs must "point to a defendant's policy or policies causing that disparity," Kennedy added.

'INEFFECTIVE AND UNFAIR'
The disparate impact theory is opposed by business interests because it allows for a broad range of business decisions related to housing to be subject to civil rights litigation.
"Discrimination has no place in the United States, and the government should be equipped to hold accountable those who practice it. However, disparate impact is ineffective and unfair, and will ultimately harm those it is intended to protect," said David Hirschmann, president of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce's Center for Capital Markets Competitiveness.
Hirschmann welcomed what he called "severe limitations" imposed by the court on what kind of claims can be made.
Justice Samuel Alito wrote in a dissenting opinion that the ruling will "have unfortunate consequences for local government, private enterprise, and those living in poverty."
Alito cited an earlier case in which what he called a city's good faith attempt to fix "deplorable housing conditions" for renters was subjected to a legal challenge under the theory.
 National civil rights groups had tried to keep the issue away from the conservative-leaning high court. In the past three years, two other cases that raised the same question about the scope of fair-housing law were taken up by the high court but settled with the help of the rights groups before the justices could rule.
 Under Chief Justice John Roberts leadership, a five-justice conservative majority previously had curtailed remedies for race discrimination in a series of cases involving federal voting rights, promotion tests for firefighters and integration plans designed to balance out whites and blacks throughout a school district and offset segregated housing.
"The way to stop discrimination on the basis of race is to stop discriminating on the basis of race," Roberts wrote in 2007.
 The case is Texas Department of Housing and Community Affairs v. Inclusive Communities Project, U.S. Supreme Court, No. 13-1371.

(Reporting by Lawrence Hurley; Editing by Will Dunham)
Justice Anthony Kennedy
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
