<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Yahoo">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:42:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nuke deal remains elusive after deadline, but talks continue</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/diplomatic-process-us-resolve-tested-nuke-deadline-nears-080613056--politics.html</Link>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:34:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Terror' attack in France followed by gunfire at Tunisia tourist spot</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/man-decapitated-and-several-hurt-in-suspected-islamist-attack-in-grenoble-factory-092920187.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>More games 
Tunisia Gunfire At Tourist Hotspot As Man Decapitated In French 'Islamist' Attack
Separate attacks see gunman open fire on beach in Tunisian tourist resort, as man is decapitated in 'Islamist attack' near Grenoble
By Chris Parsons 3 hours ago

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:38:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Same-sex marriage among last 5 Supreme Court cases</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/same-sex-marriage-among-last-5-supreme-court-073847423.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>.
View photo
John Becker, 30, of Silver Spring, Md., waves a rainbow flag in support of gay marriage outside of the Supreme Court in Washington, Thursday June 25, 2015. The same-sex marriage ruling is among the remaining to be released before the term ends at the end of June. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)
The right of same-sex couples to marry is the biggest of five cases still to be decided by the Supreme Court.
The justices gave the Obama administration big victories Thursday, in upholding a key part of the health care overhaul and the use of a potent tool to fight housing discrimination. The justices will take the bench again Friday to hand down more opinions. They should finish their work by early next week.
In rare instances, the court will put off decisions and order a case to be argued again in the next term.
This is also the time of the year when a justice could announce a retirement. But no justice, including 82-year-old Ruth Bader Ginsburg, has given any hint that retirement is imminent.
A look at the cases that remain:
Gay marriage: Same-sex couples want the court to declare that gay and lesbian couples can marry anywhere in the United States. Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Tennessee are asking the court to uphold bans on same-sex marriage and allow the political process, not the courts, to handle major societal changes. Same-sex couples can marry in 36 states.
Lethal injection: Death-row inmates in Oklahoma are objecting to the use of the sedative midazolam in lethal-injection executions after the drug was implicated in several botched executions. Their argument is that the drug does not reliably induce a coma-like sleep that would prevent them from experiencing the searing pain of the paralytic and heart-stopping drugs that follow sedation.
Independent redistricting commissions: Roughly a dozen states have adopted independent commissions to reduce partisan politics in drawing congressional districts. The case from Arizona involves a challenge from Republican state lawmakers who complain that they can't be completely cut out of the process without violating the Constitution.
Mercury emissions: Industry groups and Republican-led states assert that environmental regulators overstepped their bounds by coming up with expensive limits on the emissions of mercury and other toxic pollutants from power plants without taking account of the cost of regulation at the start of the process. The first-ever limits on mercury emissions, more than a decade in the making, began to take effect in April.
Repeat offenders: The court is considering whether a catchall provision of the Armed Career Criminal Act, which gives longer prison terms to people with at least three prior violent felony convictions, is so vague that it sweeps in relatively minor crimes.
Ruth Bader Ginsburg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:29:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>9 killed in Alaska sightseeing plane crash</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/missing-plane-carrying-9-found-cliff-side-alaska-003600347.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Recovery efforts resume Friday for 9 killed in Alaska crash
By MARK THIESSEN 3 hours ago

Nine dead in small plane crash in Alaska

Nine dead in small plane crash in Alaska
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Nine dead in small plane crash in Alaska
 Replay video
ShowBiz Minute: Diamond, Swift, Harry Potter

Highlights of this day in history:  President John F. Kennedy rallies West Berlin during the Cold War; The U.N. Charter signed; Scientists complete first rough map of the human genetic code; Charlie Chaplin&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;The Gold Rush&amp;#39; premieres.  (June 26)
Load More
ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP)  Alaska emergency crews will attempt Friday to recover the remains of eight cruise ship passengers and a pilot who were killed when their sightseeing plane crashed in a remote and rugged area of southeastern Alaska.
Wind and rain prevented any recovery after the wreckage of the aircraft was found Thursday against a granite rock face, 800 feet above a lake.
There was no immediate indication of why the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop went down, killing the nine people during the sightseeing excursion. No names have been released.
Clint Johnson, head of the National Transportation Safety Board's Alaska office, said it was too soon to know circumstances of the crash, including whether the plane flew into the cliff.
The NTSB was assembling a high-level team to investigate the crash, including three members from Alaska and at least two people from Washington, D.C.
"The initial rescue crew that went in had a very tough time because of the terrain," Johnson said. "It's a very steep, mountainous area, and weather conditions caused them to stand down."
The Holland America Line cruise ship Westerdam sits in dock in Ketchikan, Alaska, on Thursday, June 
He earlier confirmed the deaths: "''We have nine fatalities."
Coast Guard Petty Officer Lauren Steenson said the agency received a report around 2:15 p.m. that the plane was overdue. Troopers said an emergency locator transmitter activated in the Misty Fjords National Monument, and a helicopter pilot spotted the downed aircraft above Ella Lake, about 800 miles southeast of Anchorage.
Promech Air, an airline based in Ketchikan, operated the shore excursion sold through Holland America Line, the cruise ship company said in a statement. The eight passengers were guests on the Westerdam, which is on a seven-day cruise that departed Seattle on Saturday.
"We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those onboard the plane and their families," the statement said. "Holland America Line is extending its full support to traveling companions of the guests involved."
Promech said that the crash happened about 11:20 a.m., and the plane was one of five Otter aircraft in its fleet.
"There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling," Marcus Sessoms, president of Promech Air, said in a statement. "At this moment, all of us share the pain and anguish of this terrible event.  Our thoughts and our prayers go out to everyone touched by this tragedy."
The Ketchikan Daily News reported the Westerdam had been scheduled to leave the city at 1 p.m., but it remained in port Thursday evening.
The airline's website advertises tours of the 2-million-acre Misty Fjord National Monument in its float planes.
"Towering granite cliffs, 1,000-foot waterfalls, lush and remote valleys and serene crystalline lakes make up this incredible landscape," it says.
___
Associated Press writer Kathy McCarthy in Seattle contributed to this report.
ANCHORAGE, Alaska
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:01:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obamacare ruling puts Supreme Court on hot seat in U.S. presidential race</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/obamacare-ruling-puts-supreme-court-hot-seat-u-050459645.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Obamacare ruling puts Supreme Court on hot seat in U.S. presidential race
By James Oliphant 2 hours ago
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:09:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear talks near deadline</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/iran-nuclear-talks-enter-final-phase-48-hours-084259413.html</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nuke deal remains elusive after deadline, but talks continue
By BRADLEY KLAPPER 47 minutes ago

Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears

Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
 Replay video
ShowBiz Minute: Weintraub, Cosby, Box Office

Spain&amp;#39;s Red Cross says one person was gored and six others injured as thousands of daredevils dashed alongside fighting bulls through the streets of Pamplona. The San Fermin Festival began on Tuesday. (July 7)
Load More
VIENNA (AP)  Iran nuclear talks busted through their second deadline in a week Tuesday, casting new questions about the ability of world powers to cut off all Iranian pathways to a bomb through diplomacy. But the parties agreed to continue their talks.
"We knew it would have been difficult, challenging, and sometimes hard," said Federica Mogherini, the European Union's foreign policy chief. Negotiations, she said, will continue for the next couple of days despite hitting some "tense" moments.
As the latest target date arrived for a deal setting a decade of restrictions on Iran's nuclear program, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry, Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif and other top diplomats huddled in Vienna in search of a breakthrough. All had spoken of deep differences remaining even after 11 days of discussions, and there was no public indication they had resolved disputes ranging from inspection rules on suspicious Iranian sites to limits on Tehran's research and development of advanced nuclear technology.
"The last, difficult, political issues, we have to solve," Mogherini said.
Diplomats extended their discussions by a week when they missed their goal of a pact by June 30, after passing previous deadlines in July 2014 and last November. For Kerry and his team, pressure is increasing from skeptical U.S. allies and members of Congress. If the accord isn't sent over to American lawmakers by Thursday, their month-long review period would be doubled to 60 days, hampering the ability of the Obama administration to offer speedy economic benefits to Iran for nuclear concessions.
In Tehran Tuesday, Iran's Atomic Energy Organization declared it had reached a "general understanding" in parallel talks with the U.N. nuclear agency on "joint cooperation." The Iranians have made similar claims previously, and it was unclear if any process was established for the International Atomic Energy Agency's long-stymied investigation of past nuclear weapons work by the Islamic Republic  a demand of Washington and its partners in negotiations in Austria's capital.
View gallery
European Union foreign affairs chief Federica Mogherini (left) and Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad
There, in a baroque, 19th-century palace, Kerry gathered early Tuesday with the foreign ministers of Britain, China, France, Germany and Russia. The larger group was to meet with Zarif at some point later in the day, with the clock ticking. Russia's Sergey Lavrov and China's Wang Yi were expected for a gathering of emerging economies in the Russian city of Ufa on Wednesday, and White House spokesman Josh Earnest said another prolongation of talks was "certainly possible."
The U.S. is in a tough spot. President Barack Obama has expended significant political capital on finalizing an agreement that has prompted suspicion from Iran's regional rival, Saudi Arabia, outright hostility from America's closest Mideast ally, Israel, and deep ambivalence even among Obama's Democratic allies in Congress. They're concerned that the accord would leave Iran's nuclear infrastructure largely intact and compel the West to provide the leading U.S.-designated state sponsor of terrorism with potentially hundreds of billions of dollars' worth of economic relief from international sanctions.
To ease their concerns, Obama and Kerry have vowed to hold out for a "good deal" that verifiably keeps Iran at least a year away from a nuclear weapons capability for at least a decade. Current intelligence estimates put the Iranians only two to three months away from amassing enough material for a nuclear warhead, if they pursued such a course. As part of the guarantee, the administration has repeatedly threatened to abandon negotiations if they prove fruitless or appear as an Iranian stall for time.
On-and-off talks with Tehran have been going on for more than a decade, though this incarnation has come closest to any resolution. The latest effort began in secret a couple of years ago and gained speed after the election of moderate-leaning Iranian President Hassan Rouhani in 2013. By November that year, Iran and the six world powers clinched an interim nuclear agreement and began the process for a comprehensive accord.
Over the weekend, a cautious Kerry told reporters that talks on the final package "could go either way."
View gallery
Workers construct a nuclear power plant in Bushehr, 1215 km (755 miles) south of Tehran, April 3, 20
"If we don't have a deal, if there's absolute intransigence, if there's an unwillingness to move on the things that are important, President Obama has always said we'll be prepared to walk away," Kerry said. "It's not what anybody wants. We want to get an agreement. But I've said from the moment I became involved in this we want a good agreement, only a good agreement, and we're not going to shave anywhere at the margins in order just to get an agreement."
Republicans hostile to compromise with Iran have been urging the U.S. to pull back from the talks. Their refrain for several months has been that Obama and Kerry want a deal more than the Iranians do, and have let red lines erode on Iranian enrichment capacity, inspections and providing limited sanctions relief. The president and his top advisers vehemently reject such claims.
Iran has its own red lines, defiantly outlined in recent weeks by Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, the nation's supreme leader. They include a quick easing of sanctions, and rejection of any inspections of military sites or interviews with Iranian nuclear scientists.
___
Associated Press writer George Jahn contributed.
John Kerry
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 08:25:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lawyers: Cosby's drugs-sex admission could help women's suit</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/lawyers-cosbys-drugs-sex-admission-could-help-womens-051603756.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>A Riverside County woman suing Bill Cosby for sexual battery allegedly tried to extort money in exchange for her silence, the comedian&amp;#39;s attorney says.
Load More
PHILADELPHIA (AP)  Bill Cosby's admission that he obtained quaaludes to give young women he was pursuing for sex could bolster defamation claims lodged by his accusers, the women's lawyers said after The Associated Press reported on newly released court documents.
Cosby in sworn testimony unsealed Monday admitted that he gave the now-banned sedative to at least one of his accusers and to unnamed others. His lawyer interfered before he could answer deposition questions in 2005 about how many women were given drugs and whether they knew about it.
"If today's report is true, Mr. Cosby admitted under oath 10 years ago sedating women for sexual purposes," said Lisa Bloom, attorney for model Janice Dickinson, who contends she was drugged and raped. "Given that, how dare he publicly vilify Ms. Dickinson and accuse her of lying when she tells a very similar story?"
The AP had gone to court to compel the release of a deposition in a sexual abuse lawsuit filed by former Temple University employee Andrea Constand  the first of a cascade of lawsuits against Cosby that have severely damaged his image as doting TV dad Dr. Cliff Huxtable on "The Cosby Show" from 1984 to 1992.
His lawyers objected to the release of the material, arguing it would embarrass him. Ultimately, a judge seized on Cosby's public moralizing as he unsealed portions of the deposition that had been filed in court.
"The stark contrast between Bill Cosby, the public moralist and Bill Cosby, the subject of serious allegations concerning improper (and perhaps criminal) conduct, is a matter as to which the AP  and by extension the public  has a significant interest," U.S. District Judge Eduardo Robreno wrote.
View gallery
Janice Dickinson arrives at the LA Premiere of "Lord of the Freaks" on Monday, June 29, 20
Cosby, 77, has been accused by more than two dozen women of sexual misconduct in episodes dating back more than four decades. He has never been charged with a crime, and the statute of limitations on most of the accusations has expired.
The entertainer settled Constand's lawsuit under confidential terms in 2006. Even the judge never saw the settlement terms, although the documents show that Cosby at one point offered the accuser an "educational trust" fund.
His lawyers in the Philadelphia case did not immediately return telephone and email messages Monday. The AP does not identify victims of sexual assault, but Constand's lawyer said she consented to be identified although she did not want to comment.
Cosby's lawyers insisted during the deposition that two of the accusers knew they were taking quaaludes from the comedian, according to the documents.
Nevertheless, attorneys for some of the numerous women suing Cosby seized on the testimony as powerful corroboration of what they have been saying all along: that he drugged and raped women.
View gallery
This excerpt from a 2005 deposition given by entertainer Bill Cosby, and released Monday, July 6, 20
"The women have been saying they've been drugged and abused, and these documents appear to support the allegations," said lawyer Joe Cammarata, who represents accuser Therese Serignese, one of three women suing Cosby for defamation in Massachusetts. She has also agreed to have her name published.
Celebrity attorney Gloria Allred, representing other women, said she also hopes to use the admission in civil court cases against the comedian.
Cosby, giving sworn testimony in the lawsuit accusing him of sexually assaulting Constand at his home near Philadelphia in 2004, said he obtained seven quaalude prescriptions in the 1970s. Constand's lawyer asked if he had kept the sedatives through the 1990s  after they were banned  but was frustrated by objections from Cosby's attorney.
"When you got the quaaludes, was it in your mind that you were going to use these quaaludes for young women that you wanted to have sex with?" lawyer Dolores M. Troiani asked.
"Yes," Cosby answered.
Attorney Gloria Allred (L) speaks accompanied by Actress Lili Bernard (R) announcing allegations aga
"Did you ever give any of these young women the quaaludes without their knowledge?"
Cosby's lawyer again objected, leading Troiani to petition the federal judge to force Cosby to cooperate.
Cosby later said he gave Constand three half-pills of Benadryl, although Troiani in the documents voices doubt that was the drug involved. Constand thought he was giving her an herbal remedy, she said in her lawsuit. She recalls having him touch her breasts and put her hand on his penis, and woke up to find her clothes askew, according to her lawsuit. Cosby called any sexual contact consensual, according to arguments made by Troiani.
"This evidence shows a pattern in which defendant 'mentored' naive young women and introduced drugs into the relationship, with and without the woman's knowledge, in order for him to achieve sexual satisfaction," Troiani wrote in a motion to compel Cosby to answer deposition questions.
Cosby had fought the AP's efforts to unseal the testimony, with his lawyer arguing that the deposition could reveal details of Cosby's marriage, sex life and prescription drug use.
View gallery
Therese Serignese and her attorney, Joseph Cammarata speak to reporters outside U.S. District Court 
"It would be terribly embarrassing for this material to come out," lawyer George M. Gowen III argued in June. He also said the material would "prejudice him in eyes of the jury pool in Massachusetts," where Cosby is fighting defamation lawsuits brought by the women who say his representatives smeared them by accusing them of lying.
Robreno, the judge, had temporarily sealed some documents in the Constand lawsuit but never ruled on a final seal before the case was settled. Under federal court rules in Pennsylvania, documents must be unsealed after two years unless a party can show specific harm. Robreno ruled that Cosby's potential embarrassment was insufficient.
Robreno asked last month why Cosby was fighting the release of his sworn testimony, given that the accusations in the Constand lawsuit already were public. "Why would he be embarrassed by his own version of the facts?" Robreno said.
Cosby resigned in December from the board of trustees at Temple, where he was the popular face of the Philadelphia school in advertisements, fundraising campaigns and commencement speeches.
Lawyer Gayle Sproul, representing the AP, in court last month called the married Cosby "an icon" who "held himself out as someone who would guide the public in ways of morality."
Troiani, summarizing her evidence, painted a starkly different picture.
Cosby "has evidenced a predilection for sexual contact with women who are unconscious or drugged. His victims are young, 'star struck' and totally trusting of his public persona," Troiani argued.
Bill Cosby
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:47:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece faces last chance to stay in euro as cash runs out</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/germany-france-press-greece-fast-credible-proposals-020951804--business.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Greece faces last chance to stay in euro as cash runs out
By Paul Taylor and Renee Maltezou 1 hour ago

Next video starts in : 7 Play
Emergency euro zone summit
Load More
By Paul Taylor and Renee Maltezou
BRUSSELS (Reuters) - Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras had a final chance to present credible reform proposals to an emergency euro zone summit on Tuesday to persuade skeptical creditors to reopen aid talks before his country's banks run out of money.
With Greek lenders down to their last few days of cash and the European Central Bank tightening the noose on their funding, Tsipras must convince the bloc's other 18 leaders, many of whom are exasperated with five years of crisis, to authorize negotiations fast on a new loan to rescue Greece.
But Greek officials said the leftist premier's proposals would not go far beyond a plan he sent to the euro zone last week before Greek voters overwhelmingly rejected the austerity terms of a bailout in a referendum on Sunday.
The leaders of Germany and France, the currency area's two main powers, said after conferring on Monday that the door was still open to a deal to save Greece from plunging into economic turmoil and ditching the euro.
Chancellor Angela Merkel, under pressure in Germany to cut Greece loose, made clear it was up to Tsipras to come up with convincing proposals after Athens spurned the tax rises, spending cuts and pension and labor reforms that were on the table before its 240 billion euro bailout expired last week.
View gallery
A street vendor reacts as as she sits behind used items for sale in central Athens, Greece, July 7, 
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker, under suspicion from both sides for trying to broker a last-minute deal, told the European Parliament: "There are some in the European Union who openly or secretly are working to exclude Greece from the euro zone."
He did not name names but may have been referring to German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble, who has made no secret of his scepticism about Greece's fitness to stay in the euro and last week suggested a possible "temporary" exit.
From the Greek side, the key to making any deal politically acceptable will be to win a stronger commitment from Merkel and other lenders to reschedule Greece's giant debt burden, which the International Monetary Fund says is unsustainable.
Without some firmer pledge of debt relief, neither Greece nor the IMF is likely to accept a deal. But that may be more than Germany and its northern allies can swallow.
Schaeuble said on arrival for a preparatory meeting of finance ministers that anyone who had read the EU treaty knew debt write-offs were forbidden in the euro zone. He did not rule out other forms of restructuring.
View gallery
Newly appointed Greek Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos (C) is welcomed by Eurogroup President Jero
Asked about reports that Greece was seeking an immediate bridging loan of several billion euros, Italian Finance Minister Pier Carlo Padoan the creditors would listen to Greek requests.
"The door is open to negotiations, but there isn't much time left and the situation is urgent both for Greece and for Europe," French President Francois Hollande said in a joint media appearance with Merkel in Paris on Monday.
At stake at the emergency summit beginning at 6 p.m. in Brussels is more than just the future of Greece, a nation of 11 million that makes up just 2 percent of the euro zone's economic output and population.
If Greek banks run out of money and the country has to print its own currency, it could mean a state leaving the euro for the first time since it was launched in 1999, creating a precedent and fuelling doubts about the long-term viability of an incomplete European monetary union.
"Even if it did not trigger a short-term domino effect, the integrity of the euro zone would come under fresh threat with each episode of political uncertainty within member countries," said Thibault Mercier, an analyst at BNP Paribas.
View gallery
A pensioner leans against the main gate of the national bank of Greece as he waits to withdraw a max
Even in France, the euro zone country most sympathetic to Athens, an opinion poll published on Tuesday showed one in two people want Greece to leave the euro zone.
CONCESSIONS UNCLEAR
Strengthened by the overwhelming 61.3 percent 'No' vote in Sunday's referendum, the leftist Tsipras won the unprecedented support of all other Greek party leaders on Monday and replaced his abrasive Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis with the soft-spoken negotiator Euclid Tsakalotos.
Tsakalotos entered the euro zone finance ministers' meeting without comment. Eurogroup chairman Jeroen Dijsselbloem said it was up to Greece to show a credible way forward.
"The pressure is especially on the Greeks, the banks are closed and the situation is difficult. I guess the Greek government has an interest in coming up with serious and credible solutions soon," Dijsselbloem told reporters.
View gallery
German Chancellor Angela Merkel and French President Francois Hollande want serious proposals from G
In an intensive round of telephone diplomacy, Tsipras spoke to the heads of the ECB, the IMF and the European Commission, as well as Merkel, Russian President Vladimir Putin and U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew.
The United States, China and Japan all called for a solution in which Greece stays in the euro zone.
Tsipras gave little clue of what reform concessions he would make to try to convince deeply skeptical European leaders to lend Athens more money after five months of acrimonious and fruitless negotiations with his leftist administration.
Even with the country on the brink of economic collapse, Greek officials said the government was still seeking exceptions from its reform pledges for special interests.
Athens wants to keep a 30 percent discount on value added tax on Greek islands and delay defense spending from cuts, which rightist junior coalition partners the Independent Greeks have called "red lines". It is also resisting raising VAT on restaurants to 23 percent, and wants to wait until 2019 to phase out an income supplement for poorer pensioners, officials said.
View gallery
A man rubs his head while browsing his smartphone outside a brokerage house in Beijing Tuesday, July
Juncker told EU lawmakers he was working night and day to get negotiations reopened and chided the Greeks for their aggressive approach, saying it was unacceptable to accuse the EU of behaving like "terrorists", as Varoufakis did last week.
"Throwing Greece out of the monetary union or indeed the European Union is not something we want or indeed should want," the EU's chief executive said.
European Central Bank policymaker Ewald Nowotny suggested the bank might be able to provide some sort of bridge funding while Greece negotiated a longer-term conditional loan to see it over a crucial July 20 bond redemption to the ECB.
Greek newspapers dramatized the make-or-break nature of the Brussels showdown.
Centrist daily Ethnos headlined: "Time has run out for a solution before catastrophe," while the center-right Eleftheros Typos said: "Tsipras games finish at today's council: Time of crisis: deal or Grexit."
View gallery
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, center, leaves after a meeting with Greek political part
A clear majority of Greece's 18 partners favor a hard line at the summit, arguing that they too are democracies and that Greeks should not get easier money because they had rejected the austerity terms, casting further doubt on whether they would implement any reforms agreed now.
The ECB left unchanged its emergency liquidity lifeline for Greek banks but raised the discount it charges on collateral they present for funds - a measure banking sources said was largely symbolic since the total they could borrow was capped.
A bank closure in force since the talks collapsed was prolonged until Thursday at least, and cash withdrawals remain limited to 60 euros a day, with 20 euro notes running out.
The Athens stock exchange was also ordered closed for two days in Tuesday and Wednesday to throttle speculation.
(Additional reporting by Costas Pitas, Angeliki Koutantou and George Georgiopoulos in Athens, Julia Fioretti and Alastair Macdonald in Brussels, Paul Carrel in Berlin John O'Donnell in Frankfurt and Mark John in Paris; Writing by Paul Taylor; editing by John Stonestreet and Giles Elgood)
Europe News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:32:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>S.F. sheriff defends prior release of suspect in pier slaying</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/sf-sheriff-defends-prior-release-suspect-pier-slaying-073221388.html</Link>
        <Description/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <MainBody>SF sheriff defends prior release of suspect in pier slaying
By JANIE HAR and AMY TAXIN 3 hours ago
=======
        <MainBody>European tour operators evacuate thousands from Tunisia after attack
By Tarek Amara 5 hours ago
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c

Shooting Raises Questions About Sanctuary Policy

Shooting Raises Questions About Sanctuary Policy
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Shooting Raises Questions About Sanctuary Policy
 Replay video
The future of travel? A tube called Hyperloop

A woman was shot dead while taking a walk with her boyfriend in Los Angeles Hollywood area on Sunday night.
Load More
<<<<<<< HEAD
SAN FRANCISCO (AP)  San Francisco Sheriff Ross Mirkarimi has defended his office's decision to release a Mexican man who was in the U.S. illegally and who is now suspected in the killing of a woman at a sightseeing pier.
Mirkarimi said that the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency should earlier have issued an arrest warrant for Francisco Sanchez.
"ICE knew that he had been deported five times," Mirkarimi said. "You would have thought he met a threshold that he required a court order or a warrant. They did not do that."
Prosecutors on Monday charged Sanchez with murder in the death of Kathryn Steinle, who was shot and killed last Wednesday as she and her father took a walk on the popular Pier 14.
Steinle's killing has brought criticism down on this liberal city because Sanchez had been deported repeatedly and was out on the streets after San Francisco officials disregarded a request from immigration authorities to keep him locked up.
San Francisco is one of dozens of cities and counties across the country that do not fully cooperate with federal immigration authorities. The city goes so far as to promote itself as a "sanctuary" for people in the country illegally.
View gallery
San Francisco Sheriff Ross Mirkarimi gestures during an interview Monday, July 6, 2015, in San Franc
In a jailhouse interview with a TV station, Sanchez, a 45-year-old repeat drug offender, appeared to confirm that he came to the city because of its status as a sanctuary.
The case has prompted a flurry of criticism from ICE officials, politicians and commenters on social media, all of whom portrayed the slaying as a preventable tragedy.
"Most of the blame should fall squarely on the shoulders of the San Francisco sheriff, because his department had custody of him and made the choice to let him go without notifying ICE," said Jessica Vaughan, director of policy studies at the Washington-based Center for Immigration Studies, which wants tougher immigration enforcement.
Rep. Bob Goodlatte, the Virginia Republican who chairs the House Judiciary Committee, blamed sanctuary practices and the Obama administration, saying: "The tragic murder of Kate Steinle once again underscores the need to end these reckless policies."
Mayor Ed Lee issued a statement saying city policy was never intended to protect "repeat, serious and violent felons." He asked for federal and local agencies to review what happened.
View gallery
Flowers and a candle lay on the ground following a vigil for Kathryn Steinle, Monday, July 6, 2015, 
California Attorney General Kamala Harris, a former San Francisco district attorney who is running for U.S. Senate, cautioned that when it comes to immigration, "our policy should not be informed by our collective outrage about one man's conduct."
Many other San Francisco politicians stayed quiet as mourners held a vigil at Pier 14 on the downtown waterfront, where the 32-year-old Steinle was gunned down, seemingly at random. She had recently moved to San Francisco.
While many cities have scaled back cooperation with ICE, few have gone as far as San Francisco.
For more than two decades, San Francisco has been considered a sanctuary for people in the U.S. illegally.
The city's sanctuary law prohibits city employees from helping federal authorities with immigration investigations or arrests unless required by law or warrant. That said, the ordinance does not prohibit local law enforcement from informing ICE that they've arrested someone in the country illegally for a felony offense or who has prior felony convictions.
View gallery
This undated photo provided by the San Francisco Police Department shows Francisco Sanchez. The fata
From jail, Sanchez told a KGO-TV reporter in a mix of Spanish and English that he found the gun wrapped in a T-shirt while sitting on a bench at the pier.
"So I picked it up and ... it started to fire on its own," Sanchez said, adding that he heard three shots go off.
Asked if he came to San Francisco because of its sanctuary status, he said yes.
"I only want to say that if the court wants to find me guilty, I wouldn't get mad," Sanchez said during the interview, in which he appeared confused and spoke incoherently at times.
___
Lisa Leff and Paul J. Elias in San Francisco contributed to this report.
San Francisco
=======
By Tarek Amara
SOUSSE, Tunisia (Reuters) - Tour companies were evacuating thousands of foreign holidaymakers from Tunisia on Saturday, a day after a gunman killed 39 people at a beach hotel in an attack claimed by Islamic State.
Tunisia's Prime Minister Habib Essid said most of the dead were British, and Britain's foreign office said 15 Britons had been confirmed killed in the attack in the resort town of Sousse, 140 km (90 miles) south of the capital Tunis.
A German, a Belgian and an Irish woman have also been identified, foreign and Tunisian officials said.
It was the second major attack in the North African country this year, following an Islamist militant assault on the Bardo Museum in Tunis in March when gunmen killed a group of foreign visitors as they arrived by bus.
Tunisia has undergone a largely peaceful transition to democracy since its 2011 Arab Spring uprising, but its army has been fighting a rise in Islamist militancy.
Tunisia's tourism minister called Friday's attack in one of the country's most popular resorts for Europeans a "catastrophe" and authorities vowed to toughen security, drafting in army reserves and arming tourism police at beaches and hotels.
Saloua Kadri, Sousse tourism commissioner, said more than 3,000 foreign tourists had fled the town on Saturday, including around 2,200 British and nearly 600 Belgians.
Dozens of tourists were waiting to take flights out from the nearby Ennfida airport.
"We don't want to stay any longer, we just want to see our family, parents ... so leaving as soon as possible," said Hannah Russel, an British tourist.
View gallery
<<<<<<< HEAD
A supporter of the Affordable Care Act celebrates after the Supreme Court up held the law in the 6-3
By James Oliphant
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Infuriated by a U.S. Supreme Court ruling that kept President Barack Obamas healthcare program intact, conservative activists and Republican presidential candidates vowed on Thursday to make the role of the high court a central issue in the 2016 presidential election.
Conservative ire was trained particularly on Chief Justice John Roberts, who wrote the majority opinion that preserved the subsidy regime underpinning the Affordable Care Act, even though another Republican appointee, Justice Anthony Kennedy, also voted with the majority.
Roberts, who was appointed to the court by Republican President George W. Bush, has voted with court conservatives on many landmark cases, including ones involving campaign-finance laws and voting rights.  But he also enraged opponents of the Affordable Care Act three years ago when he cast a deciding vote in rejecting a different legal challenge to the law.
Hes let down the [conservative] movement, said Curt Levey of the Committee for Justice, which advocates for conservative judicial nominees. He may feel he has no obligation to the movement.
Some conservatives have been skeptical of Roberts from the start, saying he was maddeningly opaque about his judicial philosophy during his 2005 Senate confirmation hearings. Roberts had spent only about two years  as a federal appeals court judge, which meant a sparse paper trail illuminating his judicial philosophy.
View gallery
Interns with media organizations run with the decision upholding the Affordable Care Act at the Supr
In opening remarks during his confirmation hearing before the U.S. Senate judiciary committee in 2005, Roberts spoke neutrally, noting that "Judges are not politicians who can promise to do certain things in exchange for votes" and vowing to "confront every case with an open mind."
We wanted to be supportive, but there were these nagging doubts, said Carrie Severino, policy director of the conservative Judicial Crisis Network. You cant assume someone is going to go south, but it appears the concerns were warranted. Its what happens when you nominate someone who doesnt have a clear record.
Levey said that the pressure will now fall on Republican presidential hopefuls to spell out in detail their views on court appointments - and simple generalities about being faithful to the letter of the U.S. Constitution wont cut it.
It might have been enough before today for presidential candidates to spout the usual things about appointing someone who interprets rather than writes the law. I think youll have to say more now, he said. Each candidate will have to do something to show the base how they will avoid appointing another Roberts.
Mark Levin, a frequent critic of the court who heads the conservative Landmark Legal Foundation, said Republican senators, too, will need to take their responsibility far more seriously and much more aggressively scrutinize these nominees.
Beyond that, Jay Sekulow, a prominent conservative lawyer who has argued a dozen cases before the high court, suggested that the healthcare ruling will prompt a debate on the presidential campaign trail over the justices proper function. What the court said that is that if legislation is written poorly, we can fix it, he said. Thats very different from the traditional role of the court.
Indeed, some Republican candidates were scathing Thursday in their assessment of the decision. Mike Huckabee, the former Republican governor of Arkansas, termed it an out-of-control act of judicial tyranny. Ted Cruz, the senator from Texas, accused the high court of usurping the role of Congress. Unelected judges have once again become legislators, and bad ones at that, he said.
In that vein, the ruling, along with a decision on the legality of same-sex marriage bans that could come as early as Friday, could hand Republicans a twin-barreled weapon with which to galvanize conservative voters into action. Four years ago, conversely, it was Democrats who made a Supreme Court ruling a centerpiece of their election message, blasting the courts decision in the Citizens United case, which opened the door for massive corporate campaign expenditures.
Obamas successor, whether Republican or Democrat, could play an outsized role in shaping the future of the court, said Severino. The next president could replace Justice [Ruth Bader] Ginsburg or possibly [Justices] Kennedy and Scalia, she said. It would be World War III in terms of the amount of influence that president would have.
(Additional reporting by Alana Wise in New York; Editing by Caren Bohan and Sue Horton)
Chief Justice John Roberts
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:23:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama to deliver eulogy Friday for slain South Carolina pastor</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/obama-deliver-eulogy-friday-slain-south-carolina-pastor-091039658.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Obama to deliver eulogy Friday for slain South Carolina pastor
By David Adams 3 hours ago

U.S. President Barack Obama  at the White House in Washington June 25, 2015.   REUTERS/Jonathan Erns
By David Adams
CHARLESTON, S.C. (Reuters) - South Carolina will take a step forward in healing the wounds of last week's mass shooting when President Barack Obama arrives on Friday to deliver the eulogy for the pastor of the historic church where the attack took place.
Reverend Clementa Pinckney, a widely admired state senator and pastor of Charleston's Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church, was among the nine people who died when a gunman opened fire during Bible study.
The massacre has sparked an intense dialogue across the southern United States over the legacy of slavery and its symbols, centering on the Civil War-era battle flag of the Confederacy.
Addressing the shooting last week, Obama said it raised questions "about a dark part of our history."
Nicknamed "Mother Emanuel," the Gothic Revival-style house of worship is the oldest A.M.E. church in the southeastern United States, and was founded by slaves.
View gallery
Louise Brown walks in the "March for Black Lives" after passing by the Emanuel African Met
In an unusual step, Obama will be accompanied by both First Lady Michele Obama and Vice President Joe Biden for the funeral in a Charleston college arena. All three knew Pinckney personally.
During his presidency, Obama has spoken at half a dozen memorial services for victims of mass shootings in Texas, Arizona, Colorado and Connecticut.
"Ive had to make statements like this too many times," a visibly upset Obama said from the White House last week. "Communities like this have had to endure tragedies like this too many times."
Obama repeated previous calls he has made for tougher gun laws, a politically thorny issue in the United States where the constitution guarantees the right to own guns.
"At some point, we as a country will have to reckon with the fact that this type of mass violence does not happen in other advanced countries. It doesnt happen in other places with this kind of frequency," he said.
View gallery
Gary Washington stands over the casket of his mother, Ethel Lance, as she is buried at the Emanuel A
Married with two children, Pinckney was a talented orator with a baritone voice and began preaching at 13. A Democrat, at 23 he became the youngest African-American in South Carolina history to be elected to the state legislature.
Several thousand turned out on Thursday evening for Pinckney's wake at Emanuel, the line of mourners stretching for three blocks, including 200 college fraternity brothers, friends, politicians and members of the public, both black and white.
"I cried when I got here," said Katharine Moseley, a Texas bus driver who drove 20 hours from Austin. "I was raised in the A.M.E. church."
Lutheran bishop Mike Rhyne also drove down with his wife and three children from central Pennsylvania to pay tribute to his friend and fellow seminary student. "He was one of the best men I have ever met," he said.
Pinckney's high school friends Kevin Riley, 41, and Lachandra Colbert, 42, traveled from Maryland for the funeral. "We wouldn't miss this. He was our classmate," said Riley. "He was on track to be someone really important," Riley added.
View gallery
Police lead suspected shooter Dylann Roof, 21, into the courthouse in Shelby, North Carolina, June 1
Mourners universally echoed the words of forgiveness by relatives of their slain churchgoers for the white man, Dylann Roof, accused of the murders.
"We are not the ones to judge, we leave that to God," said Maxine Frasier Riley, 65, a retired school guidance counselor.
The Department of Justice has opened a hate crime investigation into the shooting.
Roof posed with the Confederate flag in photos posted online and allegedly made racist remarks to his victims as he opened fire.
In the aftermath of the slayings, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley and other Republicans have called for the flag's removal from the State House grounds, saying it is divisive.
The controversy has spread across the country, with politicians adding to voices clamoring for the removal of Confederate symbols and names, and major retailers removing merchandise with Confederate images from stores and websites.
(Additonal reporting by Roberta Rampton in Washington and Harriet McLeod in Charleston; Editing by Nick Macfie)
Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:43:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. top court backs Obamacare, president says it's here to stay</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/supreme-court-upholds-key-obamacare-insurance-subsidies-141618866--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>U.S. top court backs Obamacare, president says it's here to stay
By Lawrence Hurley 15 hours ago
=======
A boy holds a candle and flowers as he attends a protest to condemn the attack by a gunman at the be
Sarah Maeson, another Briton flying back to Manchester, said: "We don't feel safe. Constantly hearing sirens and helicopters is not really helping your nerves."
EXTRA FLIGHTS
Tunisian authorities named the gunman as Saif Rezgui, a student who they say was not known to them. Dressed in shorts and T-shirt, Rezgui opened fire on the beach of the Imperial Marhaba hotel on Friday, picking out foreigners and leaving Tunisians alive.
Witnesses said he made his way to the pool and hotel, his killing spree ending only when he was shot dead by police.
Tour operators Thomson and First Choice, which are owned by German travel group TUI, said they had about 6,400 customers across Tunisia at the time of the attack, including several of the people killed and injured.
They sent 10 planes to evacuate tourists and said 1,000 had already been repatriated. They also said they would cancel all their holiday packages to Tunisia for at least the next week.
TUI's German tour operator TUI also organized flights for tourists wishing to return home and TUI's Belgian airline, Jetairfly, sent six empty planes to bring tourists back from the island of Djerba and from Ennfida airport on Saturday.
German Foreign Minister Frank-Walter Steinmeier confirmed one German had been killed, but said there may be others.
Tobias Ellwood, a junior minister at Britain's foreign office, told reporters in London the British death toll could rise as there were several who had been seriously wounded.
"This is the most significant terrorist attack on British people since 7/7," he said, referring to attacks on the London transport system on July 7, 2005, that killed 52 people.
NOT ON WATCHLIST
Tunisian authorities said the gunman was not on any watchlist of known potential militants. But one source said Rezgui appeared to have been radicalized over the last six months by Islamist militant recruiters.
As one countermeasure, Prime Minister Essid said that Tunisia planned within a week to close down 80 mosques that remain outside state control for inciting violence.
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have gone to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighboring Libya, where some have set up training camps and vowed to return to attack their homeland.
The attack took place during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan and was one of three linked to Islamist militants on three different continents on Friday.
In France, a decapitated body daubed with Arabic writing was found, and in Kuwait a suicide bomber killed two dozen people at a mosque in Kuwait.
(Additional reporting by Estelle Shirbon in London and Erik Kirschbaum in Berlin; Writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Susan Fenton and Raissa Kasolowsky)
Tunisia
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:49:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Carolina Senate expected to vote to remove Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/south-carolina-senate-expected-vote-remove-confederate-flag-094915626.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>South Carolina Senate expected to vote to remove Confederate flag
By Harriet McLeod 3 hours ago

.
View photo
A Confederate flag stands in front of the South Carolina State House in Columbia, South Carolina July
By Harriet McLeod
CHARLESTON, S.C. (Reuters) - South Carolina's Senate is poised to pass legislation Tuesday to remove the Confederate battle flag from the state house, where it has flown for five decades despite being viewed by many as a symbol of slavery.
A bill to banish the flag from the Capitol grounds to a museum is headed on Tuesday for a third and final vote in the Senate, which it is considered virtually certain to pass. Then it will be taken up by the House of Representatives and could become law as early as Thursday.
The legislation, deemed a non-starter only months ago, has garnered strong bipartisan support in the wake of the June 17 killings of nine African-American churchgoers during Bible study at Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church in the port city of Charleston, about two hours south of the state capital Columbia. Photos of the white man charged in the shooting showed him posing with the flag on a website that also carried a racist manifesto.
Support for the flag has evaporated in an emotional wave of sympathy for the victims and their families, who were widely acclaimed for expressing unconditional forgiveness for the shooter at his bond hearing less than 48 hours after the murders.
Several politicians say the shootings opened their eyes to the divisive nature of the flag and what it means to South Carolina's black population.
"The world changed on ... June 17, not only for the victims and their families, but the entire world took notice," said Senator Joel Lourie, a white Democrat.
"Let today be the beginning of a new story about the state of South Carolina ... a story of how we removed a symbol (and)  helped heal a nation and a state in their mourning," he said on the Senate floor on Monday.
While most politicians recognize the flag is part of South Carolina's heritage, honoring those who died for the southern Confederacy in the Civil War, many agree it should not be flown in public places.
The bill passed a Senate reading Monday by a 37-3 margin and could be approved as early as Thursday. South Carolina's Republican Governor Nikki Haley says she will remove the flag immediately if the law is passed.
The flag was raised atop the State House in 1961 in what critics say was a deliberate slap in the face to the black civil rights movement. It was moved in 2000 to a memorial for the Civil War dead that sits only yards from the entrance to the state Capitol.
(Writing by David Adams; Editing by Cynthia Osterman)
South Carolina
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:07:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bill Cosby said in 2005 lawsuit he gave Quaaludes to women for sex</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/bill-cosby-said-2005-lawsuit-gave-quaaludes-women-000126059.html</Link>
        <Description/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <MainBody>Bill Cosby said in 2005 lawsuit he gave Quaaludes to women for sex
12 hours ago
.
View photo
Comedian Bill Cosby performs at The Temple Buell Theatre in Denver, Colorado January 17, 2015. REUTERS/Barry
LOS ANGELES (Reuters) - Comedian Bill Cosby testified in 2005 that he had obtained Quaaludes with the intent of giving the sedatives to young women in order to have sex with them, according to court documents unsealed on Monday.
Cosby, 77, made the admission during testimony in a civil case brought by a former Temple University employee, Andrea Constand, who alleged that Cosby tricked her into taking drugs before he sexually assaulted her.
The case was settled for an undisclosed sum in 2006 but the documents in the case were unsealed on Monday after the Associated Press went to court.
Cosby's lawyers had argued that the documents would cause severe embarrassment to the comedian-actor, who is best known for playing lovable father figure Dr. Cliff Huxtable on the hit TV comedy series "The Cosby Show" in the 1980s and 1990s.
A representative for Cosby did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Monday.
More than 40 women have come forward in the past year alleging Cosby drugged and sexually assaulted them in incidents dating back decades. His attorneys have consistently denied the allegations.
Cosby has never been criminally charged and most of the allegations exceed the statute of limitations. However, his career has taken a hit in the past year with TV projects and live shows being canceled. He also stepped down from the board of trustees at Temple University, his alma mater.
Cosby testified that in the 1970s he had obtained seven prescriptions for Quaaludes, the brand name for a sedative and muscle relaxant that was widely abused as a recreational drug in the 1970s.
"When you got the Quaaludes, was it in your mind that you were going to use these Quaaludes for young women that you wanted to have sex with?" Cosby was asked in the 2005 deposition.
"Yes," he replied.
Asked whether he ever gave them to young women, his lawyers raised a lengthy series of objections.
Cosby testified later that he gave Constand one and a half pills of the over-the-counter antihistamine drug Benadryl.
Cosby has said little directly about the slew of allegations against him, telling ABC television in an interview in May that he did not wish to discuss them.
"I can't speak; I just don't want to argue; I don't talk about it," Cosby he said.
(Reporting by Piya Sinha-Roy; Editing by Jill Serrjeant, Bill Trott and Lisa Shumaker)
Bill Cosby
=======
        <MainBody>Witnesses describe 'hell' of Taiwan water park blast
By Benjamin Yeh 4 hours ago
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f

.
.
Taipei (AFP) - Witnesses described the scene at a Taiwan water park as "hell" after a ball of fire ripped through a crowd, with authorities putting the injured at more than 500 on Sunday, almost 200 of them seriously hurt.
The injury toll in the blast late Saturday, which came as coloured powder being sprayed on the partygoers ignited, more than doubled as officials began to track down victims who had taken themselves to hospital or been ferried there by others.
Horrifying amateur video footage showed crowds of young revellers dancing in front of a stage and cheering as clouds of green and yellow powder covered them at the "colour party".
But their joy turned to terror when the powder suddenly erupted into flames engulfing them in an inferno as they ran screaming for their lives.
Some were dressed only in swimwear and images from the scene show many with severe burns being tended by those who escaped.
One male student who sustained minor injuries described the scene as "hell".
View gallery
People tend to an injured woman at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in the Pa
"There was blood everywhere, including in the pool where lots of the injured were soaking themselves for relief from the pain," he told reporters.
His visibly shaken girlfriend added: "I saw lots of people whose skin was gone."
Ambulances had struggled to reach the scene, and victims were carried away on rubber rings and inflatable dinghies as friends desperately tried to get them out.
Bystanders poured bottles of water on the scorched skin of the injured. Trails of bloody footprints leading away from the stage remained.
Around 1,000 spectators had been at the Color Play Asia event at the Formosa Fun Coast water park, just outside the capital Taipei, according to officials.
View gallery
<<<<<<< HEAD
Supporters of the Affordable Care Act celebrate after the Supreme Court up held the law in the 6-3 vote
By Lawrence Hurley
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The U.S. Supreme Court on Thursday rejected a conservative legal challenge that could have doomed President Barack Obama's healthcare law, upholding nationwide tax subsidies crucial to his signature domestic policy achievement.
Obama strode into the White House Rose Garden after the ruling to declare that the law known as Obamacare is working, helping millions of Americans afford health insurance who otherwise would have none, and that it is "here to stay."
Chief Justice John Roberts, a conservative appointed by Republican President George W. Bush, wrote in the 6-3 ruling that Congress clearly intended for the tax subsidies that help millions of low- and moderate-income people afford private health insurance to be available in all 50 states.
The court decided that the law did not restrict the subsidies to states that establish their own online health insurance exchanges, as the challengers in the case contended.
"Congress passed the Affordable Care Act to improve health insurance markets, not to destroy them," Roberts wrote, adding nationwide availability of the credits is required to "avoid the type of calamitous result that Congress plainly meant to avoid."
View gallery
U.S. President Barack Obama delivers remarks after the Supreme Court ruled 6-3 to uphold the nationw
Roberts was joined by fellow conservative Justice Anthony Kennedy and the court's four liberal members in a ruling that may ensure Obamacare becomes a lasting element of the nation's social programs.
The ruling means the current system will remain in place, with subsidies available nationwide. If the challengers had won, at least 6.4 million people in at least 34 states would have lost subsidies worth an average of $272 per month.
It marked the second time in three years the high court ruled against a major challenge to the law brought by conservatives. Both rulings were written by Roberts. Unlike the 2012 case, in which the court was split 5-4, Kennedy joined Roberts in the majority this time.
The law was passed by Obama's fellow Democrats in Congress in 2010 over the unified opposition of Republicans, who have fought it since its inception.
Republicans will keep attacking Obamacare in Congress and on the 2016 presidential election campaign trail to energize right-wing voters and raise money, but little chance exists of the law being rolled back before the end of Obama's presidency in January 2017, political analysts said.
Supporters of the Affordable Care Act celebrate after the Supreme Court up held the law in the 6-3 v
Obama said the law has been "woven into the fabric of America."
"After more than 50 votes in Congress to repeal or weaken this law, after a presidential election based in part on preserving or repealing this law, after multiple challenges to this law before the Supreme Court, the Affordable Care Act is here to stay," Obama added.
The question before the justices was whether a four-word phrase in the expansive law saying subsidies are available to those buying insurance on exchanges "established by the state" has been correctly interpreted by the administration to allow subsidies to be available nationwide.
The exchanges are online marketplaces that allow consumers to shop among competing insurance plans.
Roberts wrote that although the conservative challengers' arguments about the plain meaning of the statute were "strong,' the "context and structure of the act compel us to depart from what would otherwise be the most natural reading of the pertinent statutory phrase."
Supporters of the Affordable Care Act celebrate after the Supreme Court up held the law in the 6-3 v
SCALIA DISSENTS
After Chief Justice Roberts announced the decision from the bench, Justice Antonin Scalia read for 11 minutes from his dissenting opinion inside the court's white marble and crimson-draped setting.
Scalia said the statute's words were clear, that Congress wanted to limit the credits to the state exchanges. Scalia recalled the court's 2012 decision upholding the law, again over his dissent.
"We really should start calling the law SCOTUScare," Scalia said. SCOTUS is the acronym for the Supreme Court of the United States.
"This court has no free-floating power to rescue Congress from its drafting mistakes," Scalia added.
View gallery
Interns with media organizations run with the decision upholding the Affordable Care Act at the Supr
Roberts, sitting next to him on the bench, sat stone-faced. He smiled slightly at the SCOTUScare line, but otherwise betrayed no emotion.
Conservative Justices Clarence Thomas and Samuel Alito joined Scalia's dissent.
The Obama administration said 16.4 million previously uninsured people have gained health insurance since the law was enacted. There are currently around 26 million Americans without health insurance, according to government figures.
"This is not about the Affordable Care Act as legislation, or Obamacare as a political football. This is healthcare in America," Obama said.
Congressional Republicans vowed to continue efforts to repeal Obamacare despite appeals from Democrats for them to stop.
The top two congressional Republicans denounced the law on Thursday. Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnnell said it makes life "miserable" for many people it purports to help. House of Representatives Speaker John Boehner called it "fundamentally broken."
The U.S. hospital industry breathed a collective sigh of relief on Thursday and investors cheered that the growing number of paying customers created by Obamacare would not disappear.
The ruling sparked a broad rally in shares of health insurers with an especially heavy stampede into hospital operators, which were seen as being at particular risk of facing steep losses had the subsidies been struck down.
Shares of hospital chain Tenet Healthcare surged 12.2 percent to rank as the biggest gainer for the day in the S&amp;P 500. Four other hospital operators' shares hit lifetime highs: Community Health Systems, HCA Holdings, Universal Health Services and Lifepoint Health, with gains ranging from 7.6 percent to nearly 13 percent.
Conservatives have called Obamacare a government overreach and "socialized medicine" and launched a series of legal challenges.
The current case started as a long-shot by conservative lawyers opposed to law. Financed by a libertarian Washington group called the Competitive Enterprise Institute, the lawyers recruited four people from Virginia as plaintiffs. The lead plaintiff was a self-employed limousine driver named David King.
The plaintiffs said they were "deeply disappointed" with the ruling. The law "unfairly restricts the health insurance choices of millions of people, and it threatens their jobs as well," they added.
The case is King v. Burwell, U.S. Supreme Court, No. 14-114.
(Additional reporting by Joan Biskupic and Susan Cornwell in Washington and Dan Burns in New York; Editing by Will Dunham)
Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>2015 NBA draft winners and losers</title>
        <Link>http://sports.yahoo.com/news/2015-nba-draft-winners-and-losers-062658169.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>LOSER: JAHLIL OKAFOR
Former Duke center Jahlil Okafor appeared to be the biggest competition for Kentucky forward Karl-Anthony Towns for the top pick in the draft. It was projected that if Okafor wasn't selected by Minnesota, that the Los Angeles Lakers would take him with the second overall pick.
Minnesota took Towns as expected. Lakers general manager Mitch Kupchak, however, never made Okafor a draft promise for good reason. Kupchak was quietly enamored with Ohio State guard D'Angelo Russell and selected him second.
Okafor ended up with the rebuilding Sixers with the third pick. Okafor was the best talent on the board and a surprise option for Philadelphia. Even so, the Sixers have drafted a center for the third year in a row after taking Nerlens Noel and still-injured Joel Embiid the past two seasons.
When asked how the Sixers can make it work with three young centers, Okafor said: "I don't know. It's not my job to figure out. I'll go there and work as hard as I can."
WINNER: MINNESOTA TIMBERWOLVES
The T'wolves filled their biggest roster need by taking Towns with the first overall pick. He joins an intriguing group of young teammates that includes 2015 Rookie of the Year Andrew Wiggins , 2015 dunk champion Zach LaVine , injury-plagued guard Ricky Rubio , center Gorgui Dieng and forward Shabazz Muhammad . Minnesota also acquired the draft rights to Duke point guard Tyus Jones , a Minneapolis native who was the 2015 NCAA Final Four Most Outstanding Player.
Towns should be the next great power forward in T'wolves history after Kevin Garnett and Kevin Love . He also has the challenge of trying to get Minnesota to the postseason for the first time since 2004.
"That's going to be the main goal of the season for me, making the playoffs," Towns said.
View gallery
DeMarcus Cousins remains with the Kings, for now. (Getty Images)
LOSER: SACRAMENTO KINGS
The Sacramento Kings have had one of the least memorable weeks in franchise history, which is very hard to accomplish. Yahoo Sports' Adrian Wojnarowski reported that coach George Karl would like All-Star center DeMarcus Cousins to be traded. New general manager Vlade Divac and owner Vivek Ranadive maintain they don't want to trade Cousins. A disgruntled Cousins was not dealt on draft night but could be later, a source said. The Lakers had talks with the Kings leading up to the draft.
The biggest need in recent years for the Kings has been a point guard. Sacramento passed on All-Rookie Team point guard Elfrid Payton a year ago in the draft. On Thursday, the Kings had a chance to select perhaps the best true point guard in the draft in Emmanuel Mudiay with the sixth pick. Sacramento, however, passed because Divac said Mudiay refused to work out for the Kings. The Kings took Kentucky forward-center Willie Cauley-Stein instead.
Mudiay "refused to come here and work out and I just felt I didn't know him enough to make that very important decision," Divac told reporters in Sacramento.
Back in 2009, there was a talented point guard prospect who refused to work out for the Warriors, but former general manager Larry Harris drafted him seventh overall anyway. The point guard's name was Stephen Curry.
WINNER: PORTLAND TRAIL BLAZERS
It appears that Blazers free agent LaMarcus Aldridge has played his last game in Portland. The San Antonio Spurs and Los Angeles Lakers are the front-runners to land the All-Star, a source told Yahoo Sports. The Dallas native is also expected to have interest from the Dallas Mavericks.
That's not good news for the Blazers. But in preparation for the expected departure, they acquired two forwards in trades: Mason Plumlee from the Brooklyn Nets; and Noah Vonleh from the Charlotte Hornets.
The Blazers acquired Plumlee and the draft rights to Notre Dame guard Pat Connaughton for the draft rights of Rondae Hollis-Jefferson and guard Steve Blake. Plumlee averaged 11.8 points and 7.6 rebounds in 45 games as a starter last season. Vonleh, acquired on Wednesday, was the ninth pick of last year's draft and was limited to 25 games primarily because of injury. Plumlee and Vonleh don't combine to be Aldridge by any means, but at least Blazers general manager Neil Olshey is being proactive.
LOSER: KEVON LOONEY
Former UCLA forward Kevon Looney entered the draft with two major red flags: a hip injury and sports asthma. While Looney was projected to be middle to late first-round pick, it's inevitable that such issues would hurt one's status. Even so, Looney was one of 20 prospects selected for the draft's green room with a late invitation from the NBA.
Late in the first round, however, Looney, his family and his agent Todd Ramasar abruptly departed from the room for the depths of the Barclays Center when the forward's prospects looked in doubt. But once Looney and his family received word that the champion Golden State Warriors were selecting him with the 30th and final pick of the first round, they rushed back to the green room to sit down and enjoy the once-in-a-lifetime moment in front of the TV cameras. After the Warriors' pick was announced, Looney hugged his family but turned his back on his agent who reached out to him.
Chalk this up to a tough and emotional night for the 19-year-old, who has a reputation as a good person.
WINNER: SATNAM SINGH BHAMARA
Satnam Singh Bhamara became the first Indian-born player to be drafted in the NBA when the Dallas Mavericks took him with the 52nd overall pick in the second round. The mammoth 7-foot-2, 290-pounder heard of his selection while sitting in the stands. He is considered a big project who will likely begin his career with the Mavericks' NBA Development League Texas Legends.
More NBA draft coverage:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Timberwolves select Karl-Anthony Towns with No. 1 pick in NBA draft</title>
        <Link>http://sports.yahoo.com/blogs/nba-ball-dont-lie/minnesota-timberwolves-select-karl-anthony-towns-with-no--1-pick-in-2015-nba-draft-214703304.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Content preferences
Done
NEW YORK  There might not have been a promise in place , but there's no longer any question that Flip Saunders sees immense, franchise-changing promise in the 6-foot-11-inch, 250-pound frame of Karl-Anthony Towns . The Minnesota Timberwolves head coach and president of basketball operations removed any lingering doubt on Thursday night, selecting the former University of Kentucky big man with the No. 1 overall pick in the 2015 NBA draft at Barclays Center in Brooklyn.
[ Follow Dunks Don't Lie on Tumblr: The best slams from all of basketball]
"For me, I'm just blessed to be in this opportunity to just show that a boy from Piscataway, N.J., and the Dominican Republic can make it," Towns said during his post-selection press conference. "I'm blessed to be in this situation, to be in this seat talking to all of you. It just means the world that I'm going to be able to show kids around the world that with a little hard work, determination, a little bit of luck and some guidance, you can really make it far in this world."
To be fair, there wasn't very much lingering doubt about Towns. The 19-year-old had long been considered one of the top prospects in the class of 2015. He averaged 10.3 points, 6.7 rebounds, 2.3 blocks and 1.1 assists in 21.1 minutes per game at Kentucky, playing comparatively limited minutes for an insanely deep squad that won its first 38 games before falling to Wisconsin in the Final Four.
Even while surrounded by stars in Lexington, Towns stood out as something special in the making, earning a slew of honors during his lone collegiate season  SEC Freshman of the Year, an All-SEC First Team nod, an All-American Second Team selection  and joining the likes of Duke center Jahlil Okafor and Ohio State guard D'Angelo Russell in the running for the No. 1 spot. As the pre-draft process progressed, though, Towns separated himself from even his future-star peers.
Talent evaluators grew increasingly enamored with Towns' immediate and evident gifts on the defensive end, where he proved capable under John Calipari of stalling pick-and-rolls in space, defending the rim in the paint and cleaning the defensive glass. And as the workouts wore on, the videos kept coming, with Towns comfortably stepping out to the perimeter with a smooth touch that pairs well with the interior game he showed with the Wildcats.
Suddenly, a clearer, more expansive and far more enticing picture began to emerge. When you stepped back and took a look, you saw something that seemed an awful lot like the ideal power forward/center for the state of NBA play in 2015.
Towns topped many mock drafts even before May's draft lottery, which saw the Wolves win the No. 1 pick for the first time in franchise history, their reward for finishing a Western Conference-worst 16-66 in a down and dismal 2014-15 campaign. While Saunders was reportedly enamored of the polished low-post game of Duke's Okafor, he ultimately preferred the opportunity to pair Towns' two-way potential with that of reigning Rookie of the Year Andrew Wiggins , the No. 1 pick in last year's draft , to lead Minnesota into the future alongside playmaking point guard Ricky Rubio , electric skywalking swingman Zach LaVine and a group of young complementary pieces on a Wolves team that could soon be ready to run.
Towns steps into a high-profile frontcourt spot previously occupied by the likes of franchise legend and future Hall of Famer Kevin Garnett , who returned to Minnesota at last year's trade deadline and whose status for next season remains unclear, and former All-Star Kevin Love , whom Saunders traded to the Cleveland Cavaliers last summer in a blockbuster deal that returned Wiggins and 2013 No. 1 pick Anthony Bennett . The young fella's got some pretty big shoes to fill. It's a good thing he's got pretty big feet .
"The craziest thing about those two power forwards, I think you can see some resemblance of me in both of them," Towns recently told Yahoo Sports NBA columnist Marc J. Spears . "They've shown how effective they were in Minnesota. I'm trying to make my own stamp."
One thing's for sure  Towns won't lack for confidence as he sets about the work of giving the Twin Cities faithful a winning team to support after 10 straight sub-.500 seasons, no playoff berths since 2004 and just one trip past the opening round of the playoffs in the franchise's 26-year history.
"It doesn't matter to me where I play," Towns recently told Jon Krawczynski of The Associated Press . "It matters what you do at the place you play at. It doesn't matter how successful or how unsuccessful a team is. It can all change with one pick."
Saunders, the rest of the Timberwolves brass and fans across Minnesota are banking on Towns being that one pick.
"That's going to be the main goal of the season for me, making the playoffs," Towns said Thursday. "[...] We're going to work real hard right now in the summer, get everything straight, and we're going to make sure that we go into the season with the best possible team, with the best mindset, and go out there and try to win and make it to the playoffs."
- - - - - - -
Dan Devine is an editor for Ball Don't Lie on Yahoo Sports. Have a tip? Email him at devine@yahoo-inc.com or follow him on Twitter!
Stay connected with Ball Don't Lie on Twitter @YahooBDL , "Like" BDL on Facebook and follow Dunks Don't Lie on Tumblr for year-round NBA talk, jokes and more.
Minnesota Timberwolves
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:10:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>15 emails missing from Clinton cache</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/state-dept-15-emails-missing-clinton-cache-221215204--politics.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>.
View photo
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Rodham Clinton speaks during a campaign stop at Christ the King United Church of Christ, Tuesday, June 23, 2015, in Florissant, Mo. (AP Photo/Jeff Roberson)
WASHINGTON (AP)  The State Department cannot find in its records all or part of 15 work-related emails from Hillary Rodham Clinton's private server that were released this week by a House panel investigating the 2012 attack in Benghazi, Libya, officials said Thursday.
The emails all predate the Sept. 11 assault on the U.S. diplomatic facility and include scant words written by Clinton herself, the officials said. They consist of more in a series of would-be intelligence reports passed to her by longtime political confidant Sidney Blumenthal, the officials said.
Nevertheless, the fact that the State Department says it can't find them among emails she provided surely will raise new questions about Clinton's use of a personal email account and server while secretary of state and whether she has provided the agency all of her work-related correspondence, as she claims.
Rep. Trey Gowdy, chairman of the Select Committee on Benghazi, released a statement Thursday saying, "This confirms doubts about the completeness of Clinton's self-selected public record and raises serious questions about her decision to erase her personal server  especially before it could be analyzed by an independent, neutral third-party arbiter."
When asked about the discrepancy, Nick Merrill, a Clinton campaign spokesman, said, "She has turned over 55,000 pages of materials to the State Department, including all emails in her possession from Mr. Blumenthal."
Clinton is running for the 2016 Democratic presidential nomination.
Clinton's use of the non-governmental email while in office was not publicly disclosed until earlier this year, after the committee sought her correspondence related to the Benghazi attack. She says the single account for personal and professional purposes was a matter of convenience, and says all her work emails were included in the 55,000 pages of documents she later handed over to the State Department. Emails of a personal nature were destroyed, she says.
The State Department informed the Select Benghazi Committee on Thursday that they are no longer certain that's the case, according to officials who spoke on condition of anonymity because they weren't authorized to speak publicly on the matter. The officials said Julia Frifield, the assistant secretary of state for legislative affairs, confirmed that nine emails and parts of six others that the committee made public Monday couldn't be located in the department's records.
As for 46 other, previously unreleased Libya-related Blumenthal emails published by the committee, officials said all are in the department's records. They weren't handed over to congressional investigators because they had no relevance to events in Benghazi and did not correspond to the committee's request, the officials said. The officials added that they are willing to provide emails outside the committee's initial request, but warned that doing so would require more time.
The emails missing from the State Department's records include missives from Blumenthal in which he sends media accounts about the killing of one of Libyan dictator Moammar Gadhafi's sons, various reports on internal politics among Libya's rebels and news of the assassination of a former Gadhafi minister in Vienna. The last email was sent Aug. 28, 2012, two weeks before the Benghazi attack, and none focus particularly on the eastern Libyan city.
Clinton's responses are brief. In one from August 2011, she tells Blumenthal she will be in Paris the next day to meet rebel leaders and says she had "to resort to new iPad" because she didn't have electricity or Blackberry coverage after Hurricane Irene.
In another from March 2012, she passes on an adviser's skepticism regarding one of Blumenthal's reports about political intrigue in post-Gadhafi Libya, saying: "This strain credulity based on what I know. Any other info about it?"
And after a long August 2012 note from Blumenthal about Libya's new interim President Mohamed Yousef el-Magariaf, Clinton writes: "Another keeper  thanks and please keep 'em coming." Four days later, she responds to a follow-up reports about el-Magariaf, saying: "Fascinating. I had a very good call w him."
Clinton's critics are likely to focus less on the substance of the emails than on the fact that they weren't shared with the State Department.
Gowdy, a South Carolina Republican, has pressed for an explanation of why Blumenthal gave the committee emails not previously shared by the State Department. The suggestion has been that either the department or Clinton was hiding something.
Gowdy said Thursday that the emails show Clinton "was soliciting and regularly corresponding with Sidney Blumenthal  who was passing unvetted intelligence information about Libya from a source with a financial interest in the country. It just so happens these emails directly contradict her public statement that the messages from Blumenthal were unsolicited."
Clinton aides say her submission to the department included all emails from Blumenthal and a dozen more exchanges that weren't in the records he provided the House committee. They said some from Blumenthal's record, which was provided as a Microsoft Word document, couldn't be confirmed as having been sent as emails.
State Department officials also questioned the provenance of some exchanges because they weren't formatted as emails.
___
This story corrects the breakdown of missing emails to nine full emails and parts of six others.
Hillary Rodham Clinton
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>SCOTUS Obamacare ruling: 2016 presidential candidates weigh in</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/scotus-obamacare-2016-candidates-react-122431771361.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Skrillex: The making of a superstar</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/katie-couric-exclusive-edm-superstar-skrillex-152210272.html?soc_src=mail&amp;soc_trk=ma</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Complete interview
By Katie Brinn and Andrew Rothschild
He introduces himself as Sonny Moore, but to his millions of young fans, hes Skrillex  one of the biggest names in electronic dance music (EDM). Since he first found success as an EDM DJ and producer in 2011, Skrillex has collected six Grammys, 19 million Facebook fans and an estimated $20 million  all while giving away most of his music for free.
And at just 27 years old  an age he characterizes as not young  he says he has no plans of slowing down. The EDM prodigy is churning out new collaborations with superstars both inside and outside his genre, testing the limits of his craft  and his fan base  with every new innovation.
One of his boldest, and perhaps most polarizing new partners: pop heartthrob Justin Bieber. Moore and fellow EDM DJ Diplo, under the moniker Jack , teamed up with the Biebs in early 2015 to produce the single Where Are  Now. The track quickly shot to the top of mainstream charts, drawing the ire of some EDM fans who were vocal with their criticism that Skrillex was selling out.
Yahoo global news anchor Katie Couric met up with Moore at his studio in downtown L.A. to give him a chance to respond to the criticism and to take a rare, intimate look into the life and career of one of EDMs biggest stars.
Working with Bieber
He was super-polite, Moore says of his first encounter with Justin Bieber at a party at New York Fashion Week earlier this year. The rest was history. Teaming up as Jack , Skrillex and Diplo worked on Biebers a cappella vocal track to make a hit that few of his fans saw coming.
Childhood of music and Scientology
Sporting a hardcore look from an early age, Moore says he is no stranger to being misunderstood. Youre always bullied if youre an emo kid, he admits. But he says his parents were always supportive of his alternative style and his unconventional ambitions.
The family hit a rough patch when Moore learned at age 16 that his parents had adopted him. He says his music helped him get through that period and has helped as he deals with another trial his family is now facing: the recent death of his mother. He talks about his relationship with her, how his family has come together to mourn and how Scientology has long helped his family cope with hardship.
EDM, drugs and that hairdo
Of course, its impossible to ignore the drug culture that goes hand in hand with EDMs rave scene, a scene Skrillex has so helped to define. Some critics, in fact, have linked the rise of Molly to Skrillexs ascent. Though he emphasizes that he would never want to be telling kids how to run their lives, Skrillex insists that he never uses drugs. I wouldnt be able to do 300 shows a year if I was doing drugs, he says.
Amid their conversation, Couric and Skrillex take a phone call from a special guest star, Marshmello, a mysterious EDM newcomer whose identity remains top secret. Until now, fans have even been unsure whether the rising star is a man or a woman.
Before wrapping up their chat, Skrillex gets a chance to comment on the origins of his signature haircut and muse about what his life might look like in 10 years.
Skrillex ft. Katie Couric
Not to outdo Justin Bieber, Skrillex and Couric decide there is room for one more unlikely EDM collaboration. Together, they hit the studio to churn out what could be a pretty sweet hit. Check out the final product.
Arts &amp; Entertainment
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 14:19:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Obama legacy on race</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/the-obama-legacy-on-race-president-barack-obama-122362581601.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:43:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French anti-Uber protests turn violent</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/french-cabbies-angry-uber-block-paris-airports-roads-103556123.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>The paternoster is a doorless, conveyor-belt-style elevator that is largely extinct, except in Germany, where enthusiasts have kept the lifts running. Photo: Ellen Jervell/The Wall Street Journal
Load More
Paris (AFP) - Protests against ride-booking app Uber turned violent in France on Thursday as taxi drivers set fire to vehicles and blocked major roads.
American rocker Courtney Love was caught up in the demonstrations when a vehicle she was travelling in outside Paris was attacked.
Around 3,000 cabbies took part in the strike, blocking access to the capital's Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports, and preventing cars reaching train stations around the country.
Ten people were arrested, seven police officers were injured and 70 vehicles were damaged in clashes between Uber drivers and taxi drivers.
The service, known as UberPOP, has been illegal in France since January, but the law has proved difficult to enforce and it continues to operate.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said after meeting taxi drivers' unions following a fraught day: "UberPOP is an illegal service, it must be closed down."
Until that was done, "the vehicles of UberPOP drivers should be systematically impounded when they are openly breaking the law", the minister said.
"Governing the country will never be done by the law of the jungle," Cazeneuve added.
One of the taxi drivers' representatives, Ibrahima Sylla, described the minister's words as "promises, again" and said the drivers were considering continuing the demonstrations.
Love, Kurt Cobain's widow, was caught up in a confrontation near Charles de Gaulle airport.
She tweeted that protesters "ambushed" her vehicle and "were holding our driver hostage".
She appealed to the French president in another message, writing "Francois Hollande where are the fucking police???"
French taxi drivers burn tyres during a protest against taxi app Uber in the southern city of Marsei
"This is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad," she added.
- Two vehicles torched -
In the most serious incident in Paris, one private chauffeur, who said he did not work for Uber "or any other app" was dragged from his van when he reached a blockade in the west of Paris.
Angry taxi drivers slashed the tyres of his vehicle, smashed a window and then set it and a chauffeur-driven van on fire.
Police eventually fired teargas to break up the protest on the western stretch of the ring road around the capital and cleared burning tyres.
Prime Minister Manuel Valls said during a visit to Colombia that the perpetrators of the "unacceptable" violence "can be found in both camps" and they would be found and prosecuted.
Taxi drivers are furious at what they see as unfair competition from Uber, which puts customers in touch with private drivers at prices lower than those of traditional taxis.
Licensed cabbies say the service is endangering their jobs by flooding the market with low-cost drivers.
One driver said the strikers had been driven to desperation.
"Taxi drivers -- alright, they've got big mouths -- but normally they're not aggressive," said Malia, 50, who has driven a taxi for three years.
"But these guys have families to feed, debts. They've been pushed to the brink."
- Illegal in France -
More peaceful protests took place at transport hubs in other major cities including Bordeaux, Marseille and Toulouse.
Cabbies argued that the disruption was justified.
"UberPOP is banned, but it's still here," cabbie Stephane Molla said in Bordeaux, southwest France.
Cabbies in France, like their colleagues in several other countries, have held several protests against the app -- some of which have turned violent.
On at least two occasions in Strasbourg in eastern France last week, taxi drivers posed as customers in order to lure Uber drivers to isolated spots where they were assaulted by cab drivers and their vehicles damaged.
In Paris, the government tried to strengthen its hand on Wednesday by obtaining a court order banning Uber from operating in the capital, but the company dismissed the move.
"We will fight it (in the courts) and we'll see what happens on appeal. For the time being it changes nothing, UberPOP can continue to operate," the head of Uber France, Thibaud Simphal, told the BFM Business channel.
San Francisco-based Uber, which offers several types of ride-sharing services, claims to have 400,000 UberPOP users in France.
However, its drivers do not pay taxes, do not need to undergo the 250 hours of training mandatory for French cabbies and do not require the same insurance as taxis.
Uber
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:21:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds Obamacare subsidies</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/supreme-court-upholds-obamacare-subsidies-122340028541.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:20:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What does SCOTUS Obamacare ruling mean?</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/what-does-scotus-obamacare-ruling-mean--142038782.html</Link>
=======
Bloody footprints are seen on the pavement after an explosion at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement par
One male witness told local news channel CTI: "It started on the left side of the stage. At the beginning I thought it was part of the special effects of the party but then I realised there was something wrong and people started screaming and running."
Lee Lih-jong, deputy chief of the health bureau of the New Taipei City government, said 519 people had been injured with 190 of them seriously hurt.
The severely wounded are being treated in intensive care units at 37 different hospitals.
"The reason why the burns were so severe was that in addition to burns to the skin, there were also injuries caused by burns to the respiratory organs from the large amount of colour powder inhaled," Lee told AFP.
"The next 24 hours will be critical for those severely injured."
View gallery
Local officials walk at the site of an explosion at a water park in Pali district, in New Taipei Cit
Several major hospitals in Taiwan have been asked to donate skin grafts and surgical equipment to help treat the injured, the Ministry of Health and Welfare said.
- Young victims -
One father broke down as he told how his daughter was in intensive care with third degree burns.
"She was attending a music concert... why would there be an explosion?" he wept bewildered.
"More than 80 percent of her body has been scorched," he told reporters.
View gallery
Overturned tables lie on the ground at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in th
The man, who was not named, lashed out at authorities saying they had not contacted him or offered any help.
The water park issued a statement Sunday saying it was "deeply saddened" and would cooperate with the ongoing investigation.
General manager Chen Hui-ying told reporters that all partygoers had been insured but did not say to what amount.
"Throwing coloured corn starch around... we had never heard such an activity could be dangerous," she said.
The health bureau's Lee said details of the ages of the victims were not yet available, "but all looked very young, in their 20s or even younger".
The national news agency CNA reported 13 of the injured were foreign nationals.
Among them were four from Hong Kong, two each from China and Japan, one from Macau, Malaysia and Singapore respectively, with another being identified as from "Europe or America" and the last remained of unknown origin.
"Our initial understanding is this explosion and fire... was caused by the powder spray. It could have been due to the heat of the lights on the stage," said a spokesman for the New Taipei City fire department.
Deputy fire chief Chen Chung-yueh said Sunday the blast may have been caused by "sparks from machinery or lighting equipment".
Five people including event manager Lu Chung-chi were detained by police.
They are being questioned by prosecutors on charges of offences against public safety and negligence of duties that caused severe injuries, a police spokesman said.
Color Play Asia has also run other "colour parties" in Taiwan in the past two years.
Taiwan's premier Mao Chih-kuo, who visited the injured Sunday, ordered that all such events be banned unless their safety could be assured.
Taiwan
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:02:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Clinton says Puerto Rico should have access to U.S. bankruptcy laws</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/clinton-says-puerto-rico-access-u-bankruptcy-laws-110251683.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Clinton says Puerto Rico should have access to U.S. bankruptcy laws
By Amanda Becker 2 hours ago

U.S. Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton   in Fairfax, Virginia, June 26, 2015. REUTERS/Joshua
By Amanda Becker
IOWA CITY, IOWA (Reuters) - U.S. Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton said Tuesday that Puerto Rico's public entities should be able to use U.S. bankruptcy laws to restructure some $72 billion in debt.
Like U.S. states, Puerto Rico, a commonwealth, cannot file for bankruptcy protection. Unlike U.S. states, Puerto Rico's public entities, including municipalities, are not covered by U.S. Chapter 9 bankruptcy laws.
Puerto Rico's non-voting delegate in the U.S. Congress has called for legislation that would allow Puerto Rico to access the same bankruptcy laws available to other municipalities, as has Puerto Rico's Governor Alejandro Garcia Padilla.
The U.S. Court of Appeals for the First Circuit late Monday affirmed a lower court decision to strike down Puerto Rican legislation aimed at granting local municipalities the right to enter bankruptcy, but said excluding the U.S. territory's public entities from federal bankruptcy law was unconstitutional.
"Congress and the Obama administration need to partner with Puerto Rico by providing real support and tools so that Puerto Rico cando the hard work it will taketo get on apath toward stability and prosperity," Clinton said in a statement provided to Reuters.
"As a first step, Congress should providePuerto Rico the same authority that states alreadyhaveto enable severely distressed government entities, including municipalities and public corporations, to restructure their debts under Chapter 9 of the Bankruptcy Code," Clinton added.
The White House said last week that there is "no one in the administration" that is "contemplating a federal bailout of Puerto Rico" but that the U.S. Congress should "take a look at" whether Puerto Rico's government-owned corporations should be able to access Chapter 9 bankruptcy protection.
Congressional Republicans largely oppose such a step. Republican presidential candidate Jeb Bush said in April that he thinks Puerto Rico's public agencies should have the ability to use U.S. bankruptcy laws.
"We're not talking about a bailout, we're talking about a fair shot at success," Clinton said Tuesday.
Clinton said in the statement that the "inconsistent and incoherent" application of U.S. federal law to Puerto Rico contributed to its economic situation, noting high utility rates and unemployment have led to an economy that has shrunk for eight of the last nine years.
"One troubling example of this treatment isthe lack of equity in federal funding for Puerto Rico under Medicaid and Medicare," Clinton said of health insurance programs sponsored by the U.S. government.
Clinton, also a former first lady, is the front runner for the Democratic nomination ahead of the general election in November 2016.
(Reporting by Amanda Becker in Iowa; additional reporting by Megan Davies in New York; Editing by Nick Macfie)
Puerto Rico
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Eric Holder: The Justice Department could strike deal with Edward Snowden</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/eric-holder-the-justice-department-could-strike-123393663066.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:53:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Condemned Boston Marathon bomber files motion for new trial</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/condemned-boston-marathon-bomber-files-motion-trial-185636938.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Condemned Boston Marathon bomber files motion for new trial
17 hours ago
.
View gallery
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev and his defense attorney Judy Clarke (2nd R) are shown in a courtroom sketch after he is sentenced at the federal courthouse in Boston, Massachusetts May 15, 2015. The jury in the Boston Marathon bombing trial on Friday sentenced Tsarnaev to death for helping to carry out the 2013 attack that killed three people and injured 264.    REUTERS/Jane Flavell Collins     NO SALES. NO ARCHIVES. FOR EDITORIAL USE ONLY. NOT FOR SALE FOR MARKETING OR ADVERTISING CAMPAIGNS.
BOSTON (AP)  Lawyers for Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev filed a motion for a new trial Monday, less than two weeks after he was formally sentenced to death for the 2013 attack.
The motion did not contain any details on Tsarnaev's legal arguments, saying only that a new trial is "required in the interests of justice."
Tsarnaev, 21, was convicted of 30 federal charges in the bombing, which killed three people and injured more than 260. The same jury recommended the death penalty, and a federal judge on June 24 sentenced him to death.
Tsarnaev's lawyers call the motion a "placeholder" until they can file a more detailed motion next month.
The defense also filed a request for a judgment notwithstanding the verdict. Both motions are routinely filed by defense lawyers asking a judge to toss out the jury's verdict.
A spokeswoman for U.S. Attorney Carmen Ortiz did not immediately return a call seeking comment.
During his trial, Tsarnaev's lawyers admitted that he and his brother planted two pressure-cooker bombs near the finish line of the marathon. They argued that his older brother, Tamerlan, was the mastermind of the attack and asked the jury to sentence him to life in prison instead of to death.
Tamerlan was killed during an escape attempt several days after the bombings.
Among the arguments expected to be raised in Tsarnaev's appeal is the defense contention that the trial should have been moved out of Massachusetts because of the emotional impact the bombing had here. Judge George O'Toole Jr. rejected numerous requests from Tsarnaev's lawyers to move the trial.
Dzhokhar Tsarnaev
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:36:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deported man charged with murder in San Francisco shooting</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/deported-man-charged-murder-san-francisco-shooting-003632460.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Deported man charged with murder in San Francisco shooting
By Curtis Skinner 12 hours ago

San Francisco Shooter States He Chose City for Sanctuary Policies

San Francisco Shooter States He Chose City for Sanctuary Policies
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
San Francisco Shooter States He Chose City for Sanctuary Policies
 Replay video
Swipe Right for Employment? New App Is Tinder for Job Seekers

Load More
By Curtis Skinner
SAN FRANCISCO (Reuters) - A convicted felon who had been deported from the United States to Mexico five times was charged on Monday with murder in the shooting of a woman last week at a tourist area in San Francisco.
Francisco Sanchez, 45, was arrested for the shooting of Kathryn Steinle, 32, last Wednesday evening. The case drew national attention after Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump during the weekend used the killing to decry U.S.-Mexico border security.
The San Francisco District Attorney's Office said in a statement that Sanchez would be arraigned on Tuesday.
Immigration officials said Sanchez was released from federal prison in March after a felony re-entry conviction. He was transferred to the custody of the San Francisco County Sheriff's Office on a drug arrest warrant and federal officials asked to be notified prior to his release.
The Sheriff's Office said the charges were dismissed and since there was no active warrant or judicial order for Sanchez's removal, the city's policy deemed Sanchez "ineligible for extended detention" and he was freed.
View gallery
Flowers and a candle form a makeshift memorial for shooting victim Kathryn Steinle on Pier 14 in San
Sanchez has a long criminal history including seven felonies and has been deported to Mexico five times, according to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.
Earlier on Monday, San Francisco Mayor Ed Lee expressed concern about Sanchez's release into the community and directed authorities to look at the steps they took with Sanchez leading up to the shooting.
"All agencies involved, federal and local, need to conduct quick, thorough and objective reviews of their own departmental policies and the decisions they made in this case," Lee said in a statement.
He defended his city's so-called sanctuary policy as one that protects immigrant communities and that should not shield criminals.
Dozens of such sanctuary cities across the United States limit the assistance they provide to federal immigration authorities aiming to apprehend or deport individuals.
View gallery
Flowers and a candle form a makeshift memorial for shooting victim Kathryn Steinle on Pier 14 in San
An anonymous law enforcement source told the San Francisco Chronicle newspaper that Sanchez was shooting at sea lions and struck Steinle by accident.
In a jail house interview with broadcaster KGO-TV, Sanchez admitted to the shooting, saying he had just taken several sleeping pills and the gun went off when he picked it up.
Trump, who drew heavy criticism for describing immigrants from Mexico to the United States as drug-runners and rapists during the launch of his presidential bid last month, on Saturday said the shooting was a "totally preventable act of violence committed by an illegal immigrant."

(Editing by Steve Orlofsky and Bill Trott)
SAN FRANCISCO
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:01:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bill Cosby said he obtained drugs to give to women for sex</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/ap-bill-cosby-said-obtained-000930605.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>View photo
Documents: Bill Cosby said he obtained drugs to give to women for sex
Bill Cosby admitted in 2005 that he secured quaaludes with the intent of giving them to young women he wanted to have sex with, and that he gave the sedative to at least one woman and "other people," according to documents obtained Monday by The Associated Press.
Bill Cosby
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:44:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>SC Senate votes to remove flag from Statehouse grounds</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/south-carolina-lawmakers-return-confederate-flag-debate-085829900.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>SC Senate votes to remove flag from Statehouse grounds
By JEFFREY COLLINS 9 hours ago

.
.
COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP)  The South Carolina Senate voted Monday to pull the Confederate flag off the Capitol grounds, clearing the way for a historic measure that could remove the banner more than five decades after it was first flown above the Statehouse to protest integration.
A second vote will be needed Tuesday to send the proposal to the House, where it faces a less certain future. But Monday's 37-3 vote was well over the two-thirds majority needed to advance the bill.
If the House passes the same measure, the flag and flagpole could be removed as soon as Gov. Nikki Haley signs the papers. The flag would be lowered for the last time and shipped off to the state's Confederate Relic Room, near where the last Confederate flag to fly over the Statehouse dome is stored.
The vote came at the end of a day of debate in which several white senators said they had come to understand why their black colleagues felt the flag no longer represented the valor of Southern soldiers but the racism that led the South to separate from the United States more than 150 years ago.
As the senators spoke, the desk of their slain colleague, Clementa Pinckney, was still draped in black cloth. Pinckney and eight other black people were fatally shot June 17 during Bible study at a historic African-American church in Charleston. Authorities have charged a gunman who posed for pictures with the rebel banner. Police say he was driven by racial hatred.
Several senators said the grace shown by the families of the victims willing to forgive the gunman also changed their minds.
"We now have the opportunity, the obligation, to put the exclamation point on an extraordinary narrative of good and evil, of love and mercy that will take its place in the history books," said Sen. Tom Davis, a Republican.
View gallery
State Sen. Lee Bright lets his position be known in the senate chambers July 6, 2015 in Columbia, So
After the vote, Sen. Vincent Sheheen, a Democrat whose suggestion that the flag be taken down while running for governor last year was called a "stunt" by Haley, was given a high-five from a fellow legislator.
"I thought it would happen, but never this fast," Sheheen said.
Republican Sen. Larry Martin, who for decades fought off attempts to remove the flag from Statehouse grounds, said the church shooting drew him to the same conclusion that his black colleague arrived at long ago  that the rebel flag "has more to do with what was going on in the 1960s as opposed to the 1860s."
Martin, who is white, had family who came to South Carolina's then-rugged northern backcountry from Scotland in the early 1800s. That was about the time the enslaved relatives of Sen. Darrell Jackson, a black Democrat, involuntary ended up near Columbia.
Jackson helped write the compromise that took the Confederate flag off the Statehouse dome in 2000 and put it in its current location on a pole on the Capitol's front lawn.
On Monday, he said his great-grandfather's brother fled a plantation and joined the Union army when Gen. William Sherman came storming through Columbia.
View gallery
State Sen. Danny Verdin addresses legislators in the senate chambers July 6, 2015 in Columbia, South
Jackson said he regretted not going further to get rid of the flag completely 15 years ago. But he welcomed the chance now to honor his great-grandfather, Ishmael Jackson, who escaped to freedom.
"You said we lost the war. No we didn't. Not Ishmael Jackson and the 57 percent of people who looked like him. As far as they are concerned, they won the war," Jackson said.
The Senate rejected three amendments. One would have put a different Confederate flag on the pole. A second would fly the flag only on Confederate Memorial Day, and the third would leave the flag's fate up to a popular vote.
State Sen. Lee Bright, who suggested the popular vote, said the Confederate flag has been misused by people like Dylann Roof, who is charged with murder in the church shootings and who posed in pictures with the rebel banner.
"I'm more against taking it down in this environment than any other time just because I believe we're placing the blame of what one deranged lunatic did on the people that hold their Southern heritage high," said Bright, a Republican.
The flag still has at least a few days to fly, even with Haley, business leaders and civil rights proponents wanting it down as soon as possible. There are indications the proposal could have a tougher road in the House. Some powerful Republicans have not said how they will vote, including Speaker Jay Lucas.
Some Republicans want to keep the flagpole and put a different flag on it. Suggestions have included the U.S. flag, the South Carolina flag and a flag that may have been flown by Confederate troops but does not have the same connections as the red banner with the blue cross and white stars.
House Minority Leader Todd Rutherford vowed that no Democrat would vote for a bill that leaves the flagpole up.
The bill is expected to be sent directly to the House floor Wednesday with several amendments offered, said Republican Rep. Greg Delleney, chairman of the Judiciary Committee, which would normally receive the bill before it got to the floor.
If any amendments pass, a conference committee would probably be needed to hash out differences.
___
Follow Jeffrey Collins on Twitter at https://twitter.com/JSCollinsAP .
South Carolina Senate
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:34:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>No evidence of active shooter at Walter Reed, police say</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/walter-reed-shooting-reports-162942837.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>No evidence of active shooter at Walter Reed, police say
Report of a possible gunshot triggered lockdown
By Dylan Stableford 18 hours ago
Yahoo News
.
.
Police say there is no indication there was a shooting at Walter Reed National Military Medical Center on Monday after an unconfirmed report of an active shooter on the hospital's Bethesda, Md., campus triggered a lockdown.
#WalterReed employees were told to shelter in place via a text alert. http://t.co/bwXbv77oFq pic.twitter.com/dYmZiVW2bx
 NBCWashington (@nbcwashington) July 6, 2015
According to police in Montgomery County, a 911 caller reported hearing one shot fired inside Building 1 at approximately 10:48 a.m.
Call received at approx. 10:48 a.m. for report of single shot heard on Walter Reed campus. Officers have not confirmed initial report.
The facility was placed on lockdown while local police and federal agents searched the area.
UPDATE on unconfirmed report of shot fired at #WalterReed / Bethesda. Security searching buildings. No confirmation of incident.
 U.S. Navy (@USNavy) July 6, 2015
Employees were seen being evacuated from a building with their hands raised.
#BreakingNews watching armed personnel escort #WalterReed employees out, report of a gunshot heard pic.twitter.com/HCAPgWBC2q
 Brad Freitas (@NewsChopperBrad) July 6, 2015
Staffers sheltering in place tweeted updates from inside the facility.

Are we sure it wasn't just a car backfiring on/off base? I didn't hear anything on my way in today. https://t.co/fRvRUXtFHV
 Heather (@heather_kopf) July 6, 2015
Others called their family members, who relayed messages via Twitter.
my sister asks me to tweet that she's safe &amp; in lockdown, in complete blackness &amp; someone is passing around candy #walterReed @wusa9
 Allison Baughman (@baughwoman) July 6, 2015
Nearby roads were also closed as a precaution.
Rockville pike shut down near #WalterReed where police search after a report of shooter. @wusa9 pic.twitter.com/vZ6PlaJRDI
 Hank Silverberg (@HankSilverberg) July 6, 2015
At a 1 p.m. press briefing, Montgomery Capt. Paul Starks said officials were close to completing a sweep of Building 1 and there was "no indication of any kind" that there was a shooting, and no injuries reported.
Once the building is cleared, Starks said, it would searched by bomb-sniffing dogs "out of an abundance of caution."
The sweep was completed at 1:30 p.m., police said.
Last week, a report of possible gunshots heard by an employee at the Washington Navy Yard triggered a massive law enforcement response. But a subsequent search found no evidence a shooting had occurred.
That false alarm came two years after a gunman opened fire inside a building at the Navy Yard, killing 12 people and injuring three others.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:57:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World Cup kiss a poignant moment for many</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/us-world-cup-wambach-kiss-wife-135722914.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Abby Wambach kisses wife after World Cup win
A poignant moment that wasn't lost on gay rights supporters
By Dylan Stableford 23 hours ago
Yahoo News
.
.
Abby Wambach celebrated the United States' 5-2 victory over Japan in the Women's World Cup final on Sunday, racing to the stands to kiss her wife, Sarah Huffman.
Coming on the heels of the Supreme Court's historic decision to legalize same-sex marriage, the significance of the moment wasn't lost on gay rights supporters watching on television.
On Twitter, many noted how far American culture has come since the last U.S. Women's World Cup victory in 1999.
Sweet photo, post #USWNT victory: @AbbyWambach kisses her wife, now respected nationwide http://t.co/We2DeD89kt pic.twitter.com/71OrRKE0Ug
 Freedom to Marry (@freedomtomarry) July 6, 2015
This Video Of US World Cup Winner Abby Wambach Rushing To Kiss Her Wife Will Warm Your Heart http://t.co/S3gksew0az #topprog #lgbt #USWNT
 Gay Civil Rights (@gaycivilrights) July 6, 2015
I hope younger people GET how huge it is that @AbbyWambach can kiss her wife in the stands on FOXTV and it's no big thing #Progress 
 Carolyn Hinsey (@CarolynHinsey) July 6, 2015
Wambach kisses wife on national television and camera doesn't cut away. It zooms in. We've come a long way, folks.
 Brigid Black (@brigidblack) July 6, 2015
ABBY WAMBACH KISSING HER WIFE, A UNION NOW RECOGNIZED THROUGHOUT THE USA, IS A PRETTY NICE ENDING TO THIS WORLD CUP https://t.co/1nfhQxGY38
 Ellie Hall (@ellievhall) July 6, 2015
How cool was Abby jumping into the stands to kiss her wife in front of millions on national TV? It's been a good few weeks. #PRIDE
 Abe Asher (@abe_asher) July 6, 2015
Abby Wambach kissed her wife after winning the World Cup and the whole bar went, "awwwwwww". How far we have come!
 Anne-Marije Rook (@amrook) July 6, 2015
ICYMI: That beautiful moment when @AbbyWambach sprints to find her wife after winning the #WWC2015 http://t.co/wyZ1hl6xUs via @sbnation
 Anna Aagenes (@AnnaLinaAagenes) July 6, 2015
Twitter's reaction to the U.S. win over Japan wasn't entirely beautiful, however. As the United States built a 4-0 lead following a flurry of first-half goals, some users mockingly suggested the barrage was payback for Japan's 1941 attack on Pearl Harbor, and the term "Pearl Harbor" soon began trending on Twitter.
That 4th one was for Pearl Harbor. #USA
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:47:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>After vote win, Greece's Tsipras looks to rebuild talks</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/greece-still-cash-starved-decisive-no-bailout-vote-050303610--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>After vote win, Greece's Tsipras looks to rebuild talks
By DEREK GATOPOULOS and ELENA BECATOROS 19 hours ago

Next video starts in : 7 Play
Greece at a standstill
Raw: Greek Leaders, Citizens Vote on Austerity

CNBC&amp;#39;s Rick Santelli reports on May trade balance.
Load More
ATHENS, Greece (AP)  Despite triumphing in a popular vote against austerity, Greece on Monday faced the urgent need to heal its ties with European creditors and reach a financial rescue deal that might prevent it from falling out of the euro  possibly within days.
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras won big in Sunday's referendum, in which 60 percent of Greeks rejected the economic measures creditors had proposed in exchange for loans the country needs to remain afloat. He also received the rare backing of opposition parties to restart bailout negotiations.
But his bolstered mandate to push for better concessions from creditors hit the hard reality of the country's deteriorating finances, with the banks facing the risk of collapse within days unless a rescue deal is reached.
In a sign that he hopes to reach a deal as soon as possible, Tsipras appointed a new mild-mannered finance minister to lead talks with bailout creditors and replace Yanis Varoufakis, the hard-talking professor who clashed regularly with his European counterparts.
Euclid Tsakalotos, a 55-year-old economist, appears more willing to reach a compromise with creditors and will be tested as soon as Tuesday, when he will meet the other 18 eurozone finance ministers in Brussels.
That meeting is meant to seek the basis for a deal that European leaders, including Tsipras, might discuss at an emergency summit later in the day. Ahead of the summit, Tsipras spoke by phone with German Chancellor Angela Merkel.
View gallery
A street vendor reacts as as she sits behind used items for sale in central Athens, Greece, July 7, 
Greece's financial situation is getting more difficult by the day. It had to close the banks last week to prevent their collapse in the face of a run, and imposed limits on cash withdrawals and transfers.
Greek banks remained closed Monday, with only a few branches opening for pensioners to receive emergency assistance. Louka Katseli, head of the Greek Bank Association, said she expected banks to remain closed for at least two more days.
The government is expected to extend the restrictions on withdrawals after the European Central Bank makes a decision later Monday on cash support for Greek banks.
The ECB has frozen the amount of credit it allows Greek banks to draw on, even though their cash requirements are growing as people rush to withdraw what money they can.
Analysts say that if the ECB keeps the amount of credit on hold, Greek banks will come under increasing pressure and the government could have to make the limits on cash withdrawals even tougher.
View gallery
Elderly people argue with a bank worker as they wait to be allowed into the bank to withdraw a maxim
The ongoing Greek drama hurt stocks around the world, particularly in Europe. The losses were not as great as some had feared, however, suggesting investors think that a Greek exit from the euro, while devastating for the country and destabilizing in Europe, would be manageable for the global economy.
"The 'no' vote in Greece's referendum on Sunday dramatically increases the risk of a slide toward a disorderly Greek exit from the eurozone," ratings agency Fitch said.
"An agreement between Greece and its official creditors remains possible, but time is short and the risk of policy missteps, or that the two sides simply cannot agree a deal, is high."
With all ballots counted, 61.3 percent of voters in Sunday's referendum said "no" to the question of whether they would accept creditors' proposed measures.
Tsipras has agreed to imposing more harsh austerity measures, following a six-year recession, but wants eurozone lenders to grant the country better terms for bailout debt repayments.
View gallery
People line up to use ATM machines of a bank after government's decision for limited daily cash 
"The prime minister is ... committed to starting a fundamental debate on dealing with the problem of sustainability of the Greek national debt," a statement signed by the government and three pro-European opposition parties said.
European officials appear to be split on Greece's demand for easier debt repayment.
France's finance minister, Michel Sapin, indicated that discussing Greece's debt is not taboo, saying the country could not recover with its current obligations "in the months and years to come."
Germany, however, remains highly reluctant to discuss debt relief.
Finance Ministry spokesman Martin Jaeger said Germany's "position is well-known ... a debt cut is not an issue for us."
A man walks in central Athens, Monday, July 6, 2015. Greeces finance minister has resigned followin
German Vice Chancellor Sigmar Gabriel said Europe should be preparing to help Greeks with humanitarian assistance.
"The situation that is now being created by the referendum makes me sad, because life for the Greek population is going to get harder in the coming days and weeks," he said.
"After yesterday's celebrations in the streets there's a danger of a rude awakening soon."
___
Demetris Nellas and Menelaos Hadjicostis in Athens, Greece, Lori Hinnant in Paris, Raf Casert in Brussels and Geir Moulson in Berlin contributed.
Alexis Tsipras
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:37:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope puts family first at outdoor Mass in steamy Guayaquil</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/more-1-million-expected-popes-mass-south-america-040722132.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Pope puts family first at outdoor Mass in steamy Guayaquil
By NICOLE WINFIELD and ALLEN PANCHANA 9 hours ago

Raw: Pope Francis Departs for South America

Raw: Pope Francis Departs for South America
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Raw: Pope Francis Departs for South America
 Replay video
<<<<<<< HEAD
Al Shabaab gunmen kill 14 in attack on Kenyan workers
=======
President Obama sings "Amazing Grace during Rev. Clementa Pinckney's funeral service in South Carolina

Now watching Up next
Load More
SOUSSE, Tunisia (AP)  A young man pulled a Kalashnikov from a beach umbrella and sprayed gunfire at European sunbathers at a Tunisian resort, killing at least 39 people  one of three deadly attacks Friday from Europe to North Africa to the Middle East that followed a call to violence by Islamic State extremists.
The shootings in the Tunisian resort of Sousse happened at about the same time as a bombing at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait and an attack on a U.S.-owned factory in France that included a beheading. It was unclear if the violence was linked but it came days after the IS militants urged their followers "to make Ramadan a month of calamities for the nonbelievers." In all, the assailants killed at least 65 people.
The SITE Intelligence Group reported later that the IS claimed credit for the Tunisia attack on its Twitter account and identified the gunman as Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani.
The attack in Tunisia, the country's worst ever, comes just months after the March 18 massacre at the national Bardo museum in Tunis that killed 22 people, again mostly tourists, and has called into question the newly elected government's ability to protect the country.
"Once again, cowardly and traitorous hands have struck Tunisia, targeting its security and that of its children and visitors," President Beji Caid Essebsi told reporters at the RIU Imperial Marhaba hotel, near the beach rampage site.
Essebsi promised "painful but necessary" measures, adding: "No country is safe from terrorism, and we need a global strategy of all democratic countries."
View gallery
Bodies are covered on a Tunisian beach, in Sousse, Friday June 26, 2015. A young man unfurled an umb
Rafik Chelli, the secretary of state of the Interior Ministry, told The Associated Press that the attack was carried out by a young student not previously known to authorities. At least 36 people were reported wounded in the shooting spree, which ended when the gunman was shot to death by police.
The Islamic State group claimed responsibility for the suicide bombing at the Shiite mosque in Kuwait City that killed at least 27 people and wounded scores of other worshippers at midday prayers  the first such attack in the mostly quiet and relatively secure Gulf Arab nation in more than two decades.
In southeastern France, a man with ties to Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory, touching off an explosion that injured two people. Authorities arriving at the site made a grisly discovery: the severed head of the driver's employer was found hanging at the plant entrance.
The suspect, Yassine Salhi, was seized by an alert firefighter, authorities said, and French President Francois Hollande said the attacker's intention had been to cause an explosion. A security alert for the southeast region was raised to its highest level for the next three days, and the U.S. Embassy in Paris warned American citizens to be vigilant.
In an audio recording released Tuesday, the Islamic State called on its supporters to increase attacks during Ramadan and "be keen on waging invasion in this eminent month and commit martyrdom."
View gallery
Map locates Sousse, Tunisia, where gunmen killed several people.; 1c x 3 inches; 46.5 mm x 76 mm;
In Britain, police said they were tightening security at major events after the attacks in France, Kuwait and Tunisia, including for the weekend events of Armed Forces Day and the Pride London gay and lesbian festival.
The attacks were condemned by the United Nations, the U.S., Israel and others.
"We stand with these nations as they respond to attacks on their soil today," the White House said. Pentagon spokesman Col. Steve Warren added it was "too soon to tell whether or not these various and far-flung attacks were coordinated centrally or whether they were coincidental."
The carnage in Tunisia began on the beach, where tourists described hearing what sounded like fireworks and then running for their lives when they realized it was gunfire. Video of the aftermath showed medics using beach chairs as stretchers to carry away people in swimsuits.
"He had a parasol in his hand. He went down to put it in the sand and then he took out his Kalashnikov and began shooting wildly," Chelli said of the gunman.
View gallery
Injured people are treated on a Tunisian beach, in Sousse, Friday June 26, 2015. A young man unfurle
He then entered the pool area of the Imperial Marhaba hotel before moving inside, killing people as he went.
British tourist Gary Pine told AP he was on the beach with his wife around noon when heard the shooting. They shouted for their son to get out of the water, grabbed their bag and ran for the hotel. Their son told them he saw someone shot on the beach.
There was "sheer panic" at the hotel, Pine said. "There were a lot of concerned people, a few people in tears with panic and a few people  older guests  they'd turned their ankles or there was a few little minor injuries and nicks and scrapes."
Elizabeth O'Brien, an Irish tourist who was with her two sons, told Irish Radio she was on the beach when the shooting began.
"I thought, 'Oh my God. It sounds like gunfire,' so I just ran to the sea to my children and grabbed our things" before fleeing to their hotel room, she said.
Injured people are treated near the area where an attack took place in Sousse, Tunisia, Friday June 
The Health Ministry said the dead included Tunisians, British, Germans and Belgians, without giving a breakdown.
British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond says at least five Britons were killed but expected to toll to rise because a high proportion of the dead were believed to be British.
Since overthrowing its secular dictator in 2011, Tunisia has been plagued by terrorist attacks, although only recently have they targeted the tourism sector, which makes up nearly 15 percent of GDP.
"The Foreign Office will declare the summer effectively over for Tunisia, and it will destroy  besides the lives taken  the tens of thousands of livelihoods who depend on tourism for a living," said Simon Calder, a London-based travel commentator. Nearly half a million Britons visited Tunisia in 2014.
At a news conference at his office in the capital Tunis, Prime Minister Habib Essid said he would immediately  close mosques outside the control of the ministry of religious affairs and call army reservists into active service and place them around the country.
View gallery
Injured people are treated near the area where an attack took place in Sousse, Tunisia, Friday June 
"No mosque that does not confirm to the law will be tolerated," he said, referring to those that incite to terrorism.
The attacks are also a blow to Tunisia's image as a stable, democratic nation emerging from its revolution in 2011, said Jonathan Hill, a professor of Defense Studies at King's College in London.
"The terrorists are attacking Tunisia's reputation," he said. "Not just as a safe and welcoming destination for Western holidaymakers, but as the one real success story to emerge out of the Arab Spring."
International police agency Interpol offered investigative help in the wake of Friday's violence. Interpol Secretary-General Juergen Stock said the attacks "show the truly global dimension to current terrorist threats."
___
Schemm reported from Rabat, Morocco. Associated Press Writers Bouazza Ben Bouazza in Tunis, Jill Lawless and Greg Katz in London, Shawn Pogatchnik in Dublin and Angela Charlton in Paris contributed to this report.
___
This story has been corrected to reflect that authorities now say there was only one gunman, not two, and that the message from the Islamic State was an audio recording, not a video.
Tunisia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:03:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bitter dissents in gay marriage case reveals deep divide in high court</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/bitter-dissents-in-gay-marriage-case-lays-bare-122528649891.html</Link>
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Content preferences
Done
The U.S. Supreme Court ruled on Thursday to uphold the availability of tax subsidies related to President Barack Obamas signature healthcare law, the 2010 Affordable Care Act better known as Obamacare.
Yahoo global news anchor Katie Couric hosted a special live discussion of the ruling with Yahoo News chief White House correspondent Olivier Knox, Yahoo News national affairs reporter Liz Goodwin, and National Constitution Center President and CEO Jeff Rosen.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:58:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>House completes Obama's trade items as Pacific pact looms</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/senate-house-prepare-complete-obamas-trade-agenda-071045807--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>House completes Obama's trade items as Pacific pact looms
By CHARLES BABINGTON 19 hours ago

.
View photo
Graphic shows Senate vote on Trade Promotion Authority; 1c x 4 inches; 46.5 mm x 101 mm;
WASHINGTON (AP)  The Republican-led Congress completed President Barack Obama's trade package Thursday, overwhelmingly passing a worker training program just weeks after it was stymied.
The House voted 286 to 138 to renew the job retraining program for workers displaced by international trade. Obama had said he wanted to sign that bill alongside the "fast track" negotiating authority that Congress approved a day earlier.
Usually a Democratic priority, the retraining bill briefly became hostage to Democrats' failed efforts to block fast track.
The House measure also renews the African Growth and Opportunity Act.
Obama and his trade opponents are shifting their focus to proposed trade agreements under negotiation for years. The first, the Trans-Pacific Partnership, involves the United States, Japan, Canada and nine other Pacific-rim nations.
The fast-track law allows Congress to ratify or reject such agreements, but not change or filibuster them.
Most House Democrats, along with major labor unions, opposed fast track, saying free-trade pacts send U.S. jobs abroad.
House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi, D-Calif., said Thursday's votes mark "the end of phase one" in the trade debate, but "the fight will continue." The next step, she said, is "to shine a sharp, clear, bright light" on details of the Pacific-rim proposal.
Passage of the trade bills mark a huge win for the president, and one paradoxically spearheaded by Republicans. And it's a defeat for the AFL-CIO and unions and environmental groups that fiercely opposed it. Some have vowed to punish the relatively small number of congressional Democrats who opposed them.
But Obama  much like the last Democratic president, Bill Clinton  portrays expanded trade as crucial in a global, high-tech economy. Most Republicans agree, but most congressional Democrats, especially in the House, do not.
Trade has opened the most striking breach between a Democratic president and the lawmakers who overwhelmingly backed him on health care and other hard-fought issues.
Pelosi and fellow House Democrats dealt Obama a humiliating rebuke on June 12, when they derailed his trade package only hours after he traveled to the Capitol to personally ask for their help. The House voted 302-126 that day to reject the job retraining portion of the package. Nearly half the "no" votes came from Democrats.
Republican leaders, with White House support, restructured the legislative package and passed fast track with big GOP margins, plus modest Democratic support.
On Thursday, only six House Democrats voted against the job retraining program. Among Republicans, 132 voted against the program, and 111 voted for it.
Rep. Paul Ryan, chairman of the House Ways and Means Committee, said some Democrats had questioned Republicans' promises to support the job retraining program even after fast track was secured.
To pass the trade legislation, Ryan, R-Wis., told House colleagues before Thursday's vote, "We needed a little bit of trust. We are here today to keep our word."
Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:39:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds discrimination claims in housing case</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/supreme-court-upholds-broad-discrimination-claims-under-housing-141124553--finance.html</Link>
=======
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 01:04:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'The Reverend President': Obama sings Amazing Grace in eulogy</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/the-reverend-president-obama-sings-amazing-122531605241.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 21:56:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tourists describe scenes of panic in Tunisia attack</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/tourists-flee-panic-tunisia-resort-attack-141651648.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tourists describe scenes of panic in Tunisia attack
By Robin Millard June 26, 2015 2:56 PM

.
.
London (AFP) - British holidaymakers told how they fled in panic from Friday's gun massacre on a Tunisian beach resort, screaming and running for cover when they realised they were under attack.
Five Britons were among the 37 dead in the shootings in Port el Kantaoui outside the town of Sousse.
Survivors told how they were caught by bullets while others were in hysterics as their wounded partners were rushed to hospital.
Frightened tourists hid in their hotel rooms and barricaded themselves in, while a pregnant woman went into labour in the confusion.
British tourists caught up in the attack recounted their ordeal to British media.
One man said he was hit by a bullet.
The Briton, who was not named, appeared to be speaking from a hospital.
"Someone firing a gun, and then I looked at my wife and she got up and ran, and as I turned a bullet just hit me in my arm, and I just ran to the sea," he said, in footage on BBC television.
- Shot in front of wife -
Olivia Leathley, 24, heard "loud bangs" and saw from her hotel room people fleeing the beach, as holiday company representatives blew whistles.
View gallery
Tunisian medics stand next to covered bodies in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destina
Going to the lobby to find out what was happening, she saw a woman whose husband had "been shot in the stomach in front of her".
"She got dragged away by hotel reps trying to get her to safety but she was a complete mess. She was in hysterics.
"All she said was that he'd been shot and that he was there bleeding on the beach and he was just saying, 'I love you, I love you', and then his eyes rolled back into his head."
Leathley said she believed the woman had been taken to hospital to see her injured husband.
"All of a sudden, from the level just below the lobby there was a huge sound of loads of machine gun fire and one of the reps just said 'run'.
"I was crying and we heard the machine gun fire and it was so loud and it seemed like it was just behind us, it seemed so close."
A group of eight people hid in a room with no windows "and just crouched and waited until they said it was OK", she said.
Back in the hotel, she said: "There was a pregnant woman earlier in the lobby who has now gone into labour."
Ellie Makin, from Ripon in northern England, was on the right-hand edge of her hotel's section of beach.
Tourists react at the Riu Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist des
"All I saw was a gun and an umbrella being dropped," she told ITV television.
"Then he started firing to the right hand side of us. If he had fired to the left I don't know what would have happened, but we were very lucky."
She said she ran to her hotel.
"We just saw panic, everyone just got up and fled as soon as we realised it was gunfire.
"A guy ran up into the hotel and started shooting again and everyone fled. He was just below us, if we'd have walked down the stairs we'd have met him halfway.
"I ran to a room upstairs with somebody and their kids and we hid."
- 'Crying and going hysterical' -
Product manager Gary Pine said he heard an estimated 20 to 30 shots before tourists ran to their hotels for cover.
"Only when you could start hearing bullets whizzing around your ear do you realise it was something a lot more serious than firecrackers," he told Sky News television.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach.
"You could see quite quickly the panic that was starting to ensue."
His son told him as they fled: "'I just saw someone get shot'.
"I'm now stood in reception with probably 200 other international guests. Do we leave? Do we stay? Where do we go? What do we do?"
Susan Ricketts told Sky News: "Everybody just started running in and screaming. The whole place just cleared."
She said there were "people crying and going hysterical."
Tomas O Riordain, a UK resident from Cork in Ireland, was in a neighbouring hotel.
"It was all over three or four minutes after it started," he told RTE radio, saying he had two daughters at the beach and "just had to wait and see if they came back".
It was the second time he had been caught up in a terror attack, as he was in Liverpool Street in London during the July 7, 2005 bombings almost a decade ago.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:34:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Terror' attack in France followed by gunfire at Tunisia tourist spot</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/man-decapitated-and-several-hurt-in-suspected-islamist-attack-in-grenoble-factory-092920187.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>More games 
Tunisia Beach Gunfire Kills 'At Least 27' As Man Decapitated In French 'Islamist' Attack
Separate attacks see gunman open fire on beach in Tunisian tourist resort, as man is decapitated in 'Islamist attack' near Grenoble
By Chris Parsons June 26, 2015 5:29 AM

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:00:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Clementa Pinckney eulogy caps a roller-coaster stretch for Obama</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/clementa-pinckney-eulogy-caps-a-roller-coaster-122456191261.html</Link>
        <Description>Barack Obama is experiencing arguably the most pivotal stretch of his tumultuous and consequential two-term presidency as he heads to Charleston Friday to once again take up the unwelcome mantle of comforter in chief.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:29:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>9 killed in Alaska sightseeing plane crash</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/missing-plane-carrying-9-found-cliff-side-alaska-003600347.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Recovery efforts resume Friday for 9 killed in Alaska crash
By MARK THIESSEN June 26, 2015 5:29 AM
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c

Hollywood star, Jessica Alba enjoys Giambattista Valli&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;exquisite&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;feminine&amp;#39; couture fashion show at Paris Fashion Week. (July 7)
Load More
GUAYAQUIL, Ecuador (AP)  Pope Francis received a hero's welcome in Ecuador's biggest city Monday as he celebrated the first public Mass of his South American tour, telling hundreds of thousands of faithful their families are the bedrock of society but need to be supported better and strengthened.
In his homily, Francis praised families as the nucleus of society, calling them "the nearest hospital, the first school for the young, the best home for the elderly." He said miracles are performed every day inside a family out of love, but sometimes the love and happiness run out.
"How many women, sad and lonely, wonder when love left, when it slipped away from their lives?" he asked. "How many elderly people feel left out of family celebrations, cast aside and longing each day for a little love?"
Firefighters sprayed water from hoses on the crowd to provide relief from a searing sun and high humidity that made the 86 degree Fahrenheit temperature in the Pacific port city of Guayaquil feel at least 10 degrees hotter.
Many pilgrims had spent the night outdoors, and some walked for miles to reach the park on Guayaquil's northern outskirts to catch a glimpse of history's first Latin American pope celebrating Mass on his home turf. They said it was well worth the discomfort.
"I'm tired, I'm hungry, I haven't slept, but I'm also full of emotion and joy in my heart," said Vicente Huilcatoma, a former police officer who walked 25 miles (40 kilometers) to reach Samanes Park.
View gallery
A group of young people wave flags representing the colors of Vatican City as they wait for the arri
The Vatican originally estimated more than 1 million people would turn out for the Mass, and government organizers put the crowd at above that figure in the hour before the service began. But Gabriel Almeida, the government spokesman at the scene, rolled back the estimate to about 550,000 after officials viewed aerial images of the area.
Across the park, flags from Ecuador and more than a half dozen other countries waved above the enormous sea of people, who were divided into quadrants that Francis looped around slowly on his popemobile to cheers of "Francisco! Francisco!"
The pope's homily brought Janeth Valencia Bersosa to tears. The primary school teacher came to the Mass with her older sister Pilar from Cuenca, about 125 miles (200 kilometers) away, spending the night in the park and then baking under the heat of the noontime Mass. She said it was worth it.
"Francis has given us back hope in our families, in those we love the most, the nucleus of society," she said. "I wept at each phrase."
Francis has dedicated the first two years of his pontificate to family issues, giving weekly catechism lessons on different aspects of family life and inviting the entire church to study ways to provide better pastoral care for Catholic families facing difficulties today, including people who are divorced, gays and families in "nontraditional" situations.
View gallery
Pope Francis laughs as he meets the journalists aboard the papal airplane on the occasion of his vis
A preliminary meeting of bishops on these issues ended last year in bitter divisions between liberals and conservatives, particularly over ministering to gays and to Catholics who divorce and remarry outside the church. Church teaching holds that Catholics who enter into a second marriage without having the first one annulled cannot receive Communion.
In his homily Monday, Francis said he hoped the second meeting of bishops on family life, scheduled for October, would come up with "concrete solutions to the many difficult and significant challenges facing families in our time."
"I ask you to pray fervently for this intention, so that Christ can take even what might seem to us impure, scandalous or threatening, and turn it ... into a miracle."
"Families today need miracles!" he added.
The Vatican spokesman, the Rev. Federico Lombardi, said Francis wasn't referring to the gay or divorce issue specifically but was making a more general reference that he hoped the bishops would "help the church chart this path of leaving a situation of sin to one of grace."
View gallery
Ecuador's President Rafael Correa, right, welcomes Pope Francis upon his arrival at Quito Airpor
Upon his arrival in Guayaquil, the pontiff allowed several acolytes on the tarmac to take selfies with him. He then headed to the Shrine of the Divine Mercy, where 2,000 invitees gathered, including young cancer patients, residents of homes for the elderly abandoned by their families and some of Guayaquil's poorest people.
He told those gathered that he would pray for them "and I won't charge you a thing. All I ask, please, is that you pray for me."
After the open-air Mass, Francis had lunch with a group of Jesuits at a nearby high school.
A highlight was his reunion with the Rev. Francisco Cortes, a priest affectionately known as "Padre Paquito," to whom the Argentina-born pope, then the Rev. Jorge Mario Bergoglio, entrusted his seminarians on study trips to Ecuador years ago.
In a recent interview with The Associated Press, Cortes couldn't fathom that Bergoglio remembered him, much less made a point of coming to have lunch. "I don't know what to ask him," the soon-to-be 91-year-old Cortes said. "I'm really just a Mr. Nobody."
View gallery
Pope Francis waves to the crowd as he rides aboard the Popemobile in streets of Quito, Ecuador, Sund
Returning to the capital of Quito at dusk, Francis paid a 50-minute courtesy visit to Rafael Correa at the presidential palace. When it ended, Correa ushered him to reception line of dozens that took a quarter hour to negotiate.
The pope then prayed in Quito's cathedral and went out on the steps to address a crowd, many of whom had waited hours to see him and endured a deluge. But instead of giving the short speech that he had prepared, Francis offered a brief blessing.
Tuesday brings another big public Mass, this time in Quito, as well as a meeting with the country's bishops, a speech at Ecuador's Catholic University and an evening gathering with civil society groups, including indigenous leaders.
Tens of thousands who lined up outside the Quito park where the Mass was to be held got soaked in a punishing rain and hail storm. People grabbed what they could to protect themselves. They tore vinyl advertising placards off the metal fences surrounding the park, which was the city's international airport until two years ago.
Some just shrugged it off. Although her clothes were soaked and she shivered in the cold of Quito's 9,000-foot altitude, 71-year-old Angelica Naranjo said: "This isn't a sacrifice. It's a demonstration of faith."
Quito security chief Juan Zapata said officials would distribute blankets from stocks kept by civil defense authorities.
___
<<<<<<< HEAD
Associated Press writers Jacobo Garcia and Frank Bajak contributed to this report.
Pope Francis
=======
This story corrects the breakdown of missing emails to nine full emails and parts of six others.
Hillary Rodham Clinton
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>SCOTUS Obamacare ruling: 2016 presidential candidates weigh in</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/scotus-obamacare-2016-candidates-react-122431771361.html</Link>
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Supreme Court upholds broad housing discrimination claims
By Lawrence Hurley 16 hours ago

The U.S. Supreme Court in Washington. (Gary Cameron/Reuters)
By Lawrence Hurley
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - A divided U.S. Supreme Court on Thursday embraced a broad interpretation of discrimination claims allowed under the landmark Fair Housing Act, a blow to lenders and insurers that face such lawsuits and had urged the court to curb them.
In a 5-4 decision in a major civil rights case out of Texas, the court preserved a legal tool that has been used for decades to bring bias lawsuits over actions that have a discriminatory effect even with no evidence of discriminatory intent.
The unexpected ruling was a triumph for civil rights activists, who had feared the justices would rein in these lawsuits, and the administration of President Barack Obama, which had asked the justices to allow such claims to continue.
Justice Anthony Kennedy, a conservative who often casts the deciding vote in close cases, joined the court's four liberals in the majority.
"By recognizing that laws, policies and practices with unjustified discriminatory effects are inconsistent with the Fair Housing Act, todays decision lends support to hard-working Americans who are attempting to find good housing opportunities for themselves and their families," U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch said.
The case involved Inclusive Communities Project Inc, a nonprofit group that claimed Texas violated the law by disproportionately awarding low-income housing tax credits to developers owning properties in poor, minority-dominated neighborhoods. The group works to place low-income tenants in the more wealthy, majority white suburbs of Dallas.
The Texas case was closely watched by lenders and insurance companies, which say they are unfairly targeted. Industry groups say companies use neutral criteria when assessing risk. Based on how the law has been interpreted for decades, lawsuits could be filed over legitimate business practices, they argue.
Although a broad win for civil rights advocates on the legal theory, Kennedy, writing for the court, indicated in the ruling that the Texas plaintiffs ultimately could lose when the case returns to lower courts.
 The court was considering whether the 1968 law allows for "disparate impact" claims in which plaintiffs need to show only the discriminatory effect of a particular practice and not evidence of discriminatory intent. There was no dispute over the law's prohibition on openly discriminatory acts in the sale and rental of housing.
 For decades, disparate impact claims have been a way for lawyers representing blacks and other minorities to target policies that do not directly discriminate yet have the effect of putting certain groups at a disadvantage.
Kennedy wrote that Congress indicated in 1988 when it amended the law that it intended disparate impact claims to be available.
"It permits plaintiffs to counteract unconscious prejudices and disguised animus that escape easy classification," Kennedy added.
Kennedy also made clear there are limits to the types of claims allowed, saying "statistical disparity" alone is not enough. Plaintiffs must "point to a defendant's policy or policies causing that disparity," Kennedy added.

'INEFFECTIVE AND UNFAIR'
The disparate impact theory is opposed by business interests because it allows for a broad range of business decisions related to housing to be subject to civil rights litigation.
"Discrimination has no place in the United States, and the government should be equipped to hold accountable those who practice it. However, disparate impact is ineffective and unfair, and will ultimately harm those it is intended to protect," said David Hirschmann, president of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce's Center for Capital Markets Competitiveness.
Hirschmann welcomed what he called "severe limitations" imposed by the court on what kind of claims can be made.
Justice Samuel Alito wrote in a dissenting opinion that the ruling will "have unfortunate consequences for local government, private enterprise, and those living in poverty."
Alito cited an earlier case in which what he called a city's good faith attempt to fix "deplorable housing conditions" for renters was subjected to a legal challenge under the theory.
 National civil rights groups had tried to keep the issue away from the conservative-leaning high court. In the past three years, two other cases that raised the same question about the scope of fair-housing law were taken up by the high court but settled with the help of the rights groups before the justices could rule.
 Under Chief Justice John Roberts leadership, a five-justice conservative majority previously had curtailed remedies for race discrimination in a series of cases involving federal voting rights, promotion tests for firefighters and integration plans designed to balance out whites and blacks throughout a school district and offset segregated housing.
"The way to stop discrimination on the basis of race is to stop discriminating on the basis of race," Roberts wrote in 2007.
 The case is Texas Department of Housing and Community Affairs v. Inclusive Communities Project, U.S. Supreme Court, No. 13-1371.

(Reporting by Lawrence Hurley; Editing by Will Dunham)
Justice Anthony Kennedy
</MainBody>
    </Article>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 13:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Second prison worker arrested in New York escape</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/corrections-officer-gene-palmer-arrested-ny-prison-escape-003817852--abc-news-topstories.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Corrections Officer Gene Palmer Gave Prison Escapees Paint and Tools in Exchange for Art, Documents Say
By DOUG LANTZ, LINZIE JANIS and TOM LIDDY June 25, 2015 6:41 AM

Corrections Officer Charged in NY Prison Escape
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Corrections Officer Charged in NY Prison Escape
 Replay video
NY Prison Escapees May Have Hidden In Hunting Camp

The president responds to the Supreme Court ruling that sided with his administration&amp;#39;s major health care overhaul.
Load More
A veteran New York state corrections officer rolled out the red carpet for two convicted murderers who have made a spectacular prison break -- giving them art supplies, tools and access to the catwalks behind the walls of their cell to do electrical work, stunning court documents say.
Gene Palmer, 57, of Dannemora , was arrested Wednesday and hit with promoting prison contraband and tampering with physical evidence, both felonies, and official misconduct, a misdemeanor in connection with the "Shawshank Redemption"-style June 6 escape of Richard Matt and David Sweat from Clinton Correctional Facility .
The veteran officer, who also allegedly inadvertently passed the inmates tools in frozen hamburger meat, appeared at Plattsburgh Town Court Wednesday and did not enter a plea. He was later released from Clinton County Jail after posting $25,000 bail, the jail confirmed.
He was set to be arraigned Thursday.
According to the court documents, Palmer went shopping for art supplies at Michaels in exchange for "elaborate paintings" done by Matt -- which he burned or buried after their escape -- in addition to information about misconduct for other prisoners. He also allegedly let Sweat alter the electrical box in his cell and provided him access to the catwalk behind it.
Exclusive: Video Offers Glimpse Into Escaped Convict Richard Matt's Past
According to one of the criminal complaints, Palmer, who has 27 years on the force, gave the inmates a flathead screwdriver and needlenose pliers on four occasions between November 2014 to June 6, 2015.
He allegedly gave the inmates the tools in exchange for paintings. Matt, who reportedly painted stunning portraits of celebs , and Sweat were housed in the prison's "Honor Block," which gave well-behaved inmates privileges such as laundry and cooking as well as working as assistants to plumbers and electricians, a source told ABC News .
NY Prison Escapees May Have Hidden In Hunting Camp Play video
"I purchased and then provided paint and paint brushes for Richard Matt on two separate occasions," Palmer allegedly told investigators in a statement date June 20. He also described shopping at Michael's in Plattsburgh approximately two years ago for "white zinc paint" and "white titanium paint" as well as "one large tube of acrylic paint" for Sweat, the statement says.
Then on May 29, he said that he received a package from prison worker Joyce Mitchell, who is also accused of helping the inmates, to give to Matt, the statement said.
According to the documents, the package was a "green-colored, woven cloth bag" approximately 12 inches by 5 inches containing more than a pound of frozen hamburger meat.
The beef was packaged in styrofoam with plastic wrap but no price sticker on it, the statements said. There were also allegedly two tubes of paint and a "small, green cloth item."
The next day, he took the package and delivered it to Matt through his cell.
Did Joyce Mitchell's Husband Know About the NY Play video
"I cannot remember providing him with anything else," he allegedly said.
Palmer also admitted to allowing Sweat to work on the electrical boxes of the cell by accessing the catwalk behind them "because inmate Matt asked me and I was doing him a favor," he allegedly said.
But he denied knowing the men would escape.
"I did not realize at the time, that the assistance provided to Matt or Sweat made their escape easier," he allegedly told investigators.
He said the electrical work was done "to enhance their ability to cook in their cells," according to the statement.
NY Prison Worker's Husband Visits Her In Priso Play video
"Matt provided me with elaborate paintings and information on the illegal acts that inmates were committing within the facility," the statement said. "In turn, I provided him with benefits such as paint, paintbrushes, movement of inmates, hamburger meat, altering of electrical boxes in the catwalk areas."
In the wake of the escape, Palmer allegedly burned some of the paintings in a fire pit at his residence and buried others in the woods.
In an interview, Clinton County DA told ABC News that the pliers were used for the inmates' paintings.
"I'm not attributing those pliers in any manner to the escape," Wylie said.
He also added that bringing Matt and Sweat to the catwalk was "totally inappropriate" unless it was authorized.
Joyce Mitchell Allegedly Passed Tools to NY Prison Play video
Joyce Mitchell, who worked in the prison tailor shop, was accused of putting hacksaw blades, other tools and a screwdriver bit into the meat and then placing it into the shop's freezer, where Palmer would allegedly retrieve it, according to Wylie.
Palmer had been placed on leave, said he didn't know the tools were inside, the DA told ABC News. Mitchell echoed the sentiments, but bringing prisoners food is considered contraband, the DA said.
Matt was serving 25 years to life for kidnapping and beating a man to death in 1997. Sweat was serving life for killing a Broome County Sheriff's deputy.
The men escaped from Clinton Correctional facility, in upstate Dannemora, near the Canadian border, on June 6 in a spectacular breakout akin to that in "Shawshank Redemption."
Sweat and Matt allegedly used power tools to cut through pipes and made their way through a series of catwalks and walls to make it through to the outside where they emerged from a manhole.
They have been on the lam ever since, and despite a series of sightings, police have not been able to catch them.
This week, investigators found prison-issued underwear at a hunting cabin in Owls Head, NY. They also found food and positive DNA samples were confirmed from both suspects.
The time frame was not immediately clear.
Mitchell faces a felony charge of promoting prison contraband and a misdemeanor charge of criminal facilitation.
She has pleaded not guilty.
Before the escape she was investigated for having a suspected relationship with Sweat over the course of the past year but not enough evidence was found to take action.
Investigators were also checking Wednesday whether Mitchell may have had sex with other inmates besides Sweat.
Her lawyer, Steve Johnston, denied the allegations.
"On her behalf all I can say is that she has consistently denied having any sexual relationship with inmate Sweat," her attorney Steve Johnston said today in a statement to ABC News.
Richard Matt
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Obama to Clyburn: Charleston victims 'are my people'</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/obama-to-clyburn-charleston-victims-are-my-122373502106.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
=======
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Skrillex: The making of a superstar</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/katie-couric-exclusive-edm-superstar-skrillex-152210272.html?soc_src=mail&amp;soc_trk=ma</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Complete interview
By Katie Brinn and Andrew Rothschild
He introduces himself as Sonny Moore, but to his millions of young fans, hes Skrillex  one of the biggest names in electronic dance music (EDM). Since he first found success as an EDM DJ and producer in 2011, Skrillex has collected six Grammys, 19 million Facebook fans and an estimated $20 million  all while giving away most of his music for free.
And at just 27 years old  an age he characterizes as not young  he says he has no plans of slowing down. The EDM prodigy is churning out new collaborations with superstars both inside and outside his genre, testing the limits of his craft  and his fan base  with every new innovation.
One of his boldest, and perhaps most polarizing new partners: pop heartthrob Justin Bieber. Moore and fellow EDM DJ Diplo, under the moniker Jack , teamed up with the Biebs in early 2015 to produce the single Where Are  Now. The track quickly shot to the top of mainstream charts, drawing the ire of some EDM fans who were vocal with their criticism that Skrillex was selling out.
Yahoo global news anchor Katie Couric met up with Moore at his studio in downtown L.A. to give him a chance to respond to the criticism and to take a rare, intimate look into the life and career of one of EDMs biggest stars.
Working with Bieber
He was super-polite, Moore says of his first encounter with Justin Bieber at a party at New York Fashion Week earlier this year. The rest was history. Teaming up as Jack , Skrillex and Diplo worked on Biebers a cappella vocal track to make a hit that few of his fans saw coming.
Childhood of music and Scientology
Sporting a hardcore look from an early age, Moore says he is no stranger to being misunderstood. Youre always bullied if youre an emo kid, he admits. But he says his parents were always supportive of his alternative style and his unconventional ambitions.
The family hit a rough patch when Moore learned at age 16 that his parents had adopted him. He says his music helped him get through that period and has helped as he deals with another trial his family is now facing: the recent death of his mother. He talks about his relationship with her, how his family has come together to mourn and how Scientology has long helped his family cope with hardship.
EDM, drugs and that hairdo
Of course, its impossible to ignore the drug culture that goes hand in hand with EDMs rave scene, a scene Skrillex has so helped to define. Some critics, in fact, have linked the rise of Molly to Skrillexs ascent. Though he emphasizes that he would never want to be telling kids how to run their lives, Skrillex insists that he never uses drugs. I wouldnt be able to do 300 shows a year if I was doing drugs, he says.
Amid their conversation, Couric and Skrillex take a phone call from a special guest star, Marshmello, a mysterious EDM newcomer whose identity remains top secret. Until now, fans have even been unsure whether the rising star is a man or a woman.
Before wrapping up their chat, Skrillex gets a chance to comment on the origins of his signature haircut and muse about what his life might look like in 10 years.
Skrillex ft. Katie Couric
Not to outdo Justin Bieber, Skrillex and Couric decide there is room for one more unlikely EDM collaboration. Together, they hit the studio to churn out what could be a pretty sweet hit. Check out the final product.
Arts &amp; Entertainment
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 14:19:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Obama legacy on race</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/the-obama-legacy-on-race-president-barack-obama-122362581601.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:43:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French anti-Uber protests turn violent</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/french-cabbies-angry-uber-block-paris-airports-roads-103556123.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>President Obama delivered a powerful rendition of &amp;quot;Amazing Grace&amp;quot; at the funeral of slain Rev. Clementa Pinckney, and called on the country to honor those killed in the South Carolina church massacre. Photo: Getty
Load More
Paris (AFP) - Protests against ride-booking app Uber turned violent in France on Thursday as taxi drivers set fire to vehicles and blocked major roads.
American rocker Courtney Love was caught up in the demonstrations when a vehicle she was travelling in outside Paris was attacked.
Around 3,000 cabbies took part in the strike, blocking access to the capital's Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports, and preventing cars reaching train stations around the country.
Ten people were arrested, seven police officers were injured and 70 vehicles were damaged in clashes between Uber drivers and taxi drivers.
The service, known as UberPOP, has been illegal in France since January, but the law has proved difficult to enforce and it continues to operate.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said after meeting taxi drivers' unions following a fraught day: "UberPOP is an illegal service, it must be closed down."
Until that was done, "the vehicles of UberPOP drivers should be systematically impounded when they are openly breaking the law", the minister said.
"Governing the country will never be done by the law of the jungle," Cazeneuve added.
One of the taxi drivers' representatives, Ibrahima Sylla, described the minister's words as "promises, again" and said the drivers were considering continuing the demonstrations.
Love, Kurt Cobain's widow, was caught up in a confrontation near Charles de Gaulle airport.
She tweeted that protesters "ambushed" her vehicle and "were holding our driver hostage".
She appealed to the French president in another message, writing "Francois Hollande where are the fucking police???"
French taxi drivers burn tyres during a protest against taxi app Uber in the southern city of Marsei
"This is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad," she added.
- Two vehicles torched -
In the most serious incident in Paris, one private chauffeur, who said he did not work for Uber "or any other app" was dragged from his van when he reached a blockade in the west of Paris.
Angry taxi drivers slashed the tyres of his vehicle, smashed a window and then set it and a chauffeur-driven van on fire.
Police eventually fired teargas to break up the protest on the western stretch of the ring road around the capital and cleared burning tyres.
Prime Minister Manuel Valls said during a visit to Colombia that the perpetrators of the "unacceptable" violence "can be found in both camps" and they would be found and prosecuted.
Taxi drivers are furious at what they see as unfair competition from Uber, which puts customers in touch with private drivers at prices lower than those of traditional taxis.
Licensed cabbies say the service is endangering their jobs by flooding the market with low-cost drivers.
One driver said the strikers had been driven to desperation.
"Taxi drivers -- alright, they've got big mouths -- but normally they're not aggressive," said Malia, 50, who has driven a taxi for three years.
"But these guys have families to feed, debts. They've been pushed to the brink."
- Illegal in France -
More peaceful protests took place at transport hubs in other major cities including Bordeaux, Marseille and Toulouse.
Cabbies argued that the disruption was justified.
"UberPOP is banned, but it's still here," cabbie Stephane Molla said in Bordeaux, southwest France.
Cabbies in France, like their colleagues in several other countries, have held several protests against the app -- some of which have turned violent.
On at least two occasions in Strasbourg in eastern France last week, taxi drivers posed as customers in order to lure Uber drivers to isolated spots where they were assaulted by cab drivers and their vehicles damaged.
In Paris, the government tried to strengthen its hand on Wednesday by obtaining a court order banning Uber from operating in the capital, but the company dismissed the move.
"We will fight it (in the courts) and we'll see what happens on appeal. For the time being it changes nothing, UberPOP can continue to operate," the head of Uber France, Thibaud Simphal, told the BFM Business channel.
San Francisco-based Uber, which offers several types of ride-sharing services, claims to have 400,000 UberPOP users in France.
However, its drivers do not pay taxes, do not need to undergo the 250 hours of training mandatory for French cabbies and do not require the same insurance as taxis.
Uber
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:21:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds Obamacare subsidies</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/supreme-court-upholds-obamacare-subsidies-122340028541.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:20:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What does SCOTUS Obamacare ruling mean?</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/what-does-scotus-obamacare-ruling-mean--142038782.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>What does SCOTUS Obamacare ruling mean?
By Katie Couric June 25, 2015 10:20 AM
Yahoo News
Content preferences
Done
The U.S. Supreme Court ruled on Thursday to uphold the availability of tax subsidies related to President Barack Obamas signature healthcare law, the 2010 Affordable Care Act better known as Obamacare.
Yahoo global news anchor Katie Couric hosted a special live discussion of the ruling with Yahoo News chief White House correspondent Olivier Knox, Yahoo News national affairs reporter Liz Goodwin, and National Constitution Center President and CEO Jeff Rosen.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:58:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>House completes Obama's trade items as Pacific pact looms</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/senate-house-prepare-complete-obamas-trade-agenda-071045807--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>House completes Obama's trade items as Pacific pact looms
By CHARLES BABINGTON June 25, 2015 12:58 PM

.
View photo
Graphic shows Senate vote on Trade Promotion Authority; 1c x 4 inches; 46.5 mm x 101 mm;
WASHINGTON (AP)  The Republican-led Congress completed President Barack Obama's trade package Thursday, overwhelmingly passing a worker training program just weeks after it was stymied.
The House voted 286 to 138 to renew the job retraining program for workers displaced by international trade. Obama had said he wanted to sign that bill alongside the "fast track" negotiating authority that Congress approved a day earlier.
Usually a Democratic priority, the retraining bill briefly became hostage to Democrats' failed efforts to block fast track.
The House measure also renews the African Growth and Opportunity Act.
Obama and his trade opponents are shifting their focus to proposed trade agreements under negotiation for years. The first, the Trans-Pacific Partnership, involves the United States, Japan, Canada and nine other Pacific-rim nations.
The fast-track law allows Congress to ratify or reject such agreements, but not change or filibuster them.
Most House Democrats, along with major labor unions, opposed fast track, saying free-trade pacts send U.S. jobs abroad.
House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi, D-Calif., said Thursday's votes mark "the end of phase one" in the trade debate, but "the fight will continue." The next step, she said, is "to shine a sharp, clear, bright light" on details of the Pacific-rim proposal.
Passage of the trade bills mark a huge win for the president, and one paradoxically spearheaded by Republicans. And it's a defeat for the AFL-CIO and unions and environmental groups that fiercely opposed it. Some have vowed to punish the relatively small number of congressional Democrats who opposed them.
But Obama  much like the last Democratic president, Bill Clinton  portrays expanded trade as crucial in a global, high-tech economy. Most Republicans agree, but most congressional Democrats, especially in the House, do not.
Trade has opened the most striking breach between a Democratic president and the lawmakers who overwhelmingly backed him on health care and other hard-fought issues.
Pelosi and fellow House Democrats dealt Obama a humiliating rebuke on June 12, when they derailed his trade package only hours after he traveled to the Capitol to personally ask for their help. The House voted 302-126 that day to reject the job retraining portion of the package. Nearly half the "no" votes came from Democrats.
Republican leaders, with White House support, restructured the legislative package and passed fast track with big GOP margins, plus modest Democratic support.
On Thursday, only six House Democrats voted against the job retraining program. Among Republicans, 132 voted against the program, and 111 voted for it.
Rep. Paul Ryan, chairman of the House Ways and Means Committee, said some Democrats had questioned Republicans' promises to support the job retraining program even after fast track was secured.
To pass the trade legislation, Ryan, R-Wis., told House colleagues before Thursday's vote, "We needed a little bit of trust. We are here today to keep our word."
Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:39:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds discrimination claims in housing case</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/supreme-court-upholds-broad-discrimination-claims-under-housing-141124553--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Supreme Court upholds broad housing discrimination claims
By Lawrence Hurley June 25, 2015 4:39 PM

The U.S. Supreme Court in Washington. (Gary Cameron/Reuters)
By Lawrence Hurley
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - A divided U.S. Supreme Court on Thursday embraced a broad interpretation of discrimination claims allowed under the landmark Fair Housing Act, a blow to lenders and insurers that face such lawsuits and had urged the court to curb them.
In a 5-4 decision in a major civil rights case out of Texas, the court preserved a legal tool that has been used for decades to bring bias lawsuits over actions that have a discriminatory effect even with no evidence of discriminatory intent.
The unexpected ruling was a triumph for civil rights activists, who had feared the justices would rein in these lawsuits, and the administration of President Barack Obama, which had asked the justices to allow such claims to continue.
Justice Anthony Kennedy, a conservative who often casts the deciding vote in close cases, joined the court's four liberals in the majority.
"By recognizing that laws, policies and practices with unjustified discriminatory effects are inconsistent with the Fair Housing Act, todays decision lends support to hard-working Americans who are attempting to find good housing opportunities for themselves and their families," U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch said.
The case involved Inclusive Communities Project Inc, a nonprofit group that claimed Texas violated the law by disproportionately awarding low-income housing tax credits to developers owning properties in poor, minority-dominated neighborhoods. The group works to place low-income tenants in the more wealthy, majority white suburbs of Dallas.
The Texas case was closely watched by lenders and insurance companies, which say they are unfairly targeted. Industry groups say companies use neutral criteria when assessing risk. Based on how the law has been interpreted for decades, lawsuits could be filed over legitimate business practices, they argue.
Although a broad win for civil rights advocates on the legal theory, Kennedy, writing for the court, indicated in the ruling that the Texas plaintiffs ultimately could lose when the case returns to lower courts.
 The court was considering whether the 1968 law allows for "disparate impact" claims in which plaintiffs need to show only the discriminatory effect of a particular practice and not evidence of discriminatory intent. There was no dispute over the law's prohibition on openly discriminatory acts in the sale and rental of housing.
 For decades, disparate impact claims have been a way for lawyers representing blacks and other minorities to target policies that do not directly discriminate yet have the effect of putting certain groups at a disadvantage.
Kennedy wrote that Congress indicated in 1988 when it amended the law that it intended disparate impact claims to be available.
"It permits plaintiffs to counteract unconscious prejudices and disguised animus that escape easy classification," Kennedy added.
Kennedy also made clear there are limits to the types of claims allowed, saying "statistical disparity" alone is not enough. Plaintiffs must "point to a defendant's policy or policies causing that disparity," Kennedy added.

'INEFFECTIVE AND UNFAIR'
The disparate impact theory is opposed by business interests because it allows for a broad range of business decisions related to housing to be subject to civil rights litigation.
"Discrimination has no place in the United States, and the government should be equipped to hold accountable those who practice it. However, disparate impact is ineffective and unfair, and will ultimately harm those it is intended to protect," said David Hirschmann, president of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce's Center for Capital Markets Competitiveness.
Hirschmann welcomed what he called "severe limitations" imposed by the court on what kind of claims can be made.
Justice Samuel Alito wrote in a dissenting opinion that the ruling will "have unfortunate consequences for local government, private enterprise, and those living in poverty."
Alito cited an earlier case in which what he called a city's good faith attempt to fix "deplorable housing conditions" for renters was subjected to a legal challenge under the theory.
 National civil rights groups had tried to keep the issue away from the conservative-leaning high court. In the past three years, two other cases that raised the same question about the scope of fair-housing law were taken up by the high court but settled with the help of the rights groups before the justices could rule.
 Under Chief Justice John Roberts leadership, a five-justice conservative majority previously had curtailed remedies for race discrimination in a series of cases involving federal voting rights, promotion tests for firefighters and integration plans designed to balance out whites and blacks throughout a school district and offset segregated housing.
"The way to stop discrimination on the basis of race is to stop discriminating on the basis of race," Roberts wrote in 2007.
 The case is Texas Department of Housing and Community Affairs v. Inclusive Communities Project, U.S. Supreme Court, No. 13-1371.

(Reporting by Lawrence Hurley; Editing by Will Dunham)
Justice Anthony Kennedy
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
