<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Yahoo">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:49:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former U.S. House Speaker Hastert indicted on federal charges</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/former-u-house-speaker-hastert-indicted-federal-charges-212302057.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Former U.S. House Speaker Hastert indicted on federal charges
3 hours ago
View gallery
Former U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Dennis Hastert (R-IL) speaks during a news conference in
(Reuters) - Former U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Dennis Hastert was indicted on Thursday on federal charges, including for lying to the FBI, relating to an alleged effort to hide $3.5 million in payments to a person to conceal past misconduct.
The Illinois Republican, who left office in 2007, was charged with structuring the withdrawal of $952,000 in cash in order to evade the requirement that banks report cash transactions over $10,000, and lying to the FBI about his withdrawals, the U.S. Attorney's Office in Chicago said.
Each count of the two-count indictment carries a maximum penalty of five years in prison and a $250,000 fine.
Hastert, 73, was not available for comment, according to his office at the Dickstein Shapiro law firm in Washington where he is listed as a senior adviser.
According to the indictment, the unspecified misconduct involved payments to an unnamed individual who had been a Yorkville, Illinois, resident and had known Hastert for most of the person's life.
Before his terms in Congress, Hastert served three terms as an Illinois state representative and was a teacher at Yorkville High School in suburban Chicago for 16 years, according to a biography from Wheaton College where he graduated in 1964.
View gallery
Former U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Dennis Hastert (R-IL) announces that he will not seek a
According to the indictment, Hastert met with the person several times around 2010 and discussed past misconduct by the former lawmaker. Eventually, Hastert agreed to pay the person $3.5 million in compensation to conceal the misconduct, the indictment said.
Shortly afterward, Hastert began making cash payments to the individual, according to the indictment.
Hastert served as a congressman from suburban Chicago for more than 20 years before resigning from the House in November 2007, having lost the speaker's job when Democrats gained control of the House in the 2006 elections.
Hastert joined Dickstein Shapiro in 2008 as a senior adviser. Hastert resigned from the board of the exchange operator CME Group Inc on Thursday, the company said.
(Reporting by Eric Beech in Washington, Tom Polansek in Chicago and David Bailey in Minneapolis; Editing by Peter Cooney and Eric Beech)
Dennis Hastert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:04:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jurors hear from Holmes on video that he regretted attack</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/theater-shooting-prosecutors-build-case-holmes-sane-063454947.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Jurors hear from Holmes on video that he regretted attack
By DAN ELLIOTT 2 hours ago

Holmes Notebook Raises More Questions

Holmes Notebook Raises More Questions
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Holmes Notebook Raises More Questions
 Replay video
Holmes Trial Sparks Survivor Nightmares

Two blasts rock the Baghdad night, killing at least 10 at a pair of five-star hotels. Rough Cut (no reporter narration).
Load More
CENTENNIAL, Colo. (AP)  Jurors in the Colorado theater shooting trial heard for the first time in the gunman's own words that he regretted the attack and sometimes cried about it at night.
James Holmes' comments came about two years after the shooting, in a videotaped interview with a state-appointed psychiatrist.
On Thursday, jurors watched the video and heard testimony from the doctor, William Reid, who said he believes Holmes knew the consequences when he opened fire at a Batman movie premiere in July 2012.
In the video, Reid asks Holmes if he got emotional when his parents visited him in jail for the first time. Holmes responds, "Nope," but concedes in short answers that he sometimes cries before he goes to bed because he feels bad about the attack.
"What brings tears to your eyes?" the psychiatrist asks.
"Just regrets," Holmes responds. "Usually it's before I go to sleep."
"Regrets about?" Reid asks.
"About the shooting."
Earlier in the day, Reid testified about his conclusions from the July 2014 interviews, saying "whatever he (Holmes) suffered from" that night, he knew what he was doing.
Reminded that his task was to determine whether Holmes was legally sane during the attack, Reid declared, "whatever he suffered from, it did not prevent him from forming intent and knowing the consequences of what he was doing."
The comment briefly frustrated the prosecutor, who said his witness had jumped ahead of him, and prompted the defense to ask for a mistrial.
View gallery
FILE - In this June 4, 2013, file photo Aurora theater shooting suspect James Holmes appears in cour
Judge Carlos Samour ultimately denied the request, even as he acknowledged it might confuse jurors on the key question of the trial. They must decide whether Holmes' disease or deficient mental state at the time of the attack met Colorado's legal definition of sanity, leaving him unable to form a "culpable mental state."
Essentially, the judge said, Reid was supposed to limit his opinions to whether Holmes was capable of understanding right from wrong  but not whether he actually understood it.
"I do think someone could misunderstand the use of the term "prevent," Samour said, but he ruled that Reid's overall comments didn't violate that subtle boundary.
After a long break to settle the question, District Attorney George Brauchler asked Reid "to be precise" about his findings, and the psychiatrist gave the briefest possible responses.
Did Holmes have a serious mental illness? "Yes."
View gallery
FILE - In this Thursday, Feb. 27, 2014, file photo, District Attorney George Brauchler leaves distri
Despite that illness, did Holmes have "the capacity to know right from wrong" on July 19 and 20, the night of the attack? "Yes."
Did Holmes have the capacity to form the intent to act after deliberation, and to act knowingly? "Yes."
And did Holmes meet the legal definition of sanity? "Yes."
Holmes has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity in the attack that killed 12 people and injured 70. Colorado law gives the state the burden to prove he was sane, and therefore guilty. Prosecutors want him executed, not sent to a mental hospital.
Reid said before spending 22 hours interviewing Holmes, he interviewed Holmes' parents and dozens of others who knew him. He said he spent about 300 hours preparing for the sanity exam, including viewing more than a week of videos of Holmes in jail shortly after the attack.
"There was nothing to indicate insanity," Reid said. "He seemed to sleep at slightly odd hours. I can't think of very much else."
Reid acknowledged that Holmes' mental state had changed in the two years between the attack and the interview, including what he described as a "physical and mental breakdown" in November 2012, when Holmes was videotaped repeatedly ramming his head against a cell wall while naked.
Holmes has taken anti-psychotic medicine since then, but Reid said the episode wasn't relevant to his capacity to understand right from wrong months earlier.
The judge asked for Reid's interview after prosecutors challenged the conclusions of the first state-ordered review of his sanity, by Dr. Jeffrey Metzner in December 2013.
James Holmes
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Google wants to store all your photos for free, forever</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/tech/google-wants-to-store-all-your-photos-for-free-120120559004.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:44:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FBI launches probe into theft of U.S. taxpayer information</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/fbi-launches-probe-theft-u-taxpayer-information-174426501.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FBI launches probe into theft of U.S. taxpayer information
8 hours ago
.
View gallery
A general view of the U.S. Internal Revenue Service (IRS) building in Washington May 27, 2015. REUTERS/Jonathan
View gallery
United States Internal Revenue Service Commissioner John Koskinen appears before a House Oversight a
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The FBI said on Thursday it had begun looking into the illegal access of the tax-return information of about 100,000 people disclosed by the Internal Revenue Service earlier this week.
"The FBI has opened an investigation into the recently reported incident at the Internal Revenue Service and is working with our interagency partners to determine the nature and scope of this matter," a spokesman said.
IRS Commissioner John Koskinen said Tuesday cyber criminals had sought to gain access to personal tax information 200,000 times from February to May, and were successful in about half of those attempts.
The FBI spokesman said individuals alerted to the illegal access of information should report "any suspected instances of identify theft" to the FBI's Crime Complaint Center at the website www.ic3.gov.
On Tuesday, the Senate Finance Committee is scheduled to hear testimony about the incident from Koskinen and J. Russell George, the Treasury Department's inspector general for tax administration.
(Reporting by Lindsay Dunsmuir; Editing by Richard Cowan and Bernadette Baum)
Internal Revenue Service
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:45:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Defense in Freddie Gray case seeks to move trial from Baltimore</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/defense-freddie-gray-case-seeks-move-trial-baltimore-154510686.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Defense in Freddie Gray case seeks to move trial from Baltimore
10 hours ago
.
View photo
A girl writes on the sidewalk near North Ave and Pennsylvania Ave in Baltimore, Maryland May 1, 2015.
(Reuters) - Defense attorneys for six police officers facing criminal charges in the Freddie Gray case are seeking to have the trial moved from Baltimore, saying their clients cannot get a fair trial there, the Baltimore Sun reported on Thursday.
The lawyers filed an 85-page document on Wednesday in Baltimore Circuit Court asking for a change of venue, arguing that a "presumption of prejudice" exists in the city, the newspaper said.
Gray, a 25-year-old black man, was arrested April 12 and suffered a spinal injury in police custody. His death a week later led to protests and rioting in Baltimore that prompted a curfew and a National Guard deployment.
Defense attorneys contend that not enough time has passed to permit "the type of healing and reconciliation in the community that would be needed to dampen the effects of the events surrounding the case," the newspaper said, quoting from the document.
The six officers face charges that include second-degree murder, assault and misconduct in office.
A spokeswoman for State's Attorney's Marilyn Mosby did not respond to a request for comment on the filing.
(Reporting by Ian Simpson; Editing by Will Dunham)
the Baltimore Sun
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:47:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. President Obama visits family of journalist slain by ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/u-president-obama-visits-family-journalist-slain-isis-174759488.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>U.S. President Obama visits family of journalist slain by ISIS
8 hours ago
View photo
U.S. President Barack Obama delivers remarks at the Memorial Day observance at Arlington National Cemetery
MIAMI (Reuters) - U.S. President Barack Obama met on Thursday with the family of American journalist Steven Sotloff, who was beheaded last year by Islamic State militants.
The White House said Obama met with Sotloff's parents Art and Shirley and his sister, Lauren, while he was in Florida for fundraising and a briefing on the upcoming hurricane season.
"The president expressed his and the first ladys condolences for Stevens death," White House spokeswoman Bernadette Meehan said.
"He appreciated the chance to hear from the Sotloffs more about Stevens work as a journalist, including his passion for bringing the stories of people who are suffering to the rest of the world in the hope of making a positive difference, including in Syria."
Last September, the Islamic State militant group, also known as ISIS, released a video purporting to show the beheading of Sotloff, a 31-year old freelance journalist who was kidnapped in Syria in August 2013.
Sotloff had reported from across the Middle East and covered events in Libya for Time Magazine.
(Reporting by Jeff Mason; Editing by Toni Reinhold)
Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:00:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chicago’s heart of mercy for the disabled</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/chicago-s-heart-of-mercy-for-the-disabled-170042234.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Done

Nestled away in a northern Chicago suburb, among tree-lined streets, white picket fences and perfectly manicured lawns, is a 31-acre complex known as Misericordia . Misericordia, whose name means heart of mercy in Latin , is home to more than 600 children and adults with a wide range of physical and mental disabilities.

Sister Rosemary, a Catholic nun and devout caregiver, runs Misericordia. She has ushered in a change in care for the disabled thats being noticed around the country as religious and mental health leaders are visiting Misericordia to see what Sister Rosemary has accomplished.

When I came to Misericordia in 1969, we had 132 children under the age of 6, said Sister Rosemary. Sixty-nine of them were babies with Down syndrome. It was a time when professionals were telling parents, Get on with your life, theyre not going to amount to much anyway, you have other children to worry about. When I came, I came as a social worker and a teacher with that kind of background. I had no experience in special education, but the day I walked into Misericordia I thought, This is right  thank you God, this is right.

Sister Rosemary was one of the first caregivers who believed that caring for the disabled was about more than just providing the basics for these children  it was about making sure they enjoyed every minute of life.

Since taking over Misericordia in the late 60s, Sister Rosemary has expanded the campus into a sprawling home where those with disabilities have jobs, responsibilities and constant activities, from painting pictures to baking sweet goods. Every year, residents artworks are auctioned off at the Art Institute of Chicago, raising thousands of dollars.

Residents who need constant care are helped at a special facility that provides daily medically advanced therapy, ranging from sensory to aquatic, performed by a team of experts.

Sister Rosemary said that all of these programs are helping residents to live longer.

We developed really wonderful programs, and I see the children who are now adults today living at Misericordia, enjoying good lives, living very independent as they can, she said.

All these programs come at a cost. Misericordia is partly funded by the state of Illinois, but Sister Rosemary said that if Gov. Bruce Rauners new budget passes, the institution will be forced to increase its fundraising. Right now, Misericordia must raise $15 million in private funds annually to keep its doors open; if the governors budget passes, Sister Rosemary said that it would have to raise $21 million annually.

Despite the financial concerns, Misericordia continues to serve and grow as new homes are currently being built for the communitys aging population. Thats a group of residents who just a generation ago would not have grown to old age.

Years ago, a person with Down syndrome generally died when they were 12 or 15 years old, said Sister Rosemary. Today, doctors and teachers and therapists are all involved in their lives, so theyre living longer. Our oldest resident (with Down syndrome) is 68 years old.

Even though she doesnt have any children of her own, she feels as if all the residents at Misericordia are her children.

Its been a joy, said Sister Rosemary, as a religious sister to have this opportunity of being a mother to so many of them.
Health
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:54:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CDC investigating error that caused live anthrax shipments</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/army-chief-human-error-likely-not-cause-anthrax-142140710--politics.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>CDC investigating error that caused live anthrax shipments
By ROBERT BURNS and BRADY McCOMBS 2 hours ago

.
.
WASHINGTON (AP)  The U.S. Army's top general said Thursday that human error probably was not a factor in the Army's mistaken shipment of live anthrax samples from a chemical weapons testing site that was opened more than 70 years ago in a desolate stretch of desert in Utah.
Samples from the anthrax lot ended up at 18 labs in nine states and an Army lab in South Korea, leading more than two dozen people to get treatment for possible exposure.
Gen. Ray Odierno, the Army chief of staff, told reporters the problem may have been a failure in the technical process of killing, or inactivating, anthrax samples.
Odierno said the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention is investigating what went wrong at Dugway Proving Ground, the Army installation in Utah where the anthrax originated.
Officials said the government labs that received the suspect anthrax were at the Army's Edgewood Chemical Biological Center in Maryland and the Naval Surface Warfare Center in Virginia. The rest were commercial labs, which the Pentagon has declined to identify, citing legal constraints.
Some of the samples sent from Utah were also transferred to other labs in the U.S. by the Edgewood center, a research and development resource for nonmedical chemical and biological defense.
CDC spokesman Jason McDonald said four people at labs in Delaware, Texas and Wisconsin were recommended to get antibiotics as a precaution, although they are not sick. U.S. officials at Osan Air Base in South Korea said 22 people were being treated for possible exposure.
View gallery
FILE - This Jan. 27, 2010, file photo, shows the main gate at Dugway Proving Ground military base, a
Odierno said normal procedures had been followed, and that he was not aware that such a problem had surfaced previously at Dugway.
But there have been at least two other questionable incidents at the military post 85 miles west of Salt Lake City that has been testing chemical and biological warfare weapons since it was opened in 1942.
In 2011, Dugway was locked down for 12 hours because less than one-fourth of a teaspoon of VX nerve agent was unaccounted for.
Military officials launched an internal investigation, but the results were not released. Questions about the incident were not answered Thursday by military officials. Utah Gov. Gary Herbert said in 2011 that he met with the base commander and that the issue had been resolved to his satisfaction.
In 1968, Dugway came under scrutiny when 6,000 sheep died nearby. An Army report acknowledged that the nerve agent was found in snow and grass samples, The Salt Lake Tribune reported based on a report that was declassified in 1978. An Army spokesman said in the late 1990s that state agriculture scientists never identified the cause of death of the sheep.
Herbert said in a statement he's concerned about the incident and is working with the CDC to monitor the investigation.
View gallery
FILE - In this Sept. 18, 2013 file photo, Army Chief of Staff Gen. Ray Odierno testifies on Capitol 
Test facilities like Dugway are intended to develop ways to defend against biochemical warfare, which some fear could be used by terrorists, said Barry M. Blechman, co-founder of the Stimson Center, a nonpartisan global security group in Washington.
He doesn't know why it was sending anthrax and is perplexed at how the mistake was made.
"This is an accident that should never happen," Blechman said. "You should have double-triple-positive controls over any live, lethal agent."
Steve Erickson, of the volunteer military watchdog group Citizens Education Project, said the incident isn't cause for panic but suggests more oversight is needed.
"Ever since 9/11, there's been a propensity to throw money at biodefense," Erickson said. "When you allow these activities to blossom and burgeon over a period of years without any effective oversight, you are asking for trouble."
The Dugway Proving Ground was created by President Franklin D. Roosevelt. The site has gone through name changes and been closed and reopened several times.
It sits on 180,000 acres of flat, desert terrain. It's miles from any population base, but it has a village with an elementary and high school, medical clinic, a few restaurants, a theater, pool, gym, and homes and temporary lodging.
About 1,700 people work at Dugway, including a mix of military and nonmilitary scientists, chemists, microbiologists and engineers.
It is one of six Army equipment-testing facilities that also include sites in Maryland, Arizona, Alabama and New Mexico.
In one of the chemical testing buildings at Dugway, chambers are used to test chemical warfare agents, the Army says in online materials. An outdoor range tests smokes, obscurants and explosives.
___
Associated Press writer Brady McCombs reported from Salt Lake City.
anthrax
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Matt Bai: Hillary Clinton's not like the rest of us? Good!</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/democratic-presidential-candidate-hillary-clinton-120050918741.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:43:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pataki record: A Roosevelt Republican from N.Y.’s crime-crackdown years</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/the-george-pataki-record-a-roosevelt-republican-120112481156.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:34:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin accuses US of meddling into FIFA affairs</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/putin-accuses-us-meddling-fifa-affairs-093647908--spt.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Putin accuses US of meddling into FIFA affairs
By NATALIYA VASILYEVA 11 hours ago

Putin says FIFA arrests show US meddling abroad

Putin says FIFA arrests show US meddling abroad
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Putin says FIFA arrests show US meddling abroad
 Replay video
Dad rescues baby ducks from storm drain

View gallery
Vitaly Mutko, Russia's minister for sports arrives for a meeting of the European Soccer federati
MOSCOW (AP)  Russian President Vladimir Putin accused the United States of meddling in the affairs of soccer's governing body and hinted that its corruption investigation is part of an attempt to take the 2018 World Cup away from his country.
Putin said in televised comments Thursday that he found it "odd" that the FIFA probe was launched at the request of U.S. officials for crimes which do not involve its citizens and did not happen in the United States.
Corruption charges in the U.S. were announced Wednesday against 14 people, at least two of whom have American citizenship. Seven of the 14 were arrested Wednesday morning in Zurich ahead of a FIFA meeting and Friday's presidential election in which Sepp Blatter is expected to win a fifth term. Much of the money that allegedly changed hands went through U.S. banks, which is why U.S. officials were able to bring charges.
In a separate probe, Swiss prosecutors opened criminal proceedings into FIFA's awarding of the 2018 World Cup to Russia and the 2022 tournament to Qatar.
Putin said even if "someone has done something wrong," Russia "has nothing to do with it." He then tried to portray the probe as a U.S. attempt to go after dissenters, likening the case to the persecution of whistleblowers Julian Assange and Edward Snowden.
"Our American counterparts, unfortunately, are using the same methods to reach their goals and illegally persecute people. I don't rule out that this is the case in relation to FIFA," Putin said. "I have no doubt that this is yet another evident attempt to derail Mr. Blatter's re-election as FIFA president. We are aware of the pressure that he was subjected to in relation to Russia holding the 2018 World Cup."
Russian Sports Minister Vitaly Mutko, who is also a FIFA executive committee member and is in Zurich for the governing body's congress and presidential election, said Wednesday that his country welcomes the investigation.
Vladimir Putin
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>George Pataki announces 2016 presidential bid</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/pataki-announces-presidential-bid-120100166576.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:29:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. military mistakenly ships live anthrax to labs in nine states</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/u-military-mistakenly-ships-live-anthrax-labs-9-000151602.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>U.S. Army chief says no human error seen in anthrax mishap
By Phil Stewart 10 hours ago

.
View gallery
Spores from the Sterne strain of anthrax bacteria (Bacillus anthracis) are pictured in this handout scanning
By Phil Stewart
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. personnel working at an Army facility in Utah appeared to follow correctly all the outlined procedures to inactivate anthrax before they mistakenly shipped off live samples of the deadly bacteria, the Army's top general said on Thursday.
Army Chief of Staff General Raymond Odierno said investigators were now reviewing the procedures themselves to determine why the bacteria was not rendered inactive.
"The best I can tell there was not human error," Odierno told reporters, cautioning that his information was based solely on preliminary reports.
U.S. officials disclosed on Wednesday that U.S. Army facilities mistakenly shipped live anthrax bacteria to laboratories in nine states and an air base in South Korea.
The Pentagon has said there was no known suspected infection or risk to the public.
View gallery
Spores from the Sterne strain of anthrax bacteria (Bacillus anthracis) are pictured in this handout 
But four U.S. civilians have started taking preventive measures called post-exposure prophylaxis, which usually includes the anthrax vaccine, antibiotics or both.
Twenty-two personnel at the base in South Korea were also given precautionary medical measures although none have shown sign of exposure.
The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)  has begun an investigation of the incident. Odierno said the CDC was reviewing whether "we have to change the procedures that are in place."
Odierno did not offer specifics and said he did not know how long the procedures had been in place.
"But we definitely believe no one is in danger. We believe we followed all the proper procedures," Odierno said.
The mishap comes 11 months after the CDC, one of the government's top civilian labs, similarly mishandled anthrax.
Researchers at a lab designed to handle extremely dangerous pathogens sent what they believed were killed samples of anthrax to another CDC lab, one with fewer safeguards and therefore not authorized to work with live anthrax.
Scores of CDC employees could have been exposed to the live anthrax, but none became ill.
That incident and a similar one last spring, in which CDC scientists shipped what they thought was a benign form of bird flu but which was actually a highly virulent strain, led U.S. lawmakers to fault a "dangerous pattern" of safety lapses at government labs.
In the latest case, the Army's Dugway Proving Ground in Utah reported in March 2014 that gamma irradiation had inactivated the anthrax stock in question, and along with another Army facility, began shipments that continued through April 2015, a U.S. official said.
(Additional reporting by Sharon Begley in New York and James Pearson in Seoul; Editing by Frances Kerry)
Raymond Odierno
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Russia ‘reset’ architect to next president: Don’t try that again</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/russia-reset-architect-to-next-president-dont-120051660936.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 01:43:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Santorum faces daunting task in White House bid</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/rick-santorum-faces-steep-climb-second-white-house-072018684--election.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Rick Santorum announces second White House run
By STEVE PEOPLES and JOE MANDAK May 27, 2015 6:43 PM

Santorum Making Another Run For President

Santorum Making Another Run For President
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Santorum Making Another Run For President
 Replay video
Pataki Announces 2016 Bid, Clinton Trust Falls

May 22 -- In this Bloomberg Politics/Purple Strategies Iowa focus group video, Democratic caucus participants discuss whether the Clintons are secretive and if Bernie Sanders can pull Hillary to the left.
Load More
CABOT, Pa. (AP)  Conservative culture warrior Rick Santorum launched a 2016 White House bid on Wednesday, vowing to fight for working-class Americans in a new election season that will test his influence  and focus on social issues  in a changing Republican Party.
The former Pennsylvania senator may have exceeded his own expectations by scoring a second-place finish in the race for the Republican presidential nomination four years ago. Yet as he enters a more powerful and diverse 2016 field, he may struggle even to qualify for the debate stage in his second run.
"I am proud to stand here, among you and for you, the American workers who have sacrificed so much, to announce that I am running for president of the United States," the 57-year-old senator said, flanked by factory workers and six of his seven children in a cinderblock warehouse near his western Pennsylvania hometown.
"The last race, we changed the debate. This race, with your help and God's grace, we can change this nation."
Santorum opens this political season as a heavy underdog in a race expected to feature more than a dozen high-profile Republicans  most of them newcomers to presidential politics. He is among the nation's most prominent social conservatives, having dedicated much of his political career to opposing same-sex marriage and abortion rights, while advocating for conservative Christian family values.
He mentioned cultural issues briefly Wednesday in remarks designed to broaden his appeal to working-class Americans. "As president, I will stand for the principle that every life matters  the poor, the disabled and the unborn," said Santorum, a Catholic.
View gallery
Republican presidential candidate and former U.S. Senator Rick Santorum is flanked by his daughter E
He ultimately won 11 states in the GOP's 2012 primary election after an unexpected and narrow victory in the opening contest in Iowa, where he emerged as a conservative favorite after touring the state's 99 counties in a pickup truck.
His road to relevancy this time won't be easy.
"It's going to be much more competitive," said Foster Friess, a prominent donor who was standing near the podium during Wednesday's announcement.
Santorum has acknowledged his challenges in 2016, but says his experience could pay dividends the second time around. Most of the GOP's recent presidential nominees, Mitt Romney and President Ronald Reagan among them, needed more than one campaign to win the nomination.
He faces considerable competition for his party's social conservatives in particular. The list of Republicans already courting religious voters includes former Arkansas Gov. Mike Huckabee, a Baptist pastor who won the Iowa caucuses in 2008, former Texas Gov. Rick Perry, Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal and Texas Sen. Ted Cruz. And like Santorum, former Florida Gov. Jeb Bush is a Catholic.
View gallery
Former U.S. Sen. Rick Santorum, left, stands with his wife Karen Santorum as he announces his candid
Polling suggests a shift in voter attitudes about the importance of social issues, particularly gay marriage, which has long been a defining issue for Santorum. Like others in his party, he has appealed to religious voters recently by criticizing what he calls President Barack Obama's "war on religious freedom," which includes the broader debate over whether private businesses can deny services to same-sex couples.
Santorum promised Wednesday to "fight for the freedom for you to believe what you are called to believe, not just in your places of worship, but outside your places of worship, too."
His longshot status may keep him out of presidential debates altogether.
Only those who place in the top 10 of national polls will be allowed to participate in the first Republican presidential debate in August, according to guidelines released by network host Fox News. Santorum is on the bubble.
While advisers suggest he will benefit from a donor network that has grown in recent years, questions remain about Santorum's ability to raise money as well.
View gallery
Former U.S. Sen. Rick Santorum announces his candidacy for the Republican nomination for President o
Friess, who previously gave more than $2 million to a pro-Santorum super PAC in 2012, said he would continue to support Santorum's White House ambitions, although he plans to avoid donating large amounts directly to the campaign or a supportive super PAC, both of which would disclose their donors.
"Any giving I'm doing is going to be lower-profile and less noticed," Friess told The Associated Press.
Santorum immediately launches a rollout tour that begins in Iowa on Thursday and Friday and moves to South Carolina on Saturday and Sunday. He is not scheduled to appear in New Hampshire, where voters typically don't favor candidates who focus on social issues.
A crowd of hundreds watched Santorum's announcement at Penn United Technologies, an employee-owned manufacturing company based in the western Pennsylvania county where Santorum grew up.
Wallace Cypher, 54, who lives a half mile away, said he's backing Santorum because he wants a true conservative to win the GOP presidential nomination.
"I think he'd be a whole lot better than what we've got in there right now," Cypher said.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
