<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Yahoo">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Martin O'Malley returns to a Baltimore he barely recognizes</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/martin-omalley-returns-to-a-baltimore-he-barely-117824391151.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>NFL draft winners and losers</title>
        <Link>http://sports.yahoo.com/blogs/nfl-shutdown-corner/nfl-draft-winners-and-losers--get-ready-for-more-superstar-rookie-receivers-045734487.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Done
When you have Andrew Luck , you buy him all the toys he wants.
The Indianapolis Colts are going to keep Luck happy. He now has what is likely the deepest receiving corps in the NFL after the Colts took electric receiver Phillip Dorsett from Miami in the first round.
The Colts have other needs. The defensive line needs work. Their safety position is thin. Running back still isnt all that good. Dorsett, who is a very explosive receiver, was a luxury pick. But giving Luck the best set of targets in the league isnt a bad idea. The Carolina Panthers , who have severely underserved Cam Newton through his career, could take a hint.
Dorsett landing in Indianapolis was the last first-round piece of what looks like another great class of receivers. Itll be hard to top last years group, but many of this years first-round receivers landed in great spots for instant success.
Dorsett got with the NFLs best young quarterback.
Breshad Perriman, who has sub-4.3 40 speed, was picked by the Baltimore Ravens and will catch strong-armed Joe Flaccos deep throws (what a fun fit that is).
Nelson Agholor should play a lot from Day 1 in the Philadelphia Eagles  up-tempo offense.
DeVante Parker gets to play with the Miami Dolphins . The steady development of Dolphins quarterback Ryan Tannehill, given all the quarterback problems in the NFL, has been severely ignored. Thats a great landing spot for the 14th pick.
And of course, fourth pick Amari Cooper will be Derek Carrs No. 1 target for years to come with the Oakland Raiders and lightning-fast Kevin White matches up with one thing Chicago Bears quarterback Jay Cutler does well, which is throw deep.
All six receivers drafted in the first round landed in pretty advantageous spots. Any of them have a chance to gain 1,000 yards as a rookie, unless someone like Dorsett gets overshadowed fighting T.Y. Hilton, Andre Johnson and Donte Moncrief for targets. And there are other talented receivers like Ohio States Devin Smith and former Missouri standout Dorial Green-Beckham who could be great second-round values on Friday.
It looks like another great year for rookie receivers is coming. And Luck is a very, very happy man.
Here are the other winners and some losers from the first round of the NFL draft:
WINNERS
Jay Cutler
Cutler keeps getting chances. Good ones, too.
ESPN had a report before the draft that the Bears were trying to get the second pick from Tennessee, presumably to draft quarterback Marcus Mariota . The report said the Titans didnt want Cutler. There was no trade.
So not only did Cutler stick with the Bears, but he got a huge upgrade to his receiving corps when the Bears took White with the seventh pick . The Bears could have gone in many directions with that pick, especially with new defensive-minded coach John Fox. But instead of going in that direction, the Bears again made a move to get Cutler over a hump that hes been unable to get over for his first nine NFL seasons.
If Cutler continues to be mediocre with the Bears, he cant say its because they didnt do enough to help him.
Dallas Cowboys and their restraint
Last year the flashy first-round pick for the Cowboys would have been Johnny Manziel. They took guard Zack Martin. That boring pick became an All-Pro as a rookie.
The headline-grabbing pick this year would have been a running back. Any running back. Someone to replace DeMarco Murray. Theres really nobody on the roster now who is all too enticing for that role. But the Cowboys didnt reach. They took cornerback Byron Jones of Connecticut, a very athletic player who fills another big need thats tougher to fill.
The Cowboys get made fun of for making impulse buys. But that didnt happen on Thursday. Theyll get a running back at some point. They just didnt reach for one in the first round.
Minnesota Vikings
They could move to the losers category tomorrow, especially if they trade Adrian Peterson on the cheap after the first round has passed. But the Vikings never seemed to want to trade Peterson and didnt give in to pressure to do so. Theyre a better team in 2015 because of it  and they might be pretty good.
The Vikings have to worry about Peterson being happy, but its not like the star running back has any leverage. Hes not sitting out another year and passing up more than $12 million in salary. Hell play. The Vikings are better off for it. Thats a win for them.
Bud Dupree and the Pittsburgh Steelers
Of all 32 picks made on Thursday night, I thought that the Steelers might have made the best one when value and need are factored in.
The Steelers needed an outside linebacker to replace the retired Jason Worilds. And Dupree fell in their laps.
We didnt expect Bud Dupree to be there, Steelers general manager Kevin Colbert said, according to the team's website . That was a very easy selection. As we say all of the time we are never going to lock ourselves into any position. We want good football players and Bud Dupree certainly fits that category.
This is a gift for us to be able to get this guy at 22.
Every coach and GM say some version of that after the first round, but I believe Colbert is being sincere. Not many players like Dupree, who ran a 4.56-second 40-yard dash and had a vertical leap of 42 inches at 269 pounds, last until the 22nd pick. Dupree isnt just a workout warrior; he was a player who did everything Kentucky asked, and the Wildcats asked him to do a lot. The Steelers have many options with him. And Dupree gets to start his career with a great organization that knows a few things about defensive football. Hell be part of an outstanding linebacking corps.
The Steelers were a very good team by the end of last year. They somehow added an instant impact player with the 22nd pick.
LOSERS
If Marcus Mariota is a Pro Bowl-level quarterback for the Titans, then thats all that matters. Thats the most important position and its not easy to find. The Titans will ultimately be winners.
But the Titans passed up a lot to take Mariota.
NFL Networks Ian Rapoport reported that the Eagles offered two first-round picks, a third-round pick, defensive tackle Fletcher Cox, linebacker Mychal Kendricks, cornerback Brandon Boykin and more to the Titans. That is a lot. Like  an insane amount. Cox, Kendricks and Boykin are all young defenders who would either start right away or contribute plenty. And the Titans did have a young quarterback in Zach Mettenberger , who showed some good things as a rookie last year. Tennessee could have justified taking the mega-offer and rolling with Mettenberger for one more year.
Again, if Mariota turns out to be an elite quarterback, then it doesnt matter. The Titans wont have any regrets. But itll be hard for the Titans to forget what they passed up if he doesnt.
Zac Stacy
Stacy rushed for 973 yards as a Rams rookie in 2013, a pretty promising start to his career. Then the Rams drafted Tre Mason, who took his starting spot. And then after the Rams drafted Todd Gurley, Stacy sent out the sad panda tweet of the night, sending out a simple "Yikes" right after Gurley was drafted. He deleted the tweet shortly after sending it.
Stacy is like many players around the league. Mike Glennon's shot at ever starting for Tampa Bay is over now that the Buccaneers officially drafted Jameis Winston. The same goes for Mettenberger. Branden Oliver had a nice rookie season at running back for the Chargers but now Melvin Gordon is in town. Many others effectively lost their jobs on Thursday. That's the flip side to all the excitement from the NFL's newest first-round picks.
Cleveland Browns
I should be excited about the Browns, who made two first-round picks. And they probably ended up with two good players, as they should. But it still feels a bit underwhelming.
They reportedly were after the No. 2 pick and quarterback Marcus Mariota, and that didnt happen. They were reportedly going for quarterback Sam Bradford, and that didnt happen (truthfully though, that might be for the best). Nose tackle Danny Shelton was a fine value pick, and should help stop the run. Picking Florida State center Cameron Erving pick wasnt too splashy, to say the least.
The Browns are apparently prepared to lose center Alex Mack, who has been one of their best players. Hes coming off a broken leg, but a year ago the Browns thought it wise to match the Jacksonville Jaguars  five-year, $42 million offer sheet to Mack. He can opt out of that after this season. Its hard to be too excited when you used the 19th pick to essentially replace one of your best players because you think hes going to leave. A much-needed young receiver would have been pretty nice instead, for example.
Erving might be a fine player. But he will just replace Mack in a year, it appears. Its hard to get too excited about that scenario.
Shane Ray jokes
Oh, Twitter sure had jokes when Shane Ray was drafted by the Denver Broncos . You see, Ray was cited for marijuana possession earlier this week. Marijuana is legal in Colorado. You see where this is going. Guffaw, guffaw.
Marijuana use is not legal in the NFL, so its not like it really matters to Ray where he went. But it is a curious pick by the Broncos. Ray has a toe injury that he described as being a variation of turf toe "on the serious side." That could hinder him as a rookie. The Broncos are in extreme must-win mode with the clock ticking on Peyton Manning. Ray was a good value at No. 23 (the Broncos traded up to get him) but he also doesnt appear to be a player who will make a huge impact in 2015, especially with Von Miller and DeMarcus Ware at outside linebacker. The player is good but the fit seems a bit odd.
Lael Collins and NFL teams who had to guess on him
LSU offensive tackle Lael Collins hasnt been named a suspect in the shooting death of his ex-girlfriend , Brittany Mills, who was pregnant when she was killed. Authorities in Louisiana are questioning him. None of us know if hes innocent or guilty.
If he has nothing to do with that tragic incident, then he just lost a lot of money and had what should have been a highlight day in his life ruined.
Collins asked to be put into the supplemental draft so he could have time to clear his name, which seemed like an easy solution for everyone involved, but that was denied. After that, it wasnt a surprise at all he fell out of the first round. Theres too much uncertainty. Who knows when he might get drafted.
With every team that took a tackle in the middle of the first round, you had to wonder if Collins would have been the pick if not for this issue. There were seven offensive linemen taken in the first round. Would he have been the Bengals pick at No. 21? The Cardinals at No. 24? Would he have been picked by a team that went in another direction because Collins was untouchable? Perhaps.
If Collins is found guilty of being involved in the slightest in the tragic shooting, then clearly nobody should or will feel sorry for his draft stock falling. Thats obvious. But what if he wasnt?
- - - - - - -
Frank Schwab is the editor of Shutdown Corner on Yahoo Sports. Have a tip? Email him at shutdowncorner@yahoo.com or follow him on Twitter! Follow @YahooSchwab
Sports &amp; Recreation
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:42:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Life crawling back to normal in Nepal's quake-hit capital</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/moments-joy-nepal-2-rescued-5-days-quake-065925639.html</Link>
        <Description>KATHMANDU, Nepal (AP) — Fresh croissants emerged from a popular bakery and were quickly snapped up. Farmers delivered fresh produce and lines disappeared at gasoline stations. Slowly, life edged back toward a semblance of normal in Nepal's quake-hit capital Friday as residents packed up tents and moved indoors.</Description>
        <MainBody>Content preferences
Done
KATHMANDU, Nepal (AP)  Fresh croissants emerged from a popular bakery and were quickly snapped up. Farmers delivered fresh produce and lines disappeared at gasoline stations. Slowly, life edged back toward a semblance of normal in Nepal's quake-hit capital Friday as residents packed up tents and moved indoors.
As rescue workers continued to comb the rubble in Kathmandu for survivors, the government said it was giving the equivalent of $1,000 to families of each victim killed in Saturday's earthquake, and another $400 for funeral costs, according to state-run Nepal Radio.
The death toll from the mammoth quake climbed to 6,260, police said, including those who died in an avalanche on Mount Everest, plus more than 60 elsewhere in the region. The city got a lift Thursday when two survivors, including a 15-year-old boy, were rescued after being buried in debris for five days.
Although poorer sections of the city remained strewn with collapsed buildings, there were visibly fewer tents standing in a central part of Kathmandu that had been packed with people in the first few days after the magnitude-7.8 quake hit amid repeated aftershocks.
Krishna Maharjan, a farmer on the outskirts, brought green onions and cauliflower on his bicycle into the city.
"We are trying to get as much fresh food to the people as possible," he said. "I feel it is our small contribution. But that's what we can do and every little bit helps."
More than 130,000 houses were reportedly destroyed, according to the U.N. humanitarian office. Its chief, Valerie Amos, landed in Nepal for a three-day visit to meet victims and local leaders. She plans to visit areas outside the Kathmandu Valley, according to the deputy spokesman for the U.N. secretary-general, Farhan Haq.
"Inaccessibility to some remote areas, the lack of helicopters, poor communication and security concerns remain the main challenges in delivering relief," Haq said. In the past 48 hours, the U.N. Children's Fund, or UNICEF, has delivered nearly 30 metric tons of supplies, including tents, water purification tablets, and first aid and hygiene kits.
A group of Nepal's Gurkhas serving the British army have rushed back home to help their quake-hit countrymen get clean drinking water. The soldiers from the Queen's Gurkha Engineers Unit on Thursday set up a portable water purification unit on the Kathmandu grounds of the old royal palace.
"I am just glad I could serve my countrymen when they really needed something so necessary like clean drinking water," said Cpl. Bhesh Gurung, 34. "I have been away for 13 years serving in a foreign land and finally I can do something for my motherland."
___
Associated Press writer Cara Anna at the United Nations contributed to this report.
View photo
.
CLICK IMAGE for slideshow: A man walks along the street near a collapsed house following Saturday's earthquake
KATHMANDU, Nepal
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:08:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Protesters ready for May Day march over black man's death in Baltimore</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/baltimore-officials-ask-patience-probe-black-mans-death-021004200.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Protesters ready for May Day march over black man's death in Baltimore
By Scott Malone and Ian Simpson 59 minutes ago

.
View gallery
Protestors line up shortly before the deadline for a city-wide curfew at North Ave and Pennsylvania Ave
By Scott Malone and Ian Simpson
BALTIMORE (Reuters) - Protesters and the family of a 25-year-old black man who died of injuries sustained while in police custody planned a May Day march in Baltimore as they demanded answers and punishment for the officers involved.
Freddie Gray's death is the latest in a string of incidents exposing the tense relations between U.S. minorities and police. Protesters planned to use annual May 1 marches, marking International Labor Day, to focus attention on the case, which follows the killings of unarmed black men in recent months.
Police in Baltimore turned over their report on the case a day earlier to prosecutors but released few details publicly, though local media reports suggested Gray may have been injured while he was in the back of a police van.
After rioting in Baltimore on Monday, protests have spread to major cities around the United States, resembling scenes of outrage sparked last year by police killings of unarmed black men in Ferguson, Missouri, New York and elsewhere.
Baltimore City State's Attorney Marilyn Mosby, a black woman who is the daughter and granddaughter of police officers, has now taken over the investigation to determine what exactly happened to Gray and whether any of the six officers involved in his arrest should face criminal charges. The six have been suspended from duty.
View gallery
Police line up shortly after the deadline for a city-wide curfew at North Ave and Pennsylvania Ave i
Mosby said her office has been conducting its own independent probe. The U.S. Justice Department is also investigating the case.
"All I want her to do is one thing: Search for the truth," said U.S. Representative Elijah Cummings, a Democrat who has been a fixture in the largely peaceful protests that followed Monday's rioting. "We must allow the process to go forward."
Gray suffered spinal injuries some time between his April 12 arrest and his arrival at a police station. Police have said Gray was not restrained during the ride, a violation of department policies. He died a week later.
Despite the protests, many questions about Gray's death remain unanswered. But media reports on Thursday provided possible accounts of what may have happened.
Multiple law enforcement sources told local broadcaster WJLA that the medical examiner found Gray's neck appeared to have broken when his head slammed into the back of the van. He also suffered a head wound matching a bolt jutting from the vehicle's back door, the sources told the station.
View gallery
A man, protesting the death of Freddie Gray, is detained by police after defying a curfew in Baltimo
The Washington Post cited a prisoner, who rode in the police van with Gray but could not see him, as saying he heard sounds that suggested Gray tried to hurt himself while riding in the vehicle, according to a document written by a police investigator.
Many on the streets of Baltimore were skeptical of the idea that Gray's injuries were self-inflicted.
"The police did that," said Eugene Russell, 46. "And the police are going to get away with it."
'KAFKA-ESQUE NIGHTMARE'
Roughly 270 people have been arrested since Monday's violence - which saw stores looted, dozens of buildings and cars burned, and numerous officers injured - and officials have since imposed a citywide 10:00 p.m. curfew.
View gallery
Police line up shortly after the deadline for a city-wide curfew at North Ave and Pennsylvania Ave i
Police Commissioner Anthony Batts said on Wednesday that more than 100 people had been released without being charged, because officials could not keep up with the paperwork, though he said charges would be brought later.
But public defender Marci Tarrant Johnson described the conditions endured by many of the arrestees before their release in a Facebook posting Wednesday that has since gone viral.
Johnson wrote that many had been illegally detained for more than 24 hours and that women she interviewed had taken to using slices of bread served as part of their meals as pillows.
"Interviewing these women was emotionally exhausting. Quite a few of them began crying - so happy to finally see someone who might know why they were there, or perhaps how they might get out of this Kafka-esque nightmare," she wrote.
"The cells were designed to hold people for a few hours, not a few days," she said.
Baltimore police and the state's Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services could not be immediately reached on Friday morning to comment on the allegations.
The Associated Press reported on Wednesday that one of the officers involved in Gray's arrest had been hospitalized three years ago over mental health concerns. The report could not be independently confirmed.
(Writing by Curtis Skinner; Editing by Bernadette Baum)
Baltimore
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:52:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama administration says to provide $20 million for police body cameras</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/obama-administration-says-20-million-police-body-cameras-115236274.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Obama administration says to provide $20 million for police body cameras
By Julia Edwards 1 hour ago

.
View photo
A Colorado Springs police officer poses with a Digital Ally First Vu HD body worn camera outside the
By Julia Edwards
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The Obama administration will provide $20 million in grants to local police departments to help buy body cameras for officers, the U.S. Justice Department said on Friday.
The grants represent the first portion to be approved by Congress of a $75 million, three-year body camera funding program requested in December by President Barack Obama.
Demand for the cameras, which clip onto officers' uniforms to record interactions with citizens, has risen amid a series of deadly altercations between police and unarmed black men, followed by protests in several American cities.
Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake said last week that she would launch a body-camera pilot program after a black man died from a spinal injury while in police custody.
Some critics have accused Obama of doing too little to respond to the shootings. Democratic presidential front-runner Hillary Clinton said on Wednesday that the United States should make sure every police department has body cameras.
The cameras are expensive for police departments still struggling to regain pre-recession funding levels.
Los Angeles, which plans to deploy 860 cameras this summer, will spend $1.5 million in the first year to cover equipment, maintenance and storage.
The American Civil Liberties Union has warned that body camera use must be governed by standards that protect the privacy of those being recorded.
The federal funding will match local funds and be available only to departments that already have body camera policies in place, the Justice Department said in a fact sheet.
It will match funds dedicated to buying cameras and training police on how to use them, but not for storage of the footage they capture, which can often make up the bulk of the cost.
Departments awarded the money will be part of a pilot program, overseen by the Bureau of Justice Statistics, to evaluate the impacts of body cameras.
(Reporting by Julia Edwards; Editing by Kevin Drawbaugh, Lisa Shumaker and Susan Heavey)
President Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 08:10:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>On Clinton's age, Republican rivals imply -- but never say -- she's old</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/clintons-age-republican-rivals-imply-never-shes-old-051052929.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>.
View gallery
Former U.S. Secretary of State Hillary Clinton pumps her fists in an auto shop as she campaigns for the
By James Oliphant
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Her campaign barely three weeks old, Hillary Clinton already has been attacked by Republicans on everything from donations to herfamily's charitablefoundation, to her tenureassecretary of state andherties to Wall Street. But her rivals, and the political action committees that support them, are treading more carefully on one incendiary subject: her age.
If electedinNovember 2016, Clinton would be, at 69, the second-oldest person to take the presidential oath for the first time, behind only Ronald Reagan, who turned 70 weeks after being sworn into office in 1981.
Questions of health and fitness for the presidency dogged two former candidates of a similar age, Bob Dole in the 1996 election and John McCain in 2008,each of whom was 71 at this point in the race. Time magazine featured Dole on the cover asking whether he was"too old"for the job. McCain was so determined to show that he was healthy that he often put in back-breaking campaign days.
"I do think age is an issue in a presidential campaign,"said Steve Schmidt, who was McCains campaign manager."There is a thin line between seasoned and decrepit."
But several Republican campaigns that seem best positioned to exploit itdon'twant to touch the issue - at least directly.That's a shift from just a few months ago, when presidential hopefuls Senator Rand Paul, 52, and Wisconsin Governor Scott Walker, 47, explicitly referenced Clintons age as a possible disqualifier, and Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell likened her to a cast member of the hit TV show The Golden Girls, which featured four older women living together.
"Its a rigorous physical ordeal, I think, to be able to campaign for the presidency," Paulsaid in November, referring to Clinton's age. Now, however, Paulspresidentialcampaign doesnt want to talk about the issue. It declined further comment. As did Walkers political action committee, even though last fall, he, too, noted that he could run for president "20 years from now" and be the same age Clinton is today.
Campaign aides toPaul,Walker and Senator Marco Rubio, 43, as well as Republican strategists, told Reuters there was little appetite in the party at the moment for a direct assault on Clinton on the issues of her age and fitness for office, even after a 2012 fall that gave her a concussion and caused a potentially life-threatening blood clot.
Similarly, anti-Clinton politicalaction committees such as American Crossroads, America Rising, and Citizens United said  they had no plans to launch ads centered on her age.
POLL SHOWS DEMOCRATS UNFAZED
"Its unwise to attack a political opponent based on her immutable characteristics, like race, gender and age," said Republican pollster Kellyanne Conway. She said she has met with at least five Republican presidential campaigns seeking her services and none of themhas indicated they want to go after Clinton on issues involving her age.
With Clinton swamped by questions about foreign donations to the Clinton Foundation and criticism of her use of a private email server while at the State Department, there is also simply no reason at the moment to engage in an attack that could be more divisive than beneficial, Republican strategistssaid.
They fear thathighlighting Clintons age could alienate women voters whom Republicans need to be competitive in next years general election.
View gallery
U.S. former Secretary of State, and now a Democratic presidential candidate, Hillary Rodham Clinton,
Democratic pollster Anna Greenbergsaidwomen older than 50 wouldlikelycomprise the largest bloc of voters in 2016.
There is little evidence that Democrats and independent voters are concerned about having another president in their 70s. A Reuters/Ipsos poll conducted this month showed that Clintons age would not influence how 67percentof Democrats and 72percentof independents voted in November 2016.
And rather than downplay her age, Clinton in recent campaign events in Iowa and New Hampshire embraced herrole as a grandmother, striking sympathetic notes with other older women in the roomabout the responsibility of raising a grandchild.
Supporters have also sought to dismiss any concerns about her age as sexist, noting that shes the same age as Mitt Romney when he ran four years ago. Romney largely avoided any protracted discussion about his health.

IT'S A GENERATIONAL THING
While eschewing direct attacks, some of the Republican presidential hopefuls have found other ways to strongly hint that Clinton's age should be an issue for voters. They have repackaged the issue as "generational" and suggested she is a product of the politics of the 20th Century. That argument will grow more vivid should Clinton face a candidate who could be a generation younger than her in the general election.
When you look at Hilary Clintons age, it becomes an issue in a general election if shes running against a 40-something new face as opposed to Governor Bush, said Schmidt. Jeb Bush, the former Florida governor, is 62.
Rubio, a quarter century younger than Clinton, referred to her as a"leader from yesterday"when he announced his candidacy last month.
"We welcome the contrast (with Clinton)," said a top adviser to Rubio. "This election is going to be about the future."
Clinton's campaign declined to comment on the various statements by the Republican hopefuls, referring questions to Correct the Record, a rapid-response operation run by the pro-Clinton group American Bridge. A spokeswoman, Adrienne Watson, said it was Clinton's rivals, not her, who were behind the times.
"Republican politicians are stuck in the 90s - the 1890s," Watson said. "I'm sure all Americans, Republicans included, would appreciate it if Republican leaders would join (Clinton) in talking about our future."
She saw Rubio's comments as a coded attack on Clinton's age.
"Marco Rubio basically disqualifies himself to be president when he diminishes any American for being too young or old or anything else," Watson said.
BILL CLINTON'S PLAYBOOK
Yet Rubio's approach is similar to the one employed by Clintons husband, Bill, in his reelection campaign against Dole in 1996.
"I don't think SenatorDole is too old to be president, Clinton said at one debate. It's the age of his ideas that I question."
Dick Morris, who served asBillClintons campaign manager, said it was a subtle enough way to remind voters of the age difference between the two candidates.
"We obviously couldnt attack age directly because of older voters," Morris told Reuters. "What we did is adopt a whole strategy based on issues that would summon the memories and ideas of age without articulating it."
Dole released his medical records in 1995 to assuage concerns about his age. Butthe damage control was not entirely successful: hemistakenly called the Los Angeles Dodgers baseball team Brooklyn, and he tumbled off a stage during a rally.
Hillary Clinton, too, had what her husband seemed to term a senior moment in 2008 whenshe erroneously claimed she had come under sniper fire while on a trip to Bosnia as first lady.
Bill Clinton blamed the episode on his wife being exhausted, adding that her critics, when theyre 60, theyll forget something when theyre tired at 11 at night, too.
(Editing by Ross Colvin)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Obama’s ‘My Brother’s Keeper’ initiative spins off from White House</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/obamas-my-brothers-keeper-initiative-spins-off-117803081616.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:41:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>After Baltimore, what hope for change?</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/after-baltimore-what-hope-for-change-a-protester-117801997841.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>The real story of Carly Fiorina's record as a CEO</title>
        <Link>http://finance.yahoo.com/news/carly-fiorina-s-record-at-hewlett-packard--by-the-numbers-184234108.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>.
View photo
Potential Republican presidential candidate former Hewlett-Packard CEO Carly Fiorina speaks at the Iowa Faith and Freedom Coalition's forum in Waukee, Iowa, April 25, 2015.   REUTERS/Jim Young
Two things make Carly Fiorina unique amongst the pack of wannabe Republican nominees for president. The first is that she is a woman. The second is that Fiorina was the CEO of a high-profile public company. The former is irrefutable, the latter bears looking into.
Fiorinas record when she was CEO of Hewlett-Packard ( HPQ ) then the 11th biggest company in the countryis of course highly salient if she is to be considered seriously as a candidate, especially since she cites her business experience as the key to why she should be elected. Fiorina, whos expected to announce her candidacy on May 4, points out that she doubled revenues during her time at the company and uses her HP experience to attack Hillary Clinton, saying, Im very proud of our record. We went from a market laggard to market leader. Unlike Hillary, I have actually accomplished something.

How exactly does Carly Fiorinas tenure at HPwhere she was CEO from July 1999 until she was fired in February 2005stack up? Its true that HP was flagging when Fiorina came on board. And you can find a few Carly defenders out there: Bob Knowling, who was on HP's board of directors during Fiorina's tenure recently told CNN that, "Contrary to what has been written in terms of a lot of negative things, she did what she was hired to do and that was to lead a transformation. Another person close to the company says: She certainly does not deserve all the blame, there is plenty to go around, and you could argue that no one could have saved HP from its decline from a once great company.

Much more frequently though, the informed commentary is less flattering: She was polarizing [and] disenfranchising, a top HP executive, who joined the company immediately after Fiorina left, told Yahoo Finance. She was a value destruction machine with near zero cultural sensitivity, says a top tech CEO. Carly self excused the barrage of criticism by saying it all came with her necessary role as a change agent. I guess history doesn't welcome all saviors. The [Silicon] Valley opinion was universally and viscerally negative. I literally don't know a single person who thinks she was great and unfairly treated.
HP track record

Fiorina, 60, did try to restructure HP and execute a mega-merger with Compaq, which set off a bloody proxy fight, pitting her against Walter Hewlett, son of company co-founder Bill Hewlett. She ended up laying off thousands of employees and tried to push the companys staid culture forward into the Internet era. Its neither surprising nor conclusive that a woman CEO in those circumstances would be targeted with unattributed, qualitative criticism.

The best way to judge Fiorinas tenure then, and by extension, her potential to be the chief executive of the United States, is to simply take a dispassionate look at the numbers. It comes down to a version of the old Ronald Reagan question: Was HP better off after Carly left than when she arrived? The answer is no.

The signature event, or should I say signature saga, of Fiorinas time at HP was the tortuous purchase of rival PC maker Compaq carried out in May of 2002. Thats what set off the bitter proxy battle with Walter Hewlett, which Fiorina ultimately won. The crux of the Compaq deal (spelled out in great detail in an award-winning Fortune Magazine 2005 cover story  Why Carlys Big Bet is Failing  written by Carol Loomis) is that HP issued 1.1 billion shares of stock to Compaq shareholders, which were added to HPs existing 1.9 billion shares, meaning that HP sold 37% of its assets to Compaq shareholders.

The crown jewel of HP has long been its high-margin printer business. To follow that math, before the merger the old HP shareholders owned 100% of that business. After the merger they owned 63%. Meanwhile, by buying Compaq, HP was essentially doubling down on PCs, a much lower margin business. Why would HP want to do that? Fiorina said at the time that HP needed scale in PCs, servers and storage.

After the 2002 merger the companys results suffered. Yes, Fiorina did double HPs revenues by buying Compaq, but at what cost? Lets take a look at the numbers. In 1999 when she arrived at the company, HP had $42 billion in sales and $3.1 billion in net earnings. When she left in 2005, HP had $87 billion in sales but only $2.4 billion in earnings. In subsequent years HP would become more profitableto a large degree due to cost cutting by her successor as CEO, Mark Hurdbut the company would never become the moneymaking juggernaut Fiorina promised. Why is that? To a large degree its because HP basically traded a slice of its high-margin printer business for a larger share of the lower-margin PC business. For example, in 2004, after the merger and before Fiorina left the company, HPs printer business produced $24 billion in sales and $3.8 billion in profits, while PCs produced $25 billion in sales, but only $210 million in profits.
Betting on PCs

This decision to accentuate the PC business dogs HP to this day. Yes, its market share in PCs leaped from 6% to 13% after the merger (according to Gartner data), and is up to 18% today, but the PC business is as bereft of profits as ever and even worse, over the past several years has been declining as customers switch to tablets and smartphones. (HP still has about a 40% share of the worldwide printer marketroughly where it was when Fiorina leftbut again that business is now a much smaller piece of the overall company.) Flash forward to today: HP now has $111 billion in sales and $5 billion in net income. So 16 years after Fiorina became CEO, HPs sales have grown by 164%, while earnings have climbed only 61%.

And what about the ultimate measure of a companys performance, the stock price? Initially during Fiorinas run, the stock paced ahead of the market, but shares soon fell sharply and stayed down until she was dismissed. The bottom line is that HPs stock declined some 50% during Fiorinas tenure while the overall market, as measured by the S&amp;P 500, fell 7% (according to FactSet cumulative return data).

And how about HPs cohort? How did they perform in that time frame? The answer is not as badly or much better. IBM ( IBM ) was off 27%, while archrival Dell was roughly flat. HPs chief printer competitor, Lexmark was up 30%. Apple ( AAPL ), well into the Steve Jobs renaissancehe came back to the company in July of 1997, exactly two years before Fiorina arrived at HPsaw its stock triple in those five-and-a-half years. HPs stock did have one decidedly strong spurt in the Carly era, soaring 6.9% the day after she was terminated.

Its probably true that no top executives in HPs recent history are of presidential timber. The company appears to be snake bit in the leadership department. Subsequent to Fiorinas tenure, HPs then-chairman, the late Patricia Dunn, was implicated in a pretexting scandal where reporters were spied on. The aforementioned Mark Hurd was forced out after the HP board investigated him for expense report irregularities and sexual harassment charges by an HP contractor. (In Hurds case, HPs stock fell sharply the day he was ousted.) Hurds successor, Leo Apotheker, lasted 10 months before he too was pushed aside after an ill-fated acquisition of British software company Autonomy for $11 billion. HP had to take an $8.8 billion charge related to accounting issues at the company. As for Meg Whitman who came on board in September of 2011, HPs stock has underperformed the market during her tenure. (Coincidentally, both Whitman and Fiorina ran for office as Republicans in California in 2010. Fiorina lost a bid for a Senate seat to Barbara Boxer, while Whitman lost the 2010 gubernatorial race to Jerry Brown.)

Very few businesspeople have been successful either running for president or being presidentRoss Perot in the former category, and Herbert Hoover in the latter. At this point it seems unlikely that Carly Fiorina would break either trend. Fiorina may be qualified to be president of the United States, but not based on her time running HP.
Investment &amp; Company Information
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 22:31:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Unconventional launch for unconventional candidate: Sanders 2016</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/an-unconventional-campaign-launch-for-an-117788792666.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:00:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Scant details from Gray death probe disappoint protesters</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/baltimore-officials-no-immediate-decision-gray-case-083053498.html</Link>
        <Description>BALTIMORE (AP) — The refusal of authorities to provide more than a few sketchy details about the Freddie Gray investigation may be legally appropriate, but many people in Baltimore were finding it hard to be patient Thursday when police revealed next to nothing about the criminal investigation they turned over to the state's attorney's office.</Description>
        <MainBody>Scant details from Gray death probe disappoint protesters
By DAVID DISHNEAU and CURT ANDERSON 7 hours ago

Baltimore Police: Case Turned Over to State's Attorney

Baltimore Police: Case Turned Over to State's Attorney
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Baltimore Police: Case Turned Over to State's Attorney
 Replay video
NYPD's John Miller: I've never heard of police "rough rides"

We knew there was another prisoner inside the van with Freddie Gray and tonight we hear from him. WJZ&amp;#39;s Mike Schuh is the first to speak with Donta Allen about what he heard.
Load More
BALTIMORE (AP)  The refusal of authorities to provide more than a few sketchy details about the Freddie Gray investigation may be legally appropriate, but many people in Baltimore were finding it hard to be patient Thursday when police revealed next to nothing about the criminal investigation they turned over to the state's attorney's office.
Nearly two weeks after Gray's death, the public still doesn't know much more than it did on Day One. The central question  what caused his fatal spinal cord injury  remains a mystery.
"The transparency is just not there," the Rev. Cortly "C.D." Witherspoon said after Police Commissioner Anthony Batts refused to answer any questions Thursday.
Batts said his department's report was delivered a day ahead of time to State's Attorney Marilyn Mosby, and that from now on, any questions should go to her.
Mosby also declined to talk, issuing a statement Thursday asking "for the public to remain patient and peaceful and to trust the process of the justice system."
A coalition of news media organizations, including The Associated Press, sent a letter Thursday evening to the Baltimore Police Department seeking the immediate release of the report as information that would serve the public interest.
With rumors flying about how Gray's spine was "80 percent severed," as his family's lawyer Billy Murphy put it, police did release a new piece of information Thursday, but it served mostly to raise more questions about how truthful the six suspended officers have been with investigators.
Deputy Commissioner Kevin Davis said investigators discovered a security camera recording showing that the police van carrying Gray had made a previously undisclosed, second stop, after the 25-year-old black man was put in leg irons and before the van driver made a third stop and called for help to check on his condition. The van then made a fourth stop, to pick up another passenger, before Gray arrived at the police station with the fatal spinal-cord injury that left him unresponsive.
The Associated Press talked later Thursday with grocery store owner Jung Hyun Hwang, who said officers came in last week to make a copy. Speaking in Korean, he said the only other copy had been stolen, along with his video equipment, when looters destroyed his store Monday night. He told the AP that he didn't see what the recording showed.
Police had said Gray was obviously injured and asking for medical help when he was hoisted into the van on April 12, and unresponsive on arrival at the station. He died in a hospital after a week in a coma.
View gallery
Police stand in formation as a curfew approaches for the second night in a row, Wednesday, April 29,
Then, last week, Batts said the additional passenger who was picked up along the way had told investigators the driver did not speed, make sudden stops or "drive erratically" during the trip, and that Gray was "was still moving around, that he was kicking and making noises" up until the van arrived at the police station.
Baltimore police have been less forthcoming than police in Ferguson, Missouri, after white officer Darren Wilson fatally shot a black man, 18-year-old, Michael Brown, last year in an incident officially deemed self-defense. For example, Baltimore police haven't publicly revealed the suspended officers' races or disciplinary histories.
Beyond the slim chronology, authorities have refused to discuss evidence, such as the details of his handling to statements from any of the six suspended officers. Their names are known only because the AP and other news organizations filed public records requests for the documents police filed seeking to have Gray charged with carrying a switchblade.
"I understand there are questions people want to have answered, but unfortunately, we can't release any more about it," Capt. J. Eric Kowalczyk said.
The forensic pathologists who studied Gray's body for clues also aren't making official statements.
Bruce Goldfarb, a spokesman for the Maryland State Medical Examiner's Office, told the AP on Thursday that the office has completed Gray's autopsy, but the forensic investigation is still in process and no conclusions have been sent to police or prosecutors. When the report is complete, Goldfarb said, a copy will be sent to the Baltimore State's Attorney's Office.
"The autopsy has been done, it only takes about two and a half hours," Goldfarb said. "The autopsy is only one part of the forensic investigation. The whole point is to determine cause and manner of death, and there are lab tests and lots of other things that have to be done."
Legal experts and the Gray family lawyers say secrecy is appropriate at this point in the probe, when it's still possible that some witnesses haven't been questioned, or even found.
"By releasing too many details, you run the risk that witnesses' testimony will change to mirror the details you have released," said David S. Weinstein, a former federal prosecutor now in private practice in Miami. He said investigators must verify or corroborate much of the information they receive, and meanwhile the public could be misled that the probe is leading to a particular outcome.
Investigators also face challenges with police that are different from killings by civilians. There's the question of whether an officer acted "reasonably" considering the circumstances  a common defense in use-of-force cases. And investigators can't simply force officers to give statements or lose their jobs, because that would mean their testimony is coerced, and therefore wouldn't hold up in court, Weinstein said.
"If they are compelled to give a statement as a condition of their employment, you cannot then use those statements against them in a criminal proceeding," he said. "This is where the decision to grant immunity comes into play."
The Gray family's lawyers sought to dispel the idea that the police report would be made public at this point.
"This family wants justice, and they want justice that comes at the right time and not too soon," attorney Hassan Murphy said Wednesday.
People are right to demand transparency, but the appropriate time for disclosure is either during a trial, if charges are filed, or when prosecutors announce no indictments, said Steve Levin, a former federal prosecutor in Baltimore who now works as a defense attorney.
The voracious 24-hour news cycle is another factor, especially so when civil unrest and violence are involved. Saturating the public with information prior to filing criminal charges also can make it extremely difficult to seat an impartial jury later, said Robert Jarvis, a law professor at Nova Southeastern University.
"It makes it appear that they are not doing anything, which leads to unfounded criticism and can rush law enforcement into ill-considered action," Jarvis said.
Meanwhile, protests over Gray's death are spreading and continuing. Crowds gathered Thursday in Philadelphia and Baltimore, where a curfew went into effect for the third night without any major problems. Other protests led to arrests in New York and elsewhere.
__
Contributors include Juliet Linderman and Kasey Jones in Baltimore. Anderson reported from Miami.
Baltimore
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Bai: Democrats shouldn’t congratulate themselves on gay marriage</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/democrats-shouldnt-congratulate-themselves-on-gay-117719668816.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Bernie Sanders: Progressive social media star, pragmatic legislator</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/the-bernie-sanders-record-a-progressive-social-117724393396.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 15:45:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rescuers pull survivor from rubble 5 days after Nepal quake</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/rescuers-pull-survivor-rubble-5-days-nepal-quake-063154376.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Rescuers pull survivor from rubble 5 days after Nepal quake
By Todd Pitman April 30, 2015 8:45 AM

.
.
KATHMANDU, Nepal (AP)  Crowds cheered Thursday as a teenage boy was pulled, dazed and dusty, from the wreckage of a seven-story Kathmandu building that collapsed around him five days ago when an enormous earthquake shook Nepal.
Pemba Tamang was carried out on a stretcher, his face was covered in dust. Medics had put an IV drip into his arm and a blue brace had been placed around his neck. He appeared stunned, and his eyes blinked in the sunlight.
Nepalese rescuers, with support from an American disaster response team, had been working for hours to free Tamang, who said he was 15 years old.
L.B. Basnet, one of the police officers who helped rescue Tamang, said he was surprisingly responsive.
"He thanked me when I first approached him," said Basnet. "He told me his name, his address, and I gave him some water. I assured him we were near to him."
Rescuers eventually used jacks to lift the concrete slabs that had wedged him in, said Basnet.
Raw: More Survivors Rescued in Nepal Play video
An American disaster response team had been helping the Nepalese.
"He's not too far down, but the floors have collapsed and he'd pancaked between them," Andrew Olvera, an urban search and rescue member with the U.S. Agency for International Development's Disaster Assistance Response Team, said shortly before the boy was freed.
Twisted ropes of steel reinforcing rods were all that stopped huge concrete slabs from falling onto the scene. Two concrete floors hung down in front of the building like curtains.
"The whole operation is dangerous," Olvera said. "But it's risk versus gain. To save a human life, we'll risk almost anything."
The rescue was a rare bit of good news in a city that has known little but despair since the earthquake hit Saturday, leaving more than 5,500 people dead across this poverty-wracked Himalayan nation.
Asked how Tamang had lasted for so many days, Basnet replied: "He survived by good faith."
Pemba Tamang
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 07:43:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sen. Bernie Sanders running for president</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/vermont-sen-bernie-sanders-am-running-president-000144179--election.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Vermont Sen. Bernie Sanders says he's running for president
By DAVE GRAM April 30, 2015 12:43 AM

Bernie Sanders takes on Hillary Clinton
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Bernie Sanders takes on Hillary Clinton
 Replay video
Bernie Sanders to Enter Presidential Race and More

Bernie Sanders has made it official: he&amp;#39;s running for president. The Vermont independent senator says he will seek the Democratic nomination, joining Hillary Rodham Clinton in a race in which she&amp;#39;s the heavy favorite. (April 30)
Load More
MONTPELIER, Vt. (AP)  Promising to fight what he deems "obscene levels" of income disparity and a campaign finance system that is a "real disgrace," independent Vermont Sen. Bernie Sanders said Wednesday he will run for president as a Democrat.
RELATED: Sanders: Obama sounds like Bush, Clinton on trade
In an interview with The Associated Press, Sanders confirmed his plans to formally join the race Thursday.
The self-described "democratic socialist" enters the race as a robust liberal alternative to Hillary Rodham Clinton, and he pledged to do more than simply raise progressive issues or nudge the former secretary of state to the left in a campaign in which she is heavily favored.
"People should not underestimate me," Sanders said. "I've run outside of the two-party system, defeating Democrats and Republicans, taking on big-money candidates and, you know, I think the message that has resonated in Vermont is a message that can resonate all over this country."
As he has for months in prospective campaign stops in the early voting states, and throughout his political career, the former mayor of Burlington, Vermont, on Wednesday assailed an economic system that he said has devolved over the past 40 years and eradicated the nation's middle class.
View gallery
Senator Bernie Sanders (I-VT) addresses the International Association of Firefighters delegates at I
"What we have seen is that while the average person is working longer hours for lower wages, we have seen a huge increase in income and wealth inequality, which is now reaching obscene levels," Sanders told the AP.
RELATED: Will Sanders push Clinton to the left?
"This is a rigged economy, which works for the rich and the powerful, and is not working for ordinary Americans. ... You know, this country just does not belong to a handful of billionaires."
The son of an immigrant from Poland who sold paint for a living in Brooklyn, Sanders has for decades championed working-class Americans. He lost several statewide races in the 1970s before he was elected mayor of Burlington in 1981, and went on to represent Vermont in the U.S. House for 16 years before his election to the Senate in 2006.
An independent in the Senate, he caucuses with Democrats in Washington and he is likely to attract some interest from voters who have unsuccessfully sought to draft Massachusetts Sen. Elizabeth Warren to join the race.
View gallery
Sen. Bernie Sanders, I-Vt., joined by, from left, Sen. Charles Schumer, D-N.Y., left, Rep. Steve Is
But Sanders rejected the idea his appeal is limited to voters on the left, boldly predicting Wednesday that his message would appeal to both fellow independents and Republicans.
Sanders said he would release "very specific proposals" to raise taxes on wealthy Americans and corporations, as well as offer tuition-free education at all public colleges and universities. He touched on his past opposition to free-trade agreements, his support for heavier regulations of Wall Street and the nation's banking industry, and his vote against the Keystone XL oil pipeline as a preview of his campaign.
"So to me, the question is whose views come closer to representing the vast majority of working people in this country," Sanders said. "And you know what? I think my views do."
The 73-year-old Sanders starts his campaign as an undisputed underdog against Clinton. Sanders said he has known the former first lady, senator from New York and secretary of state for more than two decades. "I respect her and like her," he said.
He noted he has "never run a negative ad in my life," but still drew a distinction with Clinton in the interview, promising to talk "very strongly about the need not to get involved in perpetual warfare in the Middle East."
View gallery
Sen. Bernie Sanders, I-Vt., left, followed by Sen. Charles Schumer, D-N.Y., arrives for a news confe
"I voted against the war in Iraq," he said. "Secretary Clinton voted for it when she was in the Senate."
Clinton is hosting a series of fundraisers this week, starting what could be an effort that raises more than $1 billion. Sanders said he will make money and politics a central theme of his campaign, including a call for a constitutional amendment to overturn the U.S. Supreme Court's 2010 Citizens United decision, which he blames for unleashing a torrent of money from wealthy donors into politics.
"What you're looking at here is a real disgrace," he said. "It is an undermining of American democracy.
"But can we raise the hundreds of millions of dollars that we need, primarily through small campaign contributions to run a strong campaign? And I have concluded that I think there is a real chance that we can do that."
Sanders is the first major challenger to enter the race against Clinton, who earlier this month became the first Democrat to formally declare her intention to run for president. He is likely to be joined in the coming months by former Maryland Gov. Martin O'Malley, former Virginia Sen. Jim Webb and ex-Rhode Island Gov. Lincoln Chafee.
___
Follow Dave Gram on Twitter at: http://twitter.com/davegramap
Bernie Sanders
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 06:22:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Protests against police violence spread across U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/marchers-protest-police-violence-baltimore-york-010038242.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Marchers protest police violence in Baltimore, New York
By Scott Malone, Ian Simpson and Warren Strobel April 29, 2015 11:22 PM

Protesters march in Manhattan demanding justice for Freddie Gray; at least a 30 arrests

Protesters march in Manhattan demanding justice for Freddie Gray; at least a 30 arrests
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Protesters march in Manhattan demanding justice for Freddie Gray; at least a 30 arrests
 Replay video
Raw: NYC Rally to Protest Death of Freddie Gray

Load More
By Scott Malone, Ian Simpson and Warren Strobel
BALTIMORE (Reuters) - Protesters marched against police violence in cities from New York to Denver on Wednesday, and a large demonstration in Baltimore ended peacefully two days after rioting over the death of a black man injured in police custody.
The protests were the latest actions against racial profiling and police use of lethal force sparked by the deaths of African-American men in Cleveland; Ferguson, Missouri; New York and elsewhere in the past year.
New York City police arrested more than 60 people as protesters roved in separate groups through Manhattan, blocking traffic in a few areas. Smaller protests occurred in Boston, Houston, Ferguson, Missouri, Washington, D.C., Seattle and a handful of demonstrators were arrested in Denver.
In Baltimore, 3,000 National Guard troops and police stood by to enforce a 10 p.m. curfew as thousands of peaceful marchers converged on city hall. The march capped a day of calm in a city that two days earlier saw its worst rioting in decades.
Protesters in the mostly black city of Baltimore sought answers about the fate of Freddie Gray, 25, who died after suffering spinal injuries while in police custody. Police are due on Friday to give their findings on Gray's death to prosecutors but said no information will be made public.
"Can't stop, won't stop, put killer cops in cell blocks," chanted protesters in the biggest march in Baltimore since Gray died on April 19, a week after his arrest and injury.
Nineteen buildings and dozens of cars burned, stores were looted and 20 officers were hurt in Baltimore on Monday in a spasm of violence hours after Gray's funeral.
View gallery
New York Police Department officers detain a protester during a march through the Manhattan borough 
"This is for everyone who died wrongly at the hands of police," said Noy Brown-Frisby, a 35-year-old hairstylist who attended Wednesday's march with her young daughter.
But she recognized that high crime in the city of 620,000 people complicates relations with the police.
"There is so much tension. The crime is so high that when there is interaction between police and the community it becomes volatile," she said.
In New York City, police on scooters used batons to try to keep protesters on sidewalks and arrested people who moved into traffic.
The demonstrations from Union Square to Times Square and elsewhere, were reminiscent of similar demonstrations in December after a grand jury decided against charges in the case of Eric Garner, an unarmed black man who died after a police officer put him in a chokehold.
NO REPORT ON FRIDAY
Many Baltimore citizens were hoping to find out the details of Gray's death on Friday when police have said they would conclude their investigation.
Raw: NYC Rally to Protest Death of Freddie Gray Play video
"The best (outcome) would be one where the officers were disciplined and officials realized what happened and owned up to their wrongdoing," said Larry Little, 22, a Baltimore resident who joined the march on Wednesday.
Gray was arrested on April 12 after fleeing from police in a high-crime area. He was carrying a switchblade knife. He died a week later.
But police said on Wednesday that information would be turned over to the state attorney's office and could not be made public because prosecutors still have to decide whether to bring charges.
The U.S. Department of Justice is conducting a separate probe into possible civil rights violations in Gray's death.
The Washington Post reported that a prisoner who was in the same van as Gray, but who could not see him, heard him banging against the walls and believed he was intentionally trying to injure himself. The newspaper cited a police document.
"SENSELESS ACTS"
With police and National Guard troops patrolling Baltimore's streets on Wednesday, schools reopened and business resumed.
Baltimore's Major League Baseball team, the Orioles, played the Chicago White Sox in an empty stadium, a sign of the tenuous security situation.
Police have arrested close to 270 people since Monday, 18 of them on Wednesday. Police Commissioner Anthony Batts said more than 100 people had been released without being charged, because officials could not keep up with the paperwork, but he said charges would be brought later.
The violence in Baltimore prompted national figures - from the new U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch to Democratic presidential hopeful Hillary Clinton - to weigh in and vow to work on improving law enforcement and criminal justice in minority communities nationwide.
Lynch, sworn in as attorney general on Monday, called Baltimore's riots "senseless acts of violence" that are counterproductive to the ultimate goal of "developing a respectful conversation within the Baltimore community and across the nation about the way our law enforcement officers interact" with residents.
The Baltimore neighborhood that saw the worst of the violence was already filled with many burned-out buildings and vacant lots that had not been rebuilt since the 1968 riots that followed the assassination of civil rights leader Martin Luther King Jr.
(Additional reporting by Sascha Brodsky in New York and Dan Whitcomb in Los Angeles; Writing by Fiona Ortiz; Editing by Grant McCool, Lisa Shumaker and Ken Wills)
BALTIMORE
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Apr 29 22:37:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baby pulled safely from under rubble in Nepal</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/baby-pulled-safely-from-under-rubble-in-nepal-193702456.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Baby pulled safely from under rubble in Nepal
By Caitlin Dickson April 29, 2015 3:37 PM
Yahoo News
.
Soldiers rescued a 4-month-old boy from rubble left by the devastating earthquake in Nepal.
Twenty-two hours after the massive earthquake that demolished buildings and killed more than 5,000 people in Nepal, a 4-month-old boy was rescued from the rubble.
RELATED: Nepal earthquake: How you can help
The boy, named Sonit Awal, was buried under the rubble of his familys house in Bhaktapur, near Kathmandu, when it collapsed during Saturdays earthquake. According to a story in local newspaper Kathmandu Today, translated by the Guardian , rescuers tried until midnight to extract the baby from bricks and other debris that had fallen on him during the quake, but were unsuccessful. The next morning, after the childs father said he heard the baby crying throughout the night, the rescue team returned, and by 10 a.m. Sunday, it finally pulled the child to safety.
Sonit Awal was alive and, the paper reported, found free of injuries after a visit to Bhaktapur hospital. Bhaktapur was one of the areas hardest hit by the earthquake that, as of Wednesday, had killed more than 5,000 people in Nepal. Several rescue teams have been deployed to the densely-packed residential community  where mostly brick-and-wood houses and apartment buildings collapsed under the pressure  and they continue to pull survivors like Sonit from the wreckage.
Related video:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>A silent day at Camden Yards as Baltimore residents struggle to be heard</title>
        <Link>http://sports.yahoo.com/blogs/mlb-big-league-stew/a-silent-day-at-camden-yards-as-baltimore-residents-struggle-to-be-heard-215849452.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>A silent day at Camden Yards as Baltimore residents struggle to be heard
By Meredith Shiner April 29, 2015 6:07 PM
Content preferences
Done
BALTIMORE With two men on, one out in the first inning, Orioles first baseman Chris Davis belted a towering three-run homer to Eutaw Street just inside of the foul pole. It was the 80th home run in the history of Camden Yards to reach the usually fan-filled avenue behind right field, the 31st by an Oriole and the sixth from Davis.
And it barely made a sound.
Because for the first time in Major League Baseball history, two teams faced each other without a single fan in attendance. The Orioles scored six in the first inning on their way to a 8-2 victory over the visiting Chicago White Sox , anchored by that Davis moonshot. But the mammoth home run and the score could ultimately prove to be a footnote to how the game was played altogether. The silence in the ball park was a strange contrast to the noise three miles away, the epicenter of days of protests by Baltimore residents, demonstrating in the wake of 25-year-old Freddie Grays death on April 19 after spinal injuries inflicted by police here more than two weeks earlier.
It made no noise. No sound. It was just quiet, said Baltimore outfielder Adam Jones , who got out on a sacrifice fly the at-bat before the Davis homer.
Jones made a pop noise to imitate the only sound he heard at the moment, a crack of Daviss bat.Its weird. Its different. The guy at the plate has the whole entire dugout behind him. Everybody watching him, behind him. Theres nobody there. But theyre there, Jones said.
[MORE: Sights and sounds from MLB's historic fan-less game in Baltimore]
It was so quiet in the press box that every reporter (and even viewers on the White Sox broadcast) heard Orioles play-by-play man Gary Thorne yell, Good-bye!
Jones said the weirdest part about Wednesdays game was hearing everything he said: During the game, youre drowned out by all the noise, but you could hear everything, literally. I told guys you got to watch what youre saying to the umpires because theyre going to hear everything in detail.
Os relief pitcher Zach Britton said the most bizarre part was hearing himself think, not just speak, perhaps a condition that plagued White Sox starting pitcher Jeff Samardzija , who lasted only five innings after giving up seven earned runs on 10 hits.
You could hear a pin drop in there  it echoes in the stadium, off the warehouse and everything, said Britton, who pitched the ninth inning in relief for the home team.
He said he thought it affected players, especially the Sox starter. Samardzijas a really good pitcher and that didnt look like him at all, Britton said.
The game lasted a mere two hours and three minutes short by MLB standardsas walk-up music was ditched for the afternoon. Music played during batting practice and between innings, and players were announced over the public address system when they stepped up to the plate.
Pre-recorded instrumentals of the Star Spangled Banner and Take Me Out to the Ballgame played at their regularly appointed times to no one.
Dozens of fans, who were outnumbered by reporters at first pitch, stuck out the game just outside the centerfield gate, where they could see most of the infield. One fan, 37-year-old public defender Brendan Hurson stood in the crowd holding a Dont forget Freddie Gray sign. Both of the letter Os in the sign were shaped like the Orioles logo.
Some fans got free Orioles hats from the few employees who worked the stadium during the game. One fan, 29-year-old Kristina Martin, who live in Baltimore and works at a restaurant here, said that at practice Tuesday, an Orioles staffer gave her one of Daviss BP home-run balls.
As for Wednesdays home-run balls  Baltimore third baseman Manny Machado also hit one  no one knew who retrieved them or when, but an Orioles communications aide said that a staffer would probably have to find them where they landed in lieu of the fans who usually take care of such tasks.
For those in Orioles nation who didnt lurk at the gate, local bars, like the Pratt Street Ale House , tried to create a home for fans looking to watch the unusual and historic game.
But players here seemed to know that there were more important things than baseball and that the team had a role to play within the community. Before Wednesdays contest, Jones said he wanted to help the city heal and emphasized that he has been talking regularly with community leaders who are actively involved with the protests here.
[MORE: Latin MLB players use Baltimore protests to tell stories of home countries ]
Orioles Manager Buck Showalter was also reflective, especially after the game played in silence, about what he wanted his team to mean to Baltimore.
I want to be a rallying force for our city and that doesnt even mean just playing good baseball, Showalter said.
Martin, the fan who watched both Tuesdays practice and Wednesdays game from outside the parameters of the stadium, said that she and other fans were there for a simple reason.
I guess we just want them to know that were here, she said.
When Showalter was asked if he could hear the fans from outside the stadium, he said, They were heard. They were heard.
Not much else was heard Wednesday at Camden Yards just the crack of balls against bats and gloves, players yelling directions at each other, reporters, whispering as if they were covering golf.
The silence was deafening, but it was quieter still knowingthat Baltimore citizens outside the park are struggling to be heard.
More MLB coverage from Yahoo Sports:
Sports &amp; Recreation
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Apr 29 21:33:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colorado theater shooting trial: Special fund helps soothe victims and family members</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/big-and-little-ways-colorado-theater-shooting-victims-are-coping-with-the-trial-150253071.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>View gallery
.
A deputy escorts theater shooting victim Josh Nowlan from the courthouse on Monday. Nearly $140,000 in grant money
CENTENNIAL, Colo.  Many clutched tear-soaked tissues. Some closed their eyes. Others covered their faces with the palms of their hands.
Those sitting in the victims section of the courtroom coped in different ways as they sat through the first day of testimony in the Colorado theater shooting trial. A therapist assisting the prosecution team recommended that victims try swabbing fragrances on their fingers to help soothe their emotions.
So they provided scented hand lotions, said Sandy Phillips, whose 24-year-old daughter, Jessica Ghawi, was killed by the accused gunman, James Holmes.
We can put the scents on our fingers and breathe in when we start to feel overwhelmed in [the] courtroom.
View gallery
Jessica Ghawi, 24, was an aspiring sports reporter. (Family photo)
Phillips appreciates the lotion, but is sticking to her own scent remedy.
I put my daughter's perfume on my index finger, she said, her voice cracking. Its my reminder of why Im here and why I have to be here.
Holmes, once a promising neuroscience graduate student, is charged with killing 12 people and injuring 70 others at an Aurora movie house in July 2012. Holmes admits he opened fire in the theater, but has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity.
Beyond the deceased or wounded, its estimated that more than 1,300 people either witnessed the events or were directly impacted by the tragedy.
Nearly half of the 100 seats in main courtroom are dedicated to victims, their families and their friends. Bob and Arlene Holmes, the accused gunmans parents, sit with 40 reporters across the aisle.
Emotions were raw Tuesday morning as Katie Medley, the prosecutions first witness, recalled the blood pouring from her husbands face at the theater and thinking that he was dead.
We thought the shooter was going to go row by row and kill us all, said Medley, who was nine months pregnant at the time.
Witness after witness took the stand Tuesday to describe their hell and heartache, making it clear that prosecutors plan to emphasize every life Holmes ended or ruined  and that tissues will be likely in high demand.
Supply shouldnt be a problem.
Not long after the attack, the Arapahoe County District Attorneys Office sought a victim assistance grant and earmarked $942 for 600 boxes of tissues to be purchased over three years. As many as 15 pastel-colored boxes of Puffs could be seen beneath the victims' chairs in the main courtroom on Tuesday. Additional seating is available in two overflow rooms and a victims waiting area.
The grant providing the tissues is among a legacy of triumphs for victims' rights in the aftermath of the Oklahoma City bombing. Congress amended the Victims of Crime Act in 2004 to better assist survivors and witnesses through the criminal justice process. An emergency reserve with $50 million is set aside annually to help communities responding to terrorist attacks and mass violence. The money is collected from federal criminal fines, forfeitures and fees collected in U.S. courts and prisons, and pays for everything from travel to therapy.
But there wasnt a tissue budget when Oklahoma City bomber Timothy McVeigh was tried in Denver 18 years ago this week.
Those first couple of weeks, I remember us going into the bathroom and pulling out rolls of toilet paper, recalls victims' advocate Krista Flannigan. We eventually did a call-out for Kleenex donations. It's emotional, so thats a necessity.
The bombing  at the time an unprecedented terrorist attack on U.S. soil  killed 168 people and wounded nearly 700 others.
Because no protocols for a mass fatality trial existed, Flannigan and others scrambled to develop plans for transportation, a closed-circuit broadcast of the proceedings, counseling, security, funding and other unique needs.
Their model has been adapted for other mass casualty trials through the years, including the Colorado theater shooting case which began at the Arapahoe County Justice Center here this week.
They've taken extremely good care of us, every one of them, said Phillips, whose daughter was an aspiring sports journalist . Theyve been helpful in lots of little ways.
View gallery
.
Prosecutor Lisa Teesch-Maguire, standing left, questions witness Derick Spruel on Tuesday while James Holmes, seated
For money related to the Holmes case, the Arapahoe County District Attorney's Office was awarded $1,576,360, the 18th Judicial District Court received $216,914, and the Arapahoe County Sheriffs Office was awarded $139,542. Any money not used will be returned to the federal emergency fund.
Yahoo News reported in February that the theater trial had already cost at least $5.5 million in public monies, most of which went to pay lawyer salaries and security expenditures, records revealed.
Through March, the district attorney had spent $758,903 of its federal money, with 90 percent going to salaries and benefits. Four full-time staffers were brought on board, including two victims advocates and an attorney.
That prosecutor, Lisa Teesch-Maguire, will play a key role if Holmes is to be found guilty and sentenced to death. She led off the states case on Tuesday by gingerly walking witnesses through their horror at the theater.
I told him that I would take care of our baby if he didnt make it, Medley told Teesch-Maguire from the witness stand.
During recesses, Teesch-Maguire could be seen checking on victims in the courtroom gallery, stopping at times to provide a comforting pat on the back.
Colorado law requires that victims  among others  be consulted about case developments, assisted in preparing to testify, and afforded the opportunity to attend all hearings if desired.
It could be 3 oclock in the morning, and if I have a question, Im supposed to call, Phillips told Yahoo News.
Beyond the salaries and operating costs are the smaller touches that Flannigan said can save a day.
View gallery
.
Lonnie and Sandy Phillips, whose daughter, Jessica Ghawi, was killed in the theater shooting, arrive for court
Because its going to stir up a lot of emotions, said Flannigan, now director of the Institute for Crime Victim Research and Policy at Florida State University. Kleenex, water, food, and just information is critical.
Nearly $5,000 was set aside to buy 5,000 bottles of water for victims, starting with initial hearings in 2012 and continuing through the end the trial. In the courts grant budget is $42,100 for anyone needing child care to be at a hearing. Nearly $140,000 awarded to the sheriffs department is being used to pay deputies to walk victims to their cars and other areas of the courthouse.
An estimated 75 victims, including Phillips and her husband, live outside of Colorado. Each is receiving 10 days of hotel, transportation, and per-diem expenses for the trial, and three days if there is a sentencing phase.
Any little bit helps, said Phillips, who will stay with her husband in their RV for the remainder of the five-month trial once their hotel days run out next month.
Each morning before court and throughout the day, the district attorneys' advocates meet privately with the Aurora victims who may have questions and to give them an idea of whats ahead.
The gatherings follow the blueprint born from the Oklahoma City trial.
It turns into an emotional debriefing because maybe there was something said or done that was particularly upsetting, Flannigan said. And it might not even be the trial itself; it could just be something that happens in the courtroom.
Jason Sickles is a reporter for Yahoo News. Follow him on Twitter ( @jasonsickles ).
Society &amp; Culture
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Sanders: Obama sounds like Bush, Clinton on trade</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/bernie-sanders-obama-sounds-like-bush-and-clinton-117717922196.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>America’s pastime gives silence a try in Baltimore</title>
        <Link>http://sports.yahoo.com/blogs/mlb-big-league-stew/america-s-pastime-gives-silence-a-try-in-baltimore-190911636.html</Link>
        <Description>The Orioles take drastic step after rioting follows funeral of man who died in Baltimore police custody.</Description>
        <MainBody>Americas pastime gives silence a try in Baltimore
By Meredith Shiner April 29, 2015 3:11 PM
Content preferences
Done
BALTIMORE If you ever wanted to know what a baseball sounds like hitting the back of a catchers mitt  like really wanted to know the full crack of leather colliding with leather at 87 miles per hour  then there was no better place to be than Camden Yards on Wednesday at 2:03 p.m., when Orioles righty Ubaldo Jimenez threw the first pitch of a historic fan-less MLB game.
The Orioles decided to move Wednesdays previously scheduled night game to the afternoon and play in front of no fans in response to widespread protests that have consumed Baltimore for days. No one wanted to hear the crack of the ball or bat like this, and yet a packed press box and a few dozen fans lining up just outside of the centerfield concourse gate, where they could peer onto the field, did. And it was eerie.
Moments earlier, as is tradition in baseball, "The Star-Spangled Banner" blared over the public address system on an otherwise beautiful 73-degree day in Baltimore. The PA announcer asked for Ladies and gentleman to please rise, yet approximately 45,000 seats were empty, with no one there to stand. Seven Orioles players stood on the dirt near second base, looking at the flag, just past them, the few Os fans who dutifully shouted Os! at the line, Oh, say can you see.
[MORE: Latin MLB players use Baltimore protests to tell stories of home countries ]
In the press box, the only full place in the house, it was so quiet you could hear incessant typing of reporters at keyboards. Players were still announced over the PA and music played before the game and between innings, even if typical fan-favorites felt discordant with the day ( Eddie Murphys Party All The Time was about as weird as the quiet itself).
The White Sox went down 1-2-3 in the top of the first, but the Orioles would go on a tear to close the inning, notching six runs, including a three-run home run from first baseman Chris Davis, who smashed the ball toward the towering warehouses in right field. Ordinarily, a crowd would go wild as soon as they heard the crack of the bat. On Wednesday, you could hear the radio announcers making their call.
No fans or press were allowed on the concourse, so its unclear what exactly happened to Daviss moonshot once it cleared the fence, but a single security employee could be seen roaming the outfield concourse after the hit. The Orioles eventually cruised to an 8-2 victory .
Before the game kicked off, Orioles manager Buck Showalter huddled with the umpires for the afternoon. Umpires feelings or maybe just their heightened ability to hear everything were a joking concern of the skippers in a pregame press conference hours earlier.
I guess Ill have to be careful whispering sweet nothings to the umpire from the dugout, he said.
More MLB coverage from Yahoo Sports:

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Supreme Court gay marriage arguments: What the justices revealed</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/the-supreme-court-gay-marriage-arguments-what-the-117695904751.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
