<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Yahoo">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:30:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vermont's Sanders kicks off 2016 bid</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/vermonts-sanders-kick-off-2016-bid-clintons-left-071146030--election.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Vermont's Sanders kicks off 2016 bid from Clinton's left
By DAVE GRAM and KEN THOMAS 1 hour ago

Vermont's Sanders Kicks Off Presidential Bid

Vermont's Sanders Kicks Off Presidential Bid
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Vermont's Sanders Kicks Off Presidential Bid
 Replay video
Bernie Sanders on 2016: 'Don't Underestimate Me'

Stocks took a big hit on Tuesday, weighed down by concerns about Greece&amp;#39;s financal crisis and upbeat economic data that raised concerns about a rise in interest rates. Bobbi Rebell reports.
Load More
BURLINGTON, Vt. (AP)  Challenging Hillary Rodham Clinton from the left, Vermont Sen. Bernie Sanders kicked off his presidential bid Tuesday with a pitch to liberals to join him in a "political revolution" to transform the nation's economy and politics.
Sanders, who entered the Democratic race in late April, formally opened his White House campaign in Burlington, where he was first elected mayor by defeating a longtime Democratic incumbent by 10 votes. Three decades later, Sanders is the underdog again, vowing to campaign on an agenda to elevate issues like income inequality, campaign finance and climate change.
"With your support and the support of millions of people throughout this country, we begin a political revolution to transform our country economically, politically, socially and environmentally," Sanders declared to about 5,000 supporters along the shore of Lake Champlain.
"Now is not the time for thinking small," he said. "Now is not the time for the same old-same old establishment politics and stale inside-the-Beltway ideas."
A self-described "democratic socialist," the 73-year-old Sanders has a following among liberals that could push Clinton to the left. In a lengthy address, the white-haired senator said there is "something profoundly wrong" when so much of the nation's income goes to the top 1 percent of all earners.
"This grotesque level of inequality is immoral," he said. "It is bad economics. It is unsustainable."
Bernie Sanders on 2016: 'Don't Underestima Play video
His campaign kickoff in Burlington's Waterfront Park, built on industrial land reclaimed during Sanders' stint as mayor, offered a quintessential Vermont backdrop: a sun-splashed Lake Champlain, where boaters took in the scene from sailboats and motorboats.
The senator was praised by a lineup of supporters, including the founders of Vermont's popular ice cream company, Ben &amp; Jerry's, and environmental activist Bill McKibben, who predicted the campaign might someday lead to a mountaintop named "Mount Sanders."
Several leading Vermont Democrats were notably absent, including Sen. Patrick Leahy, Gov. Peter Shumlin and former Gov. Howard Dean, all of whom are supporting Clinton.
Liberals, some of whom are wary of Clinton, have unsuccessfully sought to draw Massachusetts Sen. Elizabeth Warren into the race. But in Warren's absence, Sanders hopes to fill the void as he proposes ways to rein in Wall Street banks, tackle mounting college debt and create a government-financed jobs program.
Clinton is in a commanding position by any measure, far in front of both Sanders and former Maryland Gov. Martin O'Malley, who is expected to get into the race Saturday. The Democratic field could also grow to include former Virginia Sen. Jim Webb and former Rhode Island Gov. Lincoln Chafee.
View gallery
Sen. Bernie Sanders, I-Vt., speaks on Tuesday, May 26, 2015 in Burlington, Vt., where he formally an
But it remains to be seen if liberals will coalesce around a challenger to the former secretary of state or if that slice of the anti-Clinton electorate will splinter among several candidates.
Sanders, an independent in the Senate who often votes with the Democrats, has raised more than $4 million since announcing his campaign in late April and suggested in an interview with The Associated Press last week that raising $50 million for the primaries was a possibility.
In his address, Sanders made clear he would seek to be on the forefront of liberal causes. He described the economic system as "rigged" against middle-class families and vowed to raise taxes on the wealthy and corporations and to oppose trade deals that would ship jobs overseas. To counter big money in politics, he said he would push for the public financing of elections.
To build upon President Barack Obama's health care law, Sanders supports a single-payer health care system. Instead of cutting Social Security, he said, the nation should expand Social Security benefits. To address climate change, he said, Congress should pass a carbon tax to help transition off fossil fuels.
He noted that he voted against the invasion of Iraq in 2003  Clinton has disavowed her vote in support of it  and said the U.S. should be part of an international coalition to defeat the Islamic State group.
View gallery
Sen. Bernie Sanders, I-Vt., speaks on Tuesday, May 26, 2015 in Burlington, Vt., where he formally an
Sanders has introduced legislation to make tuition free at public colleges and universities, a major piece of Warren's agenda. Clinton's campaign has signaled that she intends to make debt-free college a major piece of her campaign, too.
Richard Robinson, a Burlington retiree who attended the rally, said it was important for Sanders to be in the race, "just to get the power in the party to listen to him  particularly Hillary."
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:47:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Floodwaters deepen in Houston after city gets more rain</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/12-missing-flooding-texas-sweeps-away-vacation-home-073741185.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Floodwaters deepen in Houston after city gets more rain
By KRISTIE RIEKEN and PAUL J. WEBER 4 minutes ago

Done
KTRK  Houston
Death toll in Houston's historic flooding up to 4; disaster declaration for Harris County to be issued

Death toll in Houston's historic flooding up to 4; disaster declaration for Harris County to be issued
Now watching

Next video starts in : 7 Play
Death toll in Houston's historic flooding up to 4; disaster declaration for Harris County to be issued
 Replay video
Vermont's Sanders Kicks Off Presidential Bid

Juan Pablo Montoya held off Penske Racing teammate Will Power over the final two laps Sunday to win his second Indianapolis 500. Afterward, he celebrated on a pedal bike. (May 26)
Load More
HOUSTON (AP)  Floodwaters deepened across much of Texas on Tuesday as storms dumped almost another foot of rain on the Houston area, stranding hundreds of motorists and inundating the famously congested highways that serve the nation's fourth-largest city.
Meanwhile, the search went on for at least 13 people who were still missing, including a group that disappeared after a vacation home was swept down a river and slammed into a bridge.
Several more fatalities were reported  four in Houston and one more in Central Texas. That brought to 14 the number of people killed by the holiday weekend storms in Texas and Oklahoma.
Similar search efforts unfolded just south of the Texas-Mexico border, where crews tried to track down the missing and assessed damage in the city of Ciudad Acuna after a tornado killed 13 people Monday.
In Houston, the water rose sharply overnight as about 11 more inches of rain fell, much of it in a six-hour period. By Tuesday evening, most rivers had receded back within their banks.
The floodwaters affected virtually every part of the city and paralyzed some areas. Firefighters carried out more than 500 water rescues, most involving stranded motorists. At least 2,500 vehicles were abandoned by drivers seeking higher ground, officials said.
"Given the magnitude and how quickly it happened, in such a short period of time, I've never seen this before," said Rick Flanagan, Houston's emergency management coordinator.
View gallery
Gabby Aviles carries her daughter Audrey through floodwaters outside their apartment in Houston, Tue
The drenching weather threatened to linger. Forecasts called for a 20 to 40 percent chance of thunderstorms through the rest of the week in Houston.
The flooding closed several highways, and the ones that stayed open became a gridlocked mess.
Interstate 45 near downtown was backed up for miles on Tuesday morning, and a handful of motorists traveled the wrong way on the highway to retreat from high water.
The small cars weaved between massive 18-wheelers as other drivers stared at them in disbelief. With no end to the backup in sight, some drivers got off the freeway, only to be held up again by water covering nearby access roads.
In the Heights neighborhood about 5 miles from downtown, groups of people roamed the streets after escaping their stalled cars, and police cruisers blocked some dangerous roads.
Some motorists were stuck on I-45 all night, sleeping in their cars until the backup was cleared about 8 a.m.
View gallery
Rescue personnel grab the the hand of a man stranded in rushing water at the northwest corner of Lam
NBA fans at the Toyota Center, where the Rockets hosted a Western Conference finals game against Golden State on Monday, were asked with about two minutes left in the game not to leave the arena because of the weather.
The game ended before 11 p.m., but about 400 people remained in their seats at 1:30 a.m., choosing to stay in the building rather than brave the flooded roads that awaited them outside. Up to 150 people stayed all right, according to arena officials.
A spokeswoman for the flood district of Harris County, which includes Houston, said up to 700 homes sustained some level of damage.
Yesenia Lopez and husband, Armando, waded through knee-deep water, carrying bags of possessions over their heads. During the night, a nearby bayou overflowed and flooded their apartment complex.
"We tried to do as much as we could, saved the family portraits and stuff like that, but everything else is destroyed," she said.
The two planned to stay with her mother-in-law.
View gallery
Hudson Doty, 18, left, and Grant Guzal, 17, right, walk along the bank of the Blanco River near the 
Dripping with water, she said: "Everything is scary. That's the first time I lived through something like this, so it gives you a lot to think about."
Officials in Hays County, about 180 miles west of Houston, said 30 people who had been reported as missing were accounted for by mid-afternoon Tuesday.
Some of the worst flooding in Texas was in Wimberley, a popular tourist town along the Blanco in the corridor between Austin and San Antonio. That's where the vacation home was swept away.
The "search component" of the mission ended Monday night, meaning no more survivors were expected to be found, said Trey Hatt, a spokesman for the Hays County Emergency Operations Center.
Eight of those missing from the destroyed house were friends and family who had gathered for the holiday, said Kristi Wyatt, a spokeswoman for the City of San Marcos. She said three more were members of another family in a separate situation. An unrelated person was also missing, Wyatt said.
Young children were believed to be among the missing.
The Blanco crested above 40 feet  more than triple its flood stage of 13 feet. The river swamped Interstate 35 and closed parts of the busy north-south highway. Rescuers used pontoon boats and a helicopter to pull people out.
Hundreds of trees along the Blanco were uprooted or snapped, and they collected in piles of debris up to 20 feet high.
The deaths in Texas included a man whose body was pulled from the Blanco; a 14-year-old who was found with his dog in a storm drain; a high school senior who died after her car was caught in high water; and a man whose mobile home was destroyed by a reported tornado.
The Oklahoma Department of Emergency Management also reported four fatalities between Saturday and Monday after severe flooding and reports of tornadoes.
In Ciudad Acuna, Mayor Evaristo Perez Rivera said 300 people were treated at local hospitals after the twister, and more than 200 homes had been completely destroyed in the city of 125,000 across from Del Rio, Texas.
Thirteen people were confirmed dead  10 adults and three infants, including one that was ripped from its mother's arms by the storm.
___
Associated Press writers David Warren and Jamie Stengle in Dallas and photographer David J. Phillip in Houston contributed to this report.
Houston
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>What would White House be like without a dog?</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/a-white-house-without-dogs-an-alternate-history-119860333936.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:54:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cleveland, Justice Department announce police settlement</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/ap-source-cleveland-justice-department-reach-policing-deal-044830721.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Cleveland, Justice Department announce police settlement
By MARK GILLISPIE 57 minutes ago

DOJ, Cleveland Reach Settlement on Police Force

DOJ, Cleveland Reach Settlement on Police Force
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
DOJ, Cleveland Reach Settlement on Police Force
 Replay video
Now I Get It: America's crumbling infrastructure

Stocks took a big hit on Tuesday, weighed down by concerns about Greece&amp;#39;s financal crisis and upbeat economic data that raised concerns about a rise in interest rates. Bobbi Rebell reports.
Load More
CLEVELAND (AP)  Cleveland agreed to sweeping changes in how its police officers use force, treat the community and deal with the mentally ill, under a settlement announced Tuesday with the federal government that will put the 1,500-member department under an independent monitor.
The settlement was made public three days after a white Cleveland patrolman was acquitted of manslaughter for his role in a 137-shot barrage of police gunfire that left two unarmed black suspects dead in a car in 2012.
Mayor Frank Jackson said the ambitious plan that was worked out over five months of negotiations with the U.S. Justice Department will be expensive and will take years to put in place. But he said he sees it as a chance to set an example for other cities.
The proposed reforms come amid tension around the U.S. over a string of cases in which blacks died at the hands of police.
"As we move forward, it is my strong belief that as other cities across this country address and look at their police issues in their communities, they will be able to say, 'Let's look at Cleveland because Cleveland has done it right,'" Jackson said.
In December, after an 18-month investigation prompted in part by the 2012 shooting, the Justice Department issued a scathing report accusing Cleveland police of a pattern of excessive force and other abuses.
View gallery
Protesters congregate in front of city hall Tuesday, May 26, 2015, in Cleveland. Members of about 40
The settlement is an expansive list of items aimed at easing tensions between the police and the city's residents, especially in the black community. Cleveland is 53 percent black. About two-thirds of its police officers are white. The mayor and the police chief are black.
The reforms were outlined in a 105-page consent decree filed in federal court. It calls for new guidelines and training in the use of force; a switch to community policing, in which officers work closely with their neighborhoods; an overhaul of the machinery for investigating misconduct allegations; modernization of police computer technology; and new training in avoiding racial stereotyping and dealing with the mentally ill.
An independent monitor approved by the court will oversee the police force's compliance. Several other police departments around the country, including those in Seattle and New Orleans, are operating under federal consent decrees that involve independent oversight.
The worst examples of excessive force in the Justice Department report involved officers who endangered lives by shooting at suspects and cars, hit people over the head with guns and used stun guns on handcuffed suspects. Only six officers had been suspended for improper use of force over a three-year period.
The city is still awaiting a decision on whether any officers will be prosecuted in two other deaths: that of Tamir Rice, a 12-year-old black boy who was killed by a white rookie patrolman last November while playing with what turned out to be a pellet gun, and that of 37-year-old Tanisha Anderson, a mentally ill woman who suffocated last fall after she was subdued on the ground and handcuffed.
View gallery
Riot police stand in formation as a protest forms against the acquittal of Michael Brelo, a patrolma
U.S. Attorney Steven M. Dettelbach said that the overhaul "will help ensure the many brave men and women of the Cleveland Division of Police can do their jobs not only constitutionally, but also more safely and effectively."
Steve Loomis, president of the Cleveland Police Patrolmen's Association, said he and the union's attorneys are still studying the agreement.
"I'm hopeful it has reached some good conclusions," Loomis said. "But the devil is always in the details for these kinds of things."
Attorney James Hardiman, chairman of the NAACP Criminal Justice Committee, said his organization is looking at the agreement "with a fine-tooth comb," but added: "If I can assume everything I was told is true, it sounds like a pretty comprehensive agreement."
The mayor said that when the reforms take hold, community policing will become "part of our DNA."
The Justice Department has launched broad investigations into the practices of more than 20 police forces in the past five years, including agencies in Ferguson, Missouri, and, most recently, in Baltimore. Both cities were convulsed by violence and protests in recent months over the police-involved deaths of black men.
Then-Attorney General Eric Holder said in December that the Justice Department was enforcing settlement agreements with roughly 15 police departments, including eight consent decrees.
Saturday's verdict by a judge in favor of Patrolman Michael Brelo led to a day of mostly peaceful protests but also more than 70 arrests. Dozens of church parishioners also protested the acquittal in a downtown march Tuesday afternoon just before officials announced the settlement.
Cleveland has paid a total of $3 million to the families of the victims in the 2012 shooting, Timothy Russell and Malissa Williams. They were gunned down at the end of a 22-mile car chase that began when police mistook automobile backfire for gunshots.
Thirteen officers in all shot at the car; Brelo jumped onto the hood and fired the last 15 shots through the windshield
Justice Department
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:42:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Appeals panel won't lift hold on Obama immigration action</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/court-wont-lift-hold-obama-immigration-action-181959035.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Appeals panel won't lift hold on Obama immigration action
By KEVIN McGILL and JUAN A. LOZANO 2 hours ago

Obama Loses Bid to Implement Immigration Orders

Obama Loses Bid to Implement Immigration Orders
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Obama Loses Bid to Implement Immigration Orders
 Replay video
Hes In: Bernie Sanders Officially Launches 2016 Bid

May 26 -- Alex Gauna, an analyst at JMP Securities, and David Kirkpatrick, a contributing editor for Bloomberg, discuss Snapchat CEO Evan Spiegel&amp;#39;s reputation and the company&amp;#39;s growth prospects. They speak with Bloomberg&amp;#39;s Emily Chang on &amp;quot;Bloomberg West.&amp;quot;
Load More
NEW ORLEANS (AP)  President Barack Obama's plan to shield as many as 5 million immigrants living in the U.S. from deportation remained on hold Tuesday after a federal appeals court panel refused to allow it to take effect immediately.
Obama announced an executive action in November seeking to expand a program that protects young immigrants from deportation if they were brought to the U.S. illegally as children. The order also would extend deportation protections to some parents of U.S. citizens and permanent residents.
Although Obama argued lack of action by Congress forced him to make sweeping changes on his own, Republicans blasted the plan as an executive overreach. Twenty-six states have sued to stop it, and a federal judge based in Texas issued a preliminary injunction against it in February.
The administration is appealing that injunction and had asked a three-judge panel of the 5th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals to let the program proceed pending an argument on the merits, tentatively set for July.
But, in refusing to stay the Texas judge's injunction, 5th Circuit judges Jerry Smith and Jennifer Walker Elrod said that the federal government lawyers are unlikely to succeed on the merits of the appeal. Judge Stephen Higginson disagreed in a lengthy dissent.
Immigrant advocates decried the continued roadblock. And, White House spokeswoman Brandi Hoffine said the two-judge majority in Tuesday's ruling "chose to misinterpret the facts and the law."
View gallery
In this May 5, 2015, photo, President Barack Obama speaks during a Cinco de Mayo reception in the Ea
U.S. District Judge Andrew Hanen sided with the states and, from his court in Brownsville, Texas, issued a temporary injunction on Feb. 16 to block the plan from taking effect while the lawsuit works its way through the courts.
In denying a stay, Smith and Elrod rejected the government's argument that it has such broad discretion to defer legal action against immigrants absent judicial review. The Obama policy, the ruling said, goes beyond simple non-enforcement. "It is the affirmative act of conferring 'lawful presence' on a class of unlawfully present aliens," Smith wrote.
Higginson noted congressional inaction on the issue in his dissent and said the administration was acting within its authority.
Smith and Walker were nominated to the court by Republican presidents, Ronald Reagan and George W. Bush; Higginson, by Obama.
The White House said its appeal of the preliminary injunction will proceed on an expedited basis in the 5th Circuit while the Justice Department reviews Tuesday's opinion and contemplates other possible steps.
View gallery
Irania Sanchez, foreground, who is originally from Nicaragua and currently lives in Brooklyn, chants
"This decision is a victory for those committed to preserving the rule of law in America," Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton said in a statement.
Marielena Hincapie, executive director of the National Immigration Law Center, said the decision will result in confusion and fear in immigrant communities. But she predicted eventual victory in the courts.
The first of Obama's orders  to expand a program that protects young immigrants from deportation if they were brought to the U.S. illegally as children  was set to take effect Feb. 18. The other major part, extending deportation protections to parents of U.S. citizens and permanent residents who have been in the country for some years, had been scheduled to begin May 19.
Hanen issued his injunction believing that neither action had taken effect. But the Justice Department later told Hanen that more than 108,000 people had already received three-year reprieves from deportation as well as work permits. Hanen said the federal government had been "misleading," but he declined to sanction the government's attorneys. Earlier this month, the U.S. government told Hanen it had mistakenly awarded three-year work permits to another 2,000 people.
Along with Texas, the states seeking to block Obama's action are Alabama, Arizona, Arkansas, Florida, Georgia, Idaho, Indiana, Kansas, Louisiana, Maine, Michigan, Mississippi, Montana, Nebraska, Nevada, North Carolina, North Dakota, Ohio, Oklahoma, South Carolina, South Dakota, Tennessee, Utah, West Virginia and Wisconsin.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:25:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Storms kill 16 in Texas, Oklahoma; Houston flooded</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/storms-kill-16-texas-oklahoma-houston-flooded-002512061.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Storms kill 16 in Texas, Oklahoma; Houston flooded
By Kristen Hays and Amanda Orr 28 minutes ago

.
View gallery
An American flag, a remnant of Memorial Day holiday one day earlier, waves despite being caught in a
By Kristen Hays and Amanda Orr
HOUSTON (Reuters) - Torrential rains have killed at least 16 people in Texas and Oklahoma, including four in Houston where floods turned streets into rivers and led to about 1,000 calls for help in the fourth-most populous U.S. city, officials said on Tuesday.
The death toll is set to rise with numerous people still missing in Texas after the storms slammed the states during the Memorial Day weekend, causing record floods that destroyed hundreds of homes, swept away bridges, and even unearthed a coffin from a Houston cemetery. It washed ashore on the banks of a bayou.
"A lot of folks drove their car into high water and had to abandon those vehicles," Mayor Annise Parker said at a news conference.
Two of the dead in Houston were found in their cars and another two were found in a bayou. One was likely to be a male victim lost when an evacuation boat capsized during a water rescue by emergency crews in the morning.
The Oklahoma Medical Examiner's office said six people have died in weather-related incidents over the holiday weekend in the state.
View gallery
Larry Bowls surveys the flood damage to his friend's neighborhood in San Marcos, Texas May 26, 2
Though Parker said parts of the city were unscathed, more than 1,000 vehicles were submerged in the Houston floods and people took instead to bicycles, kayaks and surfboards to navigate water-covered streets.
The Houston Fire Department brought about 500 people to safety in boats, local media reports said.
President Barack Obama said on Tuesday he had assured Texas Governor Greg Abbott that he could count on help from the federal government as the state recovers from the floods.    Abbott has declared a state of disaster in at least 40 Texas counties, including Harris County, home to Houston.
Abbott said he has deployed the state's National Guard and was worried the death toll could rise.
"It's devastating to see what I saw on the Blanco River when this tidal wave of water just swept away neighborhoods," he said, recalling a disaster area in central Texas.
View gallery
DerryAnn Krupinsky (3rd L) coordinates where to send crews of volunteers helping with flood relief e
Twelve people are confirmed missing and about another 30 are unaccounted for due to flooding that hit along the Blanco River, county officials said. The missing were from two families whose vacation home was swept off its foundation in Wimberley, a town about 30 miles (50 km) southwest of Austin.
Search dogs and boats were being used to search for the missing. The river rose so quickly and with such force, it caused a flood gauge to break, Hays County officials said.
There was no damage estimate available for the state, which has a $1.4 trillion-a-year economy and is the country's main domestic source of energy as well as an agricultural and manufacturing power.
Houston resident Dutch Small, 40, climbed onto the roof of his car when the water came up to his knees inside his vehicle and was eventually rescued by a passing tow truck driver.
"It happened so fast. Every person that died in the flooding, I know what was going through their minds. They didn't measure the threat accurately. They were like me," Small told Reuters.
View gallery
Bill Taylor helps clean and remove debris from the interior of a friend's flood damaged home in 
The National Weather Service issued tornado and thunderstorm watches for later on Tuesday and said more rain is expected this week in Texas and Oklahoma.
More than 200 flights had been canceled by early on Tuesday evening at airports in Houston and Dallas, some of the nation's busiest, as blocked roads made it difficult for workers to get to their jobs. A sinkhole also closed a runway at the Dallas/Fort Worth International airport.
Roughly 100,000 customers lost power throughout the state after the storm due to high winds and rising waters that caused power poles to snap.
In Houston, about 11 inches (28 cm) of rainwater fell on Monday while parts of Austin were hit by as much as 7 inches (18 cm). Helicopter crews in both cities plucked people to safety who had been stranded in cars and on top of buildings.
(Writing by Jon Herskovitz; Additional reporting by Terry Wade and Amanda Orr in Houston, Jim Forsyth in San Antonio, Lisa Maria Garza in Dallas, Suzannah Gonzales in Chicago, Scott DiSavino in New York, and Eric M. Johnson in Seattle; Editing by Bill Trott and Sandra Maler)
Houston
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:09:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Data thieves gain access to 100,000 U.S. taxpayers' information: IRS</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/irs-commissioner-tax-return-information-illegally-accessed-204145370--business.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>View photo
United States Internal Revenue Service Commissioner John Koskinen appears before a House Oversight and
(Reuters) - Tax return information for about 100,000 U.S. taxpayers was illegally accessed by cyber criminals over the past four months, U.S. IRS Commissioner John Koskinen said on Tuesday, the latest in a series of data thefts that have alarmed American consumers.
From February to May, attackers sought to gain access to personal tax information 200,000 times through the agency's "Get Transcript" online application, which calls up information from previous returns, he told a news conference. About half of those attempts were successful.
The breach did not affect any IRS data outside the "Get Transcript" application, and the agency said it would  strengthen its security measures.
Koskinen said he could not comment on who the attackers might be, and a criminal investigation was ongoing.
"We're confident these are not amateurs. These are actually organized crime syndicates that not only we but everyone in the financial industry are dealing with," Koskinen said.
The data theft was largely intended to steal taxpayers' information to submit fraudulent returns next year, he said.
The agency currently believes that fewer than 15,000 fraudulent returns were processed as a result of the breach, likely resulting in refunds of less than $50 million.
The IRS security problem is the latest in a string of breaches. JPMorgan Chase as well as mega-retailers Target  and Home Depot have all suffered cyber attacks.
The IRS data theft differs in that it did not involve a computer hack. Criminals used information they had gathered about individuals to access the system as it was designed to be used, the IRS said.
The agency, which will begin to send notification letters to affected taxpayers this week, will provide free credit monitoring and protection for the victims.
Koskinen said the attackers must have had a significant amount of information already about the taxpayers.
In addition to names, addresses and Social Security numbers, the attackers would have needed so-called "out of wallet" data, personal information such as a person's first car or high school mascot, he said.
Koskinen said it was possible that identity thieves could get answers to these questions from individuals' social media accounts and compile them into searchable databases.
Koskinen said the tax agency was originally alerted to the problem by unusual activity in mid-April, which marks the end of the annual tax-filing season.
(Reporting by Brendan Pierson in New York; Editing by Sandra Maler, Richard Cowan, Mohammad Zargham and Cynthia Osterman)
John Koskinen
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:44:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colorado movie gunman wrote of 'obsession to kill' since childhood</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/colorado-movie-gunman-wrote-obsession-kill-since-childhood-234432987.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Colorado movie gunman wrote of 'obsession to kill' since childhood
By Keith Coffman 1 hour ago

James Eagan Holmes makes his first court appearance in Aurora, Colorado, July 23, 2012.   REUTERS/RJ
By Keith Coffman
CENTENNIAL, Colo.,  (Reuters) - Colorado cinema gunman James Holmes wrote in a notebook he sent to his psychiatrist prior to opening fire in a suburban theater that he had harbored an "obsession to kill" since childhood, a police officer testified at his murder trial on Tuesday.
Holmes mailed a package to the psychiatrist that included the notebook a day before he opened fire inside a cinema in the Denver suburb of Aurora during a screening of the Batman film "The Dark Knight Rises."
Prosecutors have said they will seek the death penalty for Holmes if he is convicted of killing 12 moviegoers and wounding 70 others in the July 2012 rampage.
The 27-year-old former neuroscience graduate student has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity to multiple counts of first-degree murder, attempted murder and explosive charges.
The existence of the notebook has been known since days after the attack, and was referenced by attorneys for both sides in their opening statements, but details about its contents emerged for the first time on Tuesday.
Aurora Police Sergeant Matthew Fyles read aloud excerpts from the 29-page notebook, in which Holmes allegedly wrote: "The obsession to kill since I was a kid, with age became more realistic."
Fyles said that Holmes wrote in another entry that he had thought about multiple ways to kill, including with nuclear weapons and biological warfare. He ultimately decided on a "mass murder spree" at the theater.
Defense lawyers have said Holmes suffers from schizophrenia and was not in control of his actions when he planned the attack and opened fire in the packed theater with a semiautomatic rifle, a .40 caliber pistol and a pump-action 12-gauge shotgun.
Public defender Daniel King went over other entries in the journal with Fyles during his cross-examination, including portions in which Holmes wrote about pulling his hair out when he was in high school, leaving a bald spot in the back of his head, and his diagnosis for depression.
Other entries cited in the journal included biblical and mythological references and other ramblings with one that read, "Bambi get up, you must get up."
(Editing by Cynthia Johnston and Sandra Maler)
James Holmes
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue May 26 15:36:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Joint Chiefs Chairman says U.S. blindsided by fall of Mosul</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/joint-chiefs-chairman-says-u-s--blindsided-by-fall-of-mosul-123627706.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Joint Chiefs Chairman says U.S. blindsided by fall of Mosul
Gen. Martin Dempsey admits in new documentary that Pentagon did no contingency planning for Islamic State advance
By Michael Isikoff 12 hours ago
Yahoo News
Content preferences
Done
Outgoing JointChiefs of Staff Chairman Gen. Martin Dempsey admits in a new interview that the U.S. military had done no contingency planning to prepare for the fall of Mosul when Islamic terrorists swept into Iraqs second-largest city last June and seized control.
Well, no, there were not, Dempsey replies in the interview with Frontlines Martin Smith when asked if there were any contingency plans inside the Pentagon for how to respond if Mosul were to fall to terrorists from the Islamic State (or ISIL, as the group is sometimes called.)
So, look, there were several things that surprised us about ISIL, Dempsey adds. The degree to which they were able to form their own coalition, both inside of Syria  and inside of northwestern Iraq; the military capability that they exhibited  the collapse of the Iraq Security Forces. Yeah, in those initial days, there were a few surprises.
Dempseys frank comments would appear to raise fresh questions about the performance of U.S. intelligence agencies in tracking the rise of IS as well the state of planning inside the Obama administration as it continues to grapple with a war against the Islamic State terrorists.
John Maguire, a former senior CIA officer in Iraq, called Dempseys remarks stunning and described his admission of the failure to do any planning as comparable to the intelligence failures prior to the Sept. 11 terror attacks. He noted that Islamic State terrorists had been on the march inside Iraq for months before Mosul was attacked and that IS had already seized huge swaths of territory, including the city of Fallajuh, the previous January.
Good lord, he should resign, Maguire told Yahoo News, when read a transcript of Dempseys comments for the Frontline show, Obama at War, which airs Tuesday night on PBS.
The highest ranking military officer in the country is surprised by an issue that has been percolating for over a year? said Maguire, who now serves as an advisor to the Kurdish forces battling the Islamic State. That is breathtaking. Where in hell is the Central Intelligence Agency? Weve got a $75 billion intelligence budget. There is no excuse for this.
Dempsey is not the first senior official to acknowledge that U.S. intelligence officials and the White House itself missed the ferocity of ISs advance. President Obama, in an interview with the New Yorker in January, 2014, referred to IS as the jayvee, as in a junior varsity athletic team. And Director of National Intelligence James Clapper acknowledged last September that U.S. intelligence officials underestimated IS and the ability of the Iraqi Army to fight back against the terrorists.
I didnt see the collapse of the Iraq security force in the north coming, Clapper told Washington Post columnist David Ignatius in a Sept. 18, 2004, interview. I didnt see that.
But Dempseys remarks would appear to take the issue to a new level by admitting the lack of any worst case scenario planning inside the Pentagon despite months of warnings from some U.S. intelligence officials that IS was advancing rapidly through northern Iraq and Syria. ISIL probably will attempt to take territory in Iraq and Syria in 2014, as demonstrated recently in Ramadi and Fallajuh, Lt. Gen. Michael T. Flynn, then the director of the Defense Intelligence Agency, stated in an annual threat assessment report to Congress on Feb. 14, 2014.
Smith, the Frontline correspondent who conducted the interview with Dempsey, said he, too, was taken aback by the generals comments, noting the Pentagon routinely does contingency planning for all sorts of scenarios. I cant explain it, said Smith about Dempseys comments. We had invested how many billions in the Iraqi Army? Its something you would think they would keep an eye on. Yet they seemed entirely blindsided.
Underscoring just how blindsided officials were, are comments in Obama at War from another former senior Pentagon official.
The fall of Mosul was something that we had not anticipated, Derek Chollet, the former assistant secretary of defense for international security affairs, says in the film. And the suddenness with which that fall occurred was something that  that was a shock. They seized everything from small arms to light-armored vehicles- to anti-aircraft weapons. When terrorists of this kind get their hands on weapons, it was a huge concern to us. I dont think we truly understood the depth of the problem until the fall of Mosul.
CLICK IMAGE for slideshow: A fighter of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL) holds an ISIL flag and
Today, nearly a year later, Mosul  a city of more than one million  remains firmly under IS control and the Iraqi government, working closely with the U.S. military, has pushed back plans to retake the city.
The Frontline film reviews the Obama White Houses efforts to grapple with the mounting crisis in Iraq and Syria during a time it was attempting to withdraw U.S. troops from the region.
In another part of his interview with Smith, Dempsey describes how the Pentagon was on the trigger, ready to launch military action against the regime of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad in 2013 after U.S. officials had concluded he had launched a sarin gas attack against a rebel holdout in a suburb of Damascus, thereby crossing a red line that the president had publicly said he would not permit.
The consensus was that the Pentagon would launch strikes in Syria on Saturday, Aug. 31, Smith reports in the film.
Our finger was on the trigger, Dempsey says in the film. We had gone through the targeting plans and the targeting solutions. The crews were alerted. And so we had everything in place and we were just waiting  for instructions to proceed.
But then after the British House of Commons voted not to support the action, Obama began to pull back.
It was a Friday night and I got a call from the president of the United States, Dempsey reccalls. And he said to me, I am considering an alternative course of action. And he wanted me, overnight, to consider whether a delay would, in any way, affect our ability to be effective with our military options.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:36:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Governor says deadly flooding is worst ever seen in Texas area</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/governor-says-deadly-flooding-worst-ever-seen-texas-013252232.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Governor says deadly flooding is worst ever seen in Texas area
By Kristen Hays and Amanda Orr 1 hour ago

.
By Kristen Hays and Amanda Orr
HOUSTON (Reuters) - Torrential rains have killed at least 15 people in Texas and Oklahoma, including three in Houston where floods turned streets into rivers and led to about 1,000 calls for help in the fourth-most populous U.S. city, officials said on Tuesday.
The death toll is set to rise with numerous people still missing in Texas after the storms slammed the states during the Memorial Day weekend, causing record floods that destroyed hundreds of homes, swept away bridges, and even unearthed a coffin from a Houston cemetery. It washed ashore on the banks of a bayou.
"A lot of folks drove their car into high water and had to abandon those vehicles," Mayor Annise Parker said at a news conference.
Two of the dead in Houston were found in their cars and another was spotted floating in a bayou. The Oklahoma Medical Examiner's office said six people have died in weather-related incidents over the holiday weekend in the state.
Though Parker said parts of the city were unscathed,
View gallery
Gabby Aviles carries her daughter Audrey through floodwaters outside their apartment in Houston, Tue
more than 1,000 vehicles were submerged in the Houston floods and people took instead to bicycles, kayaks and surfboards to navigate water-covered streets. The Houston Fire Department brought about 500 people to safety in boats, local media reports said.
President Barack Obama said on Tuesday he had assured Texas Governor Greg Abbott that he could count on help from the federal government as the state recovers from the floods.    Abbott has declared a state of disaster in at least 40 Texas counties, including Harris County, home to Houston.
Abbott said he has deployed the state's National Guard and was worried the death toll could rise.
"It's devastating to see what I saw on the Blanco River when this tidal wave of water just swept away neighborhoods," he said, recalling a disaster area in central Texas.
Twelve people are confirmed missing and about another 30 are unaccounted for due to flooding that hit along the Blanco River, county officials said. The missing were from two families whose vacation home was swept off its foundation in Wimberley, a town about 30 miles (50 km) southwest of Austin.
View gallery
People stand on an interstate highway as flood water covers the roads businesses and houses in San M
Search dogs and boats were being used to search for the missing. The river rose so quickly and with such force, it caused a flood gauge to break, Hays County officials said.
There was no damage estimate available for the state, which has a $1.4 trillion-a-year economy and is the country's main domestic source of energy as well as an agricultural and manufacturing power.
Houston resident Dutch Small, 40, climbed onto the roof of his car when the water came up to his knees inside his vehicle and was eventually rescued by a passing tow truck driver.
"It happened so fast. Every person that died in the flooding, I know what was going through their minds. They didn't measure the threat accurately. They were like me," Small told Reuters.
The National Weather Service issued tornado and thunderstorm watches for later on Tuesday and said more rain is expected this week in Texas and Oklahoma.
View gallery
A kayaker rows through the flood waters above Sewell Park on the Texas State University campus near 
One of those killed was an 18-year-old girl whose car was swept away by flood waters as she returned home from her high school prom, police in Devine, Texas, south of San Antonio, said.
More than 200 flights had been canceled by early on Tuesday evening at airports in Houston and Dallas, some of the nation's busiest, as blocked roads made it difficult for workers to get to their jobs. A sinkhole also closed a runway at the Dallas/Fort Worth International airport.
Roughly 100,000 customers lost power throughout the state after the storm due to high winds and rising waters that caused power poles to snap.
In Houston, about 11 inches (28 cm) of rainwater fell on Monday while parts of Austin were hit by as much as 7 inches (18 cm). Helicopter crews in both cities plucked people to safety who had been stranded in cars and on top of buildings.
(Writing by Jon Herskovitz; Additional reporting by Terry Wade and Amanda Orr in Houston, Jim Forsyth in San Antonio, Lisa Maria Garza in Dallas, Suzannah Gonzales in Chicago and Scott DiSavino in New York; Editing by Bill Trott and Sandra Maler)
Houston
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:31:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraq begins operation to oust Islamic State from Anbar</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/iraq-announces-launch-operation-drive-anbar-072655270.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Iraq begins operation to oust Islamic State from Anbar
By SINAN SALAHEDDIN 6 hours ago

.
.
BAGHDAD (AP)  Iraq vowed Tuesday to retake Anbar province  now mostly held by the Islamic State  by launching a large-scale military operation less than two weeks after suffering a humiliating defeat at the hands of the extremists in the provincial capital of Ramadi.
The operation, which Iraqi state TV said was backed by Shiite militias and Sunni pro-government fighters, is deemed critical in regaining momentum in the fight.
But as a sandstorm descended across the region, there was no sign of any major engagement against the extremists, who have been gaining ground in the province west of Baghdad despite U.S.-led airstrikes.
A Pentagon spokesman, Col. Steve Warren, said Iraqi forces have begun "shaping operations" and "security zone interactions," which he described as probing and reconnaissance actions that would precede any major combat in or around Ramadi.
The Iraqis have begun moving forward from their base at Habbaniyah, and IS fighters likewise are probing in the direction of Habbaniyah, Warren said. He added that he could not confirm that the Iraqi forces have surrounded Ramadi.
The Islamic State  also known by the acronyms ISIS and ISIL, and Daesh in Arabic  seized large parts of Anbar in early 2014 and captured Ramadi earlier in May. Iraqi forces, which had been making steady progress against the extremists in recent months with the help of the air campaign, scored a major victory in recapturing Saddam Hussein's hometown of Tikrit last month.
Elsewhere in Anbar province, the Islamic State group last week captured the Iraqi side of the key al-Walid border crossing with Syria. Those gains followed the IS seizure of the ancient town of Palmyra in Syria.
View gallery
Security forces defend their headquarters against attacks by Islamic State extremists during sand st
The launch of the operation in Anbar came only days after U.S. officials, including Defense Secretary Ash Carter, criticized Iraq's forces, saying its troops fled the IS advance on Ramadi without fighting back, leaving behind weapons and vehicles for the extremists.
Baghdad defended its troops and said preparations were underway for the large-scale counteroffensive in Anbar, involving Iranian-backed Shiite militias known as Popular Mobilization Units. That possibility sparked fears of potential sectarian violence in the Sunni-dominated province, long the site of protests and criticism of the Shiite-led government in Baghdad.
The Shiite militias chose a religious name for their campaign, deepening those worries and drawing criticism from the Pentagon. The Popular Mobilization Units have named it "Labaik Ya Hussein," which is Arabic for "I am here, Hussein"  referring to a grandson of the Prophet Muhammad and one of the most revered figures of Shiite Islam.
Warren called the title "unhelpful," adding: "We've long said ... the key to expelling ISIL from Iraq is a unified Iraq that separates itself from sectarian divides."
Karim al-Nouri, a spokesman for the Popular Mobilization Units, said the name wasn't sectarian.
"This name has no sectarian dimension (or meaning) because all Iraqis, regardless of their sect or religion, love Imam Hussein," al-Nouri said.
View gallery
Iraqi residents from Ramadi, who fled their homes as Islamic State group militants tightened their s
A spokesman for Iraq's Shiite militias said the operation would "not last for a long time," and that Iraqi forces have surrounded Ramadi on three sides.
New weapons are being used in the battle "that will surprise the enemy," said Ahmed al-Assadi, who is also a member of parliament. He told reporters that another operation was underway north of the nearby province of Salahuddin.
Plans called for the forces in Salahuddin to move against Ramadi from its northeastern side, al-Assadi added.
The Anbar operation aims to cut off supply routes and recapture the outskirts of Ramadi first  not the city itself, according to provincial councilman Faleh al-Issawi and tribesman Rafie al-Fahdawi.
They told The Associated Press there was ongoing fighting and airstrikes west and south of Ramadi on Tuesday, adding that more Sunni fighters will be armed starting Wednesday to fight the Islamic State.
The sandstorm complicated efforts to retake the city, al-Issawi said.
View gallery
White House press secretary Josh Earnest speaks during the daily news briefing at the White House in
"There is zero visibility on the front lines and our men are highly concerned that they might come under attack by Daesh in such bad weather," he said.
Security forces and Sunni militiamen who had been battling the extremists in Ramadi for months collapsed as IS fighters overran the city.
The militants gained not only new territory 70 miles (115 kilometers) west of Baghdad, but also large stocks of weapons abandoned by government forces as they fled.
Carter said Sunday that Iraqi forces had "vastly outnumbered" the IS militants in Ramadi but "showed no will to fight."
Saad al-Hadithi, a spokesman for Prime Minister Haider al-Abadi, said Carter's remarks surprised the government and that he "was likely given incorrect information."
White House spokesman Josh Earnest defended Carter's remarks, saying the Iraqi government acknowledged that the setback in Ramadi was the result of a breakdown in command and planning. Earnest added that the Iraqi forces in Ramadi had not benefited from U.S. or allied training.
He praised Iraq's announcement it had launched a major military operation to drive Islamic State from Anbar, adding: "I think that is a clear indication of the will of the Iraqi security forces to fight. And the United States and our coalition partners will stand with them as they do so."
Gen. Qassim Soleimani, the head of the elite Quds forces in Iran's Revolutionary Guard who has taken on an advisory role with the Shiite militias, lashed out Monday at U.S. efforts. The Iranian daily newspaper Javan, seen as close to the Revolutionary Guard, quoted Soleimani as saying the U.S. didn't do a "damn thing" to stop the advance on Ramadi.
"Does it mean anything else than being an accomplice in the plot?" he reportedly asked, later saying the U.S. showed "no will" in fighting IS.
Al-Abadi had urged the Shiite militias to help retake Anbar province. The militiamen have played a key role in clawing back territory from IS elsewhere in Iraq, although rights groups and Sunni residents have accused them of looting, destroying property and carrying out revenge attacks  especially after government forces recaptured Tikrit last month. Militia leaders deny the allegations.
The participation of the Shiite militias in the Anbar operation risks exacerbating tensions that arose amid retaliatory sectarian killings that roiled Iraq in 2006 and 2007. Distrust of the Shiite-led government runs deep in Anbar, where U.S. troops fought some of their bloodiest battles since Vietnam and only succeeded in rolling back militants when Sunni tribesmen and former insurgents rallied to their side as part of the Sahwa, or Awakening, movement in 2006. After the U.S. troop withdrawal, Sunni anger at Baghdad has grown steadily.
___
Associated Press writers Sameer N. Yacoub in Baghdad and Robert Burns and Jim Kuhnhenn in Washington contributed to this report.
Islamic State
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue May 26 12:38:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lawyer says allegations B.B. King was poisoned 'ridiculous'</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/2-b-b-king-daughters-allege-2-closest-193139672.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Lawyer says allegations B.B. King was poisoned 'ridiculous'
By KEN RITTER 15 hours ago

B.B. King Daughters Allege Father was Poisoned

B.B. King Daughters Allege Father was Poisoned
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
B.B. King Daughters Allege Father was Poisoned
 Replay video
Smoked Salmon Gets New Meaning With Cannabis-infused Fish

One of the world&amp;#39;s most distinguished conductors and pianists, Daniel Barenboim, has unveiled a new type of grand piano. He says it is &amp;quot;radically different&amp;quot; to the standard concert grand as it is built with straight, parallel strings that produce a superior sound. Will Gompertz is at the Royal Festival Hall on London&amp;#39;s South Bank where the piano is being unveiled.
Load More
LAS VEGAS (AP)  Two B.B. King heirs who've been most outspoken about the blues legend's care in his final days have accused King's two closest aides of poisoning him, but the attorney for King's estate called the claims ridiculous and police said there was no active homicide investigation.
Three doctors determined that King was appropriately cared-for, and King received 24-hour care and monitoring by medical professionals "up until the time that he peacefully passed away in his sleep," attorney Brent Bryson told the AP on Monday.
Daughters Karen Williams and Patty King allege that family members were prevented from visiting while King's business manager, LaVerne Toney, and his personal assistant, Myron Johnson, hastened their father's death.
Toney is named in King's will as executor of an estate that, according to court documents filed by lawyers for some of King's heirs, could total tens of millions of dollars.
Johnson was at B.B. King's bedside when he died May 14 in hospice care at home in Las Vegas at age 89. No family members were present.
"I believe my father was poisoned and that he was administered foreign substances," Patty King and Williams say in identically worded sections of affidavits provided to The Associated Press by their lawyer, Larissa Drohobyczer.
B.B. King performs at Marin Center on February 26, 2014 in San Rafael, California. (Steve Jennings/W
"I believe my father was murdered," they say.
An autopsy was performed Sunday. Test results will take up to eight weeks to obtain and shouldn't be affected by the fact that King's body had been embalmed, Clark County Coroner John Fudenberg said.
Fudenberg issued a statement Monday saying there was no immediate evidence supporting the murder allegations, and Las Vegas police Lt. Ray Steiber told the AP that there was no active homicide investigation.
Toney and Johnson each declined to comment on the accusations.
"They've been making allegations all along. What's new?" said Toney, who worked for King for 39 years and had power-of-attorney over his affairs.
View gallery
Patty King leaves a memorial service for her father B.B. King Saturday, May 23, 2015, in Las Vegas. 
A week before King's death, a judge in Las Vegas dismissed a request from Williams to take over as King's guardian.
An April 29 petition alleged that Toney had blocked King's friends from visiting him and had put her family members on King's payroll. It also alleged that large sums of money had disappeared from King's bank accounts.
But Clark County Family Court Hearing Master Jon Norheim said on May 7 that police and social services investigations in October and April uncovered no reason to take power-of-attorney from Toney.
Williams, Patty King and another daughter  Rita Washington  vowed to keep fighting.
"We lost the battle, but we haven't lost the war," Williams said then.
View gallery
Roger Alvarado cries while sitting on the back of his truck outside of a funeral home during a publi
This week's allegations come days after a public viewing in Las Vegas drew more than 1,000 fans and mourners and a weekend family-and-friends memorial drew 350. A Beale Street procession and memorial are scheduled Wednesday in Memphis, Tennessee, followed by a Friday viewing and Saturday burial in King's hometown of Indianola, Mississippi.
Fudenberg said Monday that his office's investigation shouldn't delay those services.
Bryson said the allegations were "extremely disrespectful" to King.
"He did not want invasive medical procedures," he said. "He made the decision to return home for hospice care instead of staying in a hospital. These unfounded allegations have caused Mr. King to undergo an autopsy, which is exactly what he didn't want."
Drohobyczer said she represents Williams, Patty King and most of King's nine other adult children and heirs.
"The family is sticking together ... to oust Ms. Toney based on her illegal conduct, conflicts of interest and self-dealing," she said. She alleged that Toney hastened King's death by "misconduct, or by failing to properly attend to his medical needs."
An affidavit from Patty King, who used to live at King's home, says she saw Johnson administer to King two drops of an unknown substance on his tongue during evenings for several months before his death, and that Toney never told her what the substance was.
Bryson called Drohobyczer's claims ridiculous.
"I hope they have a factual basis that they can demonstrate for their defamatory and libelous allegations," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:20:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Washington Post reporter on trial in Iran for spying</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/washington-post-reporter-spy-trial-opens-iran-062843867.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Washington Post reporter on trial in Iran for spying
By Cyril Julien 4 hours ago

Washington Post Journalist Jason Rezaian's Trial Starts Today In Tehran

Washington Post Journalist Jason Rezaian's Trial Starts Today In Tehran
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Washington Post Journalist Jason Rezaian's Trial Starts Today In Tehran
 Replay video
Smoked Salmon Gets New Meaning With Cannabis-infused Fish

One of the world&amp;#39;s most distinguished conductors and pianists, Daniel Barenboim, has unveiled a new type of grand piano. He says it is &amp;quot;radically different&amp;quot; to the standard concert grand as it is built with straight, parallel strings that produce a superior sound. Will Gompertz is at the Royal Festival Hall on London&amp;#39;s South Bank where the piano is being unveiled.
Load More
Tehran (AFP) - Washington Post correspondent Jason Rezaian went on trial behind closed doors in Iran Tuesday on charges of spying, in a case that has clouded a rapprochement with the United States.
The United States blasted the trial's "complete lack of transparency", and renewed calls for Tehran to drop "absurd" spying charges that Rezaian's brother called "laughable".
Rezaian's wife, Yeganeh Salehi, who is also a journalist, appeared in court alongside her husband and a female press photographer, Iran's official IRNA news agency reported.
The trial is being held in Branch 15 of the Tehran revolutionary court, which usually presides over political cases or those related to national security.
The first session ended after about three hours, according to MizanOnline, a news agency linked to the judiciary.
Rezaian was presented with the charges against him, including espionage, the report said.
It said Rezaian had yet to submit his defence and that the date of the next hearing would be announced later.
The United States said it was monitoring the case "as closely as possible".
"While we call for this trial to be open, we also maintain that Jason should never have been detained or put on trial in the first place," National Security Council spokeswoman Bernadette Meehan said.
View gallery
The Washington Post's executive director, Martin Baron, said the newspaper had tried to obtain a
Rezaian, an Iranian-American, has been held since July last year in a politically sensitive case that has unfolded while Iran and world powers conduct nuclear talks.

- Mother's one visit -
Tehran does not recognise dual nationality, and says the case is a purely Iranian matter.
Rezaian's wife, who worked for the English-language newspaper The National based in Abu Dhabi, was arrested along with him but released on bail after spending two and a half months in custody.
Rezaian, 39, is accused of "espionage, collaboration with hostile governments, gathering classified information and disseminating propaganda against the Islamic republic", according to his lawyer Leila Ahsan.
His American mother, Mary, has been in Iran for the past two weeks, but his brother Ali Rezaian told AFP she was not allowed into the hearing.
"The fact that Jason's trial has been closed to the public, including Jason's immediate family, fits the pattern of a complete lack of transparency and lack of due process that we've seen since Jason was first detained," Meehan said in a statement.
View gallery
Iranian-American Washington Post correspondent Jason Rezaian and his Iranian wife Yeganeh Salehi in 
"We continue to call for all of these absurd charges to be dropped and for Jason to be released immediately."
Ali Rezaian told AFP in an interview that their mother has been allowed to visit Jason once in Tehran's notorious Evin jail and to speak with him for four minutes in a separate phone call.
State media gave no details of Tuesday's hearing and no indication of how long the trial might last.
But it will overlap with the final stretch of negotiations between Iran and the major powers aimed at reaching a comprehensive agreement on Tehran's nuclear programme by a June 30 deadline.

- 'Interrogated almost daily' -
"For over five months they interrogated him on almost a daily basis," Ali Rezaian said.
"It took them that long to come up with these charges that are based on really nothing. When we've heard about what kind of evidence they have, it's laughable."
Rezaian's case has been played out in the Iranian media, where he has been accused of spying and passing information about Iran to US government officials.
Among the offences he is alleged to have committed is writing a letter to US President Barack Obama.
"There is no justice in this system, not an ounce of it, and yet the fate of a good, innocent man hangs in the balance," The Washington Post's executive director, Martin Baron said.
"Iran is making a statement about its values in its disgraceful treatment of our colleague, and it can only horrify the world community."
Rezaian's relatives have frequently expressed fears for his health, citing his need for medication to combat high blood pressure.
The California-born journalist is one of four Americans Obama has urged Iran to return home.
The others are pastor Saeed Abedini, in jail for more than two years after being convicted of undermining national security, and former US Marine Amir Hekmati, who is serving 10 years for cooperating with hostile governments.
A fourth American, retired FBI agent Robert Levinson, went missing in southern Iran eight years ago.
Company Legal &amp; Law Matters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon May 25 23:27:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Report: Cleveland, DOJ reach settlement over police</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/cleveland-u-justice-department-reach-settlement-over-police-202709272.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>One of the world&amp;#39;s most distinguished conductors and pianists, Daniel Barenboim, has unveiled a new type of grand piano. He says it is &amp;quot;radically different&amp;quot; to the standard concert grand as it is built with straight, parallel strings that produce a superior sound. Will Gompertz is at the Royal Festival Hall on London&amp;#39;s South Bank where the piano is being unveiled.
Load More
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Cleveland has reached a settlement with the U.S. Justice Department over what federal authorities said was a pattern of unconstitutional policing and excessive use of force, the New York Times reported on Monday.
The settlement could be announced as early as Tuesday, the newspaper said, citing people briefed on the matter.
The settlement would come days after a judge declared a white Cleveland police officer not guilty in the shooting deaths of an unarmed black man and a woman in 2012. The verdict on Saturday prompted protests that led to at least 71 arrests.
The details of the settlement were not immediately clear, the Times said. In similar negotiations in recent years, the Justice Department has insisted that cities allow independent monitors to oversee changes inside police departments.
Settlements are typically backed by court orders and often call for improved training and revised use-of-force policies.
Spokesmen for the Justice Department, the Cleveland police and Mayor Frank Jackson had no immediate response to requests for comment.
View gallery
Protesters are escorted to a bus for transport after getting arrested after protesting the acquittal
The results of a Justice Department investigation released in December found Cleveland police systematically engaged in excessive use of force.
Just days before the report was released, a Cleveland police officer shot and killed Tamir Rice, a 12-year-old boy who was carrying what turned out to be a replica gun that typically fires plastic pellets. The shooting is under investigation.
The Justice Department has opened nearly two dozen investigations into police departments during the administration of President Barack Obama.
Federal authorities said this month they would investigate police in Baltimore following the death of Freddie Gray, a black man who died of injuries he suffered while in police custody. Six officers have been indicted in Gray's death.
(Reporting by Ian Simpson; Editing by Peter Cooney)
Justice Department
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue May 26 06:44:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama at Arlington: Never stop paying tribute to the fallen</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/obama-pays-tribute-fallen-members-arlington-155619919--politics.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Photo on Apple&amp;#39;s site appears to show rumored device.
Load More
ARLINGTON, Va. (AP)  President Barack Obama on Monday saluted Americans who died in battle, saying the country must "never stop trying to fully repay them" for their sacrifices. He noted it was the first Memorial Day in 14 years without U.S. forces engaged in a major ground war.
Speaking under sunny skies to some 5,000 people in an amphitheater on the hallowed grounds of Arlington National Cemetery, Obama said the graveyard is "more than a final resting place of heroes."
"It is a reflection of America itself," he said, citing racial and religious diversity in the backgrounds of the men and woman who paid the ultimate sacrifice to preserve "the ideals that bind us as one nation."
His appearance is an annual rite for presidents at the cemetery nestled among verdant hills overlooking the Potomac River.
In his remarks at Arlington National Cemetery, Obama said most of the remaining troops should be removed from Afghanistan by the end of 2016.
He recognized the more than 2,200 patriots who sacrificed themselves in Afghanistan, including the final two killed before the U.S. combat mission ended late last year. He also recognized the first American killed during the "new mission" to train Afghan forces, an Army medic who died in April.
Earlier, troops stationed in that war-wracked country observed a moment of silence in honor of fallen comrades there.
View gallery
Navy Vietnam War veteran Dennis McClelland of Murrells Inlet, South Carolina, holds a U.S. flag duri
Before making his remarks, Obama laid a wreath at the Tomb of the Unknowns. He bowed his head briefly and listened with others to the playing of "Taps."
Obama said most Americans don't understand the sacrifice made by the 1 percent of the population that serves in the all-volunteer Armed Forces. But when he meets with "Gold Star" families that have lost loved ones through military service, Obama said he hears "their pride through their tears."
"I see that their hearts are still broken, and yet still full of love," he said. "They do not ask for awards or honors. They do not ask for special treatment. They are unfailingly humble. In the face of unspeakable loss, they represent the best of who we are."
Obama said the markers at Arlington signify the blessings many Americans enjoy.
"It's a debt we can never fully repay," he said, "but it is a debt we will never stop trying to fully repay."
Introducing Obama, Defense Secretary Ash Carter said, "We, your fellow Americans, lack the words to describe what you feel today because try as we may, and try as we do, we can never fully know. But we do know what your sacrifice means to us."
View gallery
President Barack Obama, accompanied by Maj. Gen. Jeffrey S. Buchanan, left, Commander of the U.S. Ar
Across the nation, Americans observed Memorial Day with parades, picnics and tributes that began earlier in the weekend.
The roar of motorcycle engines throughout the nation's capital on Sunday presaged Monday's solemn event at Arlington, as thousands of bikers saluted veterans with Rolling Thunder's "Ride for Freedom." A concert of patriotic music followed on Sunday evening. Obama held a private breakfast on Monday at the White House with representatives of veteran and military family service organizations and the national Memorial Day parade marched on Constitution Avenue.
 North Dakota marked the 25th anniversary of the groundbreaking for the state's Veterans Cemetery south of Mandan. Gov. Jack Dalrymple directed all state agencies to fly the U.S. and state flags at half-staff.
 In South Dakota, Gov. Dennis Daugaard asked residents to observe the president's request that Americans unite in prayer at 11 a.m. local time and that a moment of silence be observed at 3 p.m. for the National Moment of Remembrance.
 In Kentucky horse country, dozens of people gathered at the cemetery of the Old Friends farm to honor 11 thoroughbreds who died in the past year after being retired there. Some were racetrack winners and descendants of racing royalty, while others were also-rans or never raced at all.
 In Michigan, an ex-Navy SEAL who founded a national organization to help military and emergency service workers who have survived burns served as grand marshal of Dearborn's Memorial Day parade as the Detroit suburb joined communities around the state in marking the holiday.
 The Library of Congress has been working to build an oral history collection to capture veterans' memories of war, and the project is nearing a milestone of 100,000 records.
 In a race in Boulder, Colorado, U.S. Air Force pilot Ben Payne, a runner from Colorado Springs, ran with the names of several family members and friends who lost their lives while serving their country on a bib pinned to his back.
 With the assistance of former servicemen and -women, a Michigan State University journalism class researched and wrote a new book, "100 Questions and Answers About Veterans." The book is aimed at clearing up myths and misunderstandings about the military held by some civilians.
 During a baseball game at Wrigley Field between the Washington Nationals and Chicago Cubs, a moment of silence was observed to honor the sacrifices of veterans.
One holiday event took an unexpected turn when a waterspout uprooted an inflatable bounce house with three children inside it on a South Florida beach. Police said the youngsters were ejected before it flew over palm trees and across four lanes of traffic before landing in a parking lot. They said the children were injured, but alert and conscious when they were taken to a hospital.
___
Follow Darlene Superville on Twitter: http://www.twitter.com/dsupervilleap
Barack Obama
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue May 26 01:45:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charter nears deal for Time Warner Cable</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/charter-nears-deal-time-warner-cable-201440103--finance.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Charter nears deal for Time Warner Cable
By TALI ARBEL and DAVID KOENIG May 25, 2015 6:45 PM

View gallery
.
Charter Communications Inc. is close to buying Time Warner Cable for about $55 billion, according to two people familiar with the negotiations.
The people spoke on condition of anonymity Monday because of the private nature of the deal talks.
One of the people said the deal will be announced early Tuesday morning.
Charter had wanted to buy Time Warner Cable Inc. earlier, but Time Warner Cable chose a $45 billion offer from Comcast Corp. instead.
Comcast walked away from the Time Warner Cable deal after regulators pushed back against it. Regulators had concerns that the two companies together would undermine online video competition. The combined company would have served more than half the country's broadband subscribers, and consumer advocates said a merger would limit choices and lead to higher prices.
Time Warner Cable representative Ellen East and Charter spokesman Justin Venech both declined to comment on the talks between their companies.
View gallery
FILE - This Feb. 2, 2009 file photo shows a Time Warner Cable truck in New York .Charter Communicati
Cable companies are losing cable subscribers and facing more pressure from online services such as Netflix and Amazon for consumers who watch TV over broadband connections.
Consumer advocates were waiting to learn more details about the deal but seemed initially to regard it with less hostility than the failed Comcast bid for Time Warner Cable, which would have created a behemoth much of the Internet access in the U.S.
"I can't say that we're a big fan of industry consolidation, but realistically this doesn't really raise the same level of concern," said John Bergmayer, a lawyer with Public Knowledge.
If antitrust regulators approve the deal, Bergmayer said, they should attach conditions addressing broadband affordability, customer service and other issues.
Cable companies argue that their mergers don't hurt TV consumers because their systems don't overlap much  an argument that is disputed by consumer groups.
Matt Wood, policy director of the Internet-consumer group Free Press, said the money that the cable companies spend on mergers doesn't go to helping customers.
"Rather than buying each other up and cementing in place the local monopolies they already enjoy, they could be investing in their own networks to improve their customer service," Wood said. They could even go outside their current markets and compete against each other in more places, he said.
Shares of Time Warner Cable closed Friday at $171.18. They have climbed 13 percent so far in 2015, compared with a 3 percent gain in the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index.
Time Warner Cable
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Mon May 25 22:06:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Afghan official: 19 police, 7 soldiers dead in ongoing siege</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/afghan-official-says-suicide-bombing-kills-least-5-084301691.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>One of the world&amp;#39;s most distinguished conductors and pianists, Daniel Barenboim, has unveiled a new type of grand piano. He says it is &amp;quot;radically different&amp;quot; to the standard concert grand as it is built with straight, parallel strings that produce a superior sound. Will Gompertz is at the Royal Festival Hall on London&amp;#39;s South Bank where the piano is being unveiled.
Load More
KANDAHAR, Afghanistan (AP)  Taliban gunmen have surrounded a police compound in the volatile southern province of Helmand after killing 19 policemen and seven soldiers in an ongoing siege, a senior police officer said on Monday from inside the compound.
Napas Khan, the police chief in the Naw Zad district, told The Associated Press by telephone that the insurgents had advanced to within 20 meters (65 feet) of the compound after seizing police vehicles and weapons and blocking all roads out of Naw Zad.
"We need an immediate response from the government," Khan said.
He said the attack started at before dawn on Monday when the insurgents overran multiple police checkpoints across the district.
"They destroyed or captured most of our checkpoints and now they have reached our police headquarters," Khan said. "They are mostly firing at us from the hills overlooking our compound."
As Khan spoke, gunfire and shouting could be heard in the background.
View gallery
Afghan policemen stand guard at the site of a blast in Kabul, Afghanistan May 19, 2015. A bomb explo
Helmand has long been a heartland for the Taliban, who profit heavily from opium produced in its fertile river valley.
Government forces launched an operation against the insurgents in March, in the hope of reducing the impact of the Taliban's annual warm weather offensive. Since that offensive was launched, however, in late April, attacks across the country have intensified, spreading government forces thin.
As well as the time-worn guerrilla-style tactics of fight-and-run, the insurgents have also stepped up suicide attacks and, in some areas, targeted assassinations and kidnappings.
Also on Monday, a suicide truck bomb attack and a separate roadside bombing in southern Afghanistan killed 11 people and wounded dozens more, as the Taliban clashed with supporters of the Islamic State group in the west, officials said.
Gov. Asif Nang said the Taliban have been clashing with rival insurgents claiming allegiance to the IS group for three days in the western Farah province, leaving at least 10 Taliban fighters and 15 IS supporters dead. He provided no further details.
View gallery
Afghanistan, security forces take position during a fighting outside a government compound in the ci
The clashes provide the latest indication of a small but growing Islamic State presence in the country. Afghan and foreign officials differ over the extent to which the extremist group, which rules large parts of Syria and Iraq, is able to operate in Afghanistan  where the Taliban have been waging war against the Western-backed government for more than a decade.
The truck bomb struck the gate of the provincial council's compound in the capital of Zabul province, killing at least five people and wounding 62, council director Atta Jan Haqbayan said.
Three of the wounded were council members, Haqbayan said. Mirwais Noorzai, Zabul's police chief, said the attacker used a small truck.
President Ashraf Ghani condemned the attack. No group immediately claimed responsibility.
Insurgents have stepped up attacks in recent months in Zabul, which borders Pakistan, and a number of Hazara Shiite men have been abducted in the province.
Later on Monday, a roadside bomb exploded in neighboring Kandahar province, killing six people, according to the governor's spokesman, Samim Khopalwaq.
Three policemen were killed elsewhere in Kandahar when a firefight erupted between two groups of officers, said provincial police spokesman Zia Durrani. Four officers fled the scene, he said, adding that the incident was under investigation.
Meanwhile, in northern Sari Pul province, police said the body of a local official in charge of religious affairs, Abdul Wodod, was found Monday, three days after he was kidnapped. Gen. Habib Gulbhary, the provincial police chief, said the man was abducted by unknown assailants.
police chief
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Mon May 25 22:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mexico officials stand by account of deadly ranch shootout</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/relatives-doubt-42-men-died-shootout-mexico-ranch-040445431.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Mexico officials stand by account of deadly ranch shootout
By E. EDUARDO CASTILLO May 25, 2015 3:44 PM

Mexico Officials Stand by Account of Deadly Ranch Shootout

Mexico Officials Stand by Account of Deadly Ranch Shootout
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Mexico Officials Stand by Account of Deadly Ranch Shootout
 Replay video
Smoked Salmon Gets New Meaning With Cannabis-infused Fish

One of the world&amp;#39;s most distinguished conductors and pianists, Daniel Barenboim, has unveiled a new type of grand piano. He says it is &amp;quot;radically different&amp;quot; to the standard concert grand as it is built with straight, parallel strings that produce a superior sound. Will Gompertz is at the Royal Festival Hall on London&amp;#39;s South Bank where the piano is being unveiled.
Load More
MORELIA, Mexico (AP)  Mexican officials stood by their account Monday of a shootout that killed 42 suspected criminals and one federal police officer last week, dismissing questions raised about the lopsided death toll.
"There was not one single execution, I can say that categorically," Enrique Galindo, head of Mexico's federal police, told local media.
The 42 men died Friday during a three-hour gun battle on a ranch in Michoacan state. Officials say the fight began when police officers came under fire while responding to a report of armed men taking over the Rancho del Sol, in Ecuandureo, a township near the border with Jalisco state.
It was the deadliest such confrontation in recent memory and followed two deadly clashes in the area controlled by the powerful Jalisco New Generation cartel: The gang is blamed for an ambush that killed 15 state police officers in April and for a May 1 attack in which a rocket launcher shot down an army helicopter, killing eight soldiers.
Families of some of the men killed on Friday told The Associated Press that after viewing the remains of their loved ones, they doubted the official account. Relatives gathered at a local morgue said one body was missing an eye and had facial bruising, another had its teeth knocked inward. Another had a gunshot in the top of the head.
Galindo said a helicopter gunship had participated in the shootout and that its role had been decisive. "If the helicopter had not arrived, the death toll might have been different."
View gallery
Vehicles burn, that authorities say caught fire during a gunbattle, in a warehouse at Rancho del Sol
National Security Commissioner Monte Alejandro Rubido said at a news conference later Monday that the helicopter had been hit three times by bullets from an AR-15 assault rifle.
Authorities detained three people and confiscated 38 semi-automatic weapons, two smaller arms, a grenade launcher and a .50-caliber rifle. They had initially said they seized 40 weapons.
Speaking to the television network Televisa earlier Monday, Rubido said tests on the bodies of the victims showed they had been shot "from a considerable distance ... dozens of meters (yards)," ruling out anybody having been finished off at close range.
An official from Michoacan state, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to talk to the press, said all the dead were men and most died from gunfire.
Rubido said the three men arrested were "the only three who when told to surrender, did so. The others refused and continued shooting."
View gallery
Police drive along a road inside the Rancho del Sol, a ranch that was the site of clashes between Me
But the lopsided death toll, and photographs from the scene in which bodies appeared to have been moved, raised questions about the official version.
Family members who arrived at the morgue in the state capital, Morelia, to retrieve the bodies spoke to The Associated Press on condition of anonymity because they feared reprisals, but some were willing to provide the names of their dead relatives. Many were from Ocotlan in Jalisco state and said that a group of at least 25 men from the town had gone to the ranch after being offered work.
Juan Enrique Romero Caudillo, 34, was one of those men. Family members said he sold scrap metal to make a living.
"He said he had been offered maintenance work at the ranch," said a relative, adding that Romero didn't belong to a gang.
After seeing his corpse, the relative said Romero had been shot in the head from above and there was bruising on his face. On the death certificate, the cause of death was listed as "destruction of the brain mass due to penetration by a projectile from a firearm." It did not say if the gunshot was from close range or far away.
View gallery
A masked police officer stands guard just inside the entrance of Rancho del Sol, a ranch that was th
Romero's relative said he believed what happened on the ranch "was a massacre" not a shootout with criminal gunmen.
Relatives of Mario Alberto Valencia Vazquez, 22, said he worked in a furniture business but had been offered employment on the ranch.
One relative said Valencia's teeth had been knocked inward as if "he had been struck by something" and his body showed signs of having received blows. Another woman said her husband's face had been destroyed and was missing an eye.
Photographs from the site showed the bodies of men, some without shirts or barefoot, strewn over the ranch. Some appeared to lie with semi-automatic rifles in a field with farm equipment and others on a blood-stained patio strewn with clothes, mattresses and sleeping bags. Video of the battle obtained by The Associated Press showed federal police officers coming under fire.
Rubido dismissed photos circulating online, saying some were not from Friday's events and others were captured at different points in time.
The debate recalled a June 30 case in Tlatlaya, a rural community in Mexico state in which the army initially said 22 suspected criminals were killed in a confrontation and only one soldier had been wounded. An investigation by The Associated Press revealed that several of the suspects were executed after surrendering. Seven soldiers have been charged with wrongdoing.
"This is in no way anything like what happened in Tlatlaya," Galindo said. Officials say overwhelming power and training  police used four armored cars and the helicopter in the shootout  as well as the suspects' lack of preparation spelled the difference.
And Galindo noted that not all of the suspects at the ranch were killed. Three surrendered and were taken into custody, and a significant number escaped.
"We calculate there could have been between 60 and 70 people, because some fled," Galindo said.
Rubido said the cartel gunmen invaded the ranch last Monday, but the ranch owner, who lives in Guadalajara, did not report the takeover to authorities until Thursday. The gunmen were seeking a safe place to escape the government's pressure in Jalisco, Rubido said.
A convoy of 42 federal police were headed to the ranch to investigate when fired upon Friday morning, Rubido said. About 60 additional personnel joined them after 1  hours of the battle.
__
Associated Press writer Christopher Sherman in Mexico City contributed to this report.
Mexico
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Mon May 25 22:42:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anonymous threats against airliners prompt plane searches</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/air-france-flight-gets-military-escort-nyc-threat-162641055.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Anonymous threats against airliners prompt plane searches
May 25, 2015 3:42 PM

Content preferences
Done
NEW YORK (AP)  A series of anonymous telephone threats against commercial airliners Monday, possibly from the same source, prompted searches of at least two planes at Kennedy Airport and nearly interrupted a third flight from England, authorities said.
Authorities said the threats didn't appear to be credible and the searches were done as a precaution.
In one instance Monday morning, U.S. military jets escorted an Air France flight into New York City after someone claimed a chemical weapon was aboard the aircraft, the FBI said.
"Out of an abundance of caution, Air France flight number 22 was escorted to John F. Kennedy airport by U.S. Air Force fighter jets following a phone threat," the FBI said in a statement. "There were no incidents or hazards reported on board the flight by either the passengers or its crew. The plane has been cleared."
A Saudi Arabian Airlines flight also was being checked out because of another threat, authorities said.
A third threat was made against an American Airlines jet flying from Birmingham, England, to JFK while it was still in the air, said airline spokesman Kent Powell. Authorities initially told the pilot to land and taxi to a remote area away from the terminal but later radioed that the threat was not credible and cleared the plane to go to the terminal, Powell said.
Kennedy Airport
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Mon May 25 21:21:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tens of thousands turn up for funeral of Saudi suicide attack victims</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/tens-thousands-turn-funeral-saudi-suicide-attack-victims-162753217.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tens of thousands turn up for funeral of Saudi suicide attack victims
May 25, 2015 2:21 PM

Tens of Thousands Turn up for Funeral of Saudi Suicide Attack Victims

Tens of Thousands Turn up for Funeral of Saudi Suicide Attack Victims
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Tens of Thousands Turn up for Funeral of Saudi Suicide Attack Victims
 Replay video
Smoked Salmon Gets New Meaning With Cannabis-infused Fish

View gallery
Shi'ite Muslims carry the coffin of a Saudi man during a mass funeral for victims of last Friday
QATIF, Saudi Arabia (Reuters) - Tens of thousands of people turned out at a mass funeral in eastern Saudi Arabia for 21 Shi'ite Muslims killed last week in a suicide bombing claimed by Islamic State, a Reuters witness said.
Saudi security forces stayed away from the funeral in Qatif, as delegates converged on the city from various regions in the eastern province, where most of the country's Shi'ite Muslim minority live, to attend the burial.
"Here I am, O Hussein," the crowd chanted, invoking the name of Prophet Mohammad's grandson Imam Hussein, one of the most revered figures in Shi'ite Islam, as they marched toward the cemetery behind the flower-covered coffins, held shoulder-high by local men.
At the funeral, activists posted a picture of prominent rights activist Mikhlif al-Shammari, a member of a large Sunni Muslim tribe who had been jailed in the past, holding a placard that read: "Sectarian incitement is a time-bomb."
Friday's attack was one of the deadliest assaults in recent years in the largest Gulf Arab country, where sectarian tensions have been frayed by nearly two months of Saudi-led air strikes on Shi'ite Houthi rebels in neighboring Yemen.
Saudi King Salman, in a conciliatory statement on Sunday, said he was heartbroken over the bombing and vowed to bring anyone linked to the attack or who sympathized with it to justice.
Shi'ites, who are a small minority in the predominantly Sunni Muslim kingdom, complain of discrimination, a charge denied by the government.
Residents of Qatif had hung placards on the funeral path denouncing sectarianism and demanding equality. They also called for closing down some private television stations run by Sunni Muslim hardliners, which Shi'ites see as promoting hatred.
(Writing by Sami Aboudi; Editing by Larry King)
Saudi Arabia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Mon May 25 19:17:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At least three dead, 12 missing in US flooding</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/one-killed-several-missing-texas-flooding-224554500.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>At least three dead, 12 missing in US flooding
May 25, 2015 12:17 PM

Firefighter among victims in deadly Oklahoma flood

Firefighter among victims in deadly Oklahoma flood
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Firefighter among victims in deadly Oklahoma flood
 Replay video
Life advice for the Class of 2015

Leo and Ruth Zanger have welcomed their 100th grandchild into the world. The couple has 46 great-grandchildren, 53 grandchildren, and one great-great-grandchild.
Load More
Washington (AFP) - Rescuers searched Monday for at least 12 people missing in spectacular flash flooding in Texas and Oklahoma that also left at least three dead.
More heavy rain with potential for additional flooding was forecast.
The raging waters destroyed hundreds of homes and sent cars floating down streets, rolling and bobbing like giant toys.
In the Texas city of San Marcos, residents were ordered to evacuate their homes as flood waters rose menacingly around them, following torrential rain that turned streets into meandering rivers.
Cars and trucks were submerged and people used inflatable lounge chairs to float down the street, in surreal scenes.
As many as 400 homes in the surrounding area were destroyed, authorities said, and San Marcos opened temporary shelters to host residents who could not return home.
View gallery
Gabby Aviles carries her daughter Audrey through floodwaters outside their apartment in Houston, Tue
In Texas at least 12 people are reported missing, said Kharley Smith, emergency response coordinator for Hays County, which includes San Marcos.
She said people were forming their own search parties along the Blanco River, and warned them against this, saying it was dangerous.
"We have local resources, regional and state assets that are actively doing search and rescues. It's not safe for the general public to go down and do those rescue or search operations themselves," Smith told a news conference.
The city council said the river had broken record levels set in the 1920s.
Fire Marshal Ken Bell told CNN that at least one person was confirmed dead and crews were searching for three missing people.
At least two people also died in Oklahoma, which is located to the north of Texas.
A firefighter in the town of Claremore died when he was swept into a storm drain while trying to help a resident in floodwaters, CNN said, and a woman in Tulsa died after her car hydroplaned.
The National Weather Service warned that strong to severe thunderstorms were expected across a large stretch of the central and southern plains toward the Mississippi River Valley.
Basic Materials Industry
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Tue May 26 06:21:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fighter Jets Scramble Following at Least 6 Reports of Threats to Passenger Planes, Officials Say</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/fighter-jets-scramble-escort-air-france-plane-jfk-150126554--abc-news-topstories.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Fighter Jets Scramble Following at Least 6 Reports of Threats to Passenger Planes, Officials Say
By MEGHAN KENEALLY and JOSH MARGOLIN 21 hours ago

Air Force Fighter Jets Scramble to Protect Threatened Flights
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Air Force Fighter Jets Scramble to Protect Threatened Flights
 Replay video
Students Release 72,000 Ladybugs in School as Senior Prank

Tourism Ireland releases new video just 24 hours after country votes yes for gay marriage.
Load More
At least six flights were impacted by threats at airports in New York, New Jersey and Boston today, according to airlines and law enforcement.
JFK Airport:
An Air France plane was escorted to JFK Airport in New York City this morning after an anonymous threat was made against the flight, law enforcement officials told ABC News. The FBI said the plane has since been checked and cleared with "no incidents or hazards reported on board the flight by either the passengers or its crew."
Authorities said that the decision to have the plane escorted by two fighter jets was done "out of an abundance of caution" after the Maryland State Police McHenry Barrack, in Garrett County, received an anonymous call of a chemical weapons threat aboard Air France Flight 22, which was en route from Paris to the New York City airport.
View gallery
Fighter Jets Scramble Following at Least 6 Reports of Threats to Passenger Planes, Officials Say (AB
The tip was called in at 6:45 a.m. on an untraceable line and the caller did not identify himself, a senior federal official told ABC News. Two F-15 planes were scrambled and followed the plane into U.S. airspace, but they flew in a way so that the passengers and crew would not be able to see the military planes, sources said.
The Airbus A-330 has since landed and was taken between two runways and locked down while the threat is investigated. A police dispatch that was sent out after the jets were scrambled noted that the area where the plane was taken is generally known as the "hijack site" because it is the area used in such scenarios. During an initial investigation, nothing dangerous has been found on board, the federal official told ABC News.
A Saudi Airlines flight from Saudi Arabia was also escorted to a remote area at JFK. It was cleared and passengers were brought back to the terminal, officials said.
For an American Airlines flight from Birmingham, England, to JFK, the pilot was initially instructed to taxi to a remote area, but the threat was determined not credible and the plane was cleared to go to the terminal.
Newark Airport:
Two flights to Newark, New Jersey, were also affected -- a Delta Air Lines flight from London and a United Airlines flight from Madrid, authorities said.
Logan Airport:
A threat also turned up negative for a Delta flight from Paris to Logan Airport in Boston, authorities said.
JFK Airport
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Tue May 26 02:18:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Conservative challenger Duda wins Polish presidential vote</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/apparent-winner-polish-election-sends-message-unity-083337778.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Conservative challenger Duda wins Polish presidential vote
By VANESSA GERA May 25, 2015 7:18 PM

.
.
WARSAW, Poland (AP)  Conservative challenger Andrzej Duda has won Poland's presidential election and ousted the incumbent in a runoff vote, according to official results Monday.
Duda, a right-wing member of the European Parliament, won with 51.55 percent of the vote, the State Electoral Commission said.
President Bronislaw Komorowski, allied with the ruling pro-business Civic Platform, garnered 48.45 percent in the second round of voting on Sunday.
Turnout was 55.34 percent in this nation of more than 37 million people. Duda, a 43-year-old lawyer with experience in the government, will be taking office in August, for a five-year term.
Duda, a Roman Catholic, traveled on Monday to the Jasna Gora shrine in Czestochowa, and prayed there.
"Regardless of whether they voted for me or not, I would like Poles to say after those five years that I really tried to be the president of all Poles, that I tried to answer their needs, that I was such a person," he said.
View gallery
Opposition candidate Andrzej Duda kisses hand of the girl who gave him flowers during celebrates wit
Duda's win is a serious warning for the ruling pro-EU government, in power since 2007, before fall parliamentary elections. It could herald a major political shift in the European Union's sixth-largest economy, a country that has been able to punch above its weight in Europe without belonging to the 19-nation eurozone. Poland's influence is underlined by the fact that one of its own, Donald Tusk, now heads the European Council in Brussels.
Poland's president has limited powers, but is the head of the armed forces, and can propose and veto legislation. On foreign policy issues, the president's role is chiefly ceremonial.
The return of the Law and Justice party to power would cement Poland's turn to the right, create a new dynamic with other European countries and possibly usher in a less welcoming climate for foreign investors.
Law and Justice presents itself as a protector of those who haven't benefited from the capitalist transformation and as a defender of national interests abroad. It is staunchly pro-U.S., but has a sometimes defiant stance toward other European partners, which has created tensions in the past with the EU and neighboring Germany.
Duda says he wants new taxes on the foreign-owned banks and supermarkets to protect Polish interests, suggesting an approach similar to that of Prime Minister Viktor Orban of Hungary. He also said he wants banks returned to Polish control.
View gallery
Opposition candidate Andrzej Duda, right, celebrates with supporters his victory, as first exit poll
Analyst Jacek Kucharczyk said Poland's relations with other European powers will now depend on whether Duda sticks to the relatively moderate agenda he campaigned on or whether he embraces his party leader's more combative foreign policy stance.
"That would be a nightmare scenario for Polish foreign policy, because it would mean getting into conflicts with Germany and anti-EU stunts and aggressive rhetoric toward Russia," said Kucharczyk, president of the Institute of Public Affairs, an independent think tank in Warsaw. "We are in for a bumpy ride. The only question is how bumpy it will be."
Party supporters, however, have been rejoicing since late Sunday when exit polls indicated a victory for Duda. They say the party will do much more to help the many Poles who have not benefited from the country's economic growth, those who face low wages and job insecurity despite a quarter-century of growth. In his campaign speeches, Duda often spoke of the more than 2 million Poles who left in the past decade to seek better economic opportunities abroad.
Supporters also say Duda will do more to fight for the country's economic interests.
"Andrzej Duda is a responsible person and will be a responsible president," said Zbigniew Ziobro, a former justice minister when the Law and Justice party led the government. "He will fulfill Poland's obligations toward NATO and the European Union, but he will definitely put more stress on Poland's interests."
View gallery
Opposition candidate Andrzej Duda, center, with wife Agata, right, and daughter Kinga greet supporte
The White House, in a statement by the press secretary, congratulated Duda and said the U.S. looks forward to working with him "to advance our shared values and to build a more democratic, prosperous and secure region and to deepen the already strong partnership between our two countries,"
In Moscow, the Kremlin said President Vladimir Putin congratulated Duda and "expressed confidence that building constructive relations between Russia and Poland, based on the principles of good neighborly relations and the mutual respect of interests, would strengthen security and stability in Europe."
The rise of Duda also marks a generational shift in Polish politics. He would be the sixth president since the fall of communism in 1989, but at 43, the first who is too young to have been a major participant in the 1980s struggle between communist authorities and the Solidarity opposition movement. He apparently won a significant share of young voters on Sunday.
Duda said Monday he plans to leave Law and Justice, following a tradition of Polish presidents breaking formal ties to their parties to represent the entire nation.
Komorowski left the Civic Platform party when he won the presidency in 2010, but remained closely tied to it. Observers say that link was a key factor in his undoing, with voters punishing him for government corruption scandals and unpopular measures such as a rise in the retirement age.
___
Associated Press writers Monika Scislowska in Warsaw, and Lynn Berry in Moscow, contributed to this report.
Andrzej Duda
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Tue May 26 05:55:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Twister kills 13 in Mexico border city; 12 missing in Texas</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/deadly-storms-swamp-plains-midwest-force-texans-homes-061128015.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Twister kills 13 in Mexico border city; 12 missing in Texas
By SETH ROBBINS and MARK STEVENSON 21 hours ago

RAW: Tornado Slams Mexican Border Town

RAW: Tornado Slams Mexican Border Town
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
RAW: Tornado Slams Mexican Border Town
 Replay video
TX Residents Wake Up to Severe Storm Damage

Memphis&amp;#39; Beale Street remains a blues Mecca as it prepares to say goodbye to B.B. King, the King of the Blues.  (May 26)
Load More
CIUDAD ACUNA, Mexico (AP)  A tornado raged through a city on the U.S.-Mexico border Monday, destroying homes, flinging cars like matchsticks and ripping an infant away from its mother. At least 13 people were killed, authorities said.
In Texas, 12 people were reported missing after the vacation home they were staying in was swept away by rushing floodwaters in a small town popular with tourists.
The baby was also missing after the twister that hit Ciudad Acuna, a city of 125,000 across from Del Rio, Texas, ripped the child's carrier from the mother's hands and sent it flying, said Victor Zamora, interior secretary of the northern state of Coahuila.
Rescue workers dug through the rubble of damaged homes in a race to find victims. The twister hit a seven-block area, which Zamora described as "devastated."
Mayor Evaristo Perez Rivera said 300 people were being treated at local hospitals, and up to 200 homes had been completely destroyed.
"There's nothing standing, not walls, not roofs," said Edgar Gonzalez, a spokesman for the city government, describing some of the destroyed homes in a 3-square kilometer (1 square mile) stretch.
View gallery
A bulldozer clears away debris after a powerful tornado swept past in Ciudad Acuna, northern Mexico,
By midday, 13 people were confirmed dead  10 adults and three infants. At least five people were unaccounted for.
Gonzalez said late Monday night that rescuers were looking for four members of a family who were believed missing, adding that there were still areas of rubble that remained to be searched.
Family members and neighbors gathered around a pickup truck where the bodies of a woman and two children were laid out in the truck's bed, covered with sheets. Two relatives reached down to touch the bodies, covered their eyes and wept.
Photos from the scene showed cars with their hoods torn off, resting upended against single-story houses. One car's frame was bent around the gate of a house. A bus was seen flipped and crumpled on a roadway.
The twister struck not long after daybreak, around the time buses were preparing to take children to school, Zamora said.
View gallery
A vehicle lies on the rooftop of a home after a powerful tornado swept past in Ciudad Acuna, norther
Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto said he planned to travel to Acuna later in the day with officials from government agencies.
In the U.S., a line of storms that stretched from the Gulf of Mexico to the Great Lakes dumped record rainfall on parts of the Plains and Midwest, spawning tornadoes and causing major flooding that forced at least 2,000 Texans from their homes.
Witnesses reported seeing the swollen Blanco River push the vacation house off its foundation and smash it into a bridge. Only pieces of the home have been found, according to Hays County Judge Bert Cobb.
One person who was rescued from the home told workers that the other 12 inside were all connected to two families, Cobb said.
The house was in Wimberley Valley, an area known for its bed-and-breakfast inns and weekend rental cottages.
View gallery
A vehicle lies on the rooftop of a home after a powerful tornado swept past in Ciudad Acuna, norther
Dana Campbell, a retired engineer who lives on a bluff above the river, said the floodwaters left behind damage that resembled the path of a tornado "as far as the eye can see."
The storms were blamed for at least six deaths Saturday and Sunday in the U.S., with three in Oklahoma and three in Texas. A man's body was recovered from a flooded area along the Blanco River, which rose 26 feet in an hour and created huge piles of debris.
Trey Hatt, a spokesman for the Hays County Emergency Operations Center, said Monday that teams had halted their search for the missing at nightfall. He said "the search component is over," meaning that no more survivors are expected to be found in the flood debris, and added that recovery operations would begin Tuesday.
Texas Gov. Greg Abbott flew over parts of the Blanco on Monday, a day after heavy rains pushed the river into surrounding neighborhoods.
Abbott said the storms had "relentless tsunami-type power." He urged communities downstream to monitor flood levels and take the threat seriously.
View gallery
A bulldozer cleans up debris after a powerful tornado swept past in Ciudad Acuna, northern Mexico, M
The governor added 24 counties to his disaster declaration, bringing the total to 37, most in the eastern half of the state.
Among the worst-affected communities were Wimberley and San Marcos, along the Blanco in the corridor between Austin and San Antonio.
About 1,000 homes were damaged throughout Hays County. Five police cars were washed away, and the firehouse was flooded, said Kristi Wyatt, a spokeswoman for San Marcos.
Rivers swelled so quickly that whole communities awoke Sunday surrounded by water. The Blanco crested above 40 feet  more than triple its flood stage of 13 feet. The river swamped Interstate 35 and forced parts of the busy north-south highway to close. Rescuers used pontoon boats and a helicopter to pull people out.
Hundreds of trees along the Blanco were uprooted or snapped, and they collected in piles of debris that soared 20 feet high.
View gallery
People stand near a destroyed vehicle after a powerful tornado swept past in Ciudad Acuna, northern 
"We've got trees in the rafters," said Cherri Maley, property manager of a house where the structure's entire rear portion collapsed with the flooding, carrying away furniture.
"We had the refrigerator in a tree," she said. "I think it's a total loss."
A tornado briefly touched down Sunday in Houston, damaging rooftops, toppling trees, blowing out windows and sending at least two people to a hospital. Fire officials said 10 apartments were heavily damaged and 40 others sustained lesser damage.
Dallas faced severe flooding from the Trinity River, which was expected to crest near 40 feet Monday and lap at the foundations of an industrial park. The Red and Wichita rivers also rose far above flood stage.
___
Stevenson reported from Mexico City.
___
Associated Press writer Paul Weber in San Marcos contributed to this report.
Mexico
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Mon May 25 16:00:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>America celebrates Memorial Day weekend</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/lightbox/america-celebrates-memorial-day-weekend-1432560526-slideshow/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>America Celebrates Memorial Day Weekend
RANDALL HILL May 25, 2015 2:20 PM

.
.
Across America and around the world, towns and cities are celebrating veterans of the United States Armed Forces and the sacrifices they have made. Memorial Day is a federal holiday in America and has been celebrated since the end of the Civil War. (Getty)
Find more news-related pictures in our photo galleries and follow us on Tumblr.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Mon May 25 07:28:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>3 killed, homes washed away in Texas, Okla. floods</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/residents-rescued-flooded-homes-texas-oklahoma-121006744.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Storms flood Plains, Midwest, killing 3, forcing evacuations
By SETH ROBBINS May 25, 2015 12:28 AM

Several missing in Texas as flooding threat grows

Several missing in Texas as flooding threat grows
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Several missing in Texas as flooding threat grows
 Replay video
Life advice for the Class of 2015

Leo and Ruth Zanger have welcomed their 100th grandchild into the world. The couple has 46 great-grandchildren, 53 grandchildren, and one great-great-grandchild.
Load More
SAN MARCOS, Texas (AP)  Record rainfall wreaked havoc across a swath of the Plains and Midwest on Sunday, causing flash floods in normally dry riverbeds, spawning tornadoes and forcing at least 2,000 people in Texas from their homes.
Tornadoes struck, severely damaging an apartment complex in Houston, Texas. A firefighter in Oklahoma was swept to his death while trying to rescue people from high water and a woman in Tulsa died in a traffic-related crash. In Texas, a man's body was recovered from a flooded area along the Blanco River, which rose 26 feet in just one hour and left piles of wreckage 20 feet high, authorities said.
"It looks pretty bad out there," said Hays County emergency management coordinator Kharley Smith, describing the destruction in Wimberley, a community that is part of a fast-growing corridor between Austin and San Antonio. "We do have whole streets with maybe one or two houses left on them and the rest are just slabs," she said, noting late Sunday that three people from Wimberley still weren't accounted for.
From 350 to 400 homes were destroyed in Wimberley, many of them washed away, Smith said. In nearby San Marcos, flooding had damaged about 300 homes, she said.
Authorities also warned people to honor a night-time curfew and stay away from damaged areas, since more rain was on the way, threatening more floods with the ground saturated and waterways overflowing.
Rivers rose so fast that whole communities woke up Sunday surrounded by water. The Blanco crested above 40 feet  more than triple its flood stage of 13 feet  swamping Interstate 35 and forcing parts of the busy north-south highway to close. Rescuers used pontoon boats and a helicopter to pull people out.
View gallery
Gabby Aviles carries her daughter Audrey through floodwaters outside their apartment in Houston, Tue
Dallas also faced severe flooding from the Trinity River, which was expected to crest near 40 feet Monday and lap at the foundations of an industrial park. The Red and Wichita rivers also rose far above flood stage.
Heather Ruiz returned from work early Sunday to ankle-deep water and a muddy couch inside her home in San Marcos. She wasn't sure what to do next. "Pick up the pieces and start all over I guess. Salvage what can be salvaged and replace what needs to be replaced," Ruiz said.
This May is already the wettest on record for several cities in the southern Plains states, with days still to go and more rain on the way. So far this year, Oklahoma City has recorded 27.37 inches of rain. Last year the state's capital got only 4.29 inches.
The reasons include a prolonged warming of Pacific Ocean sea surface temperatures, which generally results in cooler air, coupled with an active southern jet stream and plentiful moisture from the Gulf of Mexico, said Meteorologist Forrest Mitchell at National Weather Service office in Norman, Oklahoma.
"It looks like the rainfall that we're getting now may actually officially end the drought," that has gripped the southern Plains states for years, Mitchell said, noting that moisture now reaches about two feet below the surface of the soil and many lakes and reservoirs are full.
View gallery
David Barry consoles his 5-year-old daughter, Marley, while she tries to sleep in a flood evacuee ro
Wichita Falls was so dry at one point that that it had to get Texas regulatory approval to recycle and treat its wastewater as drinking water dried up. By Sunday, the city reached a rainfall record, nearly 14 inches so far in May.
The storm system pushed northeast into Iowa and Illinois on Sunday after it moved through parts of Colorado, central and North Texas and most of Oklahoma. New flash flood watches were issued Sunday for western Arkansas, Missouri and parts of Kansas, and tornado warnings were issued Sunday night for parts of Illinois, Iowa, Kansas and Missouri.
About 1,000 people were evacuated from homes in Central Texas, where rescuers pulled dozens of people from high water overnight.
Tami Mallow, 41, gathered her three cats at a shelter in San Marcos while her husband put furniture on cinderblocks, and retreated to the second floor with electronics and other valuables as the floodwaters entered.
"He told me there was 2 inches of mud," Mallow said. "I don't know what the cleanup process is going to be."
View gallery
Emir Nevarez, left, and Edgar Mascorro, check out the damage on the rooftop at the Silver Springs Ap
Five San Marcos police cars were washed away and a fire station was flooded, said Kristi Wyatt, a spokeswoman for San Marcos, which imposed a 9 p.m. Sunday curfew.
Wyatt said some 1,000 homes were damaged in San Marcos, Wimberley and elsewhere in Hays County, a fast-growing area between San Antonio and Austin.
A tornado briefly touched down in Houston, damaging rooftops, toppling trees, blowing out windows and sending at least two people to a hospital. The weather service said the tornado struck with winds of about 100 mph at around 6:30 a.m. Sunday. Fire officials said 10 apartments were heavily damaged and 40 others sustained lesser damage.
Some 50 miles north of the city, about 1,000 people were preparing to spend the night away from home. The Montgomery County Office of Emergency Management issued a mandatory evacuation order to more than 400 homes near an earthen dam at Lake Lewis that was at risk of failing due to the heavy rains.
Spokeswoman Miranda Hahs said the dam owned by Entergy Texas is holding, and that it was not clear when residents would be allowed to return home.
View gallery
Heather Williams and Jayden Martinez Corpus, 12, assist the Villegas family in clearing flood-damage
In northeast Oklahoma, Capt. Jason Farley was helping rescue people at about 11:30 p.m. Saturday when he was swept into a drainage ditch. The body of the 20-year veteran was recovered an hour and a half later, Claremore Fire Chief Sean Douglas said. In Tulsa, a woman died in a weather-related traffic crash Saturday, the state Department of Emergency Management said Sunday.
Oklahoma City set a new monthly rainfall total this weekend  18.2 inches through Saturday, beating the previous one of 14.5 in 2013.
Colorado also was water-logged. A mandatory evacuation notice was issued Sunday for residents in the northeastern city of Sterling, and several counties planned to ask the governor for a disaster declaration.
___
Associated Press writers David Warren in Dallas and Tim Talley in Oklahoma City contributed to this report.
Oklahoma
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Mon May 25 17:12:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Candlelight vigil marks 1 month since deadly Nepal quake</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/candlelight-vigil-marks-1-month-since-deadly-nepal-134101751.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Candlelight vigil marks 1 month since deadly Nepal quake
By BINAJ GURUBACHARYA May 25, 2015 10:12 AM

In Wake of Ruins Nepalese Tear Down Destroyed Buildings By Hand

In Wake of Ruins Nepalese Tear Down Destroyed Buildings By Hand
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
In Wake of Ruins Nepalese Tear Down Destroyed Buildings By Hand
 Replay video
Smoked Salmon Gets New Meaning With Cannabis-infused Fish

One of the world&amp;#39;s most distinguished conductors and pianists, Daniel Barenboim, has unveiled a new type of grand piano. He says it is &amp;quot;radically different&amp;quot; to the standard concert grand as it is built with straight, parallel strings that produce a superior sound. Will Gompertz is at the Royal Festival Hall on London&amp;#39;s South Bank where the piano is being unveiled.
Load More
KATHMANDU, Nepal (AP)  Hundreds of people held a candlelight vigil in Nepal's capital Monday evening to mark one month since the earthquake that killed thousands of people and affected millions.
About 200 people gathered at the Brikutimandap grounds in the heart of Kathmandu to remember the dead. They held a minute of silence, lit candles and signed messages in memory of those killed.
"We are here to pray for peace of the people who were killed and to pledge that we will rebuild the country," student Suresh Niraula said.
In the afternoon about 400 people held hands to form a human chain around the site where Dharahara tower once stood. The Dharahara tower, built in 1832 with a 213-step spiral staircase, once offered a panoramic view of the capital. Its collapse in the earthquake crushed at least five dozen people.
The 7.8-magnitude temblor on April 25 and another powerful quake on May 12 together killed nearly 8,700 people and injured 16,800 others.
The government and development agencies are seeking money from donors to help rebuild Nepal.
The United Nations appealed for $423 million to cover key emergency sectors for three months.
U.N. official Jamie McGoldrick said Monday that only 22 percent has been funded, "a very big gap in what we need to make sure that response to this crisis is effective, efficient."
Food, tents and medicine are being flown by helicopters to remote villages in the mountains where roads don't exist or where landslides triggered by the earthquake block the way.
"We are not very well resourced for this operation so we need the international donor community to step in. Working in this country is four or five times more expensive logistically than it is in other countries. So we need the resources or we will not be able to operate," said World Food Program's Richard Regan.
KATHMANDU, Nepal
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Mon May 25 07:49:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police: Pressure cooker from suspicious DC vehicle destroyed</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/police-bomb-squad-checks-suspicious-vehicle-near-capitol-023651095.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Juan Pablo Montoya held off Penske Racing teammate Will Power over the final two laps Sunday to win his second Indianapolis 500. Afterward, he celebrated on a pedal bike. (May 26)
Load More
WASHINGTON (AP)  A bomb squad safely destroyed a pressure cooker found in a "suspicious" vehicle left unattended Sunday afternoon on the National Mall near the U.S. Capitol building and the vehicle's owner was located and arrested, a U.S. Capitol Police spokeswoman said.
Police Lt. Kimberly A. Schneider told The Associated Press that Capitol Police officers on routine patrol spotted the parked, unoccupied vehicle on a street on the mall west of the Capitol around 5 p.m. Sunday.
"Further investigation revealed a pressure cooker, and an odor of gasoline was detected," Schneider said, adding a Capitol Police bomb squad was called in because the vehicle was deemed "suspicious in nature."
She said the squad known as the Hazardous Devices Section destroyed "items of concern in the vehicle including the pressure cooker" at about 7:45 p.m. after temporarily closing off the area on the long Memorial Day holiday weekend. She did not immediately identify the other items but said only that "this safe disruption produced a loud 'bang.'
Asked by AP if the "disruption" involved controlled detonation of the items, she said that was accurate. She also said that follow-up searching of the vehicle detected "nothing hazardous." Her email said the suspicious vehicle was investigated during a Memorial Day Concert in Washington though it was unclear how many people were nearby at the time.
She said the bomb squad intervention came after authorities had set up a security perimeter around the site on 3rd Street in the nation's capital. She said that street was temporarily closed between Independence Avenue and Constitution Avenue while authorities investigated.
View gallery
The U.S. Capitol Dome, in Washington, is surrounded by scaffolding for a long-term repair project, a
After the pressure cooker was destroyed, she said, police conducted a thorough "hand search" of the vehicle and concluded their investigation by about 8:20 p.m. "with negative results and nothing hazardous found."
Asked whether police had specifically identified any threat to public safety, Schneider told AP via email: "If we can't determine whether or not an item is safe/dangerous, we'd have to treat it as dangerous until we determine otherwise. She added that was "why the items were safely disrupted, out of an abundance of caution." She didn't elaborate.
She added that the vehicle owner was located and her statement identified him as Israel Shimeles of the Washington suburb of Alexandria, Virginia. The statement said Shimeles was arrested by Capitol Police and charged with "Operating After Revocation" and that he was being processed Sunday evening at the police headquarters building.
It wasn't immediately known if he had an attorney. Schneider didn't elaborate on the charge.
Schneider also said the city's Metropolitan Police, U.S. Park Police, the U.S. Secret Service, the FBI Joint Terrorism Task Force were assisting Capitol Police.
The FBI did not immediately return a call for comment late Sunday.
Authorities have noted that pressure cookers have been used in the past to create explosive devices. Three people were killed and more than 260 others wounded in April 2013 when two pressure-cooker bombs were set off near the finish line of the Boston Marathon.
Capitol Police
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Mon May 25 05:34:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thousands of bikers gather in Washington to honor vets</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/thousands-bikers-gather-washington-honor-vets-023451819.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thousands of bikers gather in Washington to honor vets
By John Clarke May 24, 2015 10:34 PM

Rolling Thunder brings out emotional tributes to fallen

Rolling Thunder brings out emotional tributes to fallen
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Rolling Thunder brings out emotional tributes to fallen
 Replay video
Aid trickles into war-ravaged Yemen

Load More
By John Clarke
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - One week after a gathering of biker gangs in Texas that resulted in nine deaths and 170 arrests, thousands of motorcycle riders roared into the nation's capital Sunday to honor military veterans, prisoners of war and soldiers missing in action.
Rolling Thunder, an annual event that has been bringing motorcyclists and spectators to the National Mall in downtown Washington since 1988, started the "Ride for Freedom" at the Pentagon in Virginia, crossed the Potomac River over the Memorial Bridge and circled the Mall.
Organizers estimated that more than a million bikers and spectators attended, making it the largest one-day motorcycle gathering in the world, Rolling Thunder spokeswoman Nancy Regg said.
There were no reported criminal incidents at the event, Regg said.
"They're not here to party and get drunk," she said of Rolling Thunder, named after a 1965 bombing campaign against North Vietnam. "No fights. No attitudes."
View gallery
Riders take part in the Rolling Thunder First Amendment Demonstration motorcycle run on Memorial Day
Crowds cheered and waved as bikers throttled their engines and waved back. Many bikers rode with U.S. or Prisoner of War flags. A few rode with Confederate flags.
Bikers and veterans could be found scattered throughout the National Mall. Many gathered at the Vietnam and Korean War memorials. Some relaxed in the shade and drank beer.
A stage below the Lincoln Memorial hosted speakers and musicians, including former Wisconsin Governor Tommy Thompson, singer Nancy Sinatra and actor Robert Patrick.
"I thank you for your service and I thank you for my freedom," Patrick told the crowd. "Each and everyone of you are the real deal."
Throughout the day, at the edge of the stage, a scrawny, bearded man in tattered fatigues sat locked in a bamboo cage holding a sign reading "Never Forget."
Sunday's ride was part of a weekend of events that included a "blessing of the bikes" outside the National Cathedral and a day-long barbecue hosted by motorcycle manufacturer Harley-Davidson.
There were several other biker events across the country planned for the Memorial Day weekend. Rallies were held in New Mexico, Mississippi, Missouri and South Carolina with heightened security, according to media reports.
Last Sunday, 170 people were arrested in connection with the shootout among rival bikers that left nine dead and 18 wounded and turned a Waco, Texas restaurant into a blood-soaked crime scene.
(Reporting by John Clarke in Washington, D.C.; Editing by Mary Wisniewski and Eric Walsh)
National Mall
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
