<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="zeenews-india">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title> Burundi crisis escalates as opposition boycotts elections</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/burundi-crisis-escalates-as-opposition-boycotts-elections_1620555.html </Link>
        <Description>  Opposition parties will boycott Burundi`s elections in protest at the president`s bid for a third term and on concerns that voting will not be fair, party officials said, escalating the nation`s worst political crisis since a civil war ended in 2005.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Burundi crisis escalates as opposition boycotts elections
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:45
0
Comment
Bujumbura: Opposition parties will boycott Burundi`s elections in protest at the president`s bid for a third term and on concerns that voting will not be fair, party officials said, escalating the nation`s worst political crisis since a civil war ended in 2005.
Weeks of unrest followed President Pierre Nkurunziza announcement in April that he would seek another five years in office. He justified the move, which his opponents said was unconstitutional and foreign governments have criticised, on the basis of a favourable court ruling.
Almost 127,000 people, more than 1 percent of the population, have fled to neighbouring states and more are leaving, many voicing worries about possible violence during voting, the U.N. refugee agency UNHCR said.
Announcing the boycott by the group of 17 parties of the July 15 presidential election as well as a parliamentary poll scheduled for Monday, Francois Nyamoya, secretary general of the MSD party, told Reuters that voting would "not be credible."
The dispute has plunged the poor African nation into crisis, raising concerns in a region with a history of ethnic conflict and leading some Western donors to scale back aid.
Protests erupted after Nkurunziza announced his re-election bid, leading to about six weeks of almost daily clashes between stone-throwing demonstrators and police, who were seen firing into the ranks of angry youths.
The streets of the capital, where most of the rallies were held, have calmed but political tensions remain. The election schedule has already been pushed back several weeks because of the unrest.
Frederic Bamvuginyumvira of the Frodebu party said his and other opposition parties opposed the new timetable that they said was drawn up without consultation, which the government denies.
He repeated calls for the ruling party`s Imbonerakure youth wing to be disarmed, echoing comments from Western and African states. The ruling CNDD-FDD denies the youths have been armed.
One of Burundi`s vice presidents, Gervais Rufyikiri, said this week he had fled the country after he was threatened for denouncing Nkurunziza`s bid, an allegation denied by the government.
Government officials have repeatedly said they would guarantee a fair vote. When opposition parties threatened a boycott in the past, it said the ruling party`s rivals were worried about losing at the ballot box and so wanted to stay away.
Opponents say the CENI election commission that will oversee voting is biased.
Two of the commission`s five members resigned after the crisis erupted, including its vice president who fled Burundi. They have since been replaced.
UNHCR offices in the region "have been noting a steady increase in arrivals of Burundi refugees" as Burundi gears up for Monday`s vote, UNHCR spokesman Adrian Edwards told a news briefing in Geneva on Friday.
"People are telling us they are fleeing the general political instability, election-related violence, armed attacks and arbitrary arrests," he said, adding they included about 62,000 in Tanzania and 45,000 in Rwanda.
He said others were thought to have left but have not registered as refugees.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:45
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title> Tourist hotel in Tunisia&amp;#38;#039;s Sousse attacked: Security source</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/tourist-hotel-in-tunisias-sousse-attacked-security-source_1620551.html </Link>
        <Description>  A tourist hotel in the Tunisian town of Sousse has been attacked, a security source said, adding an exchange of gunfire was reported at the scene.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Zee Media Bureau
Tunis: At least 27 people have been killed in a terror attack at a tourist hotel in Tunisian town of Sousse,according to an interior ministry official.
The attack was on Imperial Marhaba hotel and the casualties includes guests as well, as per local reports.
A security source said that a gunman was killed in an exchange of gunfire at the scene. However, it is unclear whetherthere were other assailants.
Tunisia has been on high alert since March when Islamist militant gunmen attacked the Bardo museum in Tunis, killing a group of foreign tourists in one of the worst attacks in a decade in the North African country.
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:43
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title> French attack suspect `linked` to Salafist movement: Minister</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/french-attack-suspect-linked-to-salafist-movement-minister_1620541.html </Link>
        <Description>  The suspect arrested in connection with the attack Friday on a French gas factory was investigated nine years ago for radicalisation and has links to the Salafist movement, Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Paris: The suspect arrested in connection with the attack Friday on a French gas factory was investigated nine years ago for radicalisation and has links to the Salafist movement, Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said.
"He was investigated in 2006 for radicalisation, but (the probe) was not renewed in 2008. He had no criminal record," Cazeneuve said.
"This individual has links with the Salafist movement, but had not been identified as having participated in activities of a terrorist nature."

First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:30
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title> Thai police arrest 14 students in anti-junta protest</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/thai-police-arrest-14-students-in-anti-junta-protest_1620540.html </Link>
        <Description>  Police in Thailand on Friday arrested 14 students who had been protesting against the ruling junta, in defiance of a ban on public gatherings.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Thai police arrest 14 students in anti-junta protest
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:28
0
Comment
Bangkok: Police in Thailand on Friday arrested 14 students who had been protesting against the ruling junta, in defiance of a ban on public gatherings.
Thailand`s military overthrew the previous democratic government last year after months of political unrest. The junta has since stifled dissent, barring political gatherings and debate.
The students, part of a coalition of university groups from around Thailand, held street demonstrations for three days in Bangkok this week to protest against the junta, known as the National Council for Peace and Order.
"We`ve caught them all, according to the arrest warrants, and the next step is to tell them what they are accused of," Wutthichai Suponthawit, deputy superintendent of the capital`s Samran Rat police station, told Reuters.
"We will now jail them."
Thailand`s army chief accused some politicians of backing the student groups, but did not identify them.
"They are the group that is not satisfied with the administration of this government," General Udomdej Sitabutr told reporters earlier on Friday.
Around 80 students held a 10-hour protest outside a Bangkok police station on Wednesday, brandishing signs that read "Peace" and "We want power for the people" or banners reading "No coup".
Last month, 40 student activists were arrested after holding peaceful rallies on the first anniversary of the May 22 coup.
All were released but at least 11 were charged with violating the junta`s ban on political activity and face trial in military court, with jail terms of a year, if found guilty.
The 2014 coup ousted the government of Prime Minister Yingluck Shinawatra, Thailand`s first female prime minister and a scion of the Shinawatra political family.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:28
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title> Vatican signs historic accord with Palestine</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/vatican-signs-historic-accord-with-palestine_1620538.html </Link>
        <Description>  The Vatican today signed a historic first accord with Palestine, two years after officially recognising it as a state.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Vatican signs historic accord with Palestine
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:18
0
Comment
Vatican City: The Vatican today signed a historic first accord with Palestine, two years after officially recognising it as a state.
The accord, a treaty covering the life and activity of the Church in Palestine, was the first since the Vatican recognised the Palestinian state in February 2013.
The treaty, which took 15 years of negotiations to complete, was agreed in principle last month and bitterly condemned by Israel as a setback for the peace process.
The Vatican's recognition of the state of Palestine followed a November 12 vote in favour of recognition by the UN General Assembly.
Vatican officials have described it as reflecting the Church's desire to see the conflict in the Holy Land resolved by a "two-state" solution.
The Palestinian Authority considers the Vatican one of 136 countries to have recognised Palestine as a state, although the number is disputed and several recognitions by what are now European Union member states date back to the Soviet era.
The Vatican has had diplomatic relations with Israel since 1993 but has yet to conclude an accord on the Church's rights in the Jewish state which has been under discussion since 1999.
AFP
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:18
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title> It was a terrorist attack: French Prez Hollande</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/it-was-a-terrorist-attack-french-prez-hollande_1620537.html </Link>
        <Description>  French President Francois Hollande said Friday that a suspected Islamist assault on a gas factory in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates was a &amp;#34;terrorist attack&amp;#34;.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Paris: French President Francois Hollande said Friday that a suspected Islamist assault on a gas factory in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates was a "terrorist attack".
Hollande, who was rushing back to France from an EU summit to deal with the crisis, added that the person who launched the attack has been identified and that there may have been a second attacker.
"This attack was in a vehicle driven by one person, perhaps accompanied by another, which rammed its way at high speed into this establishment which contained bottles of gas," Hollande told a hastily-convened news conference.
"The intent was without doubt to cause an explosion. It was a terrorist attack."
The killing came nearly six months after the Islamist attacks in and around Paris that killed 17 people in January, starting with a shooting at satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo.
AFP
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:10
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title> China denounces US hacking accusation as `absurd`</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/china-denounces-us-hacking-accusation-as-absurd_1620536.html </Link>
        <Description>  Beijing on Friday denounced as &amp;#34;absurd logic&amp;#34; accusations by the head of US intelligence that China was the main suspect in a massive hack of government data files in Washington.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>China denounces US hacking accusation as `absurd`
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:08
0
Comment
Beijing: Beijing on Friday denounced as "absurd logic" accusations by the head of US intelligence that China was the main suspect in a massive hack of government data files in Washington.
James Clapper, US director of national intelligence, said China was "the leading suspect" behind the breach affecting personal data of millions of US government employees, which was revealed earlier this month.
Chinese foreign ministry spokesman Lu Kang responded: "We have noticed that the US is still investigating, but feels that China is responsible. This is absurd logic.
"We understand this as showing the US has adopted the presumption of guilt rather than the presumption of innocence," he added at a regular briefing.
The US has in recent years blamed several hacks on Beijing, including some it says were carried out by members of the Chinese military.
Cybersecurity specialists said the breach of data on at least four million current and former federal employees appeared to be part of an effort to build a database for espionage.
Soon after the breach was made public, US officials told media they believed China was involved. Beijing rebuffed the claims as "unscientific".
The US Office of Personnel Management said that employees, retirees, contractors and job applicants may have had their personal information compromised in the breach.
Some reports have said the number affected may be 14 million or higher, after officials said the total was still being determined.
Facing an outcry from employees and lawmakers, the US administration has announced new steps to boost the security of its online records, including in some parts that still use decades-old technology.

First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:08
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title> France launches terror investigation after decapitated body found in Lyon</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/france-launches-terror-investigation-after-decapitated-body-found-in-lyon_1620534.html </Link>
        <Description>  France on Friday launched a terror investigation after a decapitated body and a flag with Islamic inscriptions on it were found in Lyon.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>France launches terror investigation after decapitated body found in Lyon
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:07
0
Comment
London: France on Friday launched a terror investigation after a decapitated body and a flag with Islamic inscriptions on it were found in Lyon.
Another person was injured in what is suspected to be an attack on a US gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier near the city of Lyon, reported the BBC.
Reports claimed that the attack was carried out by two assailants who drove into a factory carrying the flag.
Meanwhile, the anti-terror police have nabbed a suspect, officials said.
In the wake of the attack, French President Francois Hollande will leave the European Union summit in Brussels this afternoon and return to France.Security has been beefed up at sensitive sites around Lyon in the aftermath of the attack.
This suspected terror attack comes nearly six months after the infamous strikes at the Charlie Hebdo offices in Paris, which led to the death of 12 people.

First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:07
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title> Indonesian anti-drugs chief warns against foreign boyfriends</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/indonesian-anti-drugs-chief-warns-against-foreign-boyfriends_1620523.html </Link>
        <Description>  Indonesia`s anti-narcotics chief Friday warned women in the country to be careful when dating foreigners, suggesting they could be tricked into becoming drug mules.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Indonesian anti-drugs chief warns against foreign boyfriends
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 16:49
0
Comment
Jakarta: Indonesia`s anti-narcotics chief Friday warned women in the country to be careful when dating foreigners, suggesting they could be tricked into becoming drug mules.
The remarks were the latest salvo in Indonesia`s war on narcotics and came after eight drug convicts, including seven foreigners, were put to death by firing squad in April, sparking international anger.
Head of the national anti-drugs agency, Anang Iskandar, said that many Indonesian women were languishing in prisons abroad because they were "easily tricked into drug-trafficking".
"Do not be careless in relationships with foreigners," he warned in comments to reporters in Jakarta to mark the United Nations International Day Against Drug Abuse.
"They give gifts of plane tickets, you have just got to know them and started dating. It is easy to be tempted, you have to be careful."
Indonesia has faced criticism for focusing heavily on the role of foreigners in the country`s drug problems, and failing to do enough to combat official complicity in the illicit trade.
However President Joko Widodo on Friday vowed to focus more on Indonesian security officials involved in drug-dealing and prisons where criminals run narcotics networks from behind bars.
He also reiterated his tough stance, saying: "Drug abuse is destroying the future generation. There is no other option than to declare a war on drugs."
Since taking office last year, Widodo has been a vocal supporter of the death penalty for drug offences, rejecting clemency pleas for narcotics convicts on death row.
He says dozens of people die every day due to drugs in Indonesia but observers have questioned his claims, and believe he is more focused on looking tough and regaining popularity after political missteps.
French drug convict Serge Atlaoui, who was originally due to be executed in April, this week lost an appeal against his death sentence and Jakarta says he has no more legal options to avoid the firing squad.
AFP
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 16:49
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title> Deadly explosion at Shiite mosque in Kuwait&amp;#38;#039;s capital</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/kuwait-mosque-bombing-kills-13-isis-claims-responsibility_1620520.html </Link>
        <Description> An explosion ripped through a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital during the main weekly prayers Friday causing casualties, witnesses and a security official said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait mosque bombing kills 13; ISIS claims responsibility
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:53
0
Comment
Kuwait City: The Islamic State group claimed a suicide bombing that ripped through a Shiite mosque in Kuwait on Friday that medics say killed at least 13 people.
The IS-affiliated group in Saudi Arabia, calling itself Najd Province, said militant Abu Suleiman al-Muwahhid carried out the attack on the mosque, which it claimed was spreading Shiite teachings among Sunni Muslims.
ISIS, a radical Sunni Muslim group, considers Shiites to be heretics.
Medics said the suicide bombing killed "at least 13 people, while 25 others were hospitalised."
Najd Province claimed similar bombings against Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.

First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 16:47
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title> Burundi crisis escalates as opposition boycotts elections</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/burundi-crisis-escalates-as-opposition-boycotts-elections_1620555.html </Link>
        <Description>  Opposition parties will boycott Burundi`s elections in protest at the president`s bid for a third term and on concerns that voting will not be fair, party officials said, escalating the nation`s worst political crisis since a civil war ended in 2005.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Burundi crisis escalates as opposition boycotts elections
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:45
0
Comment
Bujumbura: Opposition parties will boycott Burundi`s elections in protest at the president`s bid for a third term and on concerns that voting will not be fair, party officials said, escalating the nation`s worst political crisis since a civil war ended in 2005.
Weeks of unrest followed President Pierre Nkurunziza announcement in April that he would seek another five years in office. He justified the move, which his opponents said was unconstitutional and foreign governments have criticised, on the basis of a favourable court ruling.
Almost 127,000 people, more than 1 percent of the population, have fled to neighbouring states and more are leaving, many voicing worries about possible violence during voting, the U.N. refugee agency UNHCR said.
Announcing the boycott by the group of 17 parties of the July 15 presidential election as well as a parliamentary poll scheduled for Monday, Francois Nyamoya, secretary general of the MSD party, told Reuters that voting would "not be credible."
The dispute has plunged the poor African nation into crisis, raising concerns in a region with a history of ethnic conflict and leading some Western donors to scale back aid.
Protests erupted after Nkurunziza announced his re-election bid, leading to about six weeks of almost daily clashes between stone-throwing demonstrators and police, who were seen firing into the ranks of angry youths.
The streets of the capital, where most of the rallies were held, have calmed but political tensions remain. The election schedule has already been pushed back several weeks because of the unrest.
Frederic Bamvuginyumvira of the Frodebu party said his and other opposition parties opposed the new timetable that they said was drawn up without consultation, which the government denies.
He repeated calls for the ruling party`s Imbonerakure youth wing to be disarmed, echoing comments from Western and African states. The ruling CNDD-FDD denies the youths have been armed.
One of Burundi`s vice presidents, Gervais Rufyikiri, said this week he had fled the country after he was threatened for denouncing Nkurunziza`s bid, an allegation denied by the government.
Government officials have repeatedly said they would guarantee a fair vote. When opposition parties threatened a boycott in the past, it said the ruling party`s rivals were worried about losing at the ballot box and so wanted to stay away.
Opponents say the CENI election commission that will oversee voting is biased.
Two of the commission`s five members resigned after the crisis erupted, including its vice president who fled Burundi. They have since been replaced.
UNHCR offices in the region "have been noting a steady increase in arrivals of Burundi refugees" as Burundi gears up for Monday`s vote, UNHCR spokesman Adrian Edwards told a news briefing in Geneva on Friday.
"People are telling us they are fleeing the general political instability, election-related violence, armed attacks and arbitrary arrests," he said, adding they included about 62,000 in Tanzania and 45,000 in Rwanda.
He said others were thought to have left but have not registered as refugees.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:45
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title> Tourist hotel in Tunisia&amp;#38;#039;s Sousse attacked: Security source</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/tourist-hotel-in-tunisias-sousse-attacked-security-source_1620551.html </Link>
        <Description>  A tourist hotel in the Tunisian town of Sousse has been attacked, a security source said, adding an exchange of gunfire was reported at the scene.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Zee Media Bureau
Tunis: At least 27 people have been killed in a terror attack at a tourist hotel in Tunisian town of Sousse,according to an interior ministry official.
The attack was on Imperial Marhaba hotel and the casualties includes guests as well, as per local reports.
A security source said that a gunman was killed in an exchange of gunfire at the scene. However, it is unclear whetherthere were other assailants.
Tunisia has been on high alert since March when Islamist militant gunmen attacked the Bardo museum in Tunis, killing a group of foreign tourists in one of the worst attacks in a decade in the North African country.
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:43
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title> French attack suspect `linked` to Salafist movement: Minister</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/french-attack-suspect-linked-to-salafist-movement-minister_1620541.html </Link>
        <Description>  The suspect arrested in connection with the attack Friday on a French gas factory was investigated nine years ago for radicalisation and has links to the Salafist movement, Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Paris: The suspect arrested in connection with the attack Friday on a French gas factory was investigated nine years ago for radicalisation and has links to the Salafist movement, Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said.
"He was investigated in 2006 for radicalisation, but (the probe) was not renewed in 2008. He had no criminal record," Cazeneuve said.
"This individual has links with the Salafist movement, but had not been identified as having participated in activities of a terrorist nature."

First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:30
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title> Thai police arrest 14 students in anti-junta protest</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/thai-police-arrest-14-students-in-anti-junta-protest_1620540.html </Link>
        <Description>  Police in Thailand on Friday arrested 14 students who had been protesting against the ruling junta, in defiance of a ban on public gatherings.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Thai police arrest 14 students in anti-junta protest
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:28
0
Comment
Bangkok: Police in Thailand on Friday arrested 14 students who had been protesting against the ruling junta, in defiance of a ban on public gatherings.
Thailand`s military overthrew the previous democratic government last year after months of political unrest. The junta has since stifled dissent, barring political gatherings and debate.
The students, part of a coalition of university groups from around Thailand, held street demonstrations for three days in Bangkok this week to protest against the junta, known as the National Council for Peace and Order.
"We`ve caught them all, according to the arrest warrants, and the next step is to tell them what they are accused of," Wutthichai Suponthawit, deputy superintendent of the capital`s Samran Rat police station, told Reuters.
"We will now jail them."
Thailand`s army chief accused some politicians of backing the student groups, but did not identify them.
"They are the group that is not satisfied with the administration of this government," General Udomdej Sitabutr told reporters earlier on Friday.
Around 80 students held a 10-hour protest outside a Bangkok police station on Wednesday, brandishing signs that read "Peace" and "We want power for the people" or banners reading "No coup".
Last month, 40 student activists were arrested after holding peaceful rallies on the first anniversary of the May 22 coup.
All were released but at least 11 were charged with violating the junta`s ban on political activity and face trial in military court, with jail terms of a year, if found guilty.
The 2014 coup ousted the government of Prime Minister Yingluck Shinawatra, Thailand`s first female prime minister and a scion of the Shinawatra political family.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:28
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title> Vatican signs historic accord with Palestine</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/vatican-signs-historic-accord-with-palestine_1620538.html </Link>
        <Description>  The Vatican today signed a historic first accord with Palestine, two years after officially recognising it as a state.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Vatican signs historic accord with Palestine
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:18
0
Comment
Vatican City: The Vatican today signed a historic first accord with Palestine, two years after officially recognising it as a state.
The accord, a treaty covering the life and activity of the Church in Palestine, was the first since the Vatican recognised the Palestinian state in February 2013.
The treaty, which took 15 years of negotiations to complete, was agreed in principle last month and bitterly condemned by Israel as a setback for the peace process.
The Vatican's recognition of the state of Palestine followed a November 12 vote in favour of recognition by the UN General Assembly.
Vatican officials have described it as reflecting the Church's desire to see the conflict in the Holy Land resolved by a "two-state" solution.
The Palestinian Authority considers the Vatican one of 136 countries to have recognised Palestine as a state, although the number is disputed and several recognitions by what are now European Union member states date back to the Soviet era.
The Vatican has had diplomatic relations with Israel since 1993 but has yet to conclude an accord on the Church's rights in the Jewish state which has been under discussion since 1999.
AFP
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:18
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title> It was a terrorist attack: French Prez Hollande</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/it-was-a-terrorist-attack-french-prez-hollande_1620537.html </Link>
        <Description>  French President Francois Hollande said Friday that a suspected Islamist assault on a gas factory in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates was a &amp;#34;terrorist attack&amp;#34;.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Paris: French President Francois Hollande said Friday that a suspected Islamist assault on a gas factory in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates was a "terrorist attack".
Hollande, who was rushing back to France from an EU summit to deal with the crisis, added that the person who launched the attack has been identified and that there may have been a second attacker.
"This attack was in a vehicle driven by one person, perhaps accompanied by another, which rammed its way at high speed into this establishment which contained bottles of gas," Hollande told a hastily-convened news conference.
"The intent was without doubt to cause an explosion. It was a terrorist attack."
The killing came nearly six months after the Islamist attacks in and around Paris that killed 17 people in January, starting with a shooting at satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo.
AFP
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:10
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title> China denounces US hacking accusation as `absurd`</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/china-denounces-us-hacking-accusation-as-absurd_1620536.html </Link>
        <Description>  Beijing on Friday denounced as &amp;#34;absurd logic&amp;#34; accusations by the head of US intelligence that China was the main suspect in a massive hack of government data files in Washington.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>China denounces US hacking accusation as `absurd`
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:08
0
Comment
Beijing: Beijing on Friday denounced as "absurd logic" accusations by the head of US intelligence that China was the main suspect in a massive hack of government data files in Washington.
James Clapper, US director of national intelligence, said China was "the leading suspect" behind the breach affecting personal data of millions of US government employees, which was revealed earlier this month.
Chinese foreign ministry spokesman Lu Kang responded: "We have noticed that the US is still investigating, but feels that China is responsible. This is absurd logic.
"We understand this as showing the US has adopted the presumption of guilt rather than the presumption of innocence," he added at a regular briefing.
The US has in recent years blamed several hacks on Beijing, including some it says were carried out by members of the Chinese military.
Cybersecurity specialists said the breach of data on at least four million current and former federal employees appeared to be part of an effort to build a database for espionage.
Soon after the breach was made public, US officials told media they believed China was involved. Beijing rebuffed the claims as "unscientific".
The US Office of Personnel Management said that employees, retirees, contractors and job applicants may have had their personal information compromised in the breach.
Some reports have said the number affected may be 14 million or higher, after officials said the total was still being determined.
Facing an outcry from employees and lawmakers, the US administration has announced new steps to boost the security of its online records, including in some parts that still use decades-old technology.

First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:08
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title> France launches terror investigation after decapitated body found in Lyon</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/france-launches-terror-investigation-after-decapitated-body-found-in-lyon_1620534.html </Link>
        <Description>  France on Friday launched a terror investigation after a decapitated body and a flag with Islamic inscriptions on it were found in Lyon.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>France launches terror investigation after decapitated body found in Lyon
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:07
0
Comment
London: France on Friday launched a terror investigation after a decapitated body and a flag with Islamic inscriptions on it were found in Lyon.
Another person was injured in what is suspected to be an attack on a US gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier near the city of Lyon, reported the BBC.
Reports claimed that the attack was carried out by two assailants who drove into a factory carrying the flag.
Meanwhile, the anti-terror police have nabbed a suspect, officials said.
In the wake of the attack, French President Francois Hollande will leave the European Union summit in Brussels this afternoon and return to France.Security has been beefed up at sensitive sites around Lyon in the aftermath of the attack.
This suspected terror attack comes nearly six months after the infamous strikes at the Charlie Hebdo offices in Paris, which led to the death of 12 people.

First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:07
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title> Indonesian anti-drugs chief warns against foreign boyfriends</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/indonesian-anti-drugs-chief-warns-against-foreign-boyfriends_1620523.html </Link>
        <Description>  Indonesia`s anti-narcotics chief Friday warned women in the country to be careful when dating foreigners, suggesting they could be tricked into becoming drug mules.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Indonesian anti-drugs chief warns against foreign boyfriends
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 16:49
0
Comment
Jakarta: Indonesia`s anti-narcotics chief Friday warned women in the country to be careful when dating foreigners, suggesting they could be tricked into becoming drug mules.
The remarks were the latest salvo in Indonesia`s war on narcotics and came after eight drug convicts, including seven foreigners, were put to death by firing squad in April, sparking international anger.
Head of the national anti-drugs agency, Anang Iskandar, said that many Indonesian women were languishing in prisons abroad because they were "easily tricked into drug-trafficking".
"Do not be careless in relationships with foreigners," he warned in comments to reporters in Jakarta to mark the United Nations International Day Against Drug Abuse.
"They give gifts of plane tickets, you have just got to know them and started dating. It is easy to be tempted, you have to be careful."
Indonesia has faced criticism for focusing heavily on the role of foreigners in the country`s drug problems, and failing to do enough to combat official complicity in the illicit trade.
However President Joko Widodo on Friday vowed to focus more on Indonesian security officials involved in drug-dealing and prisons where criminals run narcotics networks from behind bars.
He also reiterated his tough stance, saying: "Drug abuse is destroying the future generation. There is no other option than to declare a war on drugs."
Since taking office last year, Widodo has been a vocal supporter of the death penalty for drug offences, rejecting clemency pleas for narcotics convicts on death row.
He says dozens of people die every day due to drugs in Indonesia but observers have questioned his claims, and believe he is more focused on looking tough and regaining popularity after political missteps.
French drug convict Serge Atlaoui, who was originally due to be executed in April, this week lost an appeal against his death sentence and Jakarta says he has no more legal options to avoid the firing squad.
AFP
First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 16:49
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title> Deadly explosion at Shiite mosque in Kuwait&amp;#38;#039;s capital</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/kuwait-mosque-bombing-kills-13-isis-claims-responsibility_1620520.html </Link>
        <Description> An explosion ripped through a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital during the main weekly prayers Friday causing casualties, witnesses and a security official said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait mosque bombing kills 13; ISIS claims responsibility
Last Updated: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 17:53
0
Comment
Kuwait City: The Islamic State group claimed a suicide bombing that ripped through a Shiite mosque in Kuwait on Friday that medics say killed at least 13 people.
The IS-affiliated group in Saudi Arabia, calling itself Najd Province, said militant Abu Suleiman al-Muwahhid carried out the attack on the mosque, which it claimed was spreading Shiite teachings among Sunni Muslims.
ISIS, a radical Sunni Muslim group, considers Shiites to be heretics.
Medics said the suicide bombing killed "at least 13 people, while 25 others were hospitalised."
Najd Province claimed similar bombings against Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.

First Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 - 16:47
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
