<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="zeenews-india">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title> Albury rape: Mayor Kevin Mack apologises for &amp;#38;#039;&amp;#38;#039;victim blaming&amp;#38;#039;&amp;#38;#039; comment</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/albury-rape-mayor-kevin-mack-apologises-for-victim-blaming-comment_1588354.html </Link>
        <Description>  Shortly after Mayor Kevin Mack encouraged women to not walk alone and to have someone with them &amp;#34;at all times&amp;#34; as that in itself, was an &amp;#34;invitation&amp;#34; for someone to take advantage of them, he has now apologised for making the comment.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Melbourne: Shortly after Mayor Kevin Mack encouraged women to not walk alone and to have someone with them "at all times" as that in itself, was an "invitation" for someone to take advantage of them, he has now apologised for making the comment.
Mack had made the statement while reacting to the rape of a 17-year-old girl in Albury, southern New South Wales, on Tuesday. He later clarified by saying that the girl had not done "anything wrong," reported ABC News.
The reaction drew widespread condemnation on social media, with many accusing the mayor of blaming the victim.
The girl was allegedly raped "at gunpoint" by three men while returning home from work. 
ANI
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 18:17
0
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title> UN urged to `shed all light` on Central African Republic child sex abuse scandal</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/un-urged-to-shed-all-light-on-central-african-republic-child-sex-abuse-scandal_1588350.html </Link>
        <Description>  Save the Children has urged France and the United Nations to &amp;#34;shed all light&amp;#34; on accusations that French soldiers sexually abused hungry children in the Central African Republic.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>UN urged to `shed all light` on Central African Republic child sex abuse scandal
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 18:11
0
Comment
Libreville: Save the Children has urged France and the United Nations to "shed all light" on accusations that French soldiers sexually abused hungry children in the Central African Republic.
"If the facts are borne out, it is essential to take the firmest measures against those behind them," the global charity said in a statement sent to AFP on Friday.
According to a French judicial source, 14 peacekeeping soldiers deployed to the chaos-ridden nation to help restore order after a 2013 coup are implicated in a probe into the alleged sexual abuse of several children -- the youngest just nine -- who had begged for something to eat.
French President Francois Hollande vowed Thursday to "show no mercy" if "some soldiers have behaved badly", a day after British newspaper The Guardian broke the story based on a leaked UN report.
The United Nations should "ensure that the child victims of these abuses are protected and benefit from all the psycho-social support that they need," said Natasha Quist, Save The Children`s director for west and central Africa, quoted in the statement in French from Dakar.
Quist urged "the United Nations and the French authorities to take all necessary measures to bring full light to bear on this affair, notably by being transparent about the investigations announced to have started."
"Humanitarian workers and elements of the peacekeeping forces have on several occasions been implicated in cases of the violation of children`s rights, including rape or exchanging food for sexual favours," Save the Children said.
"Soldiers are in the front line in complex conflict situations and are often the only ones who can make sure that children`s rights are protected," argued the charity.
The leaked report also accuses soldiers from Chad and Equatorial Guinea of abuses in the deeply poor, landlocked nation where an African peacekeeping mission was handed over to the United Nations in September last year.
A European Union military mission also operates in the country, ravaged since the 2013 coup by a conflict that took on an unprecedented religious dimension, pitting mainly Muslim former rebels against Christian vigilantes at the expense of the civilian population.
In the wake of the report in The Guardian, the French defence ministry on Wednesday said that the government had been alerted to accusations of sexual abuse against children by the UN High Commission for Human Rights in July 2014.
Prosecutors in Paris then opened an investigation into the reports, the ministry said, pledging to ensure that "the truth be found" and "the strongest penalties" imposed on those found guilty.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 18:11
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title> Kremlin says too early to speak of Ukraine peacekeeping mission</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/kremlin-says-too-early-to-speak-of-ukraine-peacekeeping-mission_1588327.html </Link>
        <Description>  Russia said on Friday that it was premature to discuss the deployment of a peacekeeping mission in war-torn eastern Ukraine before a peace deal agreed in February is implemented in full.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Kremlin says too early to speak of Ukraine peacekeeping mission
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:37
0
Comment
Moscow: Russia said on Friday that it was premature to discuss the deployment of a peacekeeping mission in war-torn eastern Ukraine before a peace deal agreed in February is implemented in full.
"Before the text of the Minsk agreement and its concrete points are implemented we believe that it would be absolutely wrong to raise any other issues including that about peacekeepers," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told Russian news agencies.
On Thursday, the Ukrainian presidency said Russian President Vladimir Putin was open to the deployment of a peacekeeping mission in Ukraine, after the leaders of both countries spoke by phone with their French and German counterparts.
"In the context of the discussion of ways towards a peaceful resolution (of the conflict), President Putin has accepted the possibility of deploying a peacekeeping contingent to the Donbass region," the Ukrainian presidency said in a statement.
Moscow however made no mention of a possible peacekeeping force in its own statement issued after the talks.
The French presidency also made no such reference, saying in a statement that the parties had reviewed the implementation of the peace accords and "considered areas for improvement".
Asked on Friday whether Putin agreed to a peacekeeping force in Ukraine, Peskov said: "No, this is not true."
Peskov said that Russia is not against the idea of a peacekeeping mission but it is not up to it to agree to one as it is not a party to the conflict.
It was up to Kiev and the rebel regions to agree on the issue, added the Kremlin spokesman.
"There is a document signed by representatives of Kiev and Donbass and guaranteed by three countries," Peskov added, insisting that the parties respect the agreement.
In February, French President Francois Hollande and German Chancellor Angela Merkel helped broker a peace deal for Ukraine in a last-ditch effort to stop months of fighting between pro-Russian separatists and Kiev forces.
Despite the Minsk ceasefire deal, European observers say both sides are still exchanging fire in the east.
The conflict has killed more than 6,000 people in the past year and displaced a million, according to the United Nations.
Ukraine`s pro-Western President Petro Poroshenko has repeatedly called for an international peacekeeping mission to his country.
But Kiev`s European and US allies appear reluctant to send weapons or troops to Ukraine for fear of escalating the conflict, which has damaged their relations with Moscow.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:37
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title> Election fever puts politics centre-stage in London</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/election-fever-puts-politics-centre-stage-in-london_1588326.html </Link>
        <Description>  When celebrity TV interviewer Jeremy Paxman is in the audience for a play in which Judi Dench has only a cameo role, something unusual is happening on the London stage: politics has become the star of the show.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Election fever puts politics centre-stage in London
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:32
0
Comment
London: When celebrity TV interviewer Jeremy Paxman is in the audience for a play in which Judi Dench has only a cameo role, something unusual is happening on the London stage: politics has become the star of the show.
Politically themed plays like "The Vote", "Dead Sheep" and a revival of "The Audience", portraying Queen Elizabeth`s dealings with past prime ministers, are drawing big audiences ahead of Britain`s most uncertain national election in decades.
Less than a week before the May 7 vote, opinion polls show Prime Minister David Cameron`s Conservatives and the opposition Labour party neck-and-neck, with a surge in Scottish nationalist support further complicating the picture.
"The Vote", a drawing-room comedy set in a London polling station with a cast of more than 40 -- including Dench, who shows up in the last 15 minutes -- is one of the hottest tickets in town, with seats sold by lottery.
It will reach a broader audience when it is broadcast live on national television on election night, its madcap finale scheduled to coincide with the polls closing.
"I think a lot of people think theatre, especially political theatre, isn`t for them, it sounds so worthy and serious and earnest," playwright James Graham told Reuters in an interview.
"From the very beginning we just wanted to make it entertaining, farcical and funny because a lot of this stuff is. There is an absurdity to how we pick our government."
The play shows everyone from a Russian lesbian and her lover to a drunken young man turning up to cast their ballots, and everything that could go wrong does.
Two teenage girls, voting for the first time, are so overwhelmed by the "old-school" use of pencils to mark ballot papers and the lack of information about the names listed that one of them, contravening a rule banning mobile phones, uses hers to ask: "Siri, who should I vote for?"
Other plays dissect the political process and the workings of government.
"Dead Sheep" portrays the downfall of Margaret Thatcher following a famous 1990 House of Commons speech by her supposedly subservient Deputy Prime Minister Geoffrey Howe, whose attack mode was once described by an opponent as "like being savaged by a dead sheep".
Thatcher, in television presenter and first-time playwright Jonathan Maitland`s production, is played by a man, Steve Nallon. He parodied Thatcher`s voice in the 1980s satirical puppet show "Spitting Image" and now applies that expertise to impersonating her as well.
It was said of Thatcher that she was "the best man in the cabinet" but Maitland said that was not the motivation for picking Nallon for the role.
"This guy isn`t any old actor, he`s like a psychological stalker of Margaret Thatcher, he knows what she had for breakfast the day she won the election ... he`s extraordinary," Maitland said.
That level of insight allows Nallon, and Maitland`s play, to provide what he said was an extra dimension to the political experience -- to show what goes on behind the scenes.
"I think the stage can deliver a really compelling, powerful and entertaining truth that amplifies what you`re seeing in the papers and hearing on the radio," Maitland said.
Or, as Graham put it, "It`s like having a backstage pass to a world that seems very closed up and inaccessible."
At a performance of "The Vote", Paxman, who conducted TV interviews with Cameron and Labour leader Ed Miliband last month, offered a different reason for the political plays` popularity: the dullness of the election campaign itself.
"This is more interesting than watching Cameron and Miliband ... posturing, inasmuch as they can even get up the energy to posture," he said.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:32
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title> Cover-up accusations in Central Africa child sex abuse scandal `offensive`: UN</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/cover-up-accusations-in-central-africa-child-sex-abuse-scandal-offensive-un_1588323.html </Link>
        <Description>  The United Nations rights office said Friday suggestions it tried to cover up allegations of the sexual abuse of children by French troops in the Central African Republic were &amp;#34;offensive&amp;#34;.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Geneva: The United Nations rights office said Friday suggestions it tried to cover up allegations of the sexual abuse of children by French troops in the Central African Republic were "offensive".
"I think any implication that (UN human rights chief) Zeid Ra`ad Al Hussein would try to cover up sexual abuse (of) children is frankly offensive and highly unlikely if you look at his personal history," Zeid`s spokesman Rupert Colville told reporters in Geneva.
Related Stories
French leader vows `no mercy` if Central African Republic child rape allegations proven
He pointed out that Zeid among other things was the author of the 2005 Zeid report, considered to be "the definitive UN report on sexual abuse in peacekeeping operations".
A number of non-governmental organisations have cried foul after revelations this week that an internal UN report was leaked last July to French authorities with allegations that French peacekeepers in CAR had sexually assaulted hungry children in exchange for food.
"The allegations of what happened to these children are abhorrent. The details obtained in interviews with alleged victims and witnesses by UN investigators... are utterly odious," Colville said, saying the UN was "extremely glad" France had launched an investigation.
He acknowledged that in the past "there have been far to many incidents of peacekeeping troops engaged in such acts, whether within UN peacekeeping forces or, as in this case, forces that are operating independently."
He said the UN rights office had been cooperating with the French investigation and welcomed Paris`s vow to call for "the harshest punishments available under the law for anyone found guilty."
The high-ranking UN employee accused of the leak, Swedish national Anders Kompass, has meanwhile been suspended with full pay pending an internal investigation, Colville confirmed.
He said the investigation, requested by Zeid, was necessary since the confidential documents had been handed over with unredacted names of victims witnesses and investigators -- "in possible breach of strict rules that exist to protect victims, witnesses and investigators."
Such people "may be extremely vulnerable to reprisals," he explained, pointing to "plenty of cases elsewhere where they have disappeared."
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:28
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title> Austria rejects US extradition of Ukrainian oligarch</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/austria-rejects-us-extradition-of-ukrainian-oligarch_1588318.html </Link>
        <Description>  An Austrian court has rejected a US request to extradite Ukrainian oligarch Dmytro Firtash on charges of bribing officials in India.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Austria rejects US extradition of Ukrainian oligarch
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:13
0
Comment
Vienna: An Austrian court has rejected a US request to extradite Ukrainian oligarch Dmytro Firtash on charges of bribing officials in India.
Firtash, 49, one of Ukraine's richest men and previously a supporter of ousted president Viktor Yanukovych, was arrested in Austria in March 2014.
He was freed on bail 10 days later for 125 million euros (USD 139 million), a record for Austria, but has had to stay in the country.
US authorities want him extradited to face charges that he and five others paid USD 18.5 million in bribes to Indian officials to secure titanium mining licences in 2006.
Firtash has rejected the charges and maintained they are politically motivated.
Presiding judge Christoph Bauer said yesterday there was "no political influence" over the decision which "was taken on a legal and factual basis".
Firtash owns Group DF, a business empire involved in energy, chemicals, media, banking and property in Ukraine and other countries including Germany, Italy and Austria.
He made his fortune importing gas to Ukraine from Russia and Central Asia via his group Rosukrenergo, since disbanded, in collaboration with Russian gas giant Gazprom.
Having backed the 2010 election campaign of Yanukovych, Firtash was able to expand his business interests, acquiring chemicals and fertiliser factories as well as TV channel Inter.
The Russian-backed Yanukovych was ousted in protests in February 2014, and Firtash's arrest in Austria came soon afterwards, although officials deny any link.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:13
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title> Two soldiers, one rebel killed in Ukraine fighting</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/two-soldiers-one-rebel-killed-in-ukraine-fighting_1588310.html </Link>
        <Description>  Two Ukrainian soldiers and one pro-Russian rebel have been killed over the past 24 hours in fighting in the country`s war-torn east despite a shaky ceasefire, officials said on Friday.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Two soldiers, one rebel killed in Ukraine fighting
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 16:52
0
Comment
Kiev: Two Ukrainian soldiers and one pro-Russian rebel have been killed over the past 24 hours in fighting in the country`s war-torn east despite a shaky ceasefire, officials said on Friday.
A Ukrainian military spokesman said that two soldiers were killed and two wounded as a result of the fighting in which he accused rebels of using heavy arms prohibited by a February truce agreement.
Rebel authorities said that one fighter was killed and one severely wounded in the clashes.
Fighting between pro-Russian rebels and the Ukrainian army has killed over 6,100 people in the past year. A wobbly truce has been in place since mid-February, but fighters from both sides have been killed in ongoing clashes in a handful of areas.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 16:52
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title> Islamist rebels battle Syrian army near Assad heartland</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/islamist-rebels-battle-syrian-army-near-assad-heartland_1588291.html </Link>
        <Description>  Islamist rebels and the Syrian Army fought fierce battles in Latakia province overnight close to President Bashar al-Assad`s ancestral home, the Army and rebels said, after weeks of insurgent gains in the country`s northwest.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Islamist rebels battle Syrian army near Assad heartland
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:59
0
Comment
Amman/Beirut: Islamist rebels and the Syrian Army fought fierce battles in Latakia province overnight close to President Bashar al-Assad`s ancestral home, the Army and rebels said, after weeks of insurgent gains in the country`s northwest.
Rebels seeking to topple Assad have in the past sought to bring their four-year-long insurgency close to coastal areas in government-held Latakia, heartland of Assad`s minority Alawite community.
An army source told state news agency SANA fighter jets hit insurgent hideouts in the northern Latakia countryside with "tens killed and wounded." Latakia is the main port in Syria and along with the capital Damascus is one of the most important government-held areas in the country.
The violence follows advances in neighbouring Idlib province by the hardline Ahrar al-Sham group and Syria`s al Qaeda wing Nusra Front as well as other allied fighters.
Rami Abdulrahman, who runs the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights monitoring group, said the Latakia battles started with an Army offensive on Thursday, backed by local militias, aimed at pushing the insurgents out of the province in order to advance on captured areas of neighbouring Idlib.
The Observatory, which collects information from a network of sources on the ground, said at least five insurgents were killed and an unidentified number from the pro-government side.
Two rebel sources said the fighting in Latakia was near the mountains of Jabal al-Akrad, close to some of the highest peaks in Syria including Nabi Younis that overlook Alawite villages and close to Qardaha, hometown of the Assad family.
"The capture of the peaks would make the Alawite villages in our firing range," said an Ahrar al-Sham commander based in Idlib on Skype.
The Observatory`s Abdulrahman said the army wanted to secure the valley and peaks in order to advance on Jisr al-Shughour, a town in Idlib province captured by insurgents a week ago.
In August 2013, Islamist rebels and foreign fighters briefly captured Alawite villages.
On Friday Syrian television said Army units targeted "groups of terrorists" in the eastern and southern Idlib countryside and "eliminated a great number of them and destroyed their weapons and munitions."
Diplomats say rebels are trying to pressure the overstretched army on as many fronts as possible to spread its resources ever more thinly.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:59
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title> Iran`s Zarif congratulates new Saudi FM despite tensions</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/irans-zarif-congratulates-new-saudi-fm-despite-tensions_1588289.html </Link>
        <Description>  Iran`s Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif congratulated his newly-installed Saudi counterpart on his appointment, Iranian media reported Friday, even as tensions flare between the rival regional powers over Yemen.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Iran`s Zarif congratulates new Saudi FM despite tensions
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:57
0
Comment
Tehran:Iran`s Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif congratulated his newly-installed Saudi counterpart on his appointment, Iranian media reported Friday, even as tensions flare between the rival regional powers over Yemen.
Zarif said he hoped that "relations between the Islamic Republic of Iran and the Saudi monarchy will develop" following the nomination of Adel al-Jubeir as Riyadh`s top diplomat.
Tensions between Sunni-dominated Saudi Arabia and Shiite Iran have soared following the launch in March of a Riyadh-led aerial campaign against Shiite Huthi rebels in Yemen.
The regional adversaries have long vied for influence in the Middle East, including in the conflicts in Syria and Iraq and in confessionally-mixed countries such as Lebanon and Bahrain.
Iran denies providing arms to Huthi rebels in Yemen and is insisting on a complete end to Saudi-led strikes as a condition for peace talks in the impoverished Gulf nation.
A former envoy to Washington, Jubeir was appointed foreign minister in a major government shake-up in the oil-rich kingdom earlier this week, replacing the world`s longest-serving chief diplomat, Prince Saud al-Faisal.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:57
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title> Myanmar rebels convene in remote Wa region</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/myanmar-rebels-convene-in-remote-wa-region_1588286.html </Link>
        <Description>  A host of Myanmar ethnic rebels began talks in the isolated Wa region bordering China Friday as they mull whether to agree a full ceasefire with the government, an armed group official said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Myanmar rebels convene in remote Wa region
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:55
0
Comment
Naypyidaw: A host of Myanmar ethnic rebels began talks in the isolated Wa region bordering China Friday as they mull whether to agree a full ceasefire with the government, an armed group official said.
The United Wa State Army (UWSA) holds sway over a secretive patch of borderland with a thousands-strong rebel fighting force, long accused of drug smuggling.
It called the meeting of around a dozen ethnic armed groups in April, despite not being part of the country`s peace talks.
"We are hoping this meeting will be strongly supportive of local peace and a nationwide ceasefire," Major Tar Pan La, spokesman of the Ta`ang National Liberation Army (TNLA), told AFP.
He added that the talks began Friday and were expected to last until May 6.
President Thein Sein has secured a draft deal with 16 rebel groups to end decades of fighting, described by the United Nations as a "historic and significant achievement".
The government wants a full nationwide ceasefire before elections in November seen as a test of reforms after decades of military rule.
But skirmishes continue in Kachin state, where a ceasefire deal collapsed in 2011 soon after the end of junta rule.
Heavy fighting has also erupted in the Kokang regions of northern Shan state, causing tens of thousands to flee over the border into China and sparking alarm in Beijing.
The Kokang fighters, who poured back into Myanmar in February after being driven out by troops in 2009 and have fought with help from the TNLA, are not part of the nation`s ceasefire talks, although they have been invited to the Wa meeting.
Bertil Lintner, author of several books on Myanmar and its ethnic minority regions, said the Wa talks were a way for Beijing to "put pressure on the government".
"They do not want to lose influence in Burma," he told AFP, using the country`s former name, adding that Beijing`s sway had diminished under the new regime, which has sought to open the country to the world after decades of isolation.
He said the Wa receive their weapons from China and are thought to be sharing them with fighters in Kokang. Both ethnic groups previously fought the government as part of the Communist Party of Burma.
Myanmar government forces have become locked in protracted conflict with Kokang ethnic Chinese rebels despite the use of air strikes and heavy artillery.
"It is a sign of weakness not a sign of strength. Casualties have been extremely high," he said of the conflict.
The UWSA signed a ceasefire with the country`s military government back in 1989 and reiterated the deal in 2011.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:55
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title> Albury rape: Mayor Kevin Mack apologises for &amp;#38;#039;&amp;#38;#039;victim blaming&amp;#38;#039;&amp;#38;#039; comment</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/albury-rape-mayor-kevin-mack-apologises-for-victim-blaming-comment_1588354.html </Link>
        <Description>  Shortly after Mayor Kevin Mack encouraged women to not walk alone and to have someone with them &amp;#34;at all times&amp;#34; as that in itself, was an &amp;#34;invitation&amp;#34; for someone to take advantage of them, he has now apologised for making the comment.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Melbourne: Shortly after Mayor Kevin Mack encouraged women to not walk alone and to have someone with them "at all times" as that in itself, was an "invitation" for someone to take advantage of them, he has now apologised for making the comment.
Mack had made the statement while reacting to the rape of a 17-year-old girl in Albury, southern New South Wales, on Tuesday. He later clarified by saying that the girl had not done "anything wrong," reported ABC News.
The reaction drew widespread condemnation on social media, with many accusing the mayor of blaming the victim.
The girl was allegedly raped "at gunpoint" by three men while returning home from work. 
ANI
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 18:17
0
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title> UN urged to `shed all light` on Central African Republic child sex abuse scandal</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/un-urged-to-shed-all-light-on-central-african-republic-child-sex-abuse-scandal_1588350.html </Link>
        <Description>  Save the Children has urged France and the United Nations to &amp;#34;shed all light&amp;#34; on accusations that French soldiers sexually abused hungry children in the Central African Republic.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>UN urged to `shed all light` on Central African Republic child sex abuse scandal
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 18:11
0
Comment
Libreville: Save the Children has urged France and the United Nations to "shed all light" on accusations that French soldiers sexually abused hungry children in the Central African Republic.
"If the facts are borne out, it is essential to take the firmest measures against those behind them," the global charity said in a statement sent to AFP on Friday.
According to a French judicial source, 14 peacekeeping soldiers deployed to the chaos-ridden nation to help restore order after a 2013 coup are implicated in a probe into the alleged sexual abuse of several children -- the youngest just nine -- who had begged for something to eat.
French President Francois Hollande vowed Thursday to "show no mercy" if "some soldiers have behaved badly", a day after British newspaper The Guardian broke the story based on a leaked UN report.
The United Nations should "ensure that the child victims of these abuses are protected and benefit from all the psycho-social support that they need," said Natasha Quist, Save The Children`s director for west and central Africa, quoted in the statement in French from Dakar.
Quist urged "the United Nations and the French authorities to take all necessary measures to bring full light to bear on this affair, notably by being transparent about the investigations announced to have started."
"Humanitarian workers and elements of the peacekeeping forces have on several occasions been implicated in cases of the violation of children`s rights, including rape or exchanging food for sexual favours," Save the Children said.
"Soldiers are in the front line in complex conflict situations and are often the only ones who can make sure that children`s rights are protected," argued the charity.
The leaked report also accuses soldiers from Chad and Equatorial Guinea of abuses in the deeply poor, landlocked nation where an African peacekeeping mission was handed over to the United Nations in September last year.
A European Union military mission also operates in the country, ravaged since the 2013 coup by a conflict that took on an unprecedented religious dimension, pitting mainly Muslim former rebels against Christian vigilantes at the expense of the civilian population.
In the wake of the report in The Guardian, the French defence ministry on Wednesday said that the government had been alerted to accusations of sexual abuse against children by the UN High Commission for Human Rights in July 2014.
Prosecutors in Paris then opened an investigation into the reports, the ministry said, pledging to ensure that "the truth be found" and "the strongest penalties" imposed on those found guilty.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 18:11
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title> Kremlin says too early to speak of Ukraine peacekeeping mission</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/kremlin-says-too-early-to-speak-of-ukraine-peacekeeping-mission_1588327.html </Link>
        <Description>  Russia said on Friday that it was premature to discuss the deployment of a peacekeeping mission in war-torn eastern Ukraine before a peace deal agreed in February is implemented in full.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Kremlin says too early to speak of Ukraine peacekeeping mission
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:37
0
Comment
Moscow: Russia said on Friday that it was premature to discuss the deployment of a peacekeeping mission in war-torn eastern Ukraine before a peace deal agreed in February is implemented in full.
"Before the text of the Minsk agreement and its concrete points are implemented we believe that it would be absolutely wrong to raise any other issues including that about peacekeepers," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told Russian news agencies.
On Thursday, the Ukrainian presidency said Russian President Vladimir Putin was open to the deployment of a peacekeeping mission in Ukraine, after the leaders of both countries spoke by phone with their French and German counterparts.
"In the context of the discussion of ways towards a peaceful resolution (of the conflict), President Putin has accepted the possibility of deploying a peacekeeping contingent to the Donbass region," the Ukrainian presidency said in a statement.
Moscow however made no mention of a possible peacekeeping force in its own statement issued after the talks.
The French presidency also made no such reference, saying in a statement that the parties had reviewed the implementation of the peace accords and "considered areas for improvement".
Asked on Friday whether Putin agreed to a peacekeeping force in Ukraine, Peskov said: "No, this is not true."
Peskov said that Russia is not against the idea of a peacekeeping mission but it is not up to it to agree to one as it is not a party to the conflict.
It was up to Kiev and the rebel regions to agree on the issue, added the Kremlin spokesman.
"There is a document signed by representatives of Kiev and Donbass and guaranteed by three countries," Peskov added, insisting that the parties respect the agreement.
In February, French President Francois Hollande and German Chancellor Angela Merkel helped broker a peace deal for Ukraine in a last-ditch effort to stop months of fighting between pro-Russian separatists and Kiev forces.
Despite the Minsk ceasefire deal, European observers say both sides are still exchanging fire in the east.
The conflict has killed more than 6,000 people in the past year and displaced a million, according to the United Nations.
Ukraine`s pro-Western President Petro Poroshenko has repeatedly called for an international peacekeeping mission to his country.
But Kiev`s European and US allies appear reluctant to send weapons or troops to Ukraine for fear of escalating the conflict, which has damaged their relations with Moscow.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:37
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title> Election fever puts politics centre-stage in London</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/election-fever-puts-politics-centre-stage-in-london_1588326.html </Link>
        <Description>  When celebrity TV interviewer Jeremy Paxman is in the audience for a play in which Judi Dench has only a cameo role, something unusual is happening on the London stage: politics has become the star of the show.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Election fever puts politics centre-stage in London
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:32
0
Comment
London: When celebrity TV interviewer Jeremy Paxman is in the audience for a play in which Judi Dench has only a cameo role, something unusual is happening on the London stage: politics has become the star of the show.
Politically themed plays like "The Vote", "Dead Sheep" and a revival of "The Audience", portraying Queen Elizabeth`s dealings with past prime ministers, are drawing big audiences ahead of Britain`s most uncertain national election in decades.
Less than a week before the May 7 vote, opinion polls show Prime Minister David Cameron`s Conservatives and the opposition Labour party neck-and-neck, with a surge in Scottish nationalist support further complicating the picture.
"The Vote", a drawing-room comedy set in a London polling station with a cast of more than 40 -- including Dench, who shows up in the last 15 minutes -- is one of the hottest tickets in town, with seats sold by lottery.
It will reach a broader audience when it is broadcast live on national television on election night, its madcap finale scheduled to coincide with the polls closing.
"I think a lot of people think theatre, especially political theatre, isn`t for them, it sounds so worthy and serious and earnest," playwright James Graham told Reuters in an interview.
"From the very beginning we just wanted to make it entertaining, farcical and funny because a lot of this stuff is. There is an absurdity to how we pick our government."
The play shows everyone from a Russian lesbian and her lover to a drunken young man turning up to cast their ballots, and everything that could go wrong does.
Two teenage girls, voting for the first time, are so overwhelmed by the "old-school" use of pencils to mark ballot papers and the lack of information about the names listed that one of them, contravening a rule banning mobile phones, uses hers to ask: "Siri, who should I vote for?"
Other plays dissect the political process and the workings of government.
"Dead Sheep" portrays the downfall of Margaret Thatcher following a famous 1990 House of Commons speech by her supposedly subservient Deputy Prime Minister Geoffrey Howe, whose attack mode was once described by an opponent as "like being savaged by a dead sheep".
Thatcher, in television presenter and first-time playwright Jonathan Maitland`s production, is played by a man, Steve Nallon. He parodied Thatcher`s voice in the 1980s satirical puppet show "Spitting Image" and now applies that expertise to impersonating her as well.
It was said of Thatcher that she was "the best man in the cabinet" but Maitland said that was not the motivation for picking Nallon for the role.
"This guy isn`t any old actor, he`s like a psychological stalker of Margaret Thatcher, he knows what she had for breakfast the day she won the election ... he`s extraordinary," Maitland said.
That level of insight allows Nallon, and Maitland`s play, to provide what he said was an extra dimension to the political experience -- to show what goes on behind the scenes.
"I think the stage can deliver a really compelling, powerful and entertaining truth that amplifies what you`re seeing in the papers and hearing on the radio," Maitland said.
Or, as Graham put it, "It`s like having a backstage pass to a world that seems very closed up and inaccessible."
At a performance of "The Vote", Paxman, who conducted TV interviews with Cameron and Labour leader Ed Miliband last month, offered a different reason for the political plays` popularity: the dullness of the election campaign itself.
"This is more interesting than watching Cameron and Miliband ... posturing, inasmuch as they can even get up the energy to posture," he said.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:32
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title> Cover-up accusations in Central Africa child sex abuse scandal `offensive`: UN</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/cover-up-accusations-in-central-africa-child-sex-abuse-scandal-offensive-un_1588323.html </Link>
        <Description>  The United Nations rights office said Friday suggestions it tried to cover up allegations of the sexual abuse of children by French troops in the Central African Republic were &amp;#34;offensive&amp;#34;.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Geneva: The United Nations rights office said Friday suggestions it tried to cover up allegations of the sexual abuse of children by French troops in the Central African Republic were "offensive".
"I think any implication that (UN human rights chief) Zeid Ra`ad Al Hussein would try to cover up sexual abuse (of) children is frankly offensive and highly unlikely if you look at his personal history," Zeid`s spokesman Rupert Colville told reporters in Geneva.
Related Stories
French leader vows `no mercy` if Central African Republic child rape allegations proven
He pointed out that Zeid among other things was the author of the 2005 Zeid report, considered to be "the definitive UN report on sexual abuse in peacekeeping operations".
A number of non-governmental organisations have cried foul after revelations this week that an internal UN report was leaked last July to French authorities with allegations that French peacekeepers in CAR had sexually assaulted hungry children in exchange for food.
"The allegations of what happened to these children are abhorrent. The details obtained in interviews with alleged victims and witnesses by UN investigators... are utterly odious," Colville said, saying the UN was "extremely glad" France had launched an investigation.
He acknowledged that in the past "there have been far to many incidents of peacekeeping troops engaged in such acts, whether within UN peacekeeping forces or, as in this case, forces that are operating independently."
He said the UN rights office had been cooperating with the French investigation and welcomed Paris`s vow to call for "the harshest punishments available under the law for anyone found guilty."
The high-ranking UN employee accused of the leak, Swedish national Anders Kompass, has meanwhile been suspended with full pay pending an internal investigation, Colville confirmed.
He said the investigation, requested by Zeid, was necessary since the confidential documents had been handed over with unredacted names of victims witnesses and investigators -- "in possible breach of strict rules that exist to protect victims, witnesses and investigators."
Such people "may be extremely vulnerable to reprisals," he explained, pointing to "plenty of cases elsewhere where they have disappeared."
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:28
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title> Austria rejects US extradition of Ukrainian oligarch</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/austria-rejects-us-extradition-of-ukrainian-oligarch_1588318.html </Link>
        <Description>  An Austrian court has rejected a US request to extradite Ukrainian oligarch Dmytro Firtash on charges of bribing officials in India.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Austria rejects US extradition of Ukrainian oligarch
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:13
0
Comment
Vienna: An Austrian court has rejected a US request to extradite Ukrainian oligarch Dmytro Firtash on charges of bribing officials in India.
Firtash, 49, one of Ukraine's richest men and previously a supporter of ousted president Viktor Yanukovych, was arrested in Austria in March 2014.
He was freed on bail 10 days later for 125 million euros (USD 139 million), a record for Austria, but has had to stay in the country.
US authorities want him extradited to face charges that he and five others paid USD 18.5 million in bribes to Indian officials to secure titanium mining licences in 2006.
Firtash has rejected the charges and maintained they are politically motivated.
Presiding judge Christoph Bauer said yesterday there was "no political influence" over the decision which "was taken on a legal and factual basis".
Firtash owns Group DF, a business empire involved in energy, chemicals, media, banking and property in Ukraine and other countries including Germany, Italy and Austria.
He made his fortune importing gas to Ukraine from Russia and Central Asia via his group Rosukrenergo, since disbanded, in collaboration with Russian gas giant Gazprom.
Having backed the 2010 election campaign of Yanukovych, Firtash was able to expand his business interests, acquiring chemicals and fertiliser factories as well as TV channel Inter.
The Russian-backed Yanukovych was ousted in protests in February 2014, and Firtash's arrest in Austria came soon afterwards, although officials deny any link.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 17:13
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title> Two soldiers, one rebel killed in Ukraine fighting</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/two-soldiers-one-rebel-killed-in-ukraine-fighting_1588310.html </Link>
        <Description>  Two Ukrainian soldiers and one pro-Russian rebel have been killed over the past 24 hours in fighting in the country`s war-torn east despite a shaky ceasefire, officials said on Friday.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Two soldiers, one rebel killed in Ukraine fighting
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 16:52
0
Comment
Kiev: Two Ukrainian soldiers and one pro-Russian rebel have been killed over the past 24 hours in fighting in the country`s war-torn east despite a shaky ceasefire, officials said on Friday.
A Ukrainian military spokesman said that two soldiers were killed and two wounded as a result of the fighting in which he accused rebels of using heavy arms prohibited by a February truce agreement.
Rebel authorities said that one fighter was killed and one severely wounded in the clashes.
Fighting between pro-Russian rebels and the Ukrainian army has killed over 6,100 people in the past year. A wobbly truce has been in place since mid-February, but fighters from both sides have been killed in ongoing clashes in a handful of areas.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 16:52
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title> Islamist rebels battle Syrian army near Assad heartland</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/islamist-rebels-battle-syrian-army-near-assad-heartland_1588291.html </Link>
        <Description>  Islamist rebels and the Syrian Army fought fierce battles in Latakia province overnight close to President Bashar al-Assad`s ancestral home, the Army and rebels said, after weeks of insurgent gains in the country`s northwest.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Islamist rebels battle Syrian army near Assad heartland
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:59
0
Comment
Amman/Beirut: Islamist rebels and the Syrian Army fought fierce battles in Latakia province overnight close to President Bashar al-Assad`s ancestral home, the Army and rebels said, after weeks of insurgent gains in the country`s northwest.
Rebels seeking to topple Assad have in the past sought to bring their four-year-long insurgency close to coastal areas in government-held Latakia, heartland of Assad`s minority Alawite community.
An army source told state news agency SANA fighter jets hit insurgent hideouts in the northern Latakia countryside with "tens killed and wounded." Latakia is the main port in Syria and along with the capital Damascus is one of the most important government-held areas in the country.
The violence follows advances in neighbouring Idlib province by the hardline Ahrar al-Sham group and Syria`s al Qaeda wing Nusra Front as well as other allied fighters.
Rami Abdulrahman, who runs the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights monitoring group, said the Latakia battles started with an Army offensive on Thursday, backed by local militias, aimed at pushing the insurgents out of the province in order to advance on captured areas of neighbouring Idlib.
The Observatory, which collects information from a network of sources on the ground, said at least five insurgents were killed and an unidentified number from the pro-government side.
Two rebel sources said the fighting in Latakia was near the mountains of Jabal al-Akrad, close to some of the highest peaks in Syria including Nabi Younis that overlook Alawite villages and close to Qardaha, hometown of the Assad family.
"The capture of the peaks would make the Alawite villages in our firing range," said an Ahrar al-Sham commander based in Idlib on Skype.
The Observatory`s Abdulrahman said the army wanted to secure the valley and peaks in order to advance on Jisr al-Shughour, a town in Idlib province captured by insurgents a week ago.
In August 2013, Islamist rebels and foreign fighters briefly captured Alawite villages.
On Friday Syrian television said Army units targeted "groups of terrorists" in the eastern and southern Idlib countryside and "eliminated a great number of them and destroyed their weapons and munitions."
Diplomats say rebels are trying to pressure the overstretched army on as many fronts as possible to spread its resources ever more thinly.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:59
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title> Iran`s Zarif congratulates new Saudi FM despite tensions</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/irans-zarif-congratulates-new-saudi-fm-despite-tensions_1588289.html </Link>
        <Description>  Iran`s Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif congratulated his newly-installed Saudi counterpart on his appointment, Iranian media reported Friday, even as tensions flare between the rival regional powers over Yemen.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Iran`s Zarif congratulates new Saudi FM despite tensions
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:57
0
Comment
Tehran:Iran`s Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif congratulated his newly-installed Saudi counterpart on his appointment, Iranian media reported Friday, even as tensions flare between the rival regional powers over Yemen.
Zarif said he hoped that "relations between the Islamic Republic of Iran and the Saudi monarchy will develop" following the nomination of Adel al-Jubeir as Riyadh`s top diplomat.
Tensions between Sunni-dominated Saudi Arabia and Shiite Iran have soared following the launch in March of a Riyadh-led aerial campaign against Shiite Huthi rebels in Yemen.
The regional adversaries have long vied for influence in the Middle East, including in the conflicts in Syria and Iraq and in confessionally-mixed countries such as Lebanon and Bahrain.
Iran denies providing arms to Huthi rebels in Yemen and is insisting on a complete end to Saudi-led strikes as a condition for peace talks in the impoverished Gulf nation.
A former envoy to Washington, Jubeir was appointed foreign minister in a major government shake-up in the oil-rich kingdom earlier this week, replacing the world`s longest-serving chief diplomat, Prince Saud al-Faisal.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:57
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title> Myanmar rebels convene in remote Wa region</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/myanmar-rebels-convene-in-remote-wa-region_1588286.html </Link>
        <Description>  A host of Myanmar ethnic rebels began talks in the isolated Wa region bordering China Friday as they mull whether to agree a full ceasefire with the government, an armed group official said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Myanmar rebels convene in remote Wa region
Last Updated: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:55
0
Comment
Naypyidaw: A host of Myanmar ethnic rebels began talks in the isolated Wa region bordering China Friday as they mull whether to agree a full ceasefire with the government, an armed group official said.
The United Wa State Army (UWSA) holds sway over a secretive patch of borderland with a thousands-strong rebel fighting force, long accused of drug smuggling.
It called the meeting of around a dozen ethnic armed groups in April, despite not being part of the country`s peace talks.
"We are hoping this meeting will be strongly supportive of local peace and a nationwide ceasefire," Major Tar Pan La, spokesman of the Ta`ang National Liberation Army (TNLA), told AFP.
He added that the talks began Friday and were expected to last until May 6.
President Thein Sein has secured a draft deal with 16 rebel groups to end decades of fighting, described by the United Nations as a "historic and significant achievement".
The government wants a full nationwide ceasefire before elections in November seen as a test of reforms after decades of military rule.
But skirmishes continue in Kachin state, where a ceasefire deal collapsed in 2011 soon after the end of junta rule.
Heavy fighting has also erupted in the Kokang regions of northern Shan state, causing tens of thousands to flee over the border into China and sparking alarm in Beijing.
The Kokang fighters, who poured back into Myanmar in February after being driven out by troops in 2009 and have fought with help from the TNLA, are not part of the nation`s ceasefire talks, although they have been invited to the Wa meeting.
Bertil Lintner, author of several books on Myanmar and its ethnic minority regions, said the Wa talks were a way for Beijing to "put pressure on the government".
"They do not want to lose influence in Burma," he told AFP, using the country`s former name, adding that Beijing`s sway had diminished under the new regime, which has sought to open the country to the world after decades of isolation.
He said the Wa receive their weapons from China and are thought to be sharing them with fighters in Kokang. Both ethnic groups previously fought the government as part of the Communist Party of Burma.
Myanmar government forces have become locked in protracted conflict with Kokang ethnic Chinese rebels despite the use of air strikes and heavy artillery.
"It is a sign of weakness not a sign of strength. Casualties have been extremely high," he said of the conflict.
The UWSA signed a ceasefire with the country`s military government back in 1989 and reiterated the deal in 2011.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 1, 2015 - 15:55
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
