<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="zeenews-india">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title> Singapore a target for IS attacks: expert</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/singapore-a-target-for-is-attacks-expert_1603647.html </Link>
        <Description>  The dreaded Islamic State terror outfit has identified Singapore, along with the US and the Philippines, as a possible target for its attacks, a noted expert said here today.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Singapore: The dreaded Islamic State terror outfit has identified Singapore, along with the US and the Philippines, as a possible target for its attacks, a noted expert said here today.
Islamic State (IS) supporters from the region have also cited the Philippines and the US as targets, Jasminder Singh, S Rajaratnam School of International Studies analyst who has compiled a report on the threat, told The Straits Times.
The development comes as Malaysia last month nabbed a cell with explosives targeting Putrajaya (the country's capital city) and the federal Parliament.
Singapore's Home Affairs Ministry on Wednesday also announced the detention of a 19-year-old student who had made plans to join the terror in Syria and carry out attacks here.
The threat to Singapore and the region is set to grow as IS' Malay archipelago combat unit, Katibah Nusantara, formed in Syria last August for South-east Asian fighters who find it easier to communicate in Bahasa (language) Indonesia and Malay rather than Arabic, gains ground, the report said.
There are now more than 700 fighters from Indonesia and over 200 fighters from Malaysia fighting in Iraq and Syria, Singh noted in the report published this week.
While they make up a small proportion of over 30,000 foreign fighters from 90 countries, the unit scored its first major combat success last month, seizing five Kurdish-held areas in Syria.
"The downward slide of jihadist appeal and success since 2009 has been reversed by Katibah Nusantara's success in Iraq and Syria," Singh wrote.
He said Malaysian fighters had also seized on local issues like the push for an Islamic penal code to win support.
The unit poses a severe threat to Singapore and South-east Asia, said Professor Rohan Gunaratna, who heads Singapore's International Centre for Political Violence and Terrorism Research.
"It has multiple functions: to train people capable of carrying out attacks in Iraq and Syria, to instigate South-east Asians to mount attacks in their home countries, and to radicalise South-east Asians online, recruit them and physically facilitate their entry into Iraq and Syria," Rohan said.
The strategy to counter this influence has to be multi-pronged, from engaging the community to exposing IS' evils online, he said.
Muslim leaders worldwide are also leading the effort to counter ISIS, he added.
PTI
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 07:27
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title> Majority of Americans support drone strikes in Pak: survey</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/majority-of-americans-support-drone-strikes-in-pak-survey_1603646.html </Link>
        <Description>  Nearly 60 per cent of Americans support the country&amp;#039;s policy of carrying out drone strikes against militants in Pakistan, according to a national survey.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Washington: Nearly 60 per cent of Americans support the country's policy of carrying out drone strikes against militants in Pakistan, according to a national survey.
The Pew survey, released yesterday, stated that while 58 per cent Americans approve of US drone strikes to target militants in countries such as Pakistan, Yemen and Somalia, about a third (35 per cent) disapproves such attacks.
The survey was conducted between May 12-18 based on telephone interviews with around 2,000 adults living in all 50 US states and the capital Washington.
It stated that the public opinion about US drone strikes has changed only modestly since February 2013, when 56 per cent approved of them.
Compared to the 74 per cent Republicans who favour the drone strikes, only 56 per cent independents and 52 per cent Democrats support them, the survey said.
While men approve of drone attacks by more than two-to-one (67 per cent to 28 per cent), the balance of opinion is much narrower among women.
Half (50 per cent) of the women approve of the use of drones, while 42 per cent disapprove them, it said.
The survey also found that a majority (56 per cent) of the Americans say the US has mostly failed in achieving its goals in Afghanistan, while 36 per cent say the it has mostly succeeded.
Also a declining share of Americans sees prospects for long-term stability in Afghanistan.
Just 29 per cent respondents say it is likely that Afghanistan will be able to maintain a stable government following the departure of US forces from the country.
More than twice as many (68 per cent) say this outcome is unlikely, the survey added.
PTI
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 06:59
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title> Rebels capture last Syrian town in Idlib province</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/rebels-capture-last-syrian-town-in-idlib-province_1603639.html </Link>
        <Description>  The Syrian army has pulled back from the north-western city of Ariha after a coalition of insurgent groups seized the last city in Idlib province in northwestern Syria near the Turkish border that was still held by the government.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Rebels capture last Syrian town in Idlib province
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 05:16
0
Comment
Amman: The Syrian army has pulled back from the north-western city of Ariha after a coalition of insurgent groups seized the last city in Idlib province in northwestern Syria near the Turkish border that was still held by the government.
A coalition of rebel groups called Jaish al Fateh, or Conquest Army, said it had taken over the city. Syria`s al Qaeda offshoot Nusra Front is a major part of the coalition.
The coalition said it had overrun several checkpoints that defended the city. The Syrian army said intense fighting was going on with Nusra forces that had infiltrated Ariha.
"There are heavy clashes between the army and the terrorists of Jabahat al Nusra who infiltrated inside the city," said an army statement released on state television.
Later the army admitted its forces had pulled back from the city, the latest string of defeats by the Syrian army and a big blow to the morale of President Assad`s government forces who have vowed to defeat Sunni militants financed by Saudi Arabia, Qatar and Turkey who seek to overthrow his rule.
"Units of our armed forces evacauated their positions in Ariha and withdrew to defensive positiions in the vicinity of the city after battles it fought facing large number of Nusra terrorists," the army source was quoted as saying.
A rebel source from Ahrar al Sham confirmed that street fighting was going on inside the city between army fighters and the insurgents. "There are many bodies that litter the streets," he said, adding that the rebels were searching for Assad`s government forces inside the city.
Many civilians have hidden inside shelters.
Syria accuses Turkey of financing and aiding rebels seeking to topple the government. Damascus says foreign jihadi fighters allowed into Syrian territory by Turkey have played a pivotal role in recent rebel gains.
Rebel sources say they have secured more U.S.-made TOW missiles in recent months that have helped them to gain a military edge over the Syrian army.
The Nusra Front has made gains in northwestern Syria alongside other insurgent groups in recent weeks, seizing the city of Idlib, the town of Jisr al-Shughour and bringing them closer to government-held coastal areas north of the capital.
The loss of Ariha would leave the insurgents in control of most of Idlib a region that borders Turkey and neighbours President Assad`s heartland in Latakia province on the Mediterranean coast.
The city, once home to more than 80,000 people, is strategically located on the main army supply lines between Idlib and Latakia.
Rebel sources said that convoys carrying army forces had fled to Oroum al Jouz, an area west of Ariha and in areas closer to President Assad`s ancestral homeland. The army did not comment.
Nusra Front is also a major force against government forces and allied militia around the northern city of Aleppo. It is fighting in southern Syria as well, and its combatants have frequently clashed with Islamic State.
Syria`s four-year-old civil war has killed a quarter of a million people and driven nearly 8 million from their homes.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 05:16
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title> Crying baby gets Canadian singer kicked off flight</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/crying-baby-gets-canadian-singer-kicked-off-flight_1603638.html </Link>
        <Description> A Canadian singer-songwriter was kicked off a United Airlines flight in San Francisco because her two-year-old toddler would not stop crying, triggering outrage from her supporters.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Crying baby gets Canadian singer kicked off flight
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 05:11
0
Comment
Ottawa: A Canadian singer-songwriter was kicked off a United Airlines flight in San Francisco because her two-year-old toddler would not stop crying, triggering outrage from her supporters.
"Just got kicked off a @united flight because my son was crying really loud," Sarah Blackwood from the band Walk Off the Earth wrote yesterday on Twitter, accusing the airline of hating mothers.
"Apparently my little two-year-old crying son was a big threat."
Canadian music award-nominated Walk Off the Earth gained international fame recording covers such as Miley Cyrus's Wrecking Ball, Pharrel Williams's Happy, and Taylor Swift's Shake It Off, and original tunes.
Blackwood, who is also seven months pregnant with another child, was booked to fly late yesterday from San Francisco to Vancouver with her son Giorgio.
The flight was operated by SkyWest Airlines, which said the crew ordered the plane back to the gate over "safety concerns."
"Despite numerous requests, the child was not seated, as required by federal regulation to ensure passenger safety, and was repeatedly in the aisle of the aircraft before departure and during taxi," the airline said in a statement defending its decision.
Fellow passengers, however, denounced the move on United's Facebook page, saying the mother tried her best to calm her son and that the flight attendant had been "unprofessional, unreasonable and insensitive."
By the time the jetliner reached the gate, they noted, the toddler had fallen asleep.
But Blackwood and her son were still forced to disembark, while crews spent 75 minutes sifting through luggage to retrieve her bags from the plane, one passenger said.
Dozens of supporters reacted angrily on Twitter.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 05:09
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title> Chinese blessing scam cons New York granny</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/chinese-blessing-scam-cons-new-york-granny_1603635.html </Link>
        <Description>  A 61-year-old Chinese man pleaded guilty Thursday to stealing $60,000 from a New York grandmother after he promised to bless her son`s alleged evil spirits away, prosecutors said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Chinese blessing scam cons New York granny
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:36
0
Comment
New York: A 61-year-old Chinese man pleaded guilty Thursday to stealing $60,000 from a New York grandmother after he promised to bless her son`s alleged evil spirits away, prosecutors said.
The defendant, Xue Fang Zhou, admitted grand larceny in the third degree, in the latest in a series of convictions linked to Chinese blessing scams that have blighted cities in North America.
Prosecutors say versions of the scam have cropped up in cities with significant Chinese populations such as Boston and San Francisco, as well as Toronto in Canada.
Manhattan District Attorney Cyrus Vance said the retired, 65-year-old grandmother lost nearly all her life savings in the October 2014 incident.
"Variations of this scam have led to thousands of dollars in losses for elderly victims here in New York and across the country," Vance said.
The elderly, superstitious and the Chinese immigrant community are at particular risk, he cautioned.
Zhou engineered an introduction to the grandmother near Manhattan`s Chinatown, informing her that her son was cursed with bad luck.
The son was at risk of harm, Zhou said, unless a blessing ritual was performed over the victim`s money.
The victim collected her valuables so Zhou could perform the purported blessing, but promptly discovered that her bag of $60,000 and jewelry had been switched with a bag of water bottles.
Zhou is the sixth person to plead guilty in Manhattan to crimes related to blessing scams in the last two years, prosecutors said.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:36
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title> Mexico catches 50 illegal migrants on plane</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/mexico-catches-50-illegal-migrants-on-plane_1603634.html </Link>
        <Description>  Mexican authorities intercepted 50 undocumented migrants from Cuba and Central America on a plane that was about to fly from Cancun to a city bordering Texas on Thursday.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Mexico catches 50 illegal migrants on plane
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:30
0
Comment
Mexico City: Mexican authorities intercepted 50 undocumented migrants from Cuba and Central America on a plane that was about to fly from Cancun to a city bordering Texas on Thursday.
The migrants had entered Mexico illegally when they were stopped in the Caribbean coast resort city before they could reach Reynosa, said an official from the National Migration Institute.
The migrants included 18 Cubans, 23 Salvadorans, five Guatemalans, two Hondurans, one from Belize and another from the Caribbean island of Granada.
In Reynosa, organized crime controls the trafficking of migrants, who are often kidnapped and held in homes until their families pay a ransom.
Some 200,000 migrants illegally enter Mexico every year across the southern border with Guatemala.
Many have hitched rides on a freight train known as 'The Beast' but are forced to find alternative routes after authorities cracked down last year.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:30
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title> Italian coast guard rescues 234 migrants off Sicily coast </title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/italian-coast-guard-rescues-234-migrants-off-sicily-coast_1603633.html </Link>
        <Description>  The Italian coast guard broadcast footage of a rescue operation recovering 234 migrants from a fishing boat in a precarious condition in the Strait of Sicily, 200 km off the coast of the Sicilian city of Augusta.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Italian coast guard rescues 234 migrants off Sicily coast
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:27
0
Comment
Rome: The Italian coast guard broadcast footage of a rescue operation recovering 234 migrants from a fishing boat in a precarious condition in the Strait of Sicily, 200 km off the coast of the Sicilian city of Augusta.
The coast guard said in a statement on Thursday that the mission occurred on Wednesday night and added that all the passengers, including 187 men, 38 women and nine children, were safely escorted to the Port of Augusta.
The boat was by spotted by an Italian Navy helicopter, after which the coast guard`s relief centre ordered two ships to assist the vessel in distress.
African migrants fleeing conflict in their countries continue to wash up on Italian shores, while the journey often leads to disasters like that on April 19, when about 850 people drowned.
The European Union has been considering measures to address the phenomenon and to fight human trafficking networks through the destruction of seized ships.
The European Commission has also proposed for EU countries to share in welcoming 40,000 asylum seekers over the next two years.
IANS
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:27
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title> Bombs outside two five-star Baghdad hotels kill at least 10</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/bombs-outside-two-five-star-baghdad-hotels-kill-at-least-10_1603632.html </Link>
        <Description>  Car bombs exploded in the parking lots of two heavily fortified five-star hotels in central Baghdad late on Thursday, killing at least 10 people, police and medical sources said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Bombs outside two five-star Baghdad hotels kill at least 10
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:24
0
Baghdad: Car bombs exploded in the parking lots of two heavily fortified five-star hotels in central Baghdad late on Thursday, killing at least 10 people, police and medical sources said.
A further 30 people were wounded in the blasts, which were around seven minutes apart.
The first bomb targeted the Babylon hotel, where government officials often hold meetings and news conferences, and the second hit the Meridian.
Iraqi authorities lifted a decade-old night-time curfew on Baghdad early this year, seeking to restore a sense of normality to the capital as security forces battle Islamic State militants who have overrun large parts of the country.
But the rate of bombings in Baghdad has increased since then.
Insurgents seized the city of Ramadi, west of Baghdad, on May 17 in the most significant military setback to the government since a U.S.-led coalition launched a campaign of airstrikes against Islamic State last August.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:24
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title> Yemen border strikes kill two Saudis, Yemen death toll near 2,000 – WHO</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/yemen-border-strikes-kill-two-saudis-yemen-death-toll-near-2000-%E2%80%93-who_1603631.html </Link>
        <Description>   Two Saudi border guards were killed and five wounded by shells fired from Yemeni territories, an Interior Ministry spokesman said late on Wednesday, as the United Nations said the war`s death toll was close to 2,000.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen border strikes kill two Saudis, Yemen death toll near 2,000  WHO
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:21
0
Comment
Cairo/Aden: Two Saudi border guards were killed and five wounded by shells fired from Yemeni territories, an Interior Ministry spokesman said late on Wednesday, as the United Nations said the war`s death toll was close to 2,000.
Saudi forces and the Houthis have been trading fire across the border since an Arab alliance began military operations against the Iranian-backed Shi`ite group in March to try to restore exiled President Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi to power.
Saudi state news agency SPA said the border guards were killed at a military post in Dhahran al-Janoub, along the border with Yemen, when projectiles fired from the Yemeni side struck.
Two of the soldiers died on the spot while five others were wounded and taken to a hospital, the agency said.
The Saudi-led coalition says it began their campaign heeding a call by Hadi after the Houthis started advancing south towards the port city of Aden, where the president was based.
The Houthis, who captured the Yemeni capital Sanaa last September, say they are fighting against Sunni Islamist militants using areas outside their control as staging grounds for attacks. They also accused officials in Hadi`s government of siphoning public funds.
On the ground, southern opposition fighters allied with Hadi said they had ambushed and killed six soldiers allied with the Houthis stationed in the south-eastern city of Zinjibar.
The World Health Organisation (WHO), which compiles figures on casualties in Yemen, said its latest figures show that 1,942 people had been killed between March 19 and May 22.
It said 7,870 people were injured in the same period.
Residents of the southern city of Aden said Houthi fighters at checkpoints outside the city had been preventing trucks carrying basic foodstuffs and qat - a narcotic leaf many Yemenis chew daily - from entering.
They said they believe the measures were a punishment after local fighters ejected the Houthis from the nearby city of Dhalea in the most serious setback for the group since March.
Houthi officials were not immediately available to comment on the reports.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:21
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title> Boss can monitor workers&amp;#38;#039; Facebook activity, top court rules</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/boss-can-monitor-workers-facebook-activity-top-court-rules_1603627.html </Link>
        <Description> : Bosses who use the social networking website Facebook to spy on their employees at work are not breaking the law, Italy`s Supreme Court has ruled.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Boss can monitor workers' Facebook activity, top court rules
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 03:58
0
Comment
Rome:: Bosses who use the social networking website Facebook to spy on their employees at work are not breaking the law, Italy`s Supreme Court has ruled.
The court ruling on Thursday was found to be in favour of a printer who fired a worker when the former caught him chatting with a woman, whose fake profile had been set up by the printer himself, on Facebook.
The sacked employee had spent 15 minutes chatting with the woman on his mobile using the Facebook Messenger app, failing meanwhile to fix a a jam that had occurred in the printing works.
The printer was within his rights to set up the fake Facebook profile and dismiss the worker as it allowed "the check of continuous illegal behaviour, on the part of the employee, already observed in the past", the court said.
It also acceptable for employees to monitor workers` use of Facebook from their mobile phones, the court ruled.
The worker had engaged in several previous conversations over Facebook during his working hours and an iPad was found on charge in his locker.
IANS
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 03:58
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title> Singapore a target for IS attacks: expert</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/singapore-a-target-for-is-attacks-expert_1603647.html </Link>
        <Description>  The dreaded Islamic State terror outfit has identified Singapore, along with the US and the Philippines, as a possible target for its attacks, a noted expert said here today.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Singapore: The dreaded Islamic State terror outfit has identified Singapore, along with the US and the Philippines, as a possible target for its attacks, a noted expert said here today.
Islamic State (IS) supporters from the region have also cited the Philippines and the US as targets, Jasminder Singh, S Rajaratnam School of International Studies analyst who has compiled a report on the threat, told The Straits Times.
The development comes as Malaysia last month nabbed a cell with explosives targeting Putrajaya (the country's capital city) and the federal Parliament.
Singapore's Home Affairs Ministry on Wednesday also announced the detention of a 19-year-old student who had made plans to join the terror in Syria and carry out attacks here.
The threat to Singapore and the region is set to grow as IS' Malay archipelago combat unit, Katibah Nusantara, formed in Syria last August for South-east Asian fighters who find it easier to communicate in Bahasa (language) Indonesia and Malay rather than Arabic, gains ground, the report said.
There are now more than 700 fighters from Indonesia and over 200 fighters from Malaysia fighting in Iraq and Syria, Singh noted in the report published this week.
While they make up a small proportion of over 30,000 foreign fighters from 90 countries, the unit scored its first major combat success last month, seizing five Kurdish-held areas in Syria.
"The downward slide of jihadist appeal and success since 2009 has been reversed by Katibah Nusantara's success in Iraq and Syria," Singh wrote.
He said Malaysian fighters had also seized on local issues like the push for an Islamic penal code to win support.
The unit poses a severe threat to Singapore and South-east Asia, said Professor Rohan Gunaratna, who heads Singapore's International Centre for Political Violence and Terrorism Research.
"It has multiple functions: to train people capable of carrying out attacks in Iraq and Syria, to instigate South-east Asians to mount attacks in their home countries, and to radicalise South-east Asians online, recruit them and physically facilitate their entry into Iraq and Syria," Rohan said.
The strategy to counter this influence has to be multi-pronged, from engaging the community to exposing IS' evils online, he said.
Muslim leaders worldwide are also leading the effort to counter ISIS, he added.
PTI
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 07:27
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title> Majority of Americans support drone strikes in Pak: survey</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/majority-of-americans-support-drone-strikes-in-pak-survey_1603646.html </Link>
        <Description>  Nearly 60 per cent of Americans support the country&amp;#039;s policy of carrying out drone strikes against militants in Pakistan, according to a national survey.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
Washington: Nearly 60 per cent of Americans support the country's policy of carrying out drone strikes against militants in Pakistan, according to a national survey.
The Pew survey, released yesterday, stated that while 58 per cent Americans approve of US drone strikes to target militants in countries such as Pakistan, Yemen and Somalia, about a third (35 per cent) disapproves such attacks.
The survey was conducted between May 12-18 based on telephone interviews with around 2,000 adults living in all 50 US states and the capital Washington.
It stated that the public opinion about US drone strikes has changed only modestly since February 2013, when 56 per cent approved of them.
Compared to the 74 per cent Republicans who favour the drone strikes, only 56 per cent independents and 52 per cent Democrats support them, the survey said.
While men approve of drone attacks by more than two-to-one (67 per cent to 28 per cent), the balance of opinion is much narrower among women.
Half (50 per cent) of the women approve of the use of drones, while 42 per cent disapprove them, it said.
The survey also found that a majority (56 per cent) of the Americans say the US has mostly failed in achieving its goals in Afghanistan, while 36 per cent say the it has mostly succeeded.
Also a declining share of Americans sees prospects for long-term stability in Afghanistan.
Just 29 per cent respondents say it is likely that Afghanistan will be able to maintain a stable government following the departure of US forces from the country.
More than twice as many (68 per cent) say this outcome is unlikely, the survey added.
PTI
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 06:59
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title> Rebels capture last Syrian town in Idlib province</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/rebels-capture-last-syrian-town-in-idlib-province_1603639.html </Link>
        <Description>  The Syrian army has pulled back from the north-western city of Ariha after a coalition of insurgent groups seized the last city in Idlib province in northwestern Syria near the Turkish border that was still held by the government.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Rebels capture last Syrian town in Idlib province
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 05:16
0
Comment
Amman: The Syrian army has pulled back from the north-western city of Ariha after a coalition of insurgent groups seized the last city in Idlib province in northwestern Syria near the Turkish border that was still held by the government.
A coalition of rebel groups called Jaish al Fateh, or Conquest Army, said it had taken over the city. Syria`s al Qaeda offshoot Nusra Front is a major part of the coalition.
The coalition said it had overrun several checkpoints that defended the city. The Syrian army said intense fighting was going on with Nusra forces that had infiltrated Ariha.
"There are heavy clashes between the army and the terrorists of Jabahat al Nusra who infiltrated inside the city," said an army statement released on state television.
Later the army admitted its forces had pulled back from the city, the latest string of defeats by the Syrian army and a big blow to the morale of President Assad`s government forces who have vowed to defeat Sunni militants financed by Saudi Arabia, Qatar and Turkey who seek to overthrow his rule.
"Units of our armed forces evacauated their positions in Ariha and withdrew to defensive positiions in the vicinity of the city after battles it fought facing large number of Nusra terrorists," the army source was quoted as saying.
A rebel source from Ahrar al Sham confirmed that street fighting was going on inside the city between army fighters and the insurgents. "There are many bodies that litter the streets," he said, adding that the rebels were searching for Assad`s government forces inside the city.
Many civilians have hidden inside shelters.
Syria accuses Turkey of financing and aiding rebels seeking to topple the government. Damascus says foreign jihadi fighters allowed into Syrian territory by Turkey have played a pivotal role in recent rebel gains.
Rebel sources say they have secured more U.S.-made TOW missiles in recent months that have helped them to gain a military edge over the Syrian army.
The Nusra Front has made gains in northwestern Syria alongside other insurgent groups in recent weeks, seizing the city of Idlib, the town of Jisr al-Shughour and bringing them closer to government-held coastal areas north of the capital.
The loss of Ariha would leave the insurgents in control of most of Idlib a region that borders Turkey and neighbours President Assad`s heartland in Latakia province on the Mediterranean coast.
The city, once home to more than 80,000 people, is strategically located on the main army supply lines between Idlib and Latakia.
Rebel sources said that convoys carrying army forces had fled to Oroum al Jouz, an area west of Ariha and in areas closer to President Assad`s ancestral homeland. The army did not comment.
Nusra Front is also a major force against government forces and allied militia around the northern city of Aleppo. It is fighting in southern Syria as well, and its combatants have frequently clashed with Islamic State.
Syria`s four-year-old civil war has killed a quarter of a million people and driven nearly 8 million from their homes.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 05:16
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title> Crying baby gets Canadian singer kicked off flight</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/crying-baby-gets-canadian-singer-kicked-off-flight_1603638.html </Link>
        <Description> A Canadian singer-songwriter was kicked off a United Airlines flight in San Francisco because her two-year-old toddler would not stop crying, triggering outrage from her supporters.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Crying baby gets Canadian singer kicked off flight
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 05:11
0
Comment
Ottawa: A Canadian singer-songwriter was kicked off a United Airlines flight in San Francisco because her two-year-old toddler would not stop crying, triggering outrage from her supporters.
"Just got kicked off a @united flight because my son was crying really loud," Sarah Blackwood from the band Walk Off the Earth wrote yesterday on Twitter, accusing the airline of hating mothers.
"Apparently my little two-year-old crying son was a big threat."
Canadian music award-nominated Walk Off the Earth gained international fame recording covers such as Miley Cyrus's Wrecking Ball, Pharrel Williams's Happy, and Taylor Swift's Shake It Off, and original tunes.
Blackwood, who is also seven months pregnant with another child, was booked to fly late yesterday from San Francisco to Vancouver with her son Giorgio.
The flight was operated by SkyWest Airlines, which said the crew ordered the plane back to the gate over "safety concerns."
"Despite numerous requests, the child was not seated, as required by federal regulation to ensure passenger safety, and was repeatedly in the aisle of the aircraft before departure and during taxi," the airline said in a statement defending its decision.
Fellow passengers, however, denounced the move on United's Facebook page, saying the mother tried her best to calm her son and that the flight attendant had been "unprofessional, unreasonable and insensitive."
By the time the jetliner reached the gate, they noted, the toddler had fallen asleep.
But Blackwood and her son were still forced to disembark, while crews spent 75 minutes sifting through luggage to retrieve her bags from the plane, one passenger said.
Dozens of supporters reacted angrily on Twitter.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 05:09
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title> Chinese blessing scam cons New York granny</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/chinese-blessing-scam-cons-new-york-granny_1603635.html </Link>
        <Description>  A 61-year-old Chinese man pleaded guilty Thursday to stealing $60,000 from a New York grandmother after he promised to bless her son`s alleged evil spirits away, prosecutors said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Chinese blessing scam cons New York granny
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:36
0
Comment
New York: A 61-year-old Chinese man pleaded guilty Thursday to stealing $60,000 from a New York grandmother after he promised to bless her son`s alleged evil spirits away, prosecutors said.
The defendant, Xue Fang Zhou, admitted grand larceny in the third degree, in the latest in a series of convictions linked to Chinese blessing scams that have blighted cities in North America.
Prosecutors say versions of the scam have cropped up in cities with significant Chinese populations such as Boston and San Francisco, as well as Toronto in Canada.
Manhattan District Attorney Cyrus Vance said the retired, 65-year-old grandmother lost nearly all her life savings in the October 2014 incident.
"Variations of this scam have led to thousands of dollars in losses for elderly victims here in New York and across the country," Vance said.
The elderly, superstitious and the Chinese immigrant community are at particular risk, he cautioned.
Zhou engineered an introduction to the grandmother near Manhattan`s Chinatown, informing her that her son was cursed with bad luck.
The son was at risk of harm, Zhou said, unless a blessing ritual was performed over the victim`s money.
The victim collected her valuables so Zhou could perform the purported blessing, but promptly discovered that her bag of $60,000 and jewelry had been switched with a bag of water bottles.
Zhou is the sixth person to plead guilty in Manhattan to crimes related to blessing scams in the last two years, prosecutors said.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:36
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title> Mexico catches 50 illegal migrants on plane</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/mexico-catches-50-illegal-migrants-on-plane_1603634.html </Link>
        <Description>  Mexican authorities intercepted 50 undocumented migrants from Cuba and Central America on a plane that was about to fly from Cancun to a city bordering Texas on Thursday.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Mexico catches 50 illegal migrants on plane
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:30
0
Comment
Mexico City: Mexican authorities intercepted 50 undocumented migrants from Cuba and Central America on a plane that was about to fly from Cancun to a city bordering Texas on Thursday.
The migrants had entered Mexico illegally when they were stopped in the Caribbean coast resort city before they could reach Reynosa, said an official from the National Migration Institute.
The migrants included 18 Cubans, 23 Salvadorans, five Guatemalans, two Hondurans, one from Belize and another from the Caribbean island of Granada.
In Reynosa, organized crime controls the trafficking of migrants, who are often kidnapped and held in homes until their families pay a ransom.
Some 200,000 migrants illegally enter Mexico every year across the southern border with Guatemala.
Many have hitched rides on a freight train known as 'The Beast' but are forced to find alternative routes after authorities cracked down last year.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:30
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title> Italian coast guard rescues 234 migrants off Sicily coast </title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/italian-coast-guard-rescues-234-migrants-off-sicily-coast_1603633.html </Link>
        <Description>  The Italian coast guard broadcast footage of a rescue operation recovering 234 migrants from a fishing boat in a precarious condition in the Strait of Sicily, 200 km off the coast of the Sicilian city of Augusta.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Italian coast guard rescues 234 migrants off Sicily coast
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:27
0
Comment
Rome: The Italian coast guard broadcast footage of a rescue operation recovering 234 migrants from a fishing boat in a precarious condition in the Strait of Sicily, 200 km off the coast of the Sicilian city of Augusta.
The coast guard said in a statement on Thursday that the mission occurred on Wednesday night and added that all the passengers, including 187 men, 38 women and nine children, were safely escorted to the Port of Augusta.
The boat was by spotted by an Italian Navy helicopter, after which the coast guard`s relief centre ordered two ships to assist the vessel in distress.
African migrants fleeing conflict in their countries continue to wash up on Italian shores, while the journey often leads to disasters like that on April 19, when about 850 people drowned.
The European Union has been considering measures to address the phenomenon and to fight human trafficking networks through the destruction of seized ships.
The European Commission has also proposed for EU countries to share in welcoming 40,000 asylum seekers over the next two years.
IANS
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:27
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title> Bombs outside two five-star Baghdad hotels kill at least 10</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/bombs-outside-two-five-star-baghdad-hotels-kill-at-least-10_1603632.html </Link>
        <Description>  Car bombs exploded in the parking lots of two heavily fortified five-star hotels in central Baghdad late on Thursday, killing at least 10 people, police and medical sources said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Bombs outside two five-star Baghdad hotels kill at least 10
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:24
0
Baghdad: Car bombs exploded in the parking lots of two heavily fortified five-star hotels in central Baghdad late on Thursday, killing at least 10 people, police and medical sources said.
A further 30 people were wounded in the blasts, which were around seven minutes apart.
The first bomb targeted the Babylon hotel, where government officials often hold meetings and news conferences, and the second hit the Meridian.
Iraqi authorities lifted a decade-old night-time curfew on Baghdad early this year, seeking to restore a sense of normality to the capital as security forces battle Islamic State militants who have overrun large parts of the country.
But the rate of bombings in Baghdad has increased since then.
Insurgents seized the city of Ramadi, west of Baghdad, on May 17 in the most significant military setback to the government since a U.S.-led coalition launched a campaign of airstrikes against Islamic State last August.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:24
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title> Yemen border strikes kill two Saudis, Yemen death toll near 2,000 – WHO</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/yemen-border-strikes-kill-two-saudis-yemen-death-toll-near-2000-%E2%80%93-who_1603631.html </Link>
        <Description>   Two Saudi border guards were killed and five wounded by shells fired from Yemeni territories, an Interior Ministry spokesman said late on Wednesday, as the United Nations said the war`s death toll was close to 2,000.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen border strikes kill two Saudis, Yemen death toll near 2,000  WHO
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:21
0
Comment
Cairo/Aden: Two Saudi border guards were killed and five wounded by shells fired from Yemeni territories, an Interior Ministry spokesman said late on Wednesday, as the United Nations said the war`s death toll was close to 2,000.
Saudi forces and the Houthis have been trading fire across the border since an Arab alliance began military operations against the Iranian-backed Shi`ite group in March to try to restore exiled President Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi to power.
Saudi state news agency SPA said the border guards were killed at a military post in Dhahran al-Janoub, along the border with Yemen, when projectiles fired from the Yemeni side struck.
Two of the soldiers died on the spot while five others were wounded and taken to a hospital, the agency said.
The Saudi-led coalition says it began their campaign heeding a call by Hadi after the Houthis started advancing south towards the port city of Aden, where the president was based.
The Houthis, who captured the Yemeni capital Sanaa last September, say they are fighting against Sunni Islamist militants using areas outside their control as staging grounds for attacks. They also accused officials in Hadi`s government of siphoning public funds.
On the ground, southern opposition fighters allied with Hadi said they had ambushed and killed six soldiers allied with the Houthis stationed in the south-eastern city of Zinjibar.
The World Health Organisation (WHO), which compiles figures on casualties in Yemen, said its latest figures show that 1,942 people had been killed between March 19 and May 22.
It said 7,870 people were injured in the same period.
Residents of the southern city of Aden said Houthi fighters at checkpoints outside the city had been preventing trucks carrying basic foodstuffs and qat - a narcotic leaf many Yemenis chew daily - from entering.
They said they believe the measures were a punishment after local fighters ejected the Houthis from the nearby city of Dhalea in the most serious setback for the group since March.
Houthi officials were not immediately available to comment on the reports.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 04:21
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title> Boss can monitor workers&amp;#38;#039; Facebook activity, top court rules</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/boss-can-monitor-workers-facebook-activity-top-court-rules_1603627.html </Link>
        <Description> : Bosses who use the social networking website Facebook to spy on their employees at work are not breaking the law, Italy`s Supreme Court has ruled.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Boss can monitor workers' Facebook activity, top court rules
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 03:58
0
Comment
Rome:: Bosses who use the social networking website Facebook to spy on their employees at work are not breaking the law, Italy`s Supreme Court has ruled.
The court ruling on Thursday was found to be in favour of a printer who fired a worker when the former caught him chatting with a woman, whose fake profile had been set up by the printer himself, on Facebook.
The sacked employee had spent 15 minutes chatting with the woman on his mobile using the Facebook Messenger app, failing meanwhile to fix a a jam that had occurred in the printing works.
The printer was within his rights to set up the fake Facebook profile and dismiss the worker as it allowed "the check of continuous illegal behaviour, on the part of the employee, already observed in the past", the court said.
It also acceptable for employees to monitor workers` use of Facebook from their mobile phones, the court ruled.
The worker had engaged in several previous conversations over Facebook during his working hours and an iPad was found on charge in his locker.
IANS
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 03:58
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
