<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="abcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:40:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Yemen Crisis a 'Humanitarian Catastrophe,' Experts Say</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/yemen-crisis-humanitarian-catastrophe-experts/story?id=31377337</Link>
        <Description>The Yemen crisis has developed into a "humanitarian catastrophe," experts say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen Crisis a 'Humanitarian Catastrophe,' Experts Say
May 28, 2015, 7:38 PM ET
Follow @alex_mallin
An armed Shiite Huthi rebel walks above debris on April 12, 2015 at the compound of Sanaa's al-Yarmuk football club which was reported hit by an air strike by the Saudi-led coalition the previous day in the Yemeni capital's northern al-Rawda district.
Muhammed Huwais/AFP/Getty Images
Its been just more than two months since a Saudi Arabia -led coalition began its airstrike campaign against Houthi rebels in Yemen , and the country has since become a humanitarian catastrophe, experts said Thursday.
I am shocked about what I have seen, said Medecins Sans Frontieres Middle East Operations Manager Pablo Marco, who spent 50 days inside the country recently. The biggest problem is the fact both parties in the conflict are not respecting the civilians and, specifically, they are not respecting medical facilities and medical staff.
Marco was one in a panel of three experts in Washington who took a hard line against attacks by the Houthis as well as the 10-country coalition engaged in a bombing campaign against them for the past 10 weeks. The U.S. provides intelligence and material support to that Arab-led coalition.
The World Health Organization said on Wednesday that more than 2,000 people have been killed and more than 8,000 injured in the conflict since airstrikes began, and that 8.6 million people are in urgent need of medical help.
Heavy Saudi-Led Airstrikes Target Shiite Rebels in Yemen
In the past, Saudi Arabia has pushed back against reports of civilians being targeted by its airstrikes and said the coalition has "exercised restraint."
Last week, U.S. State Department press director Jeff Rathke said the only solution to Yemen's crisis is "to get back to the political dialogue process," adding, "the Houthis have to cease unilateral aggressive actions inside Yemen in order for that to have a chance.
Rathke added that the U.S. has urged "Saudi and other authorities to continue to allow commercial shipments of fuel and food to avert a humanitarian crisis for the 16 million Yemenis in need of assistance. And we also understand that humanitarian aid organizations and the United Nations will continue to try to deliver aid as conditions permit.
However, the panel said dozens of hospitals have had to shut down inside the country, and nearly all that are still operating are powered by generators.
We are witnessing how the whole health system in the country is literally coming to a halt, Marco said. In a matter of 15 days or two weeks there will be hundreds of people who will be dying from this.
Philippe Bolopion, a crisis advocacy director for Human Rights Watch (HRW), said his teams have documented cases where coalition airstrikes have caused disproportionate damage to the civilian population.
He said HRW has called on the U.S. to exercise pressure on the coalition.
They have made the case that they are supportive to the coalition but are not a party to the conflict, Bolopion said. We are trying to challenge that a little bit, because according to publicly available information the U.S. has been refueling war planes in the air, providing intelligence possibly on some targets, helping with coordination. And if they are in some cases they are a party to the conflict, they could be found to be complicit to some of the violations that have occurred.
The panel said the Houthis share some of the blame for lack of access to those in need of medical assistance, citing sniper attacks and bombings around hospitals.
One of the more shocking things is that they reacted to the start of the military operation by recruiting even more children in their ranks, Bolopion said.
The panel said that the coalition could provide some relief to the health crisis by easing the tight control of Yemens border and ports. Bolopion called it a blockade, and said it hindered efforts to provide aid to the population during the five-day humanitarian ceasefire earlier this month.
Bolopion said Yemen receives almost 80 percent of its food supply from international shipments.
Its hugely dependent on the outside, and the same thing for fuel, Bolopion said.
Many have classified the conflict in Yemen since Saudi intervention as a proxy war, citing the Houthis alignment with Iran.
Robert Blecher, deputy director of the International Crisis Group, said the poor execution of the airstrike campaign has exacerbated a more domestic conflict into a regional powder-keg.
The longer this goes on, the more and more the Houthis will be forced to have an external patron, Blecher said. The highest probability of a direct Iranian-Saudi clash is in Yemen right now.
With the coalition focusing on the Houthis and the U.S. counterterrorism operations in the country severely hindered, Blecher said it has afforded al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula more territory than it has ever held before.
So far, the biggest winner politically of the fighting probably has been al Qaeda, Blecher said. Weve seen around the region -- look at Syria, look at Iraq , look at whats happening in Libya -- the longer these conflicts go on, the more ribbed these extremists become.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31377337.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 10:19:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Last Generation of China's Zipliners</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/generation-zipliners-small-chinese-village-give-centuries-tradition/story?id=31362000</Link>
        <Description>As the new China of high speed trains, highways and unbridled construction encroaches on this remote corner of the country, ziplines are quickly disappearing.</Description>
        <MainBody>China Detains Artist Who Posted Humorous Photo of President
The communities that live along the Nujiang are mostly members of the Lisu ethnic minorities, a hill tribe that have ziplining in their blood.
When asked about using the ziplines now, villagers of the Lisu ethnic minority pointed to the government-built bridges that are quickly replacing their traditional form of mode of transportation. Decades earlier the local provincial government had helped upgrade ziplines from bamboo-made cables to steel but today many of the harnesses are homemade.
In one village called Boa, locals zipped back and forth as they took their kids to school. Others were heading to jobs or to pick up supplies. For the time being, the ziplines remain the fastest way to get across the river from Boa.
ABC News
In one village called Boa, locals zipped back and forth as they took their kids to school. Others were heading to jobs or to pick up supplies.
The Chinese government have plans to build at least four new hydro-electric dams on the untouched river, although environmental advocates are pushing back. Although the plan has yet to be full approval, preparation for dams has already started as earth-moving machinery dot the winding road that runs along the Nujiang.
A 90-year-old grandmother named Qiu Maqian told "Nightline" that she grew up in Boa and has used the ziplines since the 1930s, back when the lines were made of bamboo. Metal lines replaced the bamboo in the 1970s. She said she will not be around to watch the changes, and that ziplining has been a big part of her life but she said she knows that will not last much longer.
A 17-year-old Boa villager named Pu Shaheng may be the last generation of Nujiang zipliners, but he told "Nightline" that he feels life will be easier when bridges and highways come into town.
Pu then paused and added the idea of the ziplines going away made him sad because its a lifestyle his kids and generations to come will never know.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 22:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly Heatwave Melting Roads </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/indias-deadly-heatwave-melting-roads/story?id=31341298</Link>
        <Description>A devastating heatwave has left more than 1,100 people dead over the past month in India, and photos also show the toll on the country's infrastructure.</Description>
        <MainBody>India's Deadly Heatwave Melting Roads
May 27, 2015, 3:08 PM ET
Road markings appear distorted as the asphalt starts to melt due to the high temperature in New Delhi, May 27, 2015.
Harish Tyagi/EPA
A devastating heatwave has left more than 1,100 people dead over the past month in India , and photos also show the toll on the country's infrastructure.
Temperatures in the southeastern states of Andhra Pradesh and Telengana have reached 113 degrees in the past two days, The Associated Press reported. More than 1,100 people have reportedly died in the past month from heat-related causes in those two states, with at least 852 dead in Andhra Pradesh.
Flash Floods Leave Apocalyptic Scenes Across Texas
Harish Tyagi/EPA
PHOTO: Road markings appear distorted as the asphalt starts to melt due to the high temperature in New Delhi, May 27, 2015.
Photos show asphalt road surfaces melting in New Delhi, disrupting road markings in the city.
Narinder Nanu/AFP/Getty Images
PHOTO: An Indian worker uses a ricksahw to transport ice from an ice factory in Amritsar on May 27, 2015.
A drought in much of India, along with a busy typhoon season, could spell trouble for a billion people in Asia this summer, according to AccuWeather . Public announcements urge people to drink water and stay indoors during the hottest hours of the day, the AP reported.
Sanjeev Gupta/EPA
PHOTO: Sunil, 30, gets medical treatment in Jai Prakash Narayan hospital after suffering sunstroke and severe dehydration in Bhopal Madhya Pradesh, India, May 27, 2015.
El Nio, a warm phase of the fluctuation of sea surface temperatures in the tropical Pacific Ocean, is likely leading to an above-average number of typhoons and super-typhoons, AccuWeather reports. But El Nio may displace the already-delayed monsoon, leading to below-normal rainfall in India.
Anindito Mukherjee/Reuters
PHOTO: Sheep cross a parched area of a dried-up pond on a hot summer day on the outskirts of New Delhi, May 27, 2015.
Weather officials blamed northwesterly dry and hot winds from the desert state of Rajasthan for the extreme heat.
Rajat Gupta/EPA
PHOTO: Indian laborers prepare air coolers for sale as temperature rises in New Delhi, May 27, 2015.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 19:35:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosion Narrowly Avoided After Fire Engulfs Ship Carrying Fertilizer</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/explosion-narrowly-avoided-fire-engulfs-ship-off-coast/story?id=31336440</Link>
        <Description>The freighter was carrying fertilizer in its cargo hold.</Description>
        <MainBody>Explosion Narrowly Avoided After Fire Engulfs Ship Off Coast of Germany
May 27, 2015, 12:03 PM ET
By LOUISE DEWAST
Task Force Rescue Vessels put out the fire on The Purple Beach freighter.
German Central Command for Maritime Emergencies (CCME)
A freighter carrying fertilizer -- a potentially explosive substance -- was abandoned by its crew off the coast of Germany after the vessel caught on fire, German officials told ABC News.
But after more than two days of smoldering, and a failed attempt to extinguish the flames, the ship is no longer at risk of exploding, German officials said.
Dozens of residents from Bremerhaven and nearby towns called Germany's Central Command for Maritime Emergencies on Monday asking about a large cloud of smoke emanating from a ship sailing off the coast, authorities said.
Norwegian Dawn Cruise Ship Aground in Bermuda
The 630-foot long cargo named Purple Beach was headed for the German port of Brake and had been travelling from the United Kingdom, authorities said.
The fire was initially put out, but it picked up again on Tuesday prompting the crew to evacuate, officials said. Residents were told to keep windows and doors shut as a risk of explosion was reported.
German Central Command for Maritime Emergencies (CCME)
PHOTO: Task Force Rescue Vessels put out the fire on The Purple Beach freighter.
On Wednesday, authorities managed to pour massive streams of water onto the smoking ship and firefighters were able to board the vessel, a spokesman from the Central Command said.
All of the 26 crew members who had been sent to hospital for monitoring have now been released, the spokesman added.
Rescue boats are still monitoring the situation, making sure that the temperature of the boat remains stable. In the next few hours, officials will decide whether and how to tow the ship and clear the area.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31336440.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 21:59:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>See Man's Body Covered With 1.1 Million Bees</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/man-underpants-covers-11-million-bees-sets-world/story?id=31321278</Link>
        <Description>Wearing only his underpants, Gao Bingguo set a new Guinness World Record after he covered himself with almost 1.1 million bees, collectively weighing 240 pounds.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man in Underpants Covers Himself With 1.1 Million Bees, Sets World Record
May 26, 2015, 7:09 PM ET
Chinese beekeeper Gao Bingguo is fully covered with bees as he challenges to set a new Guinness World Record in Liangzhuang, China, May 25, 2015.
Liu hongjie/AP Photo
Wearing only his underpants, Gao Bingguo set a new Guinness World Record after he covered himself with almost 1.1 million bees, collectively weighing 240 pounds.
The 55-year-old beekeeper accomplished the feat Monday morning in Tai'an, China .
Bingguo was stung more than 2,000 times and his body temperature rose to a burning 140 degrees at one point.
Thousands of Wasps Found Nesting in UK Home, Devouring Bed
Fellow beekeepers started by first placing a number of queen bees on his body to help attract worker bees. Boxes of bees were later dumped at his feet in increasingly large numbers as the bees crawled on his entire body -- except his mouth.
Binguo smoked a cigarette to prevent the bees from swarming his lips.
Liu hongjie/AP Photo
PHOTO: Assistants open boxes to dump bees on the bee-covered body of Chinese beekeeper Gao Bingguo as he challenges to set a new Guinness World Record in Liangzhuang, China, May 25, 2015.
Bingguo beat the previous world for the heaviest coat of bees on the body, which was set at about 188 pounds.
The 55-year-old man has kept bees for over 35 years.
Liu hongjie/AP Photo
PHOTO: Assistants open boxes to dump bees on the bee-covered body of Chinese beekeeper Gao Bingguo as he challenges to set a new Guinness World Record in Liangzhuang, China, May 25, 2015.
The Associated Press contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31321278.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:49:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Volcano Erupts in Galapagos -- but Wildlife Has Bigger Problems</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/galapagos-volcano-eruption-threat-wildlife-small-compared-man/story?id=31311857</Link>
        <Description>The eruption of a mile-high volcano on one of the Galapagos Islands this week has triggered concerns for the fragile and world-renowned ecosystem on the remote islands.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy
The eruption of a mile-high volcano on one of the Galapagos Islands this week has triggered concerns for the fragile and world-renowned ecosystem on the remote islands. But volcanic activity isnt the biggest threat to the region made famous by Charles Darwins studies on evolution, according to wildlife experts.
WATCH: Galapagos Island Volcano Erupts
Volcanism and eruptions are a normal part of the evolutionary ecology on the Galapagos Islands, Steve Walsh, the director of the Center for Galapagos Studies at the University of North Carolina, told ABC News. We seem to be excited about a volcano, but the Galapagos are under siege by a lot of different things.
"There are far more human-induced threats to the species of the Galapagos," said Hugo Arnal, the World Wildlife Fund's director for Ecuador .
Experts list invasive species , overfishing, pollution, overpopulation and unsustainable tourism as more significant threats.
Layne Kennedy/Corbis
PHOTO: Tourists photograph a giant tortoise eating fruit in the forest in the Galapagos Islands on June 11, 2013.
The Galapagos consist of 13 major islands formed by volcanic eruptions that occurred millions of years ago. Since Charles Darwins arrival in 1835, the Galapagos have been called a living laboratory of evolution because of wildlife found only on these islands. Giant tortoises, pink iguanas, red-footed boobies, and thousands of other unique species can only be found there.
For the first time in 33 years, Isabela Islands Wolf Volcano erupted on Monday, shooting rivers of lava down its slopes and filling the night sky with a red glare. Technicians at the Galapagos National Park determined the lava is flowing southeast and seems to be sparing the northern section of the island where the worlds only population of pink iguanas lives.
The population of the pink iguanas, yellow iguanas and land turtles are in the northeast and are out of danger, said Danny Reuda, director of ecosystems at the Galapagos National Park Service , the Ecuadorian agency responsible for managing the Galapagos.
Stephen Frink Collection/Alamy
PHOTO: A Galapagos shark is seen tangled on a long line monofilament in the Galapagos Islands in an undated image.
There is no human population near the volcano. Puerto Villamil, the nearest town, is located 115 kilometers to the south.
There is some loss of vegetation, but its an opportunity for other species to grow, Reuda said, calling the eruption a natural process. He added that officials would not interfere with the lava flow, which is beginning to freeze.
Getty Images
PHOTO: Sea lions lounge on South Plaza Island in the Galapagos Islands on Nov. 30, 2010.
People may be a bigger threat than lava, experts say. Census data shows more than 26,000 people live on the islands, a UNESCO world heritage site. Unbeknownst to many tourists, the islands do not have widespread public sewage systems, according to the World Wildlife Fund. Sewage is left to seep into the ground and the sea. With the spike in tourism, the Galapagos' pristine landscape is in danger of being transformed.
"There has been an explosion in the number of hotels and restaurants," said WWF's Arnal, who argued that the increase in tourism is the main driver for expanding trade between the archipelago and the continent, creating more chances for invasive species to reach the pristine islands.
Mark Moffett/Minden Pictures/Corbis
PHOTO: A herd of feral goats gathers near a giant tortoise in the Galapagos Islands on June 15, 2004.
Introduced plants and animals, ranging from cats to avocados, represent a huge threat to native species, which lack natural predators and are defenseless to invasive predators, according to the Galapagos National Park Service. At one point, an estimated 100,000 feral goats lived on Isabela Island and devastated the ecosystem through overgrazing. The park service eventually was forced to adopt a radical eradication plan involving helicopter-mounted machine guns and radio collared Judas goats used to locate herds. The plan was deemed a success in 2005 when the last feral goat was removed from Isabela Island, though some 266 Judas goes remain for monitoring purposes.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31311857.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:17:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Galapagos Island Volcano Erupts, Threatening Fragile Ecosystem</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/galapagos-island-volcano-erupts-threatening-fragile-ecosystem/story?id=31300581</Link>
        <Description>A volcano atop one of the Galapagos Islands has erupted for the first time in 33 years, spewing fire, smoke and lava into the night sky.</Description>
        <MainBody>Galapagos Island Volcano Erupts, Threatening Fragile Ecosystem
May 26, 2015, 12:36 AM ET
By ABC NEWS via Good Morning America
In this photo provided by Diego Paredes, guide of La Pinta Yatch Expedition, shows Wolf volcano erupting, at Isabela Island, Galapagos Islands, Ecuador, May 25, 2015.
Diego Paredes/AP Photo
Copy
A volcano atop one of the Galapagos Islands has erupted for the first time in 33 years, spewing fire, smoke and lava into the night sky  and threatening a fragile ecosystem that inspired Charles Darwin's theory of evolution.
Ecuador 's Galapagos National Park administration said the mile-high Wolf volcano erupted before dawn Monday. The eruption could be seen for miles.
Editor's Picks
Posted by Parque Nacional Galapagos on Monday, May 25, 2015
The volcano lies on the northern tip of Isabela Island, the archipelago's largest.
Authorities said no tourist activity was affected  and for now, lava flowing in the southwest direction poses no risk to the world's only population of pink iguanas, which live on the island's northwest tip.
Darwin visited the eastern Pacific island chain in 1835, and the trip influenced his findings presented in the book The origin of Species.
The Associated Press contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue May 26 15:07:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fighter Jets Scramble Following at Least 6 Threats to Planes</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/fighter-jets-scramble-escort-air-france-flight-threat/story?id=31289047</Link>
        <Description>Several planes had to be escorted to remote areas at JFK Airport.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fighter Jets Scramble Following at Least 6 Reports of Threats to Passenger Planes, Officials Say
May 25, 2015, 4:21 PM ET
Officials search an Air France plane after it lands at John F. Kennedy Airport in New York City on May 25, 2015.
WABC
At least six flights were impacted by threats at airports in New York, New Jersey and Boston today, according to airlines and law enforcement.
JFK Airport:
An Air France plane was escorted to JFK Airport in New York City this morning after an anonymous threat was made against the flight, law enforcement officials told ABC News. The FBI said the plane has since been checked and cleared with "no incidents or hazards reported on board the flight by either the passengers or its crew."
Authorities said that the decision to have the plane escorted by two fighter jets was done "out of an abundance of caution" after the Maryland State Police McHenry Barrack, in Garrett County, received an anonymous call of a chemical weapons threat aboard Air France Flight 22, which was en route from Paris to the New York City airport.
Lightning Appears to Strike 2 Planes Flying Into Sea-Tac Airport
The tip was called in at 6:45 a.m. on an untraceable line and the caller did not identify himself, a senior federal official told ABC News. Two F-15 planes were scrambled and followed the plane into U.S. airspace, but they flew in a way so that the passengers and crew would not be able to see the military planes, sources said.
The Airbus A-330 has since landed and was taken between two runways and locked down while the threat is investigated. A police dispatch that was sent out after the jets were scrambled noted that the area where the plane was taken is generally known as the "hijack site" because it is the area used in such scenarios. During an initial investigation, nothing dangerous has been found on board, the federal official told ABC News.
A Saudi Airlines flight from Saudi Arabia was also escorted to a remote area at JFK. It was cleared and passengers were brought back to the terminal, officials said.
For an American Airlines flight from Birmingham, England, to JFK, the pilot was initially instructed to taxi to a remote area, but the threat was determined not credible and the plane was cleared to go to the terminal.
Newark Airport:
Two flights to Newark, New Jersey, were also affected -- a Delta Air Lines flight from London and a United Airlines flight from Madrid, authorities said.
Logan Airport:
A threat also turned up negative for a Delta flight from Paris to Logan Airport in Boston, authorities said. 
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31289047.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:19:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  This Week in Pictures</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/photos/week-pictures-31292468</Link>
        <Description>The latest news photos from around the globe.</Description>
        <MainBody>+

Activists of the international campaigning and advocacy organization ONE install illuminated balloons with portraits of the G7 heads of state in front of the Frauenkirche cathedral prior to the G7 Finance Ministers meeting in Dresden, Germany, May 27, 2015.
Jens Meyer/AP Photo
Activists of the international campaigning and advocacy organization ONE install illuminated balloons with portraits of the G7 heads of state in front of the Frauenkirche cathedral prior to the G7 Finance Ministers meeting in Dresden, Germany, May 27, 2015.
Jens Meyer/AP Photo
Britain's Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Philip make their way towards a garden party held at Buckingham Palace in London, May 28, 2015.
Alastair Grant/AP Photo
Volunteers check honey bee hives for queen activity and perform routine maintenance as part of a collaboration between the Cincinnati Zoo and TwoHoneys Bee Co., May 27, 2015, at EcOhio Farm in Mason, Ohio. A federal rule to be proposed on May 28 would create temporary pesticide-free zones when certain plants are in bloom around bees that are trucked from farm to farm by professional beekeepers.
John Minchillo/AP Photo
A Palestinian youth dives into the Mediterranean Sea on the coast of Gaza City, May 27, 2015, as temperatures rise to about 107.6 Fahrenheit.
Mohammed Abed/AFP/Getty Images
A US para-trooper of the Army's 4th 25 Infantry Brigade Combat Team (Airborne), part of the NATO-led peacekeeping mission in Kosovo packs his parachute during a military drill near the village of Ramjan on May 27, 2015.
Armend Nimani/AFP/Getty Images
A worker uses a rickshaw to transport ice from an ice factory in Amritsar on May 27, 2015. More than 1,100 people have died in a blistering heatwave sweeping India, authorities said May 27, 2015, as forecasters warned searing temperatures would continue.
Narinder Nanu/AFP/Getty Images
A residential area is submerged in flood water after strong rainstorms hit in southwest China's Guizhou province, May 27, 2015. Heavy rain which caused mudslides and flooding in southern and central China has left at least 35 people dead and another 13 missing.
AFP/Getty Images
Bates Bennett, 14, of Memphis, Tenn. clenches his fists as he correctly spells the word "bowery" during 2015 Scripps National Spelling Bee, May 27, 2015, in Oxon Hill, Md.
Andrew Harnik/AP Photo
Tibetan spiritual leader the Dalai Lama greets devotees as he arrives to give a religious talk at the Tibetan Children's Village School in Dharmsala, India, May 27, 2015. Every year Dalai Lama gives teachings to young Tibetans at the school.
Ashwini Bhatia/AP Photo
Residents stand outside their homes as damaged cars are seen after a tornado hit the town of Ciudad Acuna, Mexico, May 25, 2015.
Ramiro Gomez/Reuters
Tourist Gina Youginkim, right, and Margaret Kahng, from South Korea, third from right, pose for a picture with clowns during a march commemorating the Peruvian clown day in Lima Peru, May 25, 2015. Hundreds of professional clowns dressed in colorful costumes, wigs and face paint marched through the streets of Lima to celebrate Peruvian Clown Day.
Rodrigo Abd/AP Photo
Russian-backed rebels smoke on the outskirts of Donetsk, eastern Ukraine, May 26, 2015. The situation in eastern Ukraine has remained tense and skirmishes between Ukrainian forces and Russia-backed separatists have continued despite a cease-fire signed in February.
Mstyslav Chernov/AP Photo
Christian Jacobs, 4, of Hertford, NC, lies on the grave of his father during Memorial Day celebrations at Arlington National Cemetery in Arlington, Virginia, May 25, 2015.
Joshua Roberts/Reuters
Hundreds of students of the school of nursing take part in an open-air examination at a playground of an vocational college in Baoji, Shaanxi province, China, May 25, 2015.
Reuters
Rohingya migrants queue up for food at a temporary shelter in Bayeun, Aceh province, Indonesia, May 25, 2015. Since May 10, thousands of Bangladeshi and Rohingya migrants have landed ashore in Indonesia, Malaysia and Thailand. Thousands more are believed to be trapped at sea in boats abandoned by their captains.
Binsar Bakkara/AP Photo
A woman with the Spanish words "Children of the corn" written on her chest attends the Corn Carnival on the global day of action against the agricultural biotechnology giant Monsanto in Mexico City, May 23, 2015. Activists gathered to support the annual "March Against Monsanto" to demand a stop to the use of agrochemicals and the production of genetically modified food (GMO's).
Marco Ugarte/AP Photo
Carl Edwards celebrates in Victory Lane after winning the NASCAR Sprint Cup series auto race at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord, N.C., May 24, 2015.
Chuck Burton/AP Photo
A Nepalese man walks past damaged houses one month after the deadly 7.8 magnitude earthquake in Kathmandu, Nepal, May 25, 2015. Two powerful earthquakes devastated Nepal on April 25 and May 12, killing nearly 8,700 people and injuring 16,800 others.
Niranjan Shrestha/AP Photo
The water line is clear on Ruth Hansen's living room wall, May 24, 2015, in San Marcos, Texas. Record rainfall was wreaking havoc across a swath of the U.S. Midwest on Sunday, causing flash floods in normally dry riverbeds, spawning tornadoes and forcing at least 2,000 people to flee.
Nell Carroll/Austin American-Statesman via AP Photo
Colin Montgomerie of Scotland hits his tee shot on the second hole during the third round of the 2015 Senior PGA Championship at the Pete Dye Course on May 23, 2015 in French Lick, Indiana.
Mike Ehrmann/Getty Images
Graduates from the U.S. Military Academy toss their hats into the air after a graduation and commissioning ceremony, May 23, 2015, in West Point, N.Y.
Mike Groll/AP Photo
Jeralean Talley, the world's oldest-known living person, is escorted down the aisle following a church service and celebration for her 116th birthday in Inkster, Michigan May 24, 2015.
Rebecca Cook/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Mon May 25 20:29:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly Tornado Leaves Cars at 90-Degree Angle</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/deadly-tornado-destroys-homes-overturns-cars-mexico/story?id=31290376</Link>
        <Description>A tornado hit the town of Ciudad Acuna, 2 miles from Laughlin Air Force base.</Description>
        <MainBody>Deadly Tornado Destroys Homes in Mexico, Leaving Cars at 90-Degree Angle
May 25, 2015, 1:29 PM ET
By EMILY SHAPIRO
A tornado struck the town of Ciudad Acuna, Mexico, near the Texas border, on May 25, 2015, causing at least 10 deaths and widespread damage.
Coahuila State Government
At least 13 people were killed today when a tornado struck the town of Ciudad Acuna, Mexico , near the Texas border, causing widespread damage that includes destroyed homes and cars flipped sideways at 90-degree angles.
The town is just two miles from Texas' Laughlin Air Force base, the largest pilot training base in the United States.
No injuries or damage were reported at the Air Force base, according to an official.
About 300 homes were affected, according to a press statement from the Coahuila Government.
Ramiro Gomez/Reuters
PHOTO: Residents stand next to a damaged car after a tornado hit the town of Ciudad Acuna, state of Coahuila, May 25, 2015.
Ramiro Gomez/Reuters
PHOTO: Residents stand outside their homes as damaged cars are seen after a tornado hit the town of Ciudad Acuna, state of Coahuila, May 25, 2015.
Coahuila State Government
PHOTO: A tornado struck the town of Ciudad Acuna, Mexico, near the Texas border, on May 25, 2015, causing at least 10 deaths and widespread damage.
Coahuila State Government
PHOTO: A tornado struck the town of Ciudad Acuna, Mexico, near the Texas border, on May 25, 2015, causing at least 10 deaths and widespread damage.
Coahuila State Government
PHOTO: A tornado struck the town of Ciudad Acuna, Mexico, near the Texas border, on May 25, 2015, causing at least 10 deaths and widespread damage.
The Associated Press contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31290376.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:56:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek Bank Deposits Fall to Lowest in More Than a Decade</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/greek-bank-deposits-fall-lowest-decade-31386192</Link>
        <Description>As bailout talks stall, Greek bank deposits fall to lowest level in more than a decade</Description>
        <MainBody>Greek Bank Deposits Fall to Lowest in More Than a Decade
ATHENS, Greece  May 29, 2015, 6:54 AM ET
Greek bank deposits have fallen to their lowest in more than a decade, new statistics show, as Greeks worried about their new government's painfully slow negotiations with creditors withdraw savings.
Figures from the European Central Bank published Friday showed more than 5 billion euros ($5.5 billion) were withdrawn in April.
That leaves household deposits at the end of the month at 139.4 billion euros ($151.9 billion), down from 145 billion euros in March. The figure is the lowest since November 2004, when deposits stood at 137.2 billion euros.
Athens has insisted in recent days it is close to a deal, indicating an agreement could come as soon as this weekend that would unlock desperately needed funds from its international bailout. But European officials have said much remains to be done.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31386192.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:55:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Says China Has Artillery Vehicles on Artificial Island</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/us-china-artillery-vehicles-artificial-island-31384868</Link>
        <Description>US says China has artillery vehicles on artificial island in South China Sea</Description>
        <MainBody>US Says China Has Artillery Vehicles on Artificial Island
SINGAPORE  May 29, 2015, 6:54 AM ET
By LOLITA C. BALDOR Associated Press
Two large artillery vehicles were detected on one of the artificial islands that China is creating in the South China Sea, U.S. officials said Friday, underscoring ongoing concerns that Beijing may try to use the land reclamation projects for military purposes.
The discovery was made at least several weeks ago by the United States, but it's not clear if the weapons are still there or if they have been moved or hidden out of sight, officials said.
The revelation comes as Defense Secretary Ash Carter begins an 11-day trip, including several stops in the Asia Pacific. He is slated to speak Saturday at an international security summit here, and is expected to reassert America's views that China and other nations must stop all land reclamation projects in the region.
Pentagon spokesman Brent Colburn said the U.S. was aware of the artillery, but he declined to provide other details, saying it is an intelligence matter. Defense officials described the weapons as self-propelled artillery vehicles, and said they posed no threat to the U.S. or American territories. The officials were not authorized to discuss the matter publicly so spoke on condition of anonymity.
The sighting was first reported by the Wall Street Journal .
U.S. officials, however, have been watching the rapidly expanding land reclamation by China, which, according to estimates, totals more than 2,000 acres in the South China Sea.
The U.S. has been flying surveillance aircraft in the region, prompting China to file a formal protest after a U.S. Navy P-8A Poseidon recently flew over one of the sites.
Carter on Wednesday made it clear that the U.S. will "fly, sail and operate wherever international law allows." But so far he has said little about what the U.S. is willing to do to get China to stop the island construction.
U.S. and other regional officials have expressed concerns about the island building, including worries that it may be a prelude to navigation restrictions or the enforcement of a possible air defense identification zone over the South China Sea. China declared such a zone over disputed Japanese-held islands in the East China Sea in 2013.
Asked about the latest imagery suggesting China had put weapons on one of the land reclamation islands, China's Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying said she is "not aware of the situation you mention, but China has clearly reiterated its position several times on the islands in the South China Sea."
She also pushed back against Carter's criticism, saying that the U.S. should be "rational and calm and stop making any provocative remarks, because such remarks not only do not help ease the controversies in the South China Sea, but they also will aggravate the regional peace and stability."
Carter has been vocal about U.S. opposition to the China construction and on Friday afternoon flew over the crowded Straits of Malacca and Singapore , in part to emphasize the need for continued freedom of navigation in the region.
On board two V-22 Ospreys, Carter and his staff and several members of the media flew over the narrow shipping lanes, which were packed with massive container ships and other vessels.
The busy waterway is "a very striking example of the link between security and prosperity and the importance of having security and stability in the Pacific," said Kelly Magsamen, the Pentagon's principle deputy assistant secretary for Asia Pacific matters.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:54:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saudi Officials: Suicide Bomber Kills 4 People in Attack on Shiite Mosque</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/saudi-officials-suicide-bomber-kills-people-attack-shiite-31386090</Link>
        <Description>Saudi officials: suicide bomber kills 4 people in attack on Shiite mosque</Description>
        <MainBody>Saudi Officials: Suicide Bomber Kills 4 People in Attack on Shiite Mosque
RIYADH, Saudi Arabia  May 29, 2015, 6:53 AM ET
Saudi officials: suicide bomber kills 4 people in attack on Shiite mosque .
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31386090.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:49:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia Steps up Propaganda Push With Online "Kremlin Trolls"</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/russia-steps-propaganda-push-online-kremlin-trolls-31382523</Link>
        <Description>Russia's army of online "trolls" at front line of campaign to shape opinion at home, in West</Description>
        <MainBody>Russia Steps up Propaganda Push With Online "Kremlin Trolls"
ST. PETERSBURG, Russia  May 29, 2015, 6:48 AM ET
By IULIIA SUBBOTOVSKA Associated Press
Deep inside a four-story marble building in St. Petersburg, hundreds of workers tap away at computers on the front lines of an information war, say those who have been inside. Known as "Kremlin trolls," the men and women work 12-hour shifts around the clock, flooding the Internet with propaganda aimed at stamping President Vladimir Putin's world vision on Russia, and the world.
The Kremlin has always dabbled in propaganda, but in the past year its troll campaign has gone into overdrive, adding hundreds of online operatives to help counter Western pressure over its role in the pro-Russian insurgency in eastern Ukraine. The program is drawing Serbia away from its proclaimed EU membership path and closer to the Russian orbit, and is targeting Germany, the United States and other Western powers. The operation has worried the European Union enough to prompt it to draw up a blueprint for fighting Russia's disinformation campaign, although details have not yet been released.
Lyuda Savchuk, a single mother with two children, worked in the St. Petersburg "troll factory" until mid-March. The 34-year-old journalist said she had some idea of the Orwellian universe she was entering when she took the job, but underestimated its intensity and scope.
"I knew it was something bad, but of course I never suspected that it was this horrible and this large-scale," she said in an interview in her apartment, which has colorful drawings on the walls for her two preschool-age children.
She described how the trolls manage several social media accounts under different nicknames. Those in her department had to bash out 160 blog posts during a 12-hour shift. Trolls in other departments flooded the Internet with doctored images and pro-Putin commentary on news stories that crop up on Russian and Western news portals.
In some departments, she said, the trolls receive daily talking points on what to write and what emotions to evoke. "It seems to me that they don't know what they are doing," Savchuk said. "They simply repeat what they are told."
She said most of the trolls are young and are attracted by relatively high monthly salaries of 40,000 to 50,000 rubles ($800 to $1,000).
Her descriptions of the work coincide with those of other former trolls who have spoken publicly, although Savchuk is one of the few willing to have her full name published. She quit after a little more than two months, after finding she couldn't stand being part of a propaganda machine.
The trolls are employed by Internet Research, which Russian news reports say is financed by a holding company headed by Putin's friend and personal chef. Those who have worked there say they have little doubt that the operation is run from the Kremlin.
St. Petersburg journalist Andrei Soshnikov, who was one of the first to report on the "troll factory," said about 400 people work in the building. A video he posted on YouTube this spring gave a rare glimpse inside the building; in one room trolls were shown sitting shoulder-to-shoulder at their computers. The operation moved into the building when it expanded in March 2014, the month Russia seized Crimea from Ukraine and provoked the first round of Western economic sanctions.
Soshnikov, a reporter at the weekly Moi Rayon, or My Region, said there has been a new push in recent months to hire more English-speaking trolls as part of an effort to sway public opinion in the United States.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:49:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi Authorities Raise Baghdad Attacks Death Toll to 15</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/iraqi-authorities-raise-baghdad-attacks-death-toll-15-31384041</Link>
        <Description>Iraqi authorities raise death toll from Baghdad hotel attacks to 15 people</Description>
        <MainBody>Iraqi Authorities Raise Baghdad Attacks Death Toll to 15
BAGHDAD  May 29, 2015, 6:47 AM ET
By SAMEER N. YACOUB Associated Press
The death toll from bombings that targeted two prominent hotels in Baghdad a day earlier rose to 15 people, with another 42 wounded, Iraqi authorities said on Friday, as a lawmaker warned that the capital is vulnerable to more attacks.
The double bombing occurred late Thursday when two separate car bombs went off in the parking lots of the Cristal, formerly Sheraton, and Babil hotels. Initial reports said 10 people were killed and 27 wounded, but the casualty figures rose overnight.
The two explosions shattered windows of the recently renovated hotels and destroyed several cars. Baghdad's top hotels are usually crowded on Thursday nights with people attending wedding celebrations or parties.
The twin attacks targeting heavily secured buildings in the heart of Baghdad demonstrate the boldness and freedom with which militants have been able to operate inside the capital. The two car bombs were detonated by remote control, police said.
Police said a third car bomb found near the Babil Hotel was discovered and defused early Friday. A police officer blamed the infiltration on the negligence of the hotel guards and the weak security measures adopted by police in Baghdad.
In Friday's violence, police and hospital officials said a roadside bomb hit a commuter bus in eastern Baghdad, killing three passengers and wounding 10 others.
All officials spoke on condition of anonymity because they are not authorized to speak to the media.
Sameer al-Shwaili, a spokesman for government's Anti-Terrorism Apparatus, said that more attacks on Baghdad are expected as military operations continue in an effort to drive out Islamic State militants from the Sunni-majority provinces of Anbar and Salahuddin.
"The situation is directly related to operations in Anbar, and operations in Tikrit. Iraq is in a state of war and what happened in Baghdad is a product of that war," al-Shwaili told The Associated Press in a telephone interview.
Nobody has claimed responsibility for the attacks, but al-Shwaili placed the blame on the Islamic State group.
"Car bombs and bombs are typically used by Daesh in a way to create fear among the citizens of Iraq," he said, using the Arabic acronym for the IS group.
Baghdad-based security expert Muataz Muhei said that Baghdad police officers and hotel security guards often lack the expertise and needed to deal with the kind of security challenges presented by the Islamic State group.
"Daesh chose those well-protected sites in order to display to the public that they are still able to hit hard targets," said Muhei.
Iraq witnesses almost daily attacks that have been frequently claimed by the Islamic State group  which seized large swaths of the country during a blitz last year and recently overran the city of Ramadi , provincial capital of Anbar province .
Fighting also continues in several parts of Salahuddin province, where government forces  backed by Shiite militias and airstrikes from the U.S.-led coalition  took back the city of Tikrit from IS militants earlier this year.

Associated Press writer Vivian Salama contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31384041.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:46:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN Nuke Agency Reports That Iran Probe Stalled</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/nuke-agency-issue-report-showing-iran-probe-stalled-31383990</Link>
        <Description>Diplomats: UN nuke agency reports that probe of alleged Iranian nuke arms work has stalled</Description>
        <MainBody>UN Nuke Agency Reports That Iran Probe Stalled
VIENNA  May 29, 2015, 6:45 AM ET
By GEORGE JAHN Associated Press
Amid accelerated international efforts to reach a nuclear deal with Iran , the U.N. atomic agency on Friday reported that work on a key element  an assessment of allegations that Tehran worked on atomic arms  remains essentially stalled.
After years of deadlock, Iran and the International Atomic Energy Agency agreed in November 2013 on a new attempt to probe the accusations. The U.S. and its allies also included the investigation into a to-do list for talks with Iran meant to curb its nuclear programs in exchange for sanctions relief.
Washington continues to insist that full lifting of sanctions depends on the IAEA's ability to thoroughly probe the accusations and deliver an assessment on its findings.
The IAEA is focused on 12 alleged activities that point to Iranian attempts to make such weapons, including suspicions that Tehran worked on the development on a nuclear payload for missiles. The IAEA started its probe last year by asking for information on less sensitive work related to nuclear arms allegedly carried out by Iran.
Since then, Iran has asserted that explosives-related experiments had civilian uses and were not related to the alleged work on nuclear weapons.
A confidential IAEA report issued Thursday and obtained by The Associated Press said that Tehran has since shared some other information on related alleged experiments but continues to hold back on the next stage of the IAEA probe.
Since August, "Iran has yet to propose any new practical measures" to bring the investigation forward, said the report.
The agency seeks to interview officials suspected of involvement in weapons research and development. It also wants to visit sites allegedly used for such work. But as the Iran-six power nuclear talks approach an end of June target date, Iranian officials are adamant that they won't allow such questioning or inspections.
Iran denies any work on  or interest  in nuclear arms. It accuses Israel, the United States and other adversaries of providing phony evidence to the agency for the probe.
"The Agency remains concerned about the possible existence in Iran of undisclosed nuclear-related activities involving military-related organizations, including activities related to the development of a nuclear payload for a missiles," said the report, issued to the IAEA's 35-nation board and the U.N. Security Council .
"Iran is required to cooperate fully with the Agency on all outstanding issues, particularly those which give rise to concerns about the possible military dimensions to Iran's nuclear program, including by providing access without delay to all sites, equipment, persons and documents requested by the Agency."
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31383990.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:45:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK Reporter Handed Suspended Sentence in Bribery Case</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/uk-reporter-handed-suspended-sentence-bribery-case-31385941</Link>
        <Description>Reporter at UK's Sun tabloid handed 18-month suspended prison sentence in police bribery case</Description>
        <MainBody>UK Reporter Handed Suspended Sentence in Bribery Case
LONDON  May 29, 2015, 6:45 AM ET
A British tabloid reporter has been handed a suspended 18-month prison sentence over a police bribery case.
Anthony France , a crime reporter for the Rupert Murdoch-owned newspaper, The Sun, was accused of cultivating a "corrupt relationship" with Heathrow Airport counter-terrorism officer Timothy Edwards over four years. Edwards had earlier admitted selling dozens of stories and news tips to the journalist for more than 20,000 pounds ($31,000).
France, 41, was convicted last week of aiding and abetting Edwards to commit misconduct in a public office.
Judge Timothy Pontius on Friday handed down the prison sentence, suspended for two years. He said France was "essentially a decent man of solid integrity."
France's trial followed a police investigation into alleged media bribery. The operation was triggered by Britain's phone-hacking media scandal.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31385941.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:45:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Myanmar Warns Against 'Finger Pointing' at Migrant Meeting</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/myanmar-warns-finger-pointing-migrant-meeting-31382153</Link>
        <Description>Myanmar decries 'finger pointing' during meeting on boat people, including persecuted minority</Description>
        <MainBody>Myanmar Warns Against 'Finger Pointing' at Migrant Meeting
BANGKOK  May 29, 2015, 6:44 AM ET
By JOCELYN GECKER and MALCOLM J. FOSTER Associated Press
Regional talks dealing with the swelling tide of boat people in Southeast Asia began Friday with a Myanmar official criticizing those who blame his country for causing the crisis, saying "finger pointing" would not help.
Htin Linn, the acting director of Myanmar's Foreign Affairs Ministry, spoke after several officials urged delegates to address the root causes of the problem  a reference to minority Rohingya Muslims who have fled persecution in predominantly Buddhist Myanmar for years  and a top U.N. official called for stateless Rohingya to be granted citizenship.
Asian nations have been beset by growing waves of desperate migrants from Bangladesh and Myanmar. In the last several weeks alone, at least 3,000 people have been rescued by fishermen or made their way ashore in Indonesia, Malaysia and Thailand. Several thousand more are believed to still be at sea after human smugglers abandoned their boats amid a regional crackdown that has unearthed the graves of dozens of people who died while being kept hostage in illegal trafficking camps.
Some are Bangladeshis who left their impoverished homeland in hope of finding jobs abroad. But many are Rohingya who have fled persecution in Myanmar, which has denied them basic rights, confined more than 100,000 to camps and denies them citizenship. There are more than 1 million Rohingya living in the country formerly known as Burma.
Volker Turk, the U.N.'s assistant high commissioner for refugees responsible for protection, said there could be no solution if root causes are not addressed.
"This will require full assumption of responsibility by Myanmar toward all its people. Granting citizenship is the ultimate goal," he said. "In the interim ... recognizing that Myanmar is their own country is urgently required (as well as) access to identity documents and the removal of restrictions on basic freedoms."
Htin Linn shot back in a speech afterward, saying Turk should "be more informed" and casting doubt on whether "the spirit of cooperation is prevailing in the room."
"Finger pointing will not serve any purpose. It will take us nowhere," he said.
Friday's meeting was attended by representatives of 17 countries directly or indirectly affected by the crisis, including the United States and Japan, and officials from international organizations such as the U.N. refugee agency and the International Organization for Migration.
The word "Rohingya" did not appear on the invitation, after Myanmar threatened to boycott the talks if it did, and most people who spoke at the beginning of Friday's meeting avoided saying it. Myanmar's government does not recognize Rohingya as an ethnic group, arguing instead they are really Bangladeshis. Bangladesh also does not recognize the Rohingya as citizens.
Southeast Asian governments have largely ignored the issue for years. The problem has recently attracted international attention amid increased media scrutiny as more migrants and refugees pour out of the Bay of Bengal. In many cases, they pay human smugglers thousands of dollars for passage to another country, but are instead held for weeks or months while traffickers extort more money from their families back home. Rights groups say some migrants have been beaten to death.
Human rights groups have urged those involved in the talks to find a better way of saving the people still stranded at sea, and to put pressure on Myanmar to end its repressive policies that drive Rohingya to flee.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:40:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nigerians Celebrate as Muhammadu Buhari Takes Over</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/muhammadu-buhari-takes-nation-crisis-31382863</Link>
        <Description>Muhammadu Buhari, first Nigerian to oust president at polls, offers hope to nation in crisis</Description>
        <MainBody>Nigerians Celebrate as Muhammadu Buhari Takes Over
ABUJA, Nigeria  May 29, 2015, 6:38 AM ET
By MICHELLE FAUL Associated Press
Nigerians celebrated their newly reinforced democracy Friday, dancing and singing songs and praises at the inauguration of Muhammadu Buhari, the first candidate to beat a sitting president at the polls.
As Buhari finished taking the oath of office in traditional robes and an embroidered cap, the crowd at Eagle Square in Nigeria's capital roared its approval. The former general then inspected troops in the plaza, decked out in colors of Nigeria's green and white flag, from the back of an open vehicle and waved at supporters.
A 21-gun salute boomed over Eagle Square during the handover of power which is a turning point in Nigeria's democratic evolution. Security was tight. In 2010, two car bombs and a grenade blast triggered by militants from Nigeria's oil patch killed 12 people at Independence Day celebrations.
Buhari has a wealth of international goodwill. A phalanx of African leaders attended the inauguration along with France's Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius and U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry , looking to mend fences broken under the discredited administration of Goodluck Jonathan .
Some nervous politicians fear Buhari's promise to retrieve ill-gotten gains for coffers emptied by massive corruption. Nigerian newspapers carried unconfirmed reports that some politicians already have returned millions of dollars in hopes of avoiding scrutiny.
"We see him as our only hope against this crippling corruption," said Efo Okorare, curator of an open-air exhibition of Nigerian leaders, pointing out the many in military uniforms. Buhari ruled briefly as a military dictator in the 1980s. The 72-year-old says that as a "born-again democrat" he can heal the woes of Africa's biggest nation, economy and oil producer.
Buhari inherits leadership of a nation plagued by an Islamic uprising has killed more than 13,000 people driven more than 1.5 million people from their homes. Nigeria is also $63 billion in debt and is borrowing to pay government workers.
Jonathan allowed the nearly 6-year-old Islamic insurgency to flourish before agreeing to an international offensive with troops from neighboring countries this year. His perceived indifference to the suffering caused by the uprising also hurt him. Presidents of neighboring countries have complained of lack of cooperation from Nigeria's government and military in the offensive against Boko Haram , the Nigerian Islamic extremist group.
Buhari, a Muslim from the north, was first installed as president after a military coup on New Year's Eve 1983. In August 1985, he was himself deposed because his fight against corruption and the life-long jail terms for politicians found guilty by military tribunals proved too draconian even for the coup plotters, who felt threatened.
Political science professor Richard Joseph of Northwestern University said Buhari's victory has hopeful international implications.
"The world desperately needs a victory against cultist jihadism. Nigeria (under Buhari) can provide it," he said.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31382863.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:34:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain's Cameron Pitches EU Reform in Berlin, Warsaw</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/britains-cameron-poland-search-support-reform-31383886</Link>
        <Description>Britain's Cameron meets with leaders in Berlin, Warsaw as he seeks changes in EU relationship</Description>
        <MainBody>Britain's Cameron Pitches EU Reform in Berlin, Warsaw
BERLIN  May 29, 2015, 6:33 AM ET
By DAVID RISING Associated Press
British Prime Minister David Cameron is pressing his case for a renegotiation of the country's relationship with the European Union with German Chancellor Angela Merkel , on the final stop of his two-day tour of four European capitals.
He arrived in Berlin Friday from Warsaw after morning meeting with Polish Prime Minister Ewa Kopacz.
Cameron's newly-elected Conservative government has promised to hold a referendum by the end of 2017 on whether Britain should remain within the EU. Ahead of that vote, he's looking to get concessions on the terms of Britain's membership.
In Paris on Thursday, Cameron urged the bloc's 27 other members to be "flexible" and "imaginative" about the EU's future  saying that his priority is "to make it more competitive and to address the concerns of the British people about our membership."
Earlier this week, Merkel's spokesman Steffen Seibert reiterated Germany's position, saying "we want, like many others in Europe, a strong Great Britain in the European Union." He added that it was Britain's responsibility, however, to decide what role the country would play in the EU.
Cameron has said he wants the country to remain in the trade bloc if he can negotiate a new, looser relationship and win concessions to curb welfare benefits to migrants from the EU.
According to her office, the Polish premier expressed strong opposition to solutions that could lead to the discrimination of Poles or other EU citizens working legally in Great Britain." Hundreds of thousands of Poles have settled in Britain since Poland joined the EU in 2004.
"By doing so she defended one of the core principles underlying the single market in the European Union," Kopacz's office said.
In a statement, Cameron's office said there were areas of agreement with Kopacz, such as the need for cutting red tape and "respecting the sovereignty of member states."
It said more discussions were needed on the interaction between free movement and national welfare systems.
Friday's talks come a day after he met French President Francois Hollande and Dutch premier Mark Rutte.

Vanessa Gera in Warsaw contributed to this report
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31383886.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:15:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Pataki Announces Presidential Bid; Oil Slicks Close California Beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' Dustin Diamond on Trial</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/pataki-announces-presidential-bid-oil-slicks-close-california-31376077</Link>
        <Description>Former NY Gov. George Pataki announces presidential bid; Suspected oil slicks close Southern California beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' actor Dustin Diamond on trial for alleged stabbing. </Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Pataki Announces Presidential Bid; Oil Slicks Close California Beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' Dustin Diamond on Trial
Lab workers across the country and US military personnel in South Korea are under observation and being provided antibiotics. After the Defense Department accidentally shipped to live anthrax pool. Labs in nine states potentially affected and in South Korea US military personnel may have actually is live at breakfast at training. She knew evacuations are under way it's been deprived overflowed their banks seem like this one playing out of Houston a young boy at his captain rescued along. Jacinto river at least 21 people have been killed in Texas Oklahoma and many are still missing. More severe weather danger today stretching from south Texas I have to Nebraska. More California beach is under threat oil blobs or tar ball scene on the coastline of close stretches of Manhattan are most that Redondo Beach. We are continuing to analyze. The beaches and tried to determine. The source for the tar balls and tar patties and washed up. Onshore yesterday so we're asking the public not to go on the water. Hurricane season officially starts this Monday June 1 President Obama just received his annual briefing at the National Hurricane Center. It is to preserve and protect that freedom for future generations that I speak. It is to preserve and protect that freedom that this morning I announced Simon candidate for the Republican. Dustin diamond of 38 year old actor best known for playing the quirky loveable geeks screech on 96 Collins saved by the bell. On trial for reckless endangerment disorderly conduct and carrying a concealed weapon for allegedly using. A knife to slash a man during a bar fight last Christmas Day according prosecutors. Asked a true. Inspiring story Chris Norton walked across the stage to receive just a club like just forty years after a terrific football injuries and left them with virtually. No chance of ever regaining any move them hello this next forty years later the 23 year old takes the stage at his graduation. Leaving his wheelchair behind.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Iraqi soldiers launch offensive and Shia militia trains volunteers to fight militants.
Now Playing: International Hotspot: Fighting ISIS in Iraq
Now Playing: Cali Beaches Close For Cleaning, George Pataki Enters 2016 Presidential Race, Air Force Academy Class of 2015
Now Playing: Pataki Announces Presidential Bid; Oil Slicks Close California Beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' Dustin Diamond on Trial
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Arrested Execs Turned FIFA Into 'Criminal Enterprise,' AG Says
Now Playing: FIFA Officials Arrested in Federal Corruption Investigation
Now Playing: Puerto Rican Taxi Driver's Final Stop: His Own Funeral
Now Playing: Galapagos Island Volcano Erupts, Threatening Fragile Ecosystem
Now Playing: New Offensive Launched Against ISIS to Regain Lost Territory
Now Playing: Rep. Mac Thornberry: 'We're Not Winning' Against ISIS
Now Playing: Iraqi Refugee Gets Graduation Surprise From Solider Who Saved Her Life
Now Playing: Women March for Peace by Crossing Korean Border
Now Playing: Ireland Legalizes Gay Marriage by Popular Vote
Now Playing: Exchange Student's Fight to Participate in Graduation Exercises at Texas High School
Now Playing: State Dept. Releases Clinton Emails; Texas Underwater; 8-Week-Old Baby Hippo Goes for a Swim
Now Playing: Video Captures Dog's Amazing Rescue From Rushing Waters
Now Playing: ISIS Makes Significant Advances in Iraq
Now Playing: California Coastline Cleanup, Migrants Arrive In Italy, Tunisian President Meets With Obama
Now Playing: ISIS Captures Ancient Syrian Town of Palmyra
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31376077,"title":"Pataki Announces Presidential Bid; Oil Slicks Close California Beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' Dustin Diamond on Trial","duration":"2:19","description":"Former NY Gov. George Pataki announces presidential bid; Suspected oil slicks close Southern California beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' actor Dustin Diamond on trial for alleged stabbing. ","url":"/International/video/pataki-announces-presidential-bid-oil-slicks-close-california-31376077","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:55:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Cali Beaches Close For Cleaning, George Pataki Enters 2016 Presidential Race, Air Force Academy Class of 2015</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/cali-beaches-close-cleaning-george-pataki-enters-2016-31375677</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 5.28.15</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Cali Beaches Close For Cleaning, George Pataki Enters 2016 Presidential Race, Air Force Academy Class of 2015
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Beware Rip Currents on the Beach This Summer
Now Playing: Pataki Announces Presidential Bid; Oil Slicks Close California Beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' Dustin Diamond on Trial
Now Playing: Cali Beaches Close For Cleaning, George Pataki Enters 2016 Presidential Race, Air Force Academy Class of 2015
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Arrested Execs Turned FIFA Into 'Criminal Enterprise,' AG Says
Now Playing: FIFA Officials Arrested in Federal Corruption Investigation
Now Playing: Puerto Rican Taxi Driver's Final Stop: His Own Funeral
Now Playing: International Hotspot: Fighting ISIS in Iraq
Now Playing: Galapagos Island Volcano Erupts, Threatening Fragile Ecosystem
Now Playing: New Offensive Launched Against ISIS to Regain Lost Territory
Now Playing: Rep. Mac Thornberry: 'We're Not Winning' Against ISIS
Now Playing: Iraqi Refugee Gets Graduation Surprise From Solider Who Saved Her Life
Now Playing: Women March for Peace by Crossing Korean Border
Now Playing: Ireland Legalizes Gay Marriage by Popular Vote
Now Playing: Exchange Student's Fight to Participate in Graduation Exercises at Texas High School
Now Playing: State Dept. Releases Clinton Emails; Texas Underwater; 8-Week-Old Baby Hippo Goes for a Swim
Now Playing: Video Captures Dog's Amazing Rescue From Rushing Waters
Now Playing: ISIS Makes Significant Advances in Iraq
Now Playing: California Coastline Cleanup, Migrants Arrive In Italy, Tunisian President Meets With Obama
Now Playing: ISIS Captures Ancient Syrian Town of Palmyra
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31375677,"title":"Cali Beaches Close For Cleaning, George Pataki Enters 2016 Presidential Race, Air Force Academy Class of 2015","duration":"3:00","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 5.28.15","url":"/International/video/cali-beaches-close-cleaning-george-pataki-enters-2016-31375677","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu May 28 00:58:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/fifa-executives-indicted-memphis-remembers-bb-king-us-31349704</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 5.27.15.</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: FIFA Officials Arrested in Federal Corruption Investigation
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Hillary Breaks Her Silence With Reporters, Fatal Flooding In Columbia, 'Blue Alert Act' signed
Now Playing: Amtrak Derailment Debris Cleaned Up, Mississippi Officer Remembered, Search for Missing US Marines Helicopter
Now Playing: Deadly Amtrak Crash in Philadelphia, Nepal Earthquake Aftermath, Indy 500 Car Flips During Practice
Now Playing: Second Earthquake Strikes Nepal, Arkansas Tornado Victims Cleanup, 'Jetman' Soars Above Dubai
Now Playing: Attorney General Announces Baltimore Investigation, NYPD Officer Mourned, Obama at Nike Headquarters
Now Playing: Oklahoma Tornado Aftermath, Quake Victims Remembered In Nepal, Air Force Football Meets Obama
Now Playing: Philadelphia Honors Fallen Officers, Sir Elton John Fights For HIVAIDS Funding, SpaceX Tests Astronaut Abort System
Now Playing: Gen. Dunford Nominated Joint Chiefs Of Staff, Huckabee Announces 2016 Bid, Cinco De Mayo
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 5/04/15
Now Playing: Freddie Gray's Death Ruled A Homicide, Gov. Christie Ally Pleads Guilty To 'Bridgegate', Yemen Airstrike Aftermath
Now Playing: Bernie Sanders Announces Presidential Candidacy , Quake Survivors Rescued, Vietnam Celebrates The 'Fall Of Saigon'
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 4/20/15
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 4/17 /15
Now Playing: Holocaust Remembrance Day, Georgia Approves Medical Marijuana Bill, Wounded Warriors Take On DC
Now Playing: Hernandez Guilty of Murder, Boston Marathon Bombings 2nd Anniversary, Helicopter Lands On US Capitol Lawn
Now Playing: Car Bomb Detonates in Somalia, Obama Pledges $200M For Displaced Iraqis, Hillary Campaigns In Iowa
Now Playing: Day in Pictures
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Victims Comment On Guilty Verdict, South Carolina Police Shooting Protest, Polar Bears Play In Poland
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31349704,"title":"FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together","duration":"0:42","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 5.27.15.","url":"/International/video/fifa-executives-indicted-memphis-remembers-bb-king-us-31349704","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed May 27 20:42:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  FIFA Officials Charged With Corruption</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/fifa-officials-charged-corruption-31339099</Link>
        <Description>Six top-ranking FIFA officials arrested in Zurich, Switzerland, at their 5-star hotel, as the U.S indicts 14 individuals on conspiracy and corruption charges.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for FIFA Officials Charged With Corruption
Breaking right now six top ranking fifa officials arrested in Zurich Switzerland. During a night at their five star hotel this. At the US and that's a total of fourteen individuals on conspiracy and corruption charges but the FBI raiding offices in Miami as well. The unsealed court documents allege he officials and other sports executives that more than 150 million dollars in bribes and kickbacks over 24 years. Hello tie Hernandez in New York US attorney general Loretta lynch just now wrapping up a news conference. On the unsealing in the indictment today its investigation growing out of allegations that the officials were paid off when it came to choosing. The next two World Cup host country when he eighteen and 20/20 two with the US. Runnerup to Qatar in 20/20 TO. Let's break it in sports business reporters there right now and the world if he thought has been rocked Daryn what can you tell us about. All the indictments and the corruption charges that we're seeing. Well I obviously you know this is been going on for a long time there's been many reporters who have alleged that bribes have been taken by. Members of soccer's organizing body fifa. But. I guess what happens here is when your now indicting for wire fraud and racketeering there's obviously. The paperwork that is there that hasn't been there before. On a federal level. That the money in in the banks carried out by US banks. And that kind of stuff and as we you said there are fourteen officials here nine fifa officials. And up the rest sports marketing executives. Some of those sports marketing executives actually. Pled guilty including Jose we low with who is a sports marketing executive at Avaya a firm called traffic. And he alone has agreed. Two to give up a 150 million dollars. From the press conference. Just a couple minutes ago. Things that just stood out. They said that they found a 110. Million dollars in bribes alone. On Copa America on the Copa America event which is going to be played in the US next year. Which is unbelievable because that's not even the World Cup. So you you've come out of this saying how much money is has been giving in bribes. If we know that single B tale alone. And then you you wonder what is next. Thief is obviously meeting in a big meeting right now. Sepp Blatter. Who's ahead of fifa his presidency is on the line and what they did say was. This is the beginning not the end see you kind of wonder. Whether the big fish here is set Blatter. The head of fifa who is not mentioned in any of this paperwork. Against Sepp Blatter that big fish and we do have some indications that people are willing to top people are looking for pleading no deals here. And as he said this is the beginning not the end so some signs that this could keep ticking upward. Yeah and in obviously these are when you when you talk about the bit that counts over forty counts and when you're alleging. A wire fraud and racketeering and this type of corruption. When you mention those types of of names of those types of crimes you're talking about major major jail time. And you'll also have what we already know. There are people that have cooperated. That had not only been indicted but have pled guilty so there are people talking. So the willingness of people to talk the willingness of people will forfeit money right away. Does this indictment gets announced. You don't means that. The the FBI in the attorney general it is. Is clearer believes that there is going to be further cooperation which would then lead to more information. Now the US lost out to cutter for the 20/20. Two World Cup allegedly under rate conditions. Any chance at those decisions could be revisited and is this how the US really became tipped off to the process of dealing with heat and all the rides that. That are required in many cases. Well kayak I I think that you know they they say that this case goes back two generations of soccer officials. 24 years. You know there there is always been this subtext. Things don't make sense and certainly for the 20/20 two games in cutter. The fact that they were awarded the games just did not make any sense a country that is a 105. Degrees in the summer. A country that had virtually no infrastructure. All of sports soccer stadiums. This just made absolutely no sense for them to win the bid sometimes there's been Olympic decision to roll cut decisions that. Snell a little fishy but this certainly went the full extent. Neighbor ready started building they are very far along in terms of their soccer stadiums there's been a lot of questions about. Human rights there are people who have died building these stadiums. It might be hard to back up but I don't think anything is out of the question right now as part fifa they are in as much trouble as anti. Forget about sports organization any organization. Has ever beating and when you just if you think that this is the beginning so I don't think you know 20/20 two still law a long way off. And perhaps. This is something that they viewed it to clean up they on do this deal even though things are far along in cutter. What about because major corporate sponsors out of this investigation affect them and really. He puts finances in the future if it's so many of their dealings Ers are suspect. Yet certainly makes it an uncomfortable day for the big sponsors like it devious like Coca-Cola like McDonald's. Makes it a good day for those companies that decided last year to end their association. Whether it would be continental tires Johnson &amp; Johnson Sony emirates airlines cast parole. All those guys decided and you happ did you think it was under some of this. Subtext under what were so talked about under the that the fact that this could happen it that these one of the reasons why these companies lap. But. It's it's very uncomfortable Levy's sponsored a makes a little bit more comfortable. That he has been sitting out press releases regarding these allegations with the sponsor's names on the bottom I think it's. Probably dated the sponsors would appreciate not having your name on the bottom of these notes. Absolutely is against Darren about their and I want to thank you so much for joining us. As the charges against fifa continue to pound. Breakfast take place in keep up with this story in real time by downloading the ABC news happened starting this story for exclusive updates on ago. Untie her nap is in New York.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Pentagon Ships Live Anthrax by Mistake
Now Playing: Raging Rivers Threaten Texas Towns
Now Playing: The GOP Candidates Just Keep on Coming
Now Playing: FIFA Officials Charged With Corruption
Now Playing: Texas, Oklahoma Residents Evacuated Due to Severe Flooding
Now Playing: Hillary Clinton Emails Released
Now Playing: President Obama Talks Iran Nuke Deal with Jewish-American Community
Now Playing: Swiss Bank UBS to Pay $545 Million Fine
Now Playing: Hillary Clinton Takes Reporters' Questions, Breaks Silence On The Campaign Trail
Now Playing: Philadelphia Amtrak Crash: Train Engineer Agrees to Meet With NTSB
Now Playing: US Military Chopper Wreckage Found in Nepal
Now Playing: President Obama Honors 131 Police Officers Fallen in the Line of Duty
Now Playing: Philadelphia Amtrak Crash: Investigation Looking at Train's Engineer and High Speed
Now Playing: Tom Brady to Appeal Suspension
Now Playing: Odell Beckham Jr. Strikes a Pose!
Now Playing: Man Detained Near White House for Flying Drone
Now Playing: Director Spike Lee Defends Upcoming Film 'Chiraq'
Now Playing: Philadelphia Amtrak Crash: Crews Start Repairing Damaged Power Lines and Tracks
Now Playing: Walmart Sets Sights on Amazon Prime
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31339099,"title":"FIFA Officials Charged With Corruption","duration":"7:24","description":"Six top-ranking FIFA officials arrested in Zurich, Switzerland, at their 5-star hotel, as the U.S indicts 14 individuals on conspiracy and corruption charges.","url":"/International/video/fifa-officials-charged-corruption-31339099","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Wed May 27 17:54:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  See Man's Body Covered With 1.1 Million Bees</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/man-covered-in-bees-sets-world-record-31332408</Link>
        <Description>Wearing only his underpants, Gao Bingguo set a new Guinness World Record after he covered himself with almost 1.1 million bees, collectively weighing 240 pounds.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for See Man's Body Covered With 1.1 Million Bees
I a lot of weird stories we dismantle stories here that what about alligator you missed yesterday would love. We do stories about world records here's well we're combining the two now but you might get a little Swedish on this. You know I love movies check up the sky having a cigarette there while setting new record. We're being covered with the most beats how would they counted them all who really knows word. It's got pilot he's 55 years old he's a beekeeper in China. Okay he actually spread honey on himself to attract the VC was stung more than 2000 times the bees collectively we're told. Weigh 240 pounds. But this is a record how do you how do you know they are you. Count. You come bee stings. I apparently am told that the cigarette. Ways to prevent the bees from action swarming his lips yes that's a good idea who the bees love honey but don't like tobacco. My and a visa told. We've talked about it before my learns of the community evident and let your knowledge that out but I didn't fed in case you missed it by the way with that they're in case you missed it was authentic guy didn't. You told me about them but thank you.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: See Man's Body Covered With 1.1 Million Bees
Now Playing: Kids Captivated by Gator on Front Lawn
Now Playing: Python's Taste for BBQ Tongs Leaves It Hospitalized
Now Playing: Koala Wanders Into Hospital Waiting Room
Now Playing: Honolulu Food Festival Showcases Spam
Now Playing: 'Van Goat': Meet Bodie, the 4-Year-Old Goat That Paints
Now Playing: California Hills Are Alive With Mystery Piano's Music
Now Playing: What This Leopard Kitten Does Will Make Your Day
Now Playing: Little Girl Scolds Aunt for Using 'Bad Word'
Now Playing: Pope Francis Receives a Special Delivery
Now Playing: Great-grandmother Skydives for 100th Birthday
Now Playing: 800-Pound Stingray Could Be Record-Breaking Catch
Now Playing: Mom Defends Boy's '50 Shades of Grey' Costume
Now Playing: 175-Pound Pit Bull Shatters Misconceptions About the Breed
Now Playing: Oregon Log Cabin Found After Vanishing Act
Now Playing: What Color Is That Dress?
Now Playing: Massachusetts Man Launches Website to Sell Snow
Now Playing: Cat Warms Up By Heater
Now Playing: Ohio Police Search for 'Jack Frost'
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31332408,"title":"See Man's Body Covered With 1.1 Million Bees","duration":"1:03","description":"Wearing only his underpants, Gao Bingguo set a new Guinness World Record after he covered himself with almost 1.1 million bees, collectively weighing 240 pounds.","url":"/International/video/man-covered-in-bees-sets-world-record-31332408","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:45:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  : Houston Flooding: 3 Dead, More Rain Expected; Body found in New York Kayak Murder Case; Iraq Launches Operation Against ISIS </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/houston-flooding-dead-rain-expected-body-found-york-31320331</Link>
        <Description>Houston floods: 3 dead and flash flood warnings in effect; Body found in New York kayak murder case; Iraq launches operation to drive ISIS from Anbar Province.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for : Houston Flooding: 3 Dead, More Rain Expected; Body found in New York Kayak Murder Case; Iraq Launches Operation Against ISIS
The lone star's doctor unseen scene dignity in Houston flash floods shouldn't major roadways and schools surging waters sweeping of course. Emergency crews scrambling to rescue drivers trapped in. It's Seattle thanks. News had even been in cars. The fourth body was part of rivers who. A new twist in the alleged I have to murder case and on and around New York's Hudson River to me after Anthony Paul. Was charged in second to regional. And county on May 24 hour. Prosecutors went off on campus when he went kayak to take on there. Fighting back Shiite militia in ramadi defending their turf from ice it's even though the terrorist group now controls that. Important city of all of ramadi has Iraqi soldiers taking up arms and wanted and it and Libor and our common MySpace. The attorney general's office the US attorney. The northern Ohio and the mayor of Cleveland disgusting I deal with the Justice Department that would change how that Cleveland Police Department operates. DOJ went into the Cleveland Police Department they're gonna work insurgencies are unleashing a community policing. The bias free police in the use of excessive force Allston make sure that every single officer hasn't. Lonnie Cameron. It at first you don't succeed try try again and that's what charter did. Snagging rival Time Warner for a whopping 55 billion dollars on the a year and a half after its first bid. Was rejected as a low ball offer after Comcast could not make a merger work with Time Warner Cable. Charters moved back in and sweetened its an ethnic faceoff an alligator going up against a trough in Louisiana. Not sure what the drivers wanting me Gator but the beast clearly doesn't like it and snack wrap in the bumper and ripping it off. After thrashing an investigator lagged all of the bumper this video give them when new meaning to the term calculator.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Watch: Texas Flash Flooding, May 2015
Now Playing: Pataki Announces Presidential Bid; Oil Slicks Close California Beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' Dustin Diamond on Trial
Now Playing: Cali Beaches Close For Cleaning, George Pataki Enters 2016 Presidential Race, Air Force Academy Class of 2015
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Arrested Execs Turned FIFA Into 'Criminal Enterprise,' AG Says
Now Playing: FIFA Officials Arrested in Federal Corruption Investigation
Now Playing: Puerto Rican Taxi Driver's Final Stop: His Own Funeral
Now Playing: International Hotspot: Fighting ISIS in Iraq
Now Playing: Galapagos Island Volcano Erupts, Threatening Fragile Ecosystem
Now Playing: New Offensive Launched Against ISIS to Regain Lost Territory
Now Playing: Rep. Mac Thornberry: 'We're Not Winning' Against ISIS
Now Playing: Iraqi Refugee Gets Graduation Surprise From Solider Who Saved Her Life
Now Playing: Women March for Peace by Crossing Korean Border
Now Playing: Ireland Legalizes Gay Marriage by Popular Vote
Now Playing: Exchange Student's Fight to Participate in Graduation Exercises at Texas High School
Now Playing: State Dept. Releases Clinton Emails; Texas Underwater; 8-Week-Old Baby Hippo Goes for a Swim
Now Playing: Video Captures Dog's Amazing Rescue From Rushing Waters
Now Playing: ISIS Makes Significant Advances in Iraq
Now Playing: California Coastline Cleanup, Migrants Arrive In Italy, Tunisian President Meets With Obama
Now Playing: ISIS Captures Ancient Syrian Town of Palmyra
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31320331,"title":": Houston Flooding: 3 Dead, More Rain Expected; Body found in New York Kayak Murder Case; Iraq Launches Operation Against ISIS ","duration":"3:00","description":"Houston floods: 3 dead and flash flood warnings in effect; Body found in New York kayak murder case; Iraq launches operation to drive ISIS from Anbar Province.","url":"/International/video/houston-flooding-dead-rain-expected-body-found-york-31320331","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:20:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Day in Pictures: 5/26/2015</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/day-pictures-5262015-31320199</Link>
        <Description>Images from across the globe: Motorists Stranded By Deadly Texas Flash Floods, Burundi Political Tensions Rise, Japan's Emperor Marks 70th Anniversary For End Of WWII, Indians Protest Ruling Political Party</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for Day in Pictures: 5/26/2015
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Texas Homes Evacuated as Wichita River Floods
Now Playing: Pataki Announces Presidential Bid; Oil Slicks Close California Beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' Dustin Diamond on Trial
Now Playing: FIFA Officials Charged With Corruption
Now Playing: See Man's Body Covered With 1.1 Million Bees
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: International Hotspot: Fighting ISIS in Iraq
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 5/26/2015
Now Playing: : Houston Flooding: 3 Dead, More Rain Expected; Body found in New York Kayak Murder Case; Iraq Launches Operation Against ISIS
Now Playing: Women March for Peace by Crossing Korean Border
Now Playing: Duke and Duchess of Cambridge Welcome Second Child
Now Playing: WATCH: A Brief History of Cinco de Mayo
Now Playing: Gen. Dunford Nominated Joint Chiefs Of Staff, Huckabee Announces 2016 Bid, Cinco De Mayo
Now Playing: Pope Francis Shows His Game With Harlem Globetrotters
Now Playing: Space Capsule Ejector Test
Now Playing: May 4, 1979: Margaret Thatcher Becomes Prime Minister #TBT
Now Playing: Dramatic Sea Rescue Saves a Dozen Lives
Now Playing: Major Earthquake Strikes Nepal
Now Playing: Elian Gonzalez Describes the Fear He Felt in Famous Photo
Now Playing: Dog Given Mouth-to-Mouth in Amazing River Rescue
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31320199,"title":"Day in Pictures: 5/26/2015","duration":"0:40","description":"Images from across the globe: Motorists Stranded By Deadly Texas Flash Floods, Burundi Political Tensions Rise, Japan's Emperor Marks 70th Anniversary For End Of WWII, Indians Protest Ruling Political Party","url":"/International/video/day-pictures-5262015-31320199","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:58:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  International Hotspot: Fighting ISIS in Iraq</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/international-hotspot-fighting-isis-iraq-31315486</Link>
        <Description>Iraqi soldiers launch offensive and Shia militia trains volunteers to fight militants.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for International Hotspot: Fighting ISIS in Iraq
Fighting back Shiite militia in ramadi defending their turf from ice it's even though the terrorist group now controls that. Important city like county. Hot spot Iraq high every. New York the fall of ramadi has Iraqi soldiers taking up arms and launching an offensive to try and liberal Anbar Province from MySpace. The BBC's frank partner is in Jordan which borders to handle bar province. And sent this report. A to the barracks until two patrol. Part of Jordan's recently formed as a brigade. That tossed by the king to secure this lonely border with Iraq to keep drug smugglers and the jihadist. We've just about to take a vote or with Iraq's neighboring Anbar Province. Jordan's desert border with Iraq here is the clay says that the forces of Islamic states have come so far to getting into the stable pro western kingdom. But long term Jordan is definitely in that sites. That's why the lost yep the Jordanian police and on the patrols have been redoubled we'll just here on the Iraqi border. But farther to the roles on the Syrian border with Jordan faces three different on groups. We remove the would this put you through fleas or the tomb. Content of his own that should lose or lifted its. Capital Amman does not look I feel like a city in the country at war yet technically it is with the Islamic state favoring Syria. Jordanian port Maine still carry out as strikes. The jihadist use the Internet to promised revenge. Sue -- safe to Jordan's public field. Have been showed some of it I went this cafe and I'm on. To a loss of random groups for snapshot of their opinions and there's brokers around us but it's Doug and attempted don't have an appropriate moments but is it. But what I Allston about Jordan's extremist sympathizers and supporters should be out right. Prices aren't. But this tranquil scene is deceptive. In this volatile region Jordan faces and a mystery inside and out. Even its western allies fear it could keep the jihadist next week target. I've gotten it keeps news Jordan. The BBC's John Simpson went to another part of the Anbar Province where a group of militia is training volunteers. To fight anxious. And Bob Providence Boston emptied basically desert and it's not neutral territory fully Islamic state. It's been a battleground for years. The Americans build fortifications. When they would he. Now as then the enemy's weapon of choice is the rates side home. We reached Gama as the government forces of firing Islamic states last few positions in the town of corporate. IS has been forced out of the rest of it yeah. Ramo pocket Fifth Amendment. We will those so called popular mobilization. Unit a militia mostly composed of Shia Muslims. Until Monday by Sheikh Ali did finish at that could carry in the uniform with his own devising. The militias so the only government troops who seem able to resist Islamic states ferocity. But Anbar Province his sonar use. And sewage Dane showed that the sheik's men will find to sectarian war here. Made a riot that about and the fitted out out couldn't. I carried the flag or for Iraq because I don't just represents Xia our Sony are to present the whole rack she. This is what they called the front line in the sense that it's that places. Let the Iraqi forces get to the last remaining Islamic state positions. Just on the other side of that reads that. Nicely the fire is out getting there aren't that many Islamic state fighters left. But they've just told the so we've got to get out in case all the fire and the excitement -- attract incoming mortar fire. And the Islamic stakes by no means finished in Anbar Province. Another BBC team traveling with the Iraqi Army came under fire from IS and the battle started. It's one of the characteristics. Of fighting a war in Anbar that he's guess the other get a look at your enemy. It's a matter of life and death of the Iraqi Government should drive Islamic state out of band. The government believes can be done and by the end of the year. Western diplomats here are inclined to greet. But it'll be an immense talks could. Don't Simpson BBC news I'm Bob. Province. You have been watching international hot spot on Caroline Costello in New York.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Pataki Announces Presidential Bid; Oil Slicks Close California Beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' Dustin Diamond on Trial
Now Playing: Cali Beaches Close For Cleaning, George Pataki Enters 2016 Presidential Race, Air Force Academy Class of 2015
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Arrested Execs Turned FIFA Into 'Criminal Enterprise,' AG Says
Now Playing: FIFA Officials Arrested in Federal Corruption Investigation
Now Playing: Puerto Rican Taxi Driver's Final Stop: His Own Funeral
Now Playing: International Hotspot: Fighting ISIS in Iraq
Now Playing: Galapagos Island Volcano Erupts, Threatening Fragile Ecosystem
Now Playing: New Offensive Launched Against ISIS to Regain Lost Territory
Now Playing: Rep. Mac Thornberry: 'We're Not Winning' Against ISIS
Now Playing: Iraqi Refugee Gets Graduation Surprise From Solider Who Saved Her Life
Now Playing: Women March for Peace by Crossing Korean Border
Now Playing: Ireland Legalizes Gay Marriage by Popular Vote
Now Playing: Exchange Student's Fight to Participate in Graduation Exercises at Texas High School
Now Playing: State Dept. Releases Clinton Emails; Texas Underwater; 8-Week-Old Baby Hippo Goes for a Swim
Now Playing: Video Captures Dog's Amazing Rescue From Rushing Waters
Now Playing: ISIS Makes Significant Advances in Iraq
Now Playing: California Coastline Cleanup, Migrants Arrive In Italy, Tunisian President Meets With Obama
Now Playing: ISIS Captures Ancient Syrian Town of Palmyra
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31315486,"title":"International Hotspot: Fighting ISIS in Iraq","duration":"5:12","description":"Iraqi soldiers launch offensive and Shia militia trains volunteers to fight militants.","url":"/International/video/international-hotspot-fighting-isis-iraq-31315486","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Sun May 24 17:33:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Women March for Peace by Crossing Korean Border</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/north-south-korean-women-march-peace-31267186</Link>
        <Description>ABC News??? Joohee Cho met with the marchers that included Gloria Steinem, Medea Benjamin, and two Nobel Peace laureates.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Women March for Peace by Crossing Korean Border
But what yeah. We're. The group has thirty international when man who. Marched down from. North Korea. That bridge right and it's the unification bridge and beyond that point is under military control and now we're Eric. In the company is toyland and it just met. When us several hundred eight women activists and now they're marching for again. I. That he didn't. Area. It's the very repressive countries that it was great for us to go there and breakthrough some of them have some real. I'll. Interactions with women that hadn't happened before I'm if he could never met an American with for an airline. I mean they had sits terrible idea. And we became close friends they were all crying when we left this morning and night he's in personal relations and what we came to do. We're not there for governments. We certainly those. Bring them but recently.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
On a state media broadcast, North Korea threatened the US with the "most disastrous final doom on its mainland."
Now Playing: North Korea Threatens US Over Hacking Row
Now Playing: US Ambassador to South Korea Defends Himself From Attack
Now Playing: Pataki Announces Presidential Bid; Oil Slicks Close California Beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' Dustin Diamond on Trial
Now Playing: Cali Beaches Close For Cleaning, George Pataki Enters 2016 Presidential Race, Air Force Academy Class of 2015
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Arrested Execs Turned FIFA Into 'Criminal Enterprise,' AG Says
Now Playing: FIFA Officials Arrested in Federal Corruption Investigation
Now Playing: Puerto Rican Taxi Driver's Final Stop: His Own Funeral
Now Playing: International Hotspot: Fighting ISIS in Iraq
Now Playing: Galapagos Island Volcano Erupts, Threatening Fragile Ecosystem
Now Playing: New Offensive Launched Against ISIS to Regain Lost Territory
Now Playing: Rep. Mac Thornberry: 'We're Not Winning' Against ISIS
Now Playing: Iraqi Refugee Gets Graduation Surprise From Solider Who Saved Her Life
Now Playing: Women March for Peace by Crossing Korean Border
Now Playing: Ireland Legalizes Gay Marriage by Popular Vote
Now Playing: Exchange Student's Fight to Participate in Graduation Exercises at Texas High School
Now Playing: State Dept. Releases Clinton Emails; Texas Underwater; 8-Week-Old Baby Hippo Goes for a Swim
Now Playing: Video Captures Dog's Amazing Rescue From Rushing Waters
Now Playing: ISIS Makes Significant Advances in Iraq
Now Playing: California Coastline Cleanup, Migrants Arrive In Italy, Tunisian President Meets With Obama
Now Playing: ISIS Captures Ancient Syrian Town of Palmyra
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31267186,"title":"Women March for Peace by Crossing Korean Border","duration":"1:36","description":"ABC News Joohee Cho met with the marchers that included Gloria Steinem, Medea Benjamin, and two Nobel Peace laureates.","url":"/International/video/north-south-korean-women-march-peace-31267186","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Sat May 23 02:47:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  State Dept. Releases Clinton Emails; Texas Underwater; 8-Week-Old Baby Hippo Goes for a Swim</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/state-dept-releases-clinton-emails-texas-underwater-week-31244633</Link>
        <Description>State Department releases 296 Hillary Clinton emails; Texas underwater: flooding forcing residents out of their homes; 8-week-old baby hippo goes for a swim at the San Diego Zoo.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for State Dept. Releases Clinton Emails; Texas Underwater; 8-Week-Old Baby Hippo Goes for a Swim
The suspect in that brutal murder to Washington DC mansion arrested. He was on the run police taken into custody after take them by US marshals. Winston charged with first degree felony murder in the brutal deaths of some Dawson novelist his wife Amy their ten year old son. And their housekeeper Revere for Wear after all it. It was handled appropriately. Hillary Clinton on the campaign trail in New Hampshire but the big focus for Manning is. Her trail of emails from her time in office as secretary of state released. Just a short time ago by the State Department 296. Of them to be exact these are the emails that she herself selected these are for emails from her private server. Today are just those emails about the bay and got the issue of but there's much more content to be drove about in the days ahead ten terror arrests in Southern California agents moving on this no talent Orange County surrounding the place knocking in the door. Where they say one of the suspects was living. We know both apparently heavy in Anaheim south of LA they were arrested overnight one in Orange County one at Los Angeles international airport. Thanks say both were gonna go overseas allegedly and join ice is. Record flooding across Texas triggering evacuation orders. In south Texas the trinity river has crested at its highest level in 21 years floods in Corpus Christi were triggered by four and a half inches of rain in just one hour. And in Wichita Falls the Red Cross is opening emergency shelters as flood warnings across that state are expected throughout the holiday weekend shocking report from. Just dug or from nineteen kids and counting. Confessed to molesting young girls and is a teenager doesn't admits he quote acted inexcusable. Florida and in touch magazine and Doug are responding to the allegations on FaceBook. Twelve years ago as a young teenager I acted inexcusable for which I am extremely sorry and deeply regret. And happy birthday Disneyland sixteen years ago Walt Disney welcome guest is iconic theme park for the first time that unforgettable opening reshaping the earmarks forever. Right now cast members and guests kicking off in dying celebration. At the park stays. More hours. Like she's got long close by whatever you're doing on this holiday weekend. Please see you at the San Diego Zoo that is eight legal debt being the mom keeping her moving edging her around in the water. Colin Denny's first swimming.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Hillary Clinton Emails Released
Now Playing: Pataki Announces Presidential Bid; Oil Slicks Close California Beaches; 'Saved By the Bell' Dustin Diamond on Trial
Now Playing: Cali Beaches Close For Cleaning, George Pataki Enters 2016 Presidential Race, Air Force Academy Class of 2015
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Arrested Execs Turned FIFA Into 'Criminal Enterprise,' AG Says
Now Playing: FIFA Officials Arrested in Federal Corruption Investigation
Now Playing: Puerto Rican Taxi Driver's Final Stop: His Own Funeral
Now Playing: International Hotspot: Fighting ISIS in Iraq
Now Playing: Galapagos Island Volcano Erupts, Threatening Fragile Ecosystem
Now Playing: New Offensive Launched Against ISIS to Regain Lost Territory
Now Playing: Rep. Mac Thornberry: 'We're Not Winning' Against ISIS
Now Playing: Iraqi Refugee Gets Graduation Surprise From Solider Who Saved Her Life
Now Playing: Women March for Peace by Crossing Korean Border
Now Playing: Ireland Legalizes Gay Marriage by Popular Vote
Now Playing: Exchange Student's Fight to Participate in Graduation Exercises at Texas High School
Now Playing: State Dept. Releases Clinton Emails; Texas Underwater; 8-Week-Old Baby Hippo Goes for a Swim
Now Playing: Video Captures Dog's Amazing Rescue From Rushing Waters
Now Playing: ISIS Makes Significant Advances in Iraq
Now Playing: California Coastline Cleanup, Migrants Arrive In Italy, Tunisian President Meets With Obama
Now Playing: ISIS Captures Ancient Syrian Town of Palmyra
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31244633,"title":"State Dept. Releases Clinton Emails; Texas Underwater; 8-Week-Old Baby Hippo Goes for a Swim","duration":"2:31","description":"State Department releases 296 Hillary Clinton emails; Texas underwater: flooding forcing residents out of their homes; 8-week-old baby hippo goes for a swim at the San Diego Zoo.","url":"/International/video/state-dept-releases-clinton-emails-texas-underwater-week-31244633","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:50:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  Nightline 5/28/15:  Generic Drugs, Once a Cheaper Option, Now Causing Sticker Shock</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Nightline/video/nightline-52815-generic-drugs-cheaper-option-now-causing-31383235</Link>
        <Description>The Last Generation of China's Zipliners; How Vine Magician Pulls Off Epic Stunts</Description>
        <MainBody>Nightline 5/28/15:  Generic Drugs, Once a Cheaper Option, Now Causing Sticker Shock
17:34 05/28/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Fri May 29 07:29:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  WN 05/28/15: Former House Speaker and Illinois Republican Dennis Hastert Indicted</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/WNT/video/wn-052815-house-speaker-illinois-republican-dennis-hastert-31381296</Link>
        <Description>Pilot accused of being drunk in the cockpit; toxic balls of oil close nine miles of California beaches.</Description>
        <MainBody>WN 05/28/15: Former House Speaker and Illinois Republican Dennis Hastert Indicted
20:12 05/28/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:32:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  GMA 05/28/15: Pentagon Accidently Sends Live Anthrax to Nine States</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/GMA/video/gma-052815-pentagon-accidently-sends-live-anthrax-states-31366458</Link>
        <Description>Rick Santorum: 'I'm Ready to Do This Again'; Social Media Craze Has Kids Summoning Demons</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for GMA 05/28/15: Pentagon Accidently Sends Live Anthrax to Nine States
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Tracy Morgan, Walmart Settle Lawsuit After Accident
Now Playing: Pilot Arrested for Alleged Intoxication After Crashing Small Plane
Now Playing: Dustin Diamond Appears in Court Facing Stabbing Charges
Now Playing: Pentagon Mistakenly Ships Live Anthrax to Labs Across US, Overseas
Now Playing: Rick Santorum: 'I'm Ready to Do This Again'
Now Playing: 6 Reported Tornadoes Touch Down in Texas
Now Playing: Authorities Say Device May Be Responsible for Spreading Cancer
Now Playing: Bruce Jenner Responds to Lawsuit, Calling Crash a 'Terrible Tragedy'
Now Playing: Health Alert: Dangers of Using a Grill Brush
Now Playing: Beware Vacation Listing Scams
Now Playing: Deals and Steals: Summer Edition
Now Playing: Injured Student Walks at Graduation for the 1st Time in 4 Years
Now Playing: Elementary School Teacher Investigated for Alleged Verbal Abuse
Now Playing: The Most Bizarre Baby Names of the Year
Now Playing: 'GMA' Gets in the Spelling Bee Spirit
Now Playing: Joe Manganiello Shot 'Magic Mike XXL' With a Torn Bicep
Now Playing: Natalie Portman Entered Harvard Eager to Prove She 'Wasn't Just a Dumb Actress'
Now Playing: Boy, 7, Shot Riding His Bike in Boston
Now Playing: Social Media Craze Has Kids Summoning Demons
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31366458,"title":"GMA 05/28/15: Pentagon Accidently Sends Live Anthrax to Nine States","duration":"6:46","description":"Rick Santorum: 'I'm Ready to Do This Again'; Social Media Craze Has Kids Summoning Demons","url":"/GMA/video/gma-052815-pentagon-accidently-sends-live-anthrax-states-31366458","section":"GMA","mediaType":"FEP"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Thu May 28 12:25:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  Nightline 05/27/15:  How 'Free Range' Parents Charged With Child Neglect Launched New Parenting Debate</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Nightline/video/nightline-052715-free-range-parents-charged-child-neglect-31356379</Link>
        <Description>Going Through Breast Reduction Surgery as a Teenager; On the Town with Country Star Sam Hunt</Description>
        <MainBody>Nightline 05/27/15:  How 'Free Range' Parents Charged With Child Neglect Launched New Parenting Debate
18:25 05/27/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Sun May 24 21:37:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  This Week 05/24/15: Hillary Clinton Benghazi Emails Get Released</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/ThisWeek/video/week-052415-hillary-clinton-benghazi-emails-released-31273454</Link>
        <Description>Guests: John Kasich, Mac Thornberry, Donna Brazile, S.E. Cupp, Rep. Keith Ellison, Bill Kristol</Description>
        <MainBody>This Week 05/24/15: Hillary Clinton Benghazi Emails Get Released
47:20 05/24/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Sat May 23 18:40:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  20/20 05/22/15:  Who's Freeloading?</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/2020/video/2020-052215-freeloading-31251557</Link>
        <Description>Worker's Compensation Fraudsters Caught Faking Injuries; Woman Discovers House Was Stolen in Real Estate Rip-Off; Police Nab Wedding Crasher Who Stole Gifts, Cash</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for 20/20 05/22/15: Who's Freeloading?
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Go Inside the World of Counterfeit Goods
Now Playing: Who Are the FLDS? Controversial Community Explained
Now Playing: FLDS Kids Struggle to Accept New Lives in the Outside World
Now Playing: Ex-Wife of FLDS Leader Fights for Child Custody
Now Playing: Former FLDS Members Finally Reunite With Kids They Left Behind
Now Playing: FLDS Kids Who Left Church Resist Their New Lives With Parents
Now Playing: Mom Struggles to Extract Kids From the Grip of FLDS
Now Playing: How 'American Sniper' Widow Is Moving on After Chris Kyle's Death
Now Playing: ABC News' John Quinones: Lessons from 'What Would You Do?'
Now Playing: The Moment When Taya Kyle Found Out 'American Sniper' Chris Kyle Was Dead
Now Playing: Taya Kyle Returns to Where 'American Sniper' Chris Kyle Died
Now Playing: 'American Sniper' Widow on Seeing Her Husband's Killer in Court
Now Playing: What 'American Sniper' Chris Kyle Was Like as Husband, Father
Now Playing: 'American Sniper' Chris Kyle's Struggle to Adjust to Civilian Life
Now Playing: 6 Items in Your Home that Could Be Counterfeit
Now Playing: How Counterfeiters Used These Tricks to Get Knockoffs into the US
Now Playing: Inside a Secret US Customs and Border Protection Warehouse
Now Playing: The Moment an Undercover Agent Bought Suspected Counterfeit Medicine
Now Playing: How Counterfeit Items Could Be Putting You and Your Family at Risk
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31251557,"title":"20/20 05/22/15: Who's Freeloading?","duration":"40:07","description":"Worker's Compensation Fraudsters Caught Faking Injuries; Woman Discovers House Was Stolen in Real Estate Rip-Off; Police Nab Wedding Crasher Who Stole Gifts, Cash","url":"/2020/video/2020-052215-freeloading-31251557","section":"2020","mediaType":"FEP"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
