<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="BBC">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:00:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Embattled Fifa votes on presidency</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32925227#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Fifa is set to vote for a new president amid a corruption scandal, with Sepp Blatter seeking a fifth term but challenged by Jordan's Prince Ali.</Description>
        <MainBody>The voting explained
Prince Ali has the support of most of Europe.
Responding to the scandal, he said that Fifa needed leadership that "accepts responsibility for its actions and does not pass blame... and restores confidence in the hundreds of millions of football fans around the world".
He said: "I am a straightforward person with straightforward ideas and ethics - a person who loves our sport."
BBC sports correspondent Alex Capstick, who is outside the congress, says Prince Ali may not win but is making inroads and could give Mr Blatter "a bloody nose".
The head of European football's governing body, Uefa, Michel Platini, has called for Mr Blatter to go.
The current and former Fifa executives indicted include Rafael Esquivel, Nicolas Leoz, Jeffrey Webb, Jack Warner, Eduardo Li, Eugenio Figueredo and Jose Maria Marin
Two criminal investigations were announced on Wednesday.
The US investigation accuses those indicted of bribery, racketeering and money-laundering involving tens of millions of dollars over 24 years since 1991.
It includes allegations of bribes to influence the outcome of bids to stage football tournaments such as the 2010 World Cup in South Africa and the 2016 Copa America in the US.
Former Fifa vice president Jack Warner, who was among those indicted, spent a night in jail in Trinidad before his release on bail of $395,000 (258,000).  He was greeted by cheering supporters.
At the scene: Rajini Vaidyanathan, BBC News, in Trinidad
Jack Warner celebrated with members of his Independent Liberal Party on leaving jail
A few hours after he was whisked from prison in an ambulance, baffling many who expected him to walk out, Jack Warner addressed a political rally of about 200 of his loyal supporters.
He was in fine spirits as he danced with and embraced many of them.
"Jack is the man", they sang as they danced and clapped.
"I, Jack Warner, know nothing about these charges," he told the adoring crowd.
In an interview with me afterwards, his first since he was released, he told me he'd never ever accepted a bribe, and that the FBI charges are part of a US vendetta against developing nations after it lost its World Cup bid.
Despite the gravity of the case against him, Mr Warner seemed relaxed.
He is one of Trinidad's most famous names, and the Fifa scandal is the prime topic of conversation here. Not everyone in Trinidad agrees that Jack Warner is innocent, but those who do, believe he's invincible.
Swiss prosecutors have launched a separate investigation into the bidding process for the World Cup tournaments in 2018 in Russia and 2022 in Qatar.
In his speech, Mr Blatter appeared to suggest there would not have been a crisis had the tournaments been awarded to different countries.
"If two other countries had emerged from the envelope, I think we may not have these problems."
England, where the media has sought to expose Fifa corruption, and the US, which is spearheading the latest investigation, lost out to Russia and Qatar in the bidding.
In another development, Fifa executive committee member and Brazilian FA president Marco Polo Del has left Switzerland and returned to Brazil.
Another Brazilian executive committee member, Jose Maria Marin, was among those detained in Switzerland on Wednesday.
Many of Fifa's major sponsors, including Coca-Cola, Visa, Adidas, McDonald's, Hyundai Motor and Budweiser,  have expressed concern over the investigations.
What do you think of the latest developments in the Fifa corruption crisis? What outcome would you like to see in Friday's Fifa presidential election? Are you in any of the regions affected by the scandal? You can share your views by emailing haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk .
If you are available to speak to a BBC journalist, please include a contact telephone number.
You can send your photos and videos to yourpics@bbc.co.uk or text them to 61124 (UK) or +44 7624 800 100 (international) number. Alternatively you can send pictures via our WhatsApp number +44 (0)7525 900971. Or you can upload here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 08:34:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China executes teacher for abuse</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-32926162#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>China's top court says it has executed a primary school teacher found guilty of raping or sexually abusing 26 girls.</Description>
        <MainBody>China executes teacher for sexually abusing 26 girls
29 May 2015
From the section China
The courts say they are seeing a rising number of child sex abuse cases
China's top court said it has executed a primary school teacher found guilty of raping or sexually abusing 26 girls.
Li Jishun had committed the crimes between 2011 and 2012 while teaching at a village school in Gansu province.
He preyed on pupils aged 4 to 11 who were "young and timid", according to a statement by the Supreme People's Court reported by local media.
It said there have been more than 7,000 child sex abuse cases in recent years and that the trend is on the rise.
'Grave threat'
Li had raped 21 of his victims and sexually abused the other five in classrooms, dormitories, and the forest surrounding the village near Wushan town.
The statement said that some of his victims had been raped or abused more than once. It made no mention of how he was caught.
But it said that the Gansu court had found him "a grave threat to society" and noted that he had committed the crimes within just one year.
"The Supreme People's Court thus believes that it was appropriate for Li Jishun to be executed," it said.
Local media ran the story with caricatures of the man depicting him as a wolf gobbling up children.
His sentencing was met with widespread approval on China's microblogging platform Weibo, with many expressing shock at the youth of his victims.
"Four years old? I can't believe it," said one. "A death sentence is too good for this man," wrote another commenter.
In a rare disclosure of abuse statistics, the Supreme People's Court told local media that the courts heard 7,145 cases of child sexual abuse between 2012 and 2014.
The figures showed that the number of cases went up by about 40% during those years.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:45:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fish fossils found by 'creationist'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-32928979#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A man from Calgary reported to be a committed creationist finds five fish fossils dating back 60 million years whilst digging a basement.</Description>
        <MainBody>Alberta 'creationist' finds 60m-year-old fish fossils
29 May 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Fossil finder Edgar Nernberg knew to call an expert at the University of Calgary
When Calgary digger driver Edgar Nernberg came across five fish fossils in his digger bucket, he knew right away his find was "extraordinary".
The Albertan, who has a longstanding interest in fossils, was digging a basement for a new home in Calgary's north-west.
Mr Nernberg is, according to reports, a donor to Alberta's Big Valley Creation Science Museum .
However, he realised these fossils should be seen by a palaeontologist.
"When the five fish fossils presented themselves to me in the excavator bucket, the first thing I said was you're coming home with me, the second thing was I better call a palaeontologist," Mr Nernberg said, according to a statement from the University of Calgary .
The specimens were in sandstone from the Paskapoo Formation, a Palaeocene age sedimentary rock which underlies parts of southern Alberta.
'Hasn't changed my mind'
About 60 million years old, these rocks preserve evidence of life from the time following the mass extinction event at the end of the Cretaceous period, which wiped out three-quarters of all species on earth, including the dinosaurs.
"Because complete fossils are relatively rare from this time period in Alberta, any such discoveries are significant as they shed light on the nature and diversity of animals that lived not long after the extinction of the dinosaurs," said University of Calgary palaeontologist Darla Zelenitsky.
According to the university, all fossils in Alberta are the property of the province, and do not belong to the landowners or the finders.
While the university makes no mention of finder Edgar Nernberg's creationist links, Canadian newspapers have made much of them.
The Calgary Sun asked the "good-natured" Mr Nernberg if his find had affected his view that the earth was created 6,000 years ago.
"No, it hasn't changed my mind. We all have the same evidence, and it's just a matter of how you interpret it," he told the paper.
"There's no dates stamped on these things."
But Dr Zelenitsky - while she might disagree about fossil dating - praised Mr Nernberg for his awareness of what the fossils were.
"Most people would have overlooked these - when these were uncovered, Edgar right away recognised them," she told the paper.
"An ordinary person might have just seen blobs in the rock."
The fossils will now go to Alberta's Royal Tyrrell Museum , where they will be cleaned and studied, and may end up on display.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:06:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Buhari assumes Nigeria presidency</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32927311#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The winner of Nigeria's presidential election, Muhammadu Buhari, is sworn in as leader of Africa's most populous country.</Description>
        <MainBody>Muhammadu Buhari is sworn in as Nigeria president
29 May 2015
From the section Africa
The winner of Nigeria's presidential election in March, Muhammadu Buhari, has been sworn in as leader of Africa's most populous country.
Mr Buhari is the first opposition figure to win a presidential election in Nigeria since independence in 1960.
He has taken over from Goodluck Jonathan, who urged his successor to unite the country in the face of the threat from Boko Haram militants.
Mr Buhari, a former military ruler, says he is a convert to democracy.
He defeated Mr Jonathan - who had been in office since 2010 - by 15.4 million votes to 12.9 million.
Nigeria handover and other African news updates
The BBC's Will Ross in the capital, Abuja, says heads of state and senior government officials have come from across the world to witness this truly historic moment for Nigeria.
In a country with a chequered history when it comes to power changing hands, this is a chance to celebrate deepening democracy, he says.
At the inauguration ceremony at Abuja's Eagle Square - Mr Jonathan handed over the constitution and national flags before Mr Buhari took his oath of office.
"I will discharge my duties to the best of my ability, faithfully and in accordance with the Constitution of the Federal Republic of Nigeria and the law," he said to cheering crowds.
The announcer declared to the audience afterwards: "Change has come to Nigeria."
Among the guests at the ceremony is US Secretary of State John Kerry and African leaders including Zimbabwe's President Robert Mugabe.
Mr Buhari comes into power as Nigeria faces significant economic as well as security challenges with an Islamist insurgency having devastated towns and villages in the north-east.
Besides tackling the Boko Haram militants, Mr Buhari has promised to stamp out corruption.
Muhammadu Buhari in focus:
Muslim from northern Nigeria, aged 72
Military ruler of Nigeria from 1984 to 1985, deposed in a coup
Seen as incorruptible
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:00:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korean hackers 'could kill'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-32925495#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Pyongyang's hackers are capable of attacks that could destroy critical infrastructure and even kill people, a high-profile defector warns.</Description>
        <MainBody>North Korean hackers 'could kill', warns key defector
By Dave Lee and Nick Kwek BBC News
29 May 2015
From the section Technology
Prof Kim says around 10-20% of Kim Jong-un's military budget is being spent on cyber-attack capabilities
North Korean hackers are capable of attacks that could destroy critical infrastructure and even kill people, a high-profile defector has warned.
Speaking exclusively to BBC Click, Prof Kim Heung-Kwang said the country had around 6,000 trained military hackers.
The warning follows last year's Sony Pictures hack - an attack attributed to North Korea.
Korean technology expert Martyn Williams stressed the threat was only "theoretical".
Prof Kim has called for international organisations to step in to prevent North Korea launching more severe attacks.
Military attack
For 20 years Prof Kim taught computer science at Hamheung Computer Technology University, before escaping the country in 2004.
While Prof Kim did not teach hacking techniques, his former students have gone on to form North Korea's notorious hacking unit Bureau 121.
The bureau, which is widely believed to operate out of China, has been credited for numerous hacks.
Many of the attacks are said to have been aimed specifically at South Korean infrastructure, such as power plants and banks.
Speaking at a location just outside the South Korean capital, Prof Kim told the BBC he has regular contact with key figures within the country who have intimate knowledge of the military's cyber operation.
"The size of the cyber-attack agency has increased significantly, and now has approximately 6,000 people," he said.
He estimated that between 10% to 20% of the regime's military budget is being spent on online operations.
"The reason North Korea has been harassing other countries is to demonstrate that North Korea has cyber war capacity," he added.
"Their cyber-attacks could have similar impacts as military attacks, killing people and destroying cities."
Stuxnet clone
Speaking more specifically, Prof Kim said North Korea was building its own malware based on Stuxnet - a hack attack, widely attributed to the US and Israel, which struck Iranian nuclear centrifuges before being discovered in 2010.
"[A Stuxnet-style attack] designed to destroy a city has been prepared by North Korea and is a feasible threat," Prof Kim said.
Earlier this year, the South Korean government blamed North Korea for a hack on the country's Hydro and Nuclear Power Plant .
"Although the nuclear plant was not compromised by the attack, if the computer system controlling the nuclear reactor was compromised, the consequences could be unimaginably severe and cause extensive casualties," Prof Kim said.
Martyn Williams is a journalist who follows closely the development of technology in North Korea.
He told the BBC: "I think it's important to underline that this is theoretical and possible from non-North Korean hackers too.
"It's conceivable that hackers would try something and lives could be at risk.
He noted an attack in 2003 on South Korean broadcasters, which he said was "an attempt to throw the country into confusion".
"If TV had gone off air and then ATMs stopped working, people might have panicked."
Inside Bureau 121
When it comes to cyber-attacks, few groups are as notorious as North Korea's Bureau 121, which has operated since the late nineties.
Most security researchers agree that the group operates out of China. Specifically, in the basement of a restaurant, rated highly on TripAdvisor for its tremendous Korean food.
Prof Kim gave several Bureau 121 members their first taste of computer science.
While he didn't teach hacking techniques, Prof Kim gave the students knowledge of the ins-and-outs of computing, networks and data transfer.
The very best students were later plucked from his course by the military and given further, more specialist training in cyber security.
Prof Kim told the BBC he feels saddened that some of the great, "bright" minds he nurtured had their potential channelled "not into improving our internet culture, but to terrorise other people using the internet".
But he conceded that his former students probably enjoyed their task, and took pride in "accomplishing Kim Jong-un's orders as a cyber warrior".
'Off the internet'
Prof Kim has called on international organisations to take action over North Korea's cyber-activity.
"We need to collect the evidence of North Korea's cyber terrorism and report them to UN Human Rights Council and other UN agencies," he told the BBC.
"If North Korea continues to cause damage in this way, an organisation such as Icann should ban North Korea."
Icann - the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers - manages the distribution of domain name including .com and .net.
It could, theoretically, shut down the use of North Korea's domain, .kp.
North Korea was blamed for a hack on Sony Pictures that temporarily halted a film's release
In a statement, Icann said its powers in this regard were limited.
"Icann does not have the power, nor remit, to ban countries from having a presence on or access to the Internet," said Duncan Burns, its head of communications.
"Icann's primary role is the coordination of the internet's unique identifiers to ensure the stability, security and resiliency of the internet.
"We rely on law enforcement and governmental regulatory agencies to police reported illegal activity."
Furthermore, disabling .kp would have minimal effect if, as is widely believed, much of North Korea's hacking force conducts its operations outside of the country.
Other measures, such as sanctions imposed by the US in the wake of the Sony Pictures hack, might have a greater impact.
But Prof Kim added: "This issue can't be solved by one or two countries.
"The international community needs to pay attention to North Korea's attempts to destroy the internet."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 10:02:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Myanmar hits back on migrant blame</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32925815#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Myanmar refuses to be singled out for blame for the Asia migrant crisis as delegates at a Bangkok conference say the situation was at an alarming level.</Description>
        <MainBody>Myanmar refuses sole blame for Asia migrant crisis
29 May 2015
From the section Asia
Myanmar has refused to be singled out for blame for the Asia migrant crisis at a conference of the regional grouping Asean in Bangkok.
Delegates said the situation was at an alarming level. Representatives of the US and UN are also at the meeting.
Thousands of people have fled Bangladesh and Myanmar by boat, heading south to Thailand, Indonesia and Malaysia.
The UN estimates about 2,600 migrants are still stranded out at sea.
Most are economic migrants from Bangladesh and Rohingya Muslims fleeing persecution in Myanmar - also known as Burma.
The crisis began earlier this year when Thailand cracked down on overland migrant routes, forcing people smugglers to use sea routes instead.
'No finger-pointing'
Myanmar's foreign ministry chief Htin Lynn said his country would co-operate in dealing with human trafficking.
But he also told delegates that on "this issue of illegal migration of boat people, you cannot single out my country.
"Finger-pointing will not serve any purpose. It will take us nowhere."
Htin Lynn said Myanmar should not be singled out for blame
In his opening remarks , Thai Foreign Minister Tanasak Patimapragorn said "the influx of irregular migrants... has reached alarming levels".
He added that "the root causes that motivated these people to leave must also be addressed", in comments apparently directed at Myanmar and Bangladesh.
US assistant secretary of state Anne Richard also urged swift action to save the lives of migrants out at sea.
Analysis: Jonathan Head, BBC News, Bangkok
There is a growing consensus on how to help those migrants caught out by Thailand's sudden move against smuggling networks. Migrant boats will no longer be pushed back to sea by Malaysia and Indonesia, although Thailand will still nudge those it finds in the direction of those two countries.
Money is being found to help support those who have already landed. Thailand has even dropped its objection to the US flying military surveillance aircraft over its territorial waters. After their harrowing voyages, the migrants should now get fair and humane treatment.
Addressing what's causing the flow of migrants is clearly going to be more difficult. The Bangladesh delegation acknowledged that many are poor economic migrants from its shores, but stressed "external factors" driving others - a veiled reference to the harsh treatment of Rohingya Muslims in Myanmar.
Almost no-one is using the word Rohingya, though. The Burmese delegation objects to this, and has warned against what it calls "finger-pointing". Consensus on the Rohingyas is still a very distant goal.
'Only discussions'
Friday's talks include representatives from 17 countries affected by "irregular migration in the Indian Ocean".
The US, Japan and Switzerland have sent observers and there are officials from the UN refugee agency UNHCR, the UN Office on Drugs and Crime and the International Organization for Migration.
However, correspondents say many of those attending are not ministerial-level and the talks are unlikely to produce a binding agreement or even a plan of action.
Most countries are unwilling take in the migrants, fearing that by accepting them they will encourage more to make the journey.
Malaysia and Indonesia have agreed to stop towing boats out to sea and to give temporary shelter to those who have landed. Thailand has only said it will stop rejecting the boats.
More than 3,000 migrants have landed in Indonesia and Malaysia in recent weeks.
Asia's migrant crisis
Rohingya Muslims mainly live in Myanmar, where they have faced decades of persecution.
Rights groups say migrants feel they have "no choice" but to leave, paying people smugglers to help them.
The UN estimates more than 120,000 Rohingya have fled in the past three years.
Traffickers usually take the migrants by sea to Thailand then overland to Malaysia.
But Thailand recently began cracking down on the migrant routes, meaning traffickers are using sea routes instead.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 09:20:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US ex-speaker charged over payments</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-32926304#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Former US House of Representatives speaker Dennis Hastert faces charges of lying to the FBI over secret payments to cover up "prior misconduct".</Description>
        <MainBody>Dennis Hastert, US ex-speaker, charged over payments
29 May 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Dennis Hastert is the longest-serving Republican House speaker in US history
Former US House of Representatives speaker Dennis Hastert has been charged over illegal cash withdrawals to pay hush money to an unnamed individual.
Mr Hastert, 73, allegedly withdrew $1.7m (1.1m; 1.6m) in small amounts to skirt federal reporting rules.
According to the indictment, he agreed to pay $3.5m to an unnamed individual to "conceal his prior misconduct".
He served as a Republican congressman from Illinois for more than 20 years until 2007.
'Individual A'
The indictment alleges that Mr Hastert, who is also charged with lying to the FBI, made a deal in 2010 with "Individual A" to make payments in recompense for unspecified prior misconduct.
Individual A lives in Yorkville, Illinois, where Mr Hastert was a high school teacher and wrestling coach between 1965 to 1981, and has known the former speaker most of his life.
According to the indictment, Mr Hastert began by making $50,000 withdrawals and passing the cash to Individual A every six weeks.
As a result of federal rules that require banks to report withdrawals of more than $10,000, the former speaker being questioned by his bank.
Thereafter, the indictment says, Mr Hastert made a series of $10,000 withdrawals in an attempt to avoid detection.
'I kept the cash'
When questioned by the FBI, Mr Hastert said he was withdrawing the money because he did not trust the bank.
"Yeah... I kept the cash. That's what I'm doing," he said.
By the time the charges were announced on Thursday, he had paid about half agreed sum of $3.5m, the indictment says.
Each of the two charges against Mr Hastert carries a maximum penalty of five years in prison and a $250,000 fine.
He could not be reached for comment.
After losing the job of speaker in 2006 and resigning from the House of Representatives in 2007, Mr Hastert joined the Washington law firm Dickstein Shapiro as a senior adviser.
The Chicago Mercantile Exchange said on Thursday that he had resigned from the law firm's board.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:24:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heat wave conditions ease in India</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-32926172#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The massive heat wave sweeping India is starting to ease, with forecasts of rain in some affected states.</Description>
        <MainBody>India heat wave eases after nearly 1,700 deaths
29 May 2015
From the section India
Most of the patients are suffering from sunstroke and dehydration
The massive heatwave sweeping India is starting to ease, with forecasts of rain in some affected states.
Officials say nearly 1,700 people have died in the worst-hit states of Telangana and Andhra Pradesh, where temperatures rose above 45C (113F).
Clouds have formed over some parts of the two states and weather officials say pre-monsoon showers are likely to provide some relief on Friday.
The monsoon is due to reach Kerala, in the south, by the end of May.
It will then sweep across the country.
In the worst-affected state of Andhra Pradesh, where temperatures have hit 47C (117F), more than 1,300 people are reported to have died since 18 May.
The state's top meteorological officer YK Reddy told BBC Hindi that heatwave conditions "have reduced considerably" and temperatures have fallen in all but two districts.
In neighbouring Telangana, where officials say at least 340 people have died from heat-related conditions, temperatures have declined.
"For all practical purposes, the heat wave has now ended in our state," BR Meena, Telangana's disaster management commissioner, told BBC Hindi.
Meanwhile India's public hospitals are struggling to cope with patients of the heatwave.
"I have been posted here for seven years, but I am feeling a lot of heat this year. We have been seeing a dozen patients of heat wave every day," Dr Anjaya of Rajiv Gandhi Institute for Medical Sciences in Andhra Pradesh told the BBC.
Hospitals in the Indian capital Delhi, where temperatures have soared to 45.5C (113.9F) have also seen a large number of patients.
Experts say a sudden onset of heat led to the heatwave this year
"Hospitals are overflowing with heatstroke victims," Ajay Lekhi, president of the Delhi Medical Association, told AFP news agency.
"Patients are complaining of severe headache and dizziness. They are also showing symptoms of delirium," he said.
Reports said there were long queues outside the All India Institute of Medical Sciences, one of Delhi's largest government-run hospitals.
"Last night there was no electricity for nearly five hours," Seema Sharma told AFP outside the hospital as she waited in line for her four-year-old son to be examined.
"You can imagine what we must have gone through. He just couldn't sleep and kept on crying. Now he has fever as well."
The Delhi-based research organisation Centre for Science and Environment said the high deaths this year could be because of the sudden onset of heat.
"This could be due to the sudden change in temperatures after a prolonged wet February and March that had kept the temperatures cool," said Arjuna Srinidhi, the group's programme manager for climate change.
What is a heatwave?
Heatwaves are defined as periods of abnormally high temperatures and usually occur between March and June in India
May is the country's hottest month, with an average maximum temperature of 41C (104F) in Delhi
Longer, more severe heatwaves are becomingly increasingly frequent globally
Intense heat can cause cramps, exhaustion and heat stroke
Thousands of people died across India during heatwaves in 2002 and 2003
In 2010 around 300 people were killed by intense temperatures, according to media reports from the time
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 09:32:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds of migrants rescued in Med</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32926374#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>EU naval vessels rescue more than 700 migrants off Sicily, as Africans continue to attempt the perilous crossing from Libya.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mediterranean migrant crisis: Hundreds rescued off Sicily
29 May 2015
From the section Europe
Tens of thousands have managed to sail to Europe this year, but many have died
A total of 741 migrants travelling in six boats have been rescued off Sicily, the Italian coastguard says.
The migrants, who had set sail from Libya, were picked up by EU naval vessels on Thursday, a coastguard spokesman told AFP news agency.
Last month the EU pledged to beef up maritime patrols and fight trafficking.
The UN estimates that 60,000 people have already tried to cross the Mediterranean in the past five months, and that about 1,800 people have died.
The death toll represents a 30-fold increase on the same period in 2014, according to the International Organization for Migration (IOM).
The rise has been attributed to chaos in Libya - the staging post for most crossings - as well as milder weather.
Many migrants are trying to escape conflict or poverty in countries such as Syria, Eritrea, Nigeria and Somalia.
Have you or has someone you know been affected by the issues in this story? Email your experiences to haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk - if you are happy to speak with a BBC journalist please give a telephone number.
Or you can contact us on WhatsApp number +44 (0)7525 900971
Or comment here:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:51:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alleged Nazi criminal dies in Canada</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32926309#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A suspected Nazi war criminal, Vladimir Katriuk, dies in Canada just weeks after being charged by Russia with war crimes.</Description>
        <MainBody>Vladimir Katriuk, alleged Nazi criminal, dies in Canada
29 May 2015
Vladimir Katriuk spent his last years on a honeybee farm in Ormstown, Quebec
A Ukrainian man suspected of being a Nazi war criminal has died in Canada.
Vladimir Katriuk was second on a most wanted list compiled by the Simon Wiesenthal Center, a US organisation which investigates Nazi war criminals.
Mr Katriuk passed away aged 93 after a long illness, his lawyer said.
His death came just hours after the Centre for Israel and Jewish Affairs said Canada should ensure he was held accountable for alleged war crimes.
Russia charged Mr Katriuk earlier this month and issued a request for him to be deported from Canada to Moscow to face trial.
Village massacre
Russia's investigative committee alleged he took part in a 1943 massacre in the village of Khatyn, which was then in the Soviet Union and is now part of Belarus.
It is thought that all 156 residents of the village were killed by a Nazi battalion made up largely of Ukrainians soldiers.
Mr Katriuk denied any involvement in the massacre, but a 2012 study by Sweden's Lund University said that he was a key participant.
A witness told the authors of the study that he lay in wait outside a barn that had been set on fire and shot anyone who attempted to escape.
Mr Katriuk allegedly deserted from his SS unit in 1944. Court documents show he lived in Paris before emigrating to Canada in 1951.
He later became a Canadian citizen and lived with his French-born wife in Ontario, working as a bee-keeper.
Canadian authorities investigated Mr Katriuk but decided not to revoke his citizenship after failing to find evidence of atrocities.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:24:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japan eruption forces evacuation</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32929491#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Mount Shindake erupts spectacularly in southern Japan, sending black ash clouds 9km into the air and forcing the evacuation of Kuchinoerabu island.</Description>
        <MainBody>Japan volcano: Mount Shindake erupts, forcing evacuation
29 May 2015
From the section Asia
A volcano has erupted on an island in Japan, spewing black clouds of ash up to 9km (5.6 miles) into the sky and forcing the evacuation of inhabitants.
One person was reported to have suffered minor facial burns from falling debris as Mount Shindake erupted on Friday morning.
Most of the 137 residents of Kuchinoerabu island were evacuated by boat.
One spoke of how the sky turned dark as the volcano erupted.
Flows of rock and super-heated gas travelled down the mountain and into the sea, turning the main harbour grey and the sea-water murky.
Shindake erupted last year for the first time since 1980, when a 14-year period of activity ended. Several people died in a 1933 eruption.
"There was a really loud 'dong' sound of an explosion, and then black smoke rose, darkening the sky," Nobuaki Hayashi, a community leader, told national broadcaster NHK.  "It smelled of sulphur."
The fire and disaster management agency has raised the alert level for the island to five, its highest level. But officials say there is no threat to human life.
Nevertheless, the eruption was big news, and Prime Minister Shinzo Abe appeared on television to pledge that he had mobilised "all functions of government" to ensure the islanders' safety.
Volcano experts have warned that more eruptions on a similar scale could follow.
Japan sits at the junction of several tectonic plates and is one of the world's most seismically active countries.
Some have linked an surge in recent volcanic activity to the devastating earthquake that struck on 11 March 2011, triggering a massive tsunami.
In September last year, Mount Ontake in central Japan erupted unexpectedly, killing dozens of hikers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:32:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Man-eating tiger' to stay in zoo</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-32926348#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A court in India's Rajasthan state rejects a plea to release a tiger who has been branded a killer and caged.</Description>
        <MainBody>India's 'man-eating' tiger to stay in Rajasthan zoo
29 May 2015
From the section India
Ustad is now caged in an enclosure smaller than a football field
A court in India's Rajasthan state has rejected a plea to release a tiger who has been branded a killer and caged.
Nine-year-old Ustad was tranquilised and shifted from a national park to a zoo earlier this month after he killed three men, including a forest guard.
A tiger lover had petitioned the court, saying caging the tiger was against India's wildlife laws.
India's tiger population stood at 2,226 in 2014. The country is home to 70% of the world's tigers.
Ustad, who lived in the 400 sq km (99,000-acre) Ranthambore National Park, popular for its tiger safaris, was shot with a tranquilising dart and driven to a zoo 400km (250 miles) away earlier this month.
He had been declared the prime suspect in the killing of a 53-year-old forest guard on 8 May. He was also accused of killing a 23-year-old local man in 2010 and a 19-year-old boy in March 2012.
The tiger is now is caged in an enclosure smaller than a football field in a zoological park in Udaipur district.
Fears for tourism
Chandramauleshwar Singh, a tiger lover and a regular visitor to Ranthambore, petitioned the high court in Rajasthan against the move.
He said the decision to move Ustad was made without "any scientific probe or investigation into the circumstance of the attack".
Mr Singh said the real reason the park decided to move Ustad was because of pressure from the local tourist industry, which feared visitors would be frightened off by the presence of a man-eater.
The high court in Rajasthan dismissed the plea saying the decision to shift Ustad can "under no stretch of imagination be held to be hasty, arbitrary or unreasonable".
The judges said they did not agree that Ustad's move was prompted by the tourist industry because "tourism thrives on the tigers of Ranthambore and it is not the other way round".
Mr Singh has now appealed to Supreme Court to take a decision on the matter.
Correspondents say the case raises questions for tiger conservation worldwide because India has been very successful in its efforts to increase its tiger population.
As the number of tigers in India have risen, their habitat has shrunk, meaning people and tigers meet more often, occasionally with disastrous results.
More than 60 people are killed by tigers every year in India.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:47:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Swiss cheese hole origins solved</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32920200#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Scientists say they have discovered why Swiss cheese has holes in it: apparently, it is all down to how dirty buckets are when the milk is collected.</Description>
        <MainBody>Swiss cheese hole mystery solved: It's all down to dirt
28 May 2015
From the section Europe
Hole again: and it is all thanks to tiny flecks of hay, say Swiss scientists
Scientists say they have discovered why Swiss cheese has holes in it: apparently, it is all down to how dirty buckets are when the milk is collected.
Contrary to what cartoons have suggested over the years, the holes are not made by mice eating their way through the cheese.
And nor are they produced by carbon dioxide released by bacteria, as popular scientific belief held.
Instead, a Swiss laboratory says they are created by flecks of hay.
Agroscope, a government agricultural institute, said "microscopically small hay particles" would fall in to buckets collecting milk, and develop into bigger holes as the cheese matures.
The process affects only some Swiss cheeses, such as Emmental and Appenzell.
Agroscope said the findings explained why fewer holes had been appearing in Swiss cheeses over the last 15 years, since more modern milking methods made it less likely for hay to fall into containers.
Scientists reached their conclusions after adding small amounts of hay dust to milk and making it into cheese over 130 days.
The research has not been peer reviewed.
The theory that bacteria caused the holes has been around since 1917, after findings were published by an American scientist, William Clark .
The cheese industry calls holes in cheese "eyes". Any cheese without eyes is known as blind.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 13:54:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India's Mysore crowns new maharaja</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-32911649#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A 23-year-old graduate from the University of Massachusetts is crowned the new maharaja of Mysore, titular head of the 600-year-old Wadiyar dynasty.</Description>
        <MainBody>India's Mysore crowns new maharaja Yaduveer Wadiyar
By Imran Qureshi BBC Hindi, Bangalore
28 May 2015
From the section India
A 23-year-old economics graduate from the University of Massachusetts has been crowned the new maharaja of Mysore, titular head of the 600-year-old Wadiyar dynasty in southern India.
Yaduveer Krishnadatta Chamaraja Wadiyar was anointed at an elaborate ceremony lasting nearly two hours.
It was conducted by more than 40 priests across 15 temples spread across the Mysore Palace grounds.
He succeeds his grand uncle Srikantadatta Narasimharaja Wadiyar.
Srikantadatta Wadiyar, who died in December 2013, was childless and did not name an heir, but his widow Pramodadevi Wadiyar adopted Yaduveer Gopalraj Urs, a relative, at a ceremony in February.
After his coronation , the maharaja became known by his full title, Yaduveer Krishnadatta Chamaraja Wadiyar.
"It was quite a spectacle. This was enormous and certainly beyond expectations," Michael Ludgrove, curator of the Royal House of Mysore, told BBC Hindi following Thursday's ceremony.
"All sections of society were here, including the representatives of the people," he added.
The crowning ceremony was attended by more than 1,000 guests from India and abroad, including former Indian prime minister HD Deve Gowda and Karnataka state Chief Minister K Siddaramaiah.
Mr Ludgrove says he has met the new maharaja just once but is quite impressed by him. "He is a man of the times. He is full of enthusiasm and potential."
The new maharaja will now become the custodian of more than 1,500 acres of land spread across Mysore, Bangalore, Hassan, Channapatna and other places in the southern state of Karnataka.
But, he will also be inheriting a legal battle with the Karnataka government, which wants to take over the palace properties.
He is also likely to face a legal challenge from one of the late maharajah's nephews, Kantharaj Urs, who is upset that he was not chosen as successor.
The dispute over the inheritance is because the Wodeyar kings have never had children - legend has it that the dynasty has suffered from a 17th Century curse .
Mr Ludgrove, who worked with the former maharaja for nearly three decades, says the Mysore royals are very similar to the British royalty.
"They are the constant. These are traditions which continue and they bring all people together. Something that is rarely seen," he says.
Historian Nanjaraj Urs says some of the members of Wadiyar dynasty had contributed greatly to the development of the state, but the crowning ceremony now is a "farce".
"The real maharajas had an intimate relationship with the people. There was affection and it is that emotional attachment which makes this family popular.
"But now it is just a function in a traditional family. You can call the ceremony by any name but all of it is within the family."
India's royalty lost their official powers when the nation gained independence in 1947 but the modern-day maharajas are still wealthy and influential.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 29 08:03:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US prophet subway cartoon is blocked</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-32925948#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Transport officials in Washington DC block plans by a free speech group to display a cartoon of the Prophet Muhammad on the subway.</Description>
        <MainBody>Washington DC officials block Muhammad subway cartoon
29 May 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
The Washington transit system has suspended all "issue-oriented" advertising
Transport officials in Washington DC have blocked plans by an American free speech pressure group to have a controversial cartoon of the Prophet Muhammad displayed on the subway.
The American Freedom Defense Initiative wanted to display the cartoon, which won first prize at an event in Texas.
Two gunmen were shot dead by police outside the event earlier this month.
Washington transport authorities on Thursday banned political, religious and advocacy adverts on the subway.
The transport authority in the US capital voted unanimously to suspend advertisements it describes as "issue-oriented".
Police blew up the car used by the Texas attackers shortly after they carried out their strike earlier this month
AFDI founder Pamela Geller strongly criticised the decision to ban the advert, describing it as an attack on free of speech.
Ms Geller commented on her website that "rewarding terror with submission is defeat, absolute and complete defeat.
"These cowards may claim that they are making people safer, but I submit to you the opposite. They are making it far more dangerous for Americans  everywhere."
The advert calls for Americans to support free speech and features a bearded, turban-wearing Muhammad waving a sword and shouting: "You can't draw me!"
In reply, a cartoon bubble portrays an artist grasping a pencil and saying: "That's why I draw you."
Ms Geller insists the cartoon is a "political opinion" which does not contain any violence.
Her organisation, described by critics as a hate group, has run controversial adverts on subways and buses in Chicago, Philadelphia and San Francisco as well as in Washington's Metro in 2012.
Ms Geller is an outspoken critic of Islam
Pamela Geller: America's controversial blogger
A staunch critic of Islam since 2005, she rose to prominence in 2010 through her online opposition to Park 51, a planned Muslim community centre in Lower Manhattan close to the World Trade Center site
Heads the American Freedom Defense Initiative (AFDI), which has also caused controversy by buying advertising space on buses in US cities, criticising Islam
The 56-year-old describes herself online as a free-speech activist, but her critics denounce her as a "bigot"
She insists the focus of her criticism is chiefly against radical Islam, but has been quoted as saying that "Islam is the most anti-semitic, genocidal ideology in the world"
Speaking of her role in organising the Muhammad Art Exhibit in Garland, she said: "We draw Muhammad because we are free... We draw Muhammad because our unalienable rights are enshrined in the First Amendment."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:35:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US charges Chinese in testing scam</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-32921737#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The US Department of Justice has charged 15 Chinese nationals with developing a scheme to have imposters take university entrance exams.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chinese nationals accused of taking SATs for others
28 May 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
US officials say the suspects posed as students to take college entrance exams
The US Department of Justice has charged 15 Chinese nationals with developing a scheme to have imposters take university entrance exams.
Prosecutors said suspects used fake passports to trick administrators into allowing people other than legitimate test takers to sit the exams.
The scheme took place between 2011 and 2015 mostly in western Pennsylvania, authorities said.
Those charged could face up to 20 years in prison if convicted.
The defendants, both male and female, range in age from 19 to 26, and are currently living in several cities - including Blacksburg, Virginia, and Boston, Massachusetts - where major universities are located, the Reuters news agency reported.
The counterfeit test takers sat for the Scholastic Aptitude Test (SAT) - a major university entrance exam in the US - as well as the Test of English as a Foreign Language (Toefl) and the Graduate Record Examination (GRE), the Justice Department said.
The SAT is a major university entrance exam in the US
The scheme's beneficiaries "fraudulently obtained admissions to American institutions of higher education," said US Attorney for the Western District of Pennsylvania David Hickton.
The prosecutor said that the students also cheated student visa requirements by using counterfeit Chinese passports.
The Pittsburgh Post-Gazette reported that 24-year-old Siyuan Zhao, who resides in Massachusetts, has been detained. Han Tong, 24, of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, who is considered the primary defendant, and 10 others will receive an order to appear in court.
The newspaper reports that three others are currently in China, and their names have been redacted from court documents.
Special Agent in Charge John Kelleghan for Homeland Security Investigations of Philadelphia said: "These students were not only cheating their way into the university, they were also cheating their way through our nation's immigration system".
The defendants could face up to 20 years in prison, a fine of $250,000 (163,000) or both for each of the wire and mail fraud counts they face.  Additionally, they face five years on top that for the conspiracy charges.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:19:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Latin Americans open Fifa enquiries</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-32925887#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Brazil begins investigations into possible Fifa corruption there, as an Argentine judge issues warrants for three businessmen wanted by the US.</Description>
        <MainBody>Latin Americans open their own Fifa enquiries
29 May 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
The CBF's headquarters is named Jose Maria Marin, who was arrested in Switzerland on Wednesday
Brazil's federal police has begun investigations into possible Fifa corruption in the country.
Justice Minister Eduardo Cardozo said they were looking at possible tax evasion and money laundering within Brazil.
Costa Rica has opened an enquiry into US accusations against Eduardo Li, head of Costa Rica's football association.
In Argentina, a judge has issued warrants for three local businessmen wanted by the US.
Brazil's President Dilma Rousseff said football in her country "will only benefit" from the US corruption investigation of Fifa and other top officials of the sport.
In the meantime, the Brazilian Football Confederation has removed the name of Jose Maria Marin from the facade of its Rio de Janeiro headquarters after the former president was arrested in Switzerland on corruption charges.
A Congressional enquiry into corruption in the CBF may also be on the agenda.
On Wednesday, the Brazilian senator and former football player Romario made a formal application for an enquiry to be opened.
Mr Marin, who faces extradition to the US, was head of the CBF from 2012 to April 2015 and headed the local committee for the organisation of the 2014 World Cup.
Up to his arrest, he was part of a Fifa committee organizing the Olympic football tournaments.
Front pages of newspapers in the Paraguayan capital, Asuncion with pictures of Nicolas Leoz,, the former president of South America's football confederation. Mr Leoz fell ill and was hospitalized in Paraguay on Wednesday as US authorities sought his extradition.
In Costa Rica, prosecutors have opened an investigation into the president of the country's football federation, Eduardo Li, who was also detained on Wednesday.
The arrest of Mr Li was met with surprise in Costa Rica. He had become a national hero after the national team's unexpected run to the quarter-finals of the World Cup in Brazil in 2014.
A spokesman for Costa Rica's public prosecutor said: "The investigation opened today aims to determine whether the hypothesis of the US Department of Justice probe related to a case of money laundering and corruption involving Eduardo Li can be corroborated."
Costa Rica's tax office said it had also opened an investigation into Mr Li's various business interests in the country.
Argentina support
In Argentina, the football association - AFA - issued a statement in support of the US led investigation into Fifa.
"The Argentine Football Association states that it supports and joins the investigations on Fifa and Conmebol representatives and members, sharing the football world's concerns as regard transparency in our beloved sport."
A judge issued arrest warrants for three businessmen accused of conspiring to win and keep lucrative media rights contracts from regional football federations in return for millions of dollars in bribes.
The warrants were issued a day after the US Justice Department had requested them.
The head of the Argentine Cabinet, Anibal Fernandez, said the country's tax authority would pursue any money owed it and that bribery should be investigated in Argentina "no matter the cost".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:04:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Neruda death probe inconclusive</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-32925398#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>New tests on the remains of the Chilean poet Pablo Neruda say they have found no conclusive evidence he was poisoned.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chilean poet Pablo Neruda death probe inconclusive
28 May 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Pablo Neruda (L) was interviewed in London in 1965 by the BBC's Latin American service
Spanish scientists investigating the death of the world famous left-wing Chilean poet, Pablo Neruda, in 1973 say they have found no conclusive evidence that he was poisoned.
The Chilean government reopened an investigation in January with new tests on his remains for protein traces caused by poisoning.
The investigators said they had found proteins explained by natural causes including advanced prostate cancer.
Tests in 2013 uncovered nothing.
The source of a third protein was not immediately clear but it was probably caused by an infection or the posthumous manipulation of the remains, the investigators said.
A final round of DNA testing is still expected to take place.
Pablo Neruda is presumed to have died of cancer days after the military coup in 1973.
His driver has alleged that agents of General Augusto Pinochet, who was leading the military coup, had taken advantage of Mr Neruda's illness to inject poison in his stomach as he lay in hospital.
Pablo Neruda, a Nobel laureate,  was famed for his passionate love poems and his outspoken communist views.
His supporters and family are divided on whether researchers should continue the tests or whether his remains should be returned to his grave near his coastal home of Isla Negra.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:16:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Zuma not liable for home upgrades</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32921715#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>South African President Jacob Zuma will not have to repay state money spent to upgrade his private home in Nkandla, the police minister says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Zuma 'will not have to repay' money spent on residence
28 May 2015
From the section Africa
Mr Zuma has previously said that he did not request the upgrades to the property
President Jacob Zuma will not have to repay state money spent to upgrade his private home in Nkandla, South Africa's police minister has said.
Nathi Nhleko said that the upgrades, including a pool costing almost 4m rand ($328,000; 215,000) were in fact security features.
Last year an independent inquiry found the president had "unduly benefited" from the upgrades.
The president has been heavily criticised over the issue.
In February the Nkandla controversy prompted chaotic scenes in parliament as leftist MPs scuffled with security.
They had been interrupting a key annual speech by Mr Zuma and demanding answers over the row.
A report last year by South Africa's anti-corruption watchdog found Mr Zuma had "unduly benefitted" from the renovations and recommended he pay back some of the money.
However Mr Zuma has maintained he would only pay money back if ordered to do so by Mr Nhleko, the police minister.
At a news conference Mr Nhleko justified his decision not to make Mr Zuma pay back any of the money by saying the upgrades were security features.
For example, Mr Nhleko explained the pool was in fact intended for use in fighting fires, and he even had a video of four policemen demonstrating how this security feature worked.
A chicken run, a cow enclosure, an amphitheatre and visitors centre were also all classed as security features by Mr Nhleko.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:51:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU withdraws Burundi poll observers</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32923214#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The European Union suspends its election monitoring mission in Burundi amid political unrest over the president's third-term bid.</Description>
        <MainBody>Burundi elections: EU withdraws poll observers
28 May 2015
From the section Africa
Protests against the third term bid have been going on for weeks
The European Union has suspended its election monitoring mission in Burundi where President Pierre Nkurunziza is seeking a third term next month.
The decision was taken because of restrictions on the media, excessive force against demonstrators and a climate of intimidation, it said.
It comes as the Catholic Church said it would no longer help organise the elections amid the political unrest.
Earlier this month, the president survived a coup attempt.
Rights groups say at least 20 people have died in protests since Mr Nkurunziza announced on 25 April that he would seek a third term.
The UN says about 70,000 people have fled to neighbouring countries fearing political violence.
EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said her team had been on the ground for more than a month.
They reported that "the election process continues to be seriously marred by restrictions on independent media, excessive use of force against demonstrators, a climate of intimidation for opposition parties and civil society and lack of confidence in the election authorities", she said in a statement .
The EU has already said it is withholding more than $2m (1.3m) of funding for the elections.
Correspondents say the statement by the Catholic Church, which is hugely influential in Burundi, is another blow for Mr Nkurunziza.
Mr Nkurunziza has been in power since 2005
Many of the country's 18 provincial electoral commissions are headed by priests, who the Catholic Church committee have asked to stand down.
Bishop Gervais Bashimiyubusa said in a statement read on Catholic radio that the church could not "endorse an election riddled with shortcomings", the AFP news agency reports.
He did not call for a boycott of the elections, but stressed that nobody should go to the polls "by threat or intimidation, or because they have been bought in one way or another".
Parliamentary elections are scheduled for 5 June and the presidential poll for 26 June.
The president's critics say his bid for a third term contravenes the constitution, which requires him to step down after two terms.
But Burundi's Constitutional Court ruled that Mr Nkurunziza's first term does not count because he was elected by parliament and not voters.
Burundi: Key facts
The country is facing its worst turmoil since the 12-year civil war ended in 2005
10.4m population
50 years - life expectancy for a man
2nd poorest country in the world
85% are Hutu, 14% Tutsi
300,000 died in civil war
UN, World Bank, CIA
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri May 29 05:54:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Australian women 'trying to join IS'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-australia-32926114#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Authorities in the Australian state of Victoria say young women are being lured by romantic notions to the Middle East to join Islamic State.</Description>
        <MainBody>Young Australian women trying to join IS, say police
29 May 2015
From the section Australia
Islamic State fighters have seized large areas of Iraq and Syria
As many as 12 young women have tried to leave Melbourne to join the Islamic State (IS) militant group, according to Australian police.
The women, aged between 18 and 29, have been recruited on social media.
Five of them are now living with IS militants in the conflict zones, according to a special investigation by Victoria Police.
Concern has been rising since mid-2014 about Australians going to the Middle East to fight for IS.
The government will soon introduce legislation allowing it to strip dual citizens fighting in Iraq or Syria of their Australian citizenship.
People working in Australia to support militant groups will also be targeted by the changes.
Task Force Pax was established in April to monitor Victorians believed to be involved with insurgents.
Early intervention
Officials from the task force told local media on Friday that another four Melbourne women made it as far as Turkey before being turned back by authorities.
One other was stopped by customs officers in Australia while two remain unaccounted for.
The young women are all from Melbourne's northern and south-eastern suburbs.
Assistant Commissioner Tracy Linford said two forensic psychologists had been embedded in the task force to help investigators understand why the young women were trying to join IS.
"The use of psychologists provides us with a far more comprehensive risk assessment and also assists in identifying early intervention opportunities," she said.
"This gives us the chance to focus on identifying those youths most at risk of radicalisation and to engage with them or their families directly."
In the past year, Australian police have conducted numerous anti-terror raids
Local media reported that one of the women was 21-year-old Zehra Duman, who allegedly travelled overseas in December to join Mahmoud Abullatif, a Melbourne man believed to be a Islamic extremist.
She travelled to Syria without her parent's knowledge, The Age newspaper reported.
It is believed Abullatif was killed while fighting with IS in January but Ms Duman has yet to return home.
Police said the young women were being sold a romantic view of life with IS, and had lied to their families about their travel plans.
Sexual servitude
Authorities were warning parents and friends of young women about the lure of IS, saying the women could end up in arranged marriages, or forced into sexual servitude in the Middle East.
"Our intelligence tells us these women are going over there to meet their partners, to marry somebody in an arranged marriage or be pushed into sexual servitude," Assistant Commissioner Linford told reporters.
The Herald Sun newspaper said mother Dullel Kassab was another of the women identified by police.
The Australian government believes at least 100 Australians are fighting with militant groups in the Middle East.
Another 150 people in Australia are known to be supporting such groups, while Australia's intelligence agency, the Australian Security Intelligence Organisation (ASIO), is investigating about 400 high-priority terrorist cases.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:22:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tajik special ops chief 'joins IS'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32917311#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Tajikistan's special forces chief appears in a video claiming to have joined Islamic State forces in Syria.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tajikistan special forces chief Gulmurod Khalimov 'joins IS'
28 May 2015
From the section Asia
Gulmurod Khalimov has been missing since the beginning of May
Tajikistan's special forces chief has appeared in a video claiming to have joined Islamic State forces in Syria.
Gulmurod Khalimov is seen in the footage dressed in black and holding a gun. He went missing in early May.
He says he joined IS in protest at Tajikistan's policy towards religion, which he says is anti-Islamic.
Hundreds of Central Asians are thought have left for Syria, but this is the first known case of such a high profile officer joining the militants.
The authorities in Tajikistan have refused to comment on his whereabouts since his disappearance, reports the BBC's Abdujalil Abdurasulov in Almaty.
'Slaughter'
Khalimov used to fight extremists at home and was one of the best trained officers in the country, our correspondent says.
In the video, which is believed to have been recorded in a Syrian camp, he says he plans to return to Tajikistan and "bring slaughter".
He voices his disillusionment with the Tajik police and talks about the hardship of thousands of Tajik working migrants in Russia.
Analysis: Khayrullo Fayz, BBC Central Asian Service
Tajikistan has been stable since the end of the civil war which followed independence
The news of a high profile Tajik commander joining IS is bound to have shocked Tajikistan's authoritarian government. YouTube - where Gulmurod Khalimov's video could be seen - was blocked almost immediately. So far no officials have been available for comment.
It's an unprecedented case for Tajikistan.
Khalimov did not belong to the thousands of Muslims in the country routinely targeted by a government intent on fighting what it sees as extremism, but was part of the very security establishment meant to counter such threats.
Many in Tajikistan are puzzled by the speed of his departure; after all he was still working in the country in April. With Central Asian militants now battling Afghan security forces just across the border in Afghanistan, the authorities in Dushanbe will be extremely concerned about the wider implications.
Khalimov's position and profile are significant enough to potentially influence other members of the security forces.
There are no official figures for the number of Tajik citizens fighting alongside Islamic State, but in January sources in the security services were quoted saying they range from 200 to 500.
Central Asian fighters have also formed their own groups such as Sabri Jamaat and Imam Bukhari Jamaat, the BBC's Abdujalil Abdurasulov says.
Many of these militants have reportedly been seen in major battles in Syrian cities, including Aleppo, Kobane and lately in Palmyra.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:37:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cameron and Merkel holding EU talks</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-32925582#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>David Cameron is holding face-to-face talks with German Chancellor Angela Merkel to persuade her to back him over EU reforms.</Description>
        <MainBody>David Cameron and Angela Merkel holding EU reform talks
29 May 2015
From the section UK Politics
David Cameron knows he has to win German support for the changes he wants
David Cameron is holding face-to-face talks with German Chancellor Angela Merkel in Berlin to persuade her to back him over EU reforms.
The PM is on a whistle-stop tour of Europe trying to gather support for changes he wants before holding the UK's EU membership referendum.
He has urged his fellow EU leaders to be "flexible and imaginative".
But one of Germany's most senior businessmen said Europe should refuse to negotiate with him.
Volker Treier, who is deputy chief executive of Germany's chamber of commerce and industry, told the BBC the German business world was "astonished" the UK was holding a referendum at all.
'Carefully thought-out'
Asked how far Ms Merkel should go in accommodating Britain's requests, he said: "Our recommendation is not to deal under such circumstances."
Mr Cameron was greeted upon his arrival in Berlin by Mrs Merkel and the two leaders listened to a military band playing their countries' national anthems.
The UK prime minister, who has already concluded a brief visit to Poland, has not set out in full detail the reforms he is pushing for but they will include tougher rules to prevent migrants claiming benefits.
Berlin is the fourth and final stop of David Cameron's tour of European capitals
David Cameron's first meeting of the day was with Polish Prime Minister Ewa Kopacz
He also wants safeguards to protect the City of London in the event of closer eurozone integration and an exemption for Britain from the EU drive for "ever closer union".
Mr Cameron believes changes to the treaties governing the EU will be needed to get the reforms the UK wants but this has so far been resisted by other European leaders.
Securing the backing of Ms Merkel, who leads Europe's largest economy, will be crucial to his chances of negotiation success.
She has previously said she wanted the UK in a "strong and successful Europe" while stressing the importance of the free movement principle, which has allowed large numbers of economic migrants from poorer EU states to move to countries like the UK and Germany in search of work.
Mr Cameron has met French President Francois Hollande
The prime minister also held talks with his Dutch counterpart, Mark Rutte
After Mr Cameron's breakfast meeting with Polish Prime Minister Ewa Kopacz, Downing Street said the UK and Poland agreed on the need for more powers for national parliaments and for countries outside the eurozone to be treated fairly in the event of closer integration within the single currency bloc.
"On immigration and welfare, Prime Minister Kopacz welcomed the prime minister's commitment to respect the principle of free movement," a No 10 spokesman added.
"They agreed that there were issues concerning the interaction between free movement and national welfare systems that should be discussed further."
Speaking ahead of the visit Rafal Trzaskowski, Poland's Minister for European Affairs, told the BBC they would listen but that any treaty change would be very difficult.
"The European Union needs Great Britain, the discussion will not be easy," he said.
"As far as treaty changes are concerned or the introduction of discriminatory measures, that would be a red line for Poland."
He added: "If every country comes with a shopping list to change European Union policies, that will be the end of the European construction, it will simply implode."
BBC Europe editor Katya Adler said Mr Cameron's four-country tour - taking in the Netherlands and France on Thursday, followed by Poland and Germany on Friday - was "carefully thought-out".
The Netherlands and Germany were seen as "open to reforming the single market", she said, while France was "trickier" and Poland seen as a "rising star".
Ahead of formal negotiations "tone is as important as content", she said, adding: "As he travels around Europe he will find an appetite for reform - but David Cameron's trickiest trick will be to persuade leaders that his way is the right way."
Mr Cameron's tour coincided with the publication of his government's EU Referendum Bill, which contains details of the question and the commitment to staging the vote by the end of 2017.
Downing Street wants voters to be asked the question: "Should the United Kingdom remain a member of the European Union?"
The Electoral Commission suggested this form of words - which would make those campaigning to stay in the EU the Yes campaign - in 2013.
Labour is backing the bill, meaning it is likely to speed through the House of Commons.
EU referendum in focus
David Cameron is starting renegotiation of the terms of Britain's EU membership ahead of a referendum. Here is some further reading on what it all means:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:08:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin makes troop deaths state secret</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32913929#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>President Vladimir Putin declares Russian troop losses in peacetime a state secret as the Kremlin continues to deny sending troops to Ukraine.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin declares Russian troop deaths in peacetime a secret
28 May 2015
From the section Europe
Vladimir Putin attended a military parade to mark Victory Day earlier this month
Russian President Vladimir Putin has signed a decree to make losses of Russian troops in peacetime a secret.
The amendment bans information about the deaths of Russian forces "during special operations" in peacetime.
The Kremlin has consistently denied sending regular troops and armour to help rebels in eastern Ukraine.
But a new report from the US says Russia has been using training camps near the border as "launching points of Russia's war in Ukraine".
The study by the Atlantic Council , published on Thursday, claims to have tracked Russian involvement in the conflict using photographs, videos and satellite images posted online.
President Putin's move to ban information about peacetime military deaths comes amid fears of a fresh offensive by Russian-backed separatists.
Men wearing military uniforms ride atop a troop transporter during exercises at Kuzminsky military training ground in the Rostov region
Reuters reporters said they had observed this week Russia's army massing troops and weaponry - including mobile rocket launchers, tanks and artillery - at a makeshift base in Kuzminsky, near the border with Ukraine.
The news agency said many of the vehicles had number plates and identifying marks removed, while servicemen had taken insignia off their fatigues - similar to some unidentified forces seen in eastern Ukraine.
A ceasefire agreement was signed in Minsk in February, but heavy fighting has continued in some areas since then.
'Secretly buried'
Before the amendment was signed by Mr Putin on Wednesday, the loss of troops was a state secret only in wartime.
The decree gives no details of what is meant by "special operations".
For months there have been reports of secret burials of Russian soldiers killed in Ukraine.
Earlier this month, Russian blogger Ruslan Leviyev said he had found three graves of Russian  officers killed by shelling in eastern Ukraine on 5 May.
Meanwhile the authors of the Atlantic Council report - including British weapons analyst Eliot Higgins - say satellite images have confirmed the movement of Russian troops and camp build-ups along the Ukrainian border.
They say Russian training camps are being used as "the staging ground" for military equipment and soldiers to be transported into Ukraine.
The most recent photograph analysed in the Atlantic Council report was taken in February.
Captured soldiers
The Kremlin has denied Western accusations that its forces are directly involved in combat, insisting that any Russians serving with the rebels are "volunteers".
Russian reporters 'attacked at secret soldier burials'
On Wednesday Russia's ambassador in Ukraine visited two men, who were captured by Kiev and accused of being elite Russian soldiers operating in the Luhansk region.
The Kremlin had demanded access to Aleksandr Aleksandrov and Yevgeny Yerofeyev, complaining that their situation was being exploited as propaganda.
The pair were charged by Kiev with involvement in "terrorist activity", after apparently confirming in video statements that they were active Russian servicemen.
Moscow said they were not serving "at the moment they were detained".
But Ukraine's President Petro Poroshenko told the BBC that the soldiers were proof that his country was engaged in a "real war" with Russia, rather than pro-Russian separatists.
He said Ukrainians should prepare for a Russian offensive in the coming months.
Nato Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg has called for an end to snap exercises by Russia close to the Ukrainian border, and demanded Russia be "more transparent when it comes to their military activities".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:43:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Syria Islamists 'seize Idlib city'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-32924268#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>An Islamist rebel coalition has seized one of the last cities in western Idlib province held by the Syrian government, activists say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syrian Islamist rebels 'seize Ariha in Idlib province'
28 May 2015
From the section Middle East
Fighters from Ahrar al Sham and other Islamist affiliates claimed one of the last government strongholds in Idlib on Thursday
An Islamist coalition that includes Syria's al-Qaeda affiliate al-Nusra Front has taken over one of the last government strongholds in western Idlib province, activists say.
The Jaish al-Fateh, or Conquest Army, took control of the city of Ariha after a "lightning offensive", the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said.
However, the Syrian army said intense fighting was still going on there.
Ariha's fall would leave most of Idlib, bordering Turkey, in rebel hands.
Since late March, rebels have claimed a number of cities in the province, including Idlib and Jisr al-Shughour.
As well as bordering Turkey, Idlib is also next to Latakia province, a government stronghold and President Bashar al-Assad's heartland.
Al-Nusra Front and allied rebel groups took control of the northern city of Idlib in March
Meanwhile, the head of the al-Nusra Front said the group had been ordered by al-Qaeda's overall leader, Ayman al-Zawahiri, not to use Syria to launch attacks on the West.
In an interview with Al Jazeera , Abu Mohammed al-Julani said al-Nusra Front was focused on capturing Damascus and toppling President Assad.
He also promised to protect Syrian minorities that disavowed Mr Assad.
The hour-long interview with Julani, broadcast on Wednesday night, was his second with Qatar-based Al Jazeera since 2013, when al-Nusra Front split from what is now Islamic State (IS).
"We are only here to accomplish one mission, to fight the regime and its agents on the ground, including Hezbollah and others," he stressed, referring to the Lebanese Shia Islamist movement that is fighting alongside government forces."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:45:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Ten killed' by Baghdad car bombs</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-32925959#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>At least 10 people die in twin bomb attacks outside central Baghdad hotels, say Iraqi police</Description>
        <MainBody>'Ten killed' by Baghdad car bombs
28 May 2015
From the section Middle East
At least 30 people were reportedly injured in the blasts
At least 10 people have died after two car bomb attacks outside central Baghdad hotels, say Iraqi police.
The explosions happened just before midnight local time (21:00 GMT). The first hit the Babylon Hotel, near the Tigris river, and the second struck the Ishtar, formerly the Sheraton Hotel.
The Reuters news agency said at least 30 people were injured in the blasts.
A night-time curfew lasting 12 years was lifted in Baghdad in February.
The BBC's Orla Guerin, in Baghdad, tweeted that gunfire was also heard .
Police said they were trying to defuse a third car bomb they found in the Babylon Hotel car park.
The two hotels are regularly busy on Thursday nights and had been renovated in recent years.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:30:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sun reporter sentenced over tip-offs</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-32928540#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A Sun newspaper reporter is given an 18-month suspended prison sentence after being found guilty of receiving story tip-offs from an anti-terror officer.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sun reporter Anthony France sentenced over misconduct
29 May 2015
From the section UK
A Sun reporter has been given an 18-month suspended prison sentence after being found guilty of receiving tip-offs from an anti-terrorism officer.
Anthony France, 41, from Watford, was found guilty of aiding and abetting PC Timothy Edwards to commit misconduct.
He cultivated a "corrupt relationship" with the Heathrow Airport officer over four years, London's Old Bailey heard.
France is the first Sun journalist to be convicted as part of a probe into alleged illegal payments to officials.
The trial heard how PC Edwards had sold 38 stories and tip-offs to France between March 2008 and July 2011 in exchange for more than 22,000.
Judge Timothy Pontius sentenced the reporter to 18 months in prison, suspended for two years, and to 200 hours of community service.
He described him as a journalist of "hitherto unblemished character" who was "essentially a decent man of solid integrity".
Judge Pontius said some of the articles that resulted from payments were "very much in the public interest", including stories about drunken airline pilots and drug smuggling.
However, others were "plainly chosen and published for their obviously salacious subject matter", he added.
Newspaper 'culture'
Payments by France had followed "an accepted procedure that doubtless had existed for some time" at the Sun, the judge said.
Transactions went through an established procedure, he added, saying it was not a case of France handing over a "grubby envelope" in a dark corner of a pub.
"If there was a wrong culture, as clearly the jury found, it is not one of Mr France's making. It was inevitably created by others for their benefit and sustained by others for their benefit," Judge Pontius said.
France - who denied the charge - told jurors he had never been advised by anyone at the Sun that speaking to a police officer or a public official might be against the law.
PC Edwards - who pleaded guilty to misconduct in a public office - was jailed for two years in 2014.
BBC home affairs correspondent June Kelly said a number of journalists from the Sun had been in court to support France during the hearing.
France, a crime reporter, had been prosecuted under Operation Elveden - the Metropolitan Police investigation into alleged inappropriate payments to police and public officials.
His conviction comes after charges against nine journalists accused of making illegal payments to officials were dropped by the Crown Prosecution Service last month.
However, when it announced the decision, the CPS said it was continuing the prosecutions of France, and two other Sun journalists in a separate case.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Fri May 29 05:03:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jail terms under 'legal highs' law</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-32919712#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A new "blanket ban" on so-called legal highs will carry prison sentences of up to seven years, the government says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Legal highs: Seven-year jail terms under 'blanket ban'
29 May 2015
From the section UK Politics
comments
Legal highs can be smoked, snorted or swallowed
A new "blanket ban" on so-called legal highs will carry prison sentences of up to seven years, the government says.
Ministers are to publish draft laws they say are a "landmark" in prohibiting the substances' production, distribution, sale and supply.
Legal highs, officially called new psychoactive substances, have been linked to a number of deaths.
Ministers said young people who took them were "taking exceptional risks with their health".
A blanket ban on legal highs, which are often sold online or on the high street, was in the Conservative Party's election manifesto and featured in the Queen's Speech.
Labour also promised to ban their sale and distribution in its manifesto .
'Fundamental change'
The Psychoactive Substances Bill applied to "any substance intended for human consumption that is capable of producing a psychoactive effect", the government said.
Alcohol, tobacco and caffeine will be excluded, and there are also exemptions for food and medical products, while controlled drugs will continue to be regulated by existing laws.
The new restrictions will also extend to the sale of nitrous oxide - also known as laughing gas or "hippy crack" - for human use.
There is currently no blanket ban on the sale of legal highs, also known as new psychoactive substances
Legal highs are psychoactive drugs that contain various chemical ingredients, some of which are illegal while others are not
They produce similar effects to illegal drugs like cocaine, cannabis and ecstasy
They are sold in a variety of forms, including powder, pills, liquids, capsules, perforated tabs and smoking mixtures
The substances are often sold in "head shops" alongside drug paraphernalia
What are legal highs?
The government said the "legitimate sale" of nitrous oxide, which is also used for food processing, medicinal and industrial purposes, would not be affected.
Home Office minister Mike Penning said the measures would "fundamentally change the way we tackle new psychoactive substances".
'Cat and mouse'
They would end the "game of cat and mouse" whereby new drugs appeared on the market more quickly than the government could identify and ban them, he said.
He added: "The blanket ban will give police and other law enforcement agencies greater powers to tackle the reckless trade in psychoactive substances, instead of having to take a substance-by-substance approach."
Legal highs are not controlled under the Misuse of Drugs Act, although individual substances, such as mephedrone, have been outlawed.
The government's proposals would apply throughout the United Kingdom, and would include powers to seize and destroy legal highs and to search people, premises and vehicles.
Civil measures - including prohibition notices and prohibition orders - will also be possible.
Commander Simon Bray, of the National Police Chiefs' Council, said: "A blanket ban on new psychoactive substances will make it simpler for law enforcement to deal with those drugs which are potentially unsafe but which may not yet be controlled."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Fri May 29 09:41:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Imax to list China unit in Hong Kong</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32926574#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Imax, the Canadian maker of widescreen cinema theatres, is planning an initial public offering (IPO) of its China unit in Hong Kong.</Description>
        <MainBody>Imax to list China unit in Hong Kong
29 May 2015
From the section Business
IMAX plans to list its Chinese subsidiary in Hong Kong
Imax, the Canadian maker of widescreen cinema theatres, is planning an initial public offering (IPO) of its China unit in Hong Kong.
The firm filed an application with the Hong Kong stock exchange on Thursday in a bid to boost growth in one of the world's fastest growing movie markets.
Imax's China profits jumped nearly 30% last year, according to the filing.
It has been rapidly expanding in the Greater China region, nearly doubling the number of theatres since 2012.
March figures indicate Imax has 239 theatres in China, Hong Kong and Taiwan, but the company says it is planning to build another 219 theatres in China.
News of the listing comes as box office revenue in the world's second largest economy jumped 36% last year to $4.9bn (3.2bn), which is nearly three times more than it was 2010.
The parent company is already listed in New York and its shares rose as much as 9% after the announcement.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:35:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>German business warns UK over EU vote</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32925350#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A UK exit from the European Union would be "disastrous" for Britain and Germany warns the German Chambers of Commerce and Industry.</Description>
        <MainBody>German firms warn UK over EU referendum
29 May 2015
From the section Business
Germany's Chambers of Commerce and Industry has warned that a UK exit from the European Union (EU) would be "disastrous" for Britain and Germany.
Volker Treier, deputy chief executive of the organisation, told the BBC that German business is "astonished" that the UK is planning a referendum over its EU membership.
Prime Minister David Cameron is due to meet Angela Merkel in Berlin on Friday.
Mr Treier said the German Chancellor should not offer concessions.
He is concerned that if the UK receives concessions then other nations might also demand negotiations over their terms of membership.
"We are really astonished about this referendum," he said.
The organisation estimates that German companies employ nearly 400,000 people in the UK.
Mr Treier said many of those companies were unsettled by the planned referendum.
If the UK were to leave the EU, he warned that a significant number of German firms would contemplate reducing their investment in Britain.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:31:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>BBC uncovers tax avoidance scheme</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32914372#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Anderson Group, one of the recruitment industry's most high-profile companies, is promoting an "aggressive" tax avoidance scheme which tax experts are calling "abusive".</Description>
        <MainBody>BBC uncovers 'aggressive' tax avoidance scheme
By Zoe Conway Reporter, BBC Radio 4 Today
29 May 2015
From the section Business
HMRC has promised to 'pursue users and promoters' of the tax avoidance scheme
Anderson Group, one of the recruitment industry's most high-profile companies, is promoting an "aggressive" tax avoidance scheme which experts are calling "abusive".
The scheme works by exploiting the government's Employment Allowance.
The scam could deprive the Treasury of tens of millions of pounds of National Insurance payments.
Anderson Group says that all of its services are fully compliant with UK tax laws.
It says it is "totally incorrect" to say that Anderson Group is promoting the scheme and says it is a product being offered by one of its clients.
Anderson Group, which calls itself the UK's "leading provider of support services to the recruitment industry" has hundreds of agencies and thousands of contractors on its books.
The tax avoidance scheme works by exploiting the government's Employment Allowance which was introduced last year.
The allowance enables companies to claim 2,000 off their annual employers' National Insurance bill and was meant to encourage small businesses to take on more workers.
Secret recording
The BBC secretly recorded Anderson Group's sales manager, Ian Moran, promoting the tax avoidance scheme to a recruitment agency.
The agency he was pitching to employs 300 workers, many of whom work in low paid jobs in warehouses or as labourers.
Mr Moran suggested that if the recruitment agency were to set up more than 100 limited companies with a couple of workers in each of them, each company could then claim the 2,000 allowance.
By Mr Moran's calculations the agency's National Insurance bill would then fall from 300,000 a year to zero.
Mr Moran suggested the recruitment agency, which has no intention of using the scheme, might like to spend the 300,000 on Bentleys and ski chalets.
The ''job's a good'un,'' he said.
HMRC losses
Mr Moran told the recruitment agency that 10,000 workers were now being employed through these companies, and the goal was to increase that to 20,000.
If National Insurance was avoided on every worker, HMRC could lose 20m in National Insurance contributions.
At the meeting, Mr Moran admitted that the Employment Allowance was being misused: ''It wasn't intended to be used exactly like this,'' he said.
''Let's be straight, but they set the rules, we'll build a product."
Companies cannot claim the Employment Allowance to avoid tax
'Having a laugh'
Robin Williamson, head of the low incomes tax reform group at the Chartered Institute of Taxation, has called the scheme "highly aggressive" and "abusive".
He says it drives a coach and horse through the legislation: ''To use the colloquial - they are having a laugh."
The Employment Allowance legislation makes it clear that artificially created companies cannot claim the allowance.
The BBC found on the Companies House website more than two thousand limited companies created by those behind the tax avoidance scheme.
"Schemes like this don't work and anyone thinking of using it should think again," Jennie Granger, head of compliance at HMRC told the BBC.
"Failing to disclose an attempted avoidance scheme is punishable by a fine of up to 1m," she added.
HMRC has promised to "pursue users and promoters" of the scheme.
'Empty shells'
Tax expert and financial reform campaigner Richard Murphy thinks the scheme's promoters are banking on the idea that by the time HMRC catch up with them, there'll be no money to recover.
'"What they'll say is: well, there's no money in any of these companies, they're all empty shells, therefore, you can sue us, you can put us in to liquidation, but they'll be nothing for you to have,'' he said.
Mr Murphy believes it's time to consider whether there should be a penalty on the directors of limited companies set up for the purposes of abusing the tax system.
None of the tax experts the BBC spoke to were surprised that this scheme was operating within the recruitment industry.
For years this sector has been dogged by allegations of tax avoidance and exploitation of low paid workers. The Treasury is consulting on ways to clean up the sector's shady practices.
'Ridiculously complex'
Speaking on the Today programme about the UK tax industry, former chair of the Public Accounts Committee Margaret Hodge said: "There are hundreds of people advising on how you could exploit the system, some of them used to worked for the government, and we need to crack down on those advisors.
"We have a ridiculously complex tax scheme with over 1,100 tax relief schemes. I think we should simplify the system.
"In 2010 the government said they'd simplify the tax system, but we ended up with 100 more tax relief schemes than we went in with."
She added that it was worth investing in HMRC because every pound invested in it brought in about 9 in recovered tax.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:33:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hartley to be dropped for World Cup</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/rugby-union/32931690</Link>
        <Description>Hooker Dylan Hartley is set to be dropped from England's World Cup training squad after his latest disciplinary breach.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hartley has won 66 caps for England
29 May 2015 Last updated at 11:33
print
Dylan Hartley set to be dropped from England World Cup squad
Hooker Dylan Hartley is set to be dropped from England's World Cup training squad after his latest disciplinary breach.
The 29-year-old Northampton captain was banned for four weeks on Wednesday for headbutting Saracens' Jamie George.
It would have ruled him out of England's opening World Cup game against Fiji on 18 September.
England head coach Stuart Lancaster will be holding a news conference at 12:30 BST.
The hooker was warned by Lancaster late last year over his disciplinary record, which has seen him banned six times, missing 50 weeks of his career through suspensions for offences ranging from gouging and biting to abusing a referee.
The England coach has already ruled Leicester centre Manu Tuilagi out of the World Cup following his conviction earlier this month for assaulting police officers.
More to follow
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:22:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fifa to vote on Blatter v Prince Ali</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/32925307</Link>
        <Description>The vote to elect Fifa's president takes place on Friday as Prince Ali bin al-Hussein challenges current chief Sepp Blatter.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sepp Blatter: "We can't let Fifa's reputation be dragged through the mud"
29 May 2015 Last updated at 11:22
print
Fifa election: Sepp Blatter and Prince Ali battle for power
Fifa's 209 member associations will decide on Friday whether to give Sepp Blatter a fifth term as president.
World football's governing body continues to reel from "a storm" of damaging corruption allegations.
But the 79-year-old Blatter has already resisted calls to resign and insists he is the man to "fix things".
Blatter, who has been at the helm of Fifa since 1998, is being challenged for the presidency by 39-year-old Jordanian Prince Ali bin al-Hussein.
Speaking before the presidential election in Zurich, Blatter admitted "these are unprecedented and difficult times for Fifa".
Prince Ali will stand against Sepp Blatter, who is seeking a fifth term in office
But he added: "It must fall to me to uphold responsibility for the well-being of the organisation.
"The events of this week unleashed a storm. The important point today is to move ahead - and the important point is transparency. We have a problem to solve."
Fifa has been dogged by scandal but faced a fresh crisis on Wednesday when bribery and racketeering charges were laid against several top officials by authorities in the United States.
A total of 14 people were indicted, with seven senior football officials arrested in dawn raids at a Zurich hotel.
All seven now face extradition to the US.
In a separate development, Swiss officials opened criminal proceedings into the bidding process for the 2018 and 2022 World Cup bid processes.
Blatter condemned the "action of individuals" for bringing "shame and humiliation" on Fifa and football but he said that it was impossible for him to "monitor everyone all of the time".
How does voting work?
Before the voting begins, the candidates will have the opportunity to speak to Fifa members for 15 minutes.
Fifa presidential election explained
Each of Fifa's 209 member associations gets a vote, so the likes of footballing minnows American Samoa have just as much of a say as nations such as England.
It is a paper vote rather than an electronic one, with member associations casting their votes by secret ballot, in alphabetical order.
In the first round, a candidate needs to get two-thirds of the vote to be declared the winner.
If the vote is closer than that, a second round of voting is held, with a simple majority enough to secure victory.
Fifa secretary general Jerome Valcke, assisted by a number of scrutineers, will control the distribution and counting of ballot papers.
Is it possible to abstain?
Yes. Six members did just at the last presidential election in 2011.
One of them was the English Football Association.
It decided to abstain after Blatter's only rival, Mohammed bin Hammam, pulled out days before the election after being suspended over bribery allegations.
Blatter was duly re-elected after receiving 186 of the 203 votes cast.
The last four Fifa presidential elections
2011: Blatter was unopposed because his rival Mohamed Bin Hammam, president of the Asian Football Federation, pulled out after being suspended over bribery allegations.
2007: No other candidate was put forward to challenge Blatter.
2002: Blatter saw off the challenge of Issa Hayatou, president of the African confederation Caf.
1998: The Swiss succeeded Joao Havelange and won a bitter election against former Uefa president Lennart Johansson.
Weren't there other candidates for 2015 vote?
Blatter faced three candidates but two withdrew last week.
Former Portugal midfielder Luis Figo, 42, and Royal Dutch Football Association president Michael van Praag, 67, pulled out of the running because they did not want to split the anti-Blatter vote.
Former Tottenham and Newcastle midfielder David Ginola, backed by a betting company, had intended to stand but failed to secure the necessary backing of five football associations.
The same fate befell Ginola's French compatriot, former Fifa executive Jerome Champagne, who left the organisation in 2011.
Who is Prince Ali?
The son of the late King Hussein and Queen Alia, he attended Sandhurst military academy in England before joining his country's armed forces.
Prince Ali of Jordan: The man taking on Sepp Blatter
He is Fifa's youngest vice-president and the youngest member of the Fifa executive committee.
In his manifesto, he talks about protecting the integrity of the game and championing human and labour rights.
He was one of a number of officials who called on Fifa to publish of the report into allegations of corruption surrounding the 2018 and 2022 World Cup bids.
He also successfully championed the lifting of Fifa's ban on the hijab - the veil worn by Muslims - in women's football.
Prince Ali is also the brother-in-law of leading racehorse owner Sheikh Mohammed, the ruler of Dubai.
How will the election unfold?
Blatter has been publicly backed by the football confederations of Asia (AFC) and Africa (Caf), which means that most of their member nations are expected to vote for him.
Prince Ali is the favoured candidate of European confederation Uefa, so he is likely to pick up most of the European votes. Platini believes "45 or 46" from 54 European members could back him.
It is not quite so clear where the votes from the North American (Concacaf) and South American (Conmebol) confederations will go.
These regions have been loyal to Blatter but there are suggestions that at least some of their member nations will back Prince Ali.
Prince Ali himself is said to believe he has the support of 60 nations outside Europe, but bookmakers currently make Blatter the 1/2 favourite.
So why is Blatter so popular?
Blatter's Fifa gave Africa its first ever World Cup with South Africa 2010, as well as a debut Asia tournament in Japan-South Korea in 2002.
Asia has publicly stated its support for the Swiss, while Nigerian Football Federation president Amaju Pinnick believes "a minimum of 50 votes" of Africa's 54 votes are also Blatter's.
It is not just major tournaments that have maintained Blatter's popularity in the two largest voting blocks.
Pinnick cites developmental programmes, coaching and facilities as further reasons that a Blatter victory would be "good for football".
"What Blatter preaches is equality and fairness among the various nations," said Pinnick. "Even if it is the smallest or biggest nation. We don't want to experiment. We don't want any new face."
What happens if Blatter wins?
The BBC has learned that Uefa could call for an extraordinary general meeting of Fifa's congress if Blatter is victorious.
If 20% of members agree with the motion, the meeting would have to take place within three months.
A motion of no confidence would almost certainly be put forward.
There are even suggestions Uefa might decide to boycott Fifa in future, or some of its tournaments such as the World Cup.
"All of these things have been discussed," Scottish Football Association chief Stewart Regan told BBC Scotland.
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:48:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Liverpool 10m Clyne bid rejected</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/32926238</Link>
        <Description>Liverpool have a 10m bid for England right-back Nathaniel Clyne, 24, rejected by Southampton.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nathaniel Clyne: Liverpool 10m bid rejected by Southampton
By Phil McNulty Chief football writer
Liverpool have had a 10m bid for England right-back Nathaniel Clyne rejected by Southampton.
Clyne, 24, has become a target for the Reds with full-back Glen Johnson, 30, at the end of his Anfield contract.
They are expected to return with an improved offer for the former Crystal Palace player, who has one year left on his contract at St Mary's.
Liverpool are also pursuing Burnley striker Danny Ings and Manchester City midfielder James Milner.
The Anfield club are attempting to rebuild following a disappointing season under manager Brendan Rodgers, in which they finished sixth in the Premier league - two points above Southampton in seventh place - and failed to win a trophy.
Clyne joined the Saints from Palace in July 2012 and is under contract until the summer of 2016.
Liverpool took Adam Lallana, Dejan Lovren and Rickie Lambert from Southampton last summer for a combined total of almost 50m.
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Fri May 29 10:30:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Neverland ranch goes up for sale</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-32927199#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Michael Jackson's Neverland ranch has gone up for sale for $100m, according to reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Michael Jackson's Neverland ranch up for sale
29 May 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Michael Jackson's Neverland ranch has gone up for sale with a price tag of $100m (65m), reports the Wall Street Journal.
The Santa Barbara development was once home to a zoo, an amusement park and its own fire station.
Much of this has gone but there is still a floral clock and a railway.
Jackson bought the house in 1987 for $19.5m but struggled to pay for it, until an investment company stepped in to help him save it from auction.
The property is now called Sycamore Valley Ranch and has undergone extensive redevelopment since Jackson's death in 2009.
Michael Jackson built a zoo and an amusement park in the grounds of Neverland
The 2,800 acre (1,100 hectare) site, at 5225 Figueroa Mountain Road, is now being sold jointly by Sotheby's and Hilton &amp; Hyland.
The estate agents have warned off fans hoping to get a glimpse inside the piece of Jackson history, telling the Wall Street Journal anyone wanting to view the property would be subject to "extensive prequalification".
"We're not going to be giving tours," said Suzanne Perkins of Sotheby's International Realty.
Jackson bought Neverland in 1987 intending to create a fantasy land for children, and moved in the following year.
It was named after an island in the story Peter Pan, where children never grow up.
After he bought it, Jackson built a zoo and fairground but it was closed to the public in 2006 after he failed to pay his staff or maintain proper insurance.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:26:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Moroder working on disco stage musical</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-32914823#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Musician and composer Giorgio Moroder is working on a new disco-themed stage musical, he tells the BBC.</Description>
        <MainBody>Giorgio Moroder working on disco stage musical
29 May 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Moroder is a pioneer of synth disco and electronic dance music
Musician and composer Giorgio Moroder has revealed he is working on a new disco-themed stage musical.
The project "is in the style of disco, using about five of my songs and some new ones," he told Radio 4's Front Row.
"I don't know the story yet. My friend Harald Kloser, a great producer who is currently doing Independence Day 2, is really an expert in writing scripts, directing and music.
"I think he's coming up with a great idea," he added.
Moroder, one of the forefathers of electronic dance music, produced huge hits for Donna Summer during the late-1970s disco era, including I Feel Love and Love to Love You Baby.
He has since collaborated with dozens of artists including David Bowie, Kylie Minogue and Daft Punk.
The 75-year-old has also won three Oscars, including one for best original score for Midnight Express.
He told Front Row presenter John Wilson that he was choosing which of his many hits to use on the production.
"Definitely Call Me (recorded by Blondie in 1980 ) but Flashdance is too typical. Maybe Take My Breath Away (from the film Top Gun)."
Moroder said there were no plans to debut the jukebox-style musical in a Broadway theatre.
"The idea is to have it in the smaller theatres in America," he explained. "The company which is investing has thousands of smaller theatres. Maybe someday we would head for Broadway but [it will be] smaller for now."
With no title or storyline, it is too early to discuss casting but Moroder insisted "we're not going to have big stars".
"We are going to use the original singers and tracks. This is all pre-recorded. Even the new songs we do will be pre-recorded. The show is more like the story behind them."
You can hear the full interview on BBC Radio 4's Front Row on Monday 1 June.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:11:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eavis had 'death threats' over Kanye</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-32929196#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Glastonbury organiser Emily Eavis says she received death threats after booking rapper Kanye West to headline the festival.</Description>
        <MainBody>Glastonbury: Emily Eavis had death threats after booking Kanye West
29 May 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Kanye West has recently recorded several songs with Paul McCartney
Emily Eavis says she received death threats after booking Kanye West to headline Glastonbury.
The rapper, whose hits include Stronger and Gold Digger, is set to play the Pyramid Stage on Saturday, 27 June.
For us getting the biggest star in the world was an amazing coup
Emily Eavis
More than 130,000 people have signed a petition protesting his appearance - seven years after Jay-Z became the first rapper to headline the festival.
"It was not a pleasant world we unwrapped," Eavis told the Times. "I had death threats and stuff."
She added: "It was horrible. It was just crazy."
Michael Eavis, 79, plans to hand the reins over to Emily in the next few years
Eavis, who organises the festival with her father Michael, said she had become accustomed to her decisions being criticised - with fans expressing outrage when Metallica and The Rolling Stones were booked for the event in 2014 and 2013.
But the scrutiny surrounding West's booking was unprecedented.
"It was getting out of control. We had Time magazine, all the American news channels saying they were going to come down. This incredible onslaught worldwide.
"It was quite upsetting because we were talking about something that was so exciting and interesting and fresh and brilliant for the festival.
"Kanye West is making the most exciting music at the moment. He is an amazing force as a performer. For us getting the biggest star in the world was an amazing coup."
Eavis, who oversees the line-up of the annual music festival, acknowledged that the pressure sometimes got to her.
"The scrutiny is daily. Whatever we do is torn apart and analysed. It's hard to concentrate on the job because you can get easily distracted by the hoo-ha," she said.
This year's festival opens its doors on 24 June. The other headliners are Foo Fighters and The Who, while Florence + The Machine, Pharrell Williams, Alt-J, George Clinton, Jamie T and Motorhead are also on the diverse bill.
The BBC is to broadcast more than 30 hours of coverage from the event and, for the first time, all of its online streams will be presented in full HD.
A live webcam from Somerset's Worthy Farm site is helping count down the final four weeks before the music starts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:31:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: 'Fifa can't be dragged through mud'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32927118#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Sepp Blatter has given his statement to delegates in a bid to win a fifth term as Fifa president.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Blatter: 'Fifa's reputation can't be dragged through mud'
29 May 2015 Last updated at 10:31 BST
Members of football's world governing body Fifa are voting for their new president at a congress in Zurich.
The vote comes two days after seven top officials were held in Zurich in a US fraud inquiry that indicted 14 people.
At the conference, Sepp Blatter told delegates the reputation of football and Fifa "couldn't be dragged through the mud".
He also said while he accepted that responsibility for Fifa rested with the president, it should also be shared.
He is being challenged for the presidency by Prince Ali bin al-Hussein of Jordan.
Read more
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Fri May 29 07:44:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: On the ground with Libyan forces</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32926184#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The BBC has been given rare access to the army that is allied to the internationally recognised government in Libya.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Counter revolution under way in Libya
29 May 2015 Last updated at 05:44 BST
Fighting between the forces loyal to the two rival Libyan governments is continuing on the outskirts of Tripoli.
The BBC has been given rare access to the army that is allied to the internationally recognised government.
It is attempting to surround the capital - which is held by militias from the Libya Dawn movement.
The BBC Arabic's Feras Kilani has this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:45:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Migrants find refuge in Aceh shelter</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32926507#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>More than 1,800 Muslim migrants from Myanmar and Bangladesh are sheltered in the Indonesian province of Aceh.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Migrants find refuge in Aceh shelter
29 May 2015 Last updated at 09:45 BST
More than 1,800 Muslim migrants from Myanmar and Bangladesh are sheltered in the Indonesian province of Aceh.
Indonesia has agreed to let them stay for one year, with international help, and has demanded the international community to help resettle them in other countries.
Alice Budisatrijo reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:00:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Balloons take tech war to North Korea</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-32921210#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>BBC Click's Dave Lee meets the activists sending anti-North Korean material into the country by balloon</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Balloons take tech war to North Korea
29 May 2015 Last updated at 00:00 BST
Some anti-North Korean activists firmly believe the best way to defeat Kim Jong-un's regime is to break the cycle of propaganda served up every day to those living north of the border.
In recent years balloons have been used to carry leaflets from the south criticising the regime in the north.
Balloons are now being packed with technology including memory sticks and DVDs. The media contains South Korean soap operas and a cut-down version of The Interview, the controversial Seth Rogen film described by Pyongyang as an "act of war".
BBC Click's Dave Lee met some of the activists and joined them for a night-time balloon launch.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:18:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Soweto fashion takes to the catwalk</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32925735#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Self taught designer Collen Monnakgotla speaks to the BBC about his fashion show.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Designer Collen Monnakgotla prepares for Soweto Fashion Week
29 May 2015 Last updated at 00:18 BST
The South African township of Soweto is currently hosting its own fashion week.
The three-day event is a platform for upcoming, often struggling, designers to showcase their work to boutique owners and potential investors.
Among those whose designs are gracing the catwalk this year is self-taught designer Collen Monnakgotla, who runs his own company, Freshwear.
The BBC caught up with him as he put the finishing touches to his range.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:07:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Volcano bursts into life in Japan</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32927111#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Dramatic footage has emerged of a volcano erupting on the Japanese island of Kuchinoerabu.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Footage of Japanese volcano eruption caught on film
29 May 2015 Last updated at 09:07 BST
Dramatic footage has emerged from Japan where a volcanic eruption was captured on film.
The volcano erupted suddenly on Kuchinoerabu Island, forcing the 137 islanders to be evacuated.
Experts say the plume of smoke reached as high as 9,000 metres.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:46:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Lighting the sun 10 billion times</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-32918431#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Scottish scientists are working at Diamond, the UK's synchrotron light source, with light that is 10 billion times brighter than the sun.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Inside the UK's biggest synchrotron light source
28 May 2015 Last updated at 17:46 BST
Scottish scientists at Diamond Light Source, the UK's national synchrotron facility, are working with light that is 10 billion times brighter than the sun.
Their work is illuminating everything from cells in the human body to aircraft components.
The facility near Didcot, Oxfordshire, uses much research from universities in Scotland.
BBC Scotland's science correspondent Kenneth Macdonald takes a closer look.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:37:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Face transplant man meets donor's sister</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-32926678#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A woman whose brother was killed in a car accident has met the man who was given his face, in a pioneering transplant operation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Face transplant patient meets donor's sister
29 May 2015 Last updated at 10:37 BST
A woman whose brother was killed in a car accident has met the man who was given his face, in a pioneering transplant operation.
Footage from Channel 9's 60 Minutes Australia shows the moment that Rebekah Aversano sees - and touches - the face of her dead brother on another person for the first time following the operation.
The recipient, Richard Norris from Australia, was injured in a shotgun incident 15 years ago.
James Partridge, the founder and chief executive of Changing Faces - a charity which supports people with facial disfigurements - told the BBC he did not know of a case where the family of the donor has met the person who has received the face.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:02:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Fifa makes and spends its money</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32923882#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>How football's ruling body makes and spends its cash</Description>
        <MainBody>How Fifa makes and spends its money
By Paul Sargeant BBC News
29 May 2015
From the section Europe
Fifa, football's governing body, is being investigated by US and Swiss authorities over claims of corruption. Fourteen people, including senior officials, are accused of accepting bribes and kickbacks estimated at more than $150m (97m) over a 24-year period.
How does the Zurich-based multi-million-pound organisation make its money and what does it spend it on?
The US-led part of the twin investigations is looking at corruption among members of the Concacaf and Conmebol, the confederations that represent national associations across the Americas and the Caribbean.
During the four-year period of the last World Cup, each national association received at least $2m (1.3m) from Fifa and continental federations received $17.5m (11.4m). So the total received by all organisations on the American continent between 2011 and 2014 was around $137m.
Meanwhile, the Swiss investigation centres on the bidding process for the 2018 and 2022 World Cups, to be held in Russia and Qatar respectively.
Any uncertainty around the World Cup is a major concern to the organisation. Fifa's own financial reports give a clear indication of how reliant the organisation is on the income each tournament generates.
Making money from the World Cup
The World Cup is the most lucrative sporting event in the world, eclipsing even the Olympics. The 2014 qualifying rounds and final tournament brought in $4.8bn (3.1bn) over four years and, after costs are taken into account, Fifa made a profit of more than $2bn.
Profit from the 2014 World Cup
That $4.8bn in revenue for the 2014 World Cup can be broken down into five key sections:
How much money does Fifa hold on to?
Fifa re-invests the majority of its revenue but it does hold on to a proportion of any profit to create a cash reserve. Fifa says that the reserve is important as it is extremely difficult to find insurance to cover the possible last-minute cancellation of a World Cup.
The value of this reserve has grown sharply in the last decade from $350m (228.6m) in 2005 to more than $1.5bn (1bn) in 2014.
The US indictment alleges over $150m (97m) in corruption during a period of over 20 years. That currently equates to around 10% of the money Fifa has on hand for emergencies.
Design by Salim Qurashi and Gerry Fletcher
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:03:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Are more people on the move?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-32912867#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Are more people on the move than ever before?</Description>
        <MainBody>Migration: Are more people on the move than ever before?
By Paul Adams BBC News
28 May 2015
From the section World
From the Mediterranean to the Andaman, it's been a season of despair, the faces of migrants haunting television screens and dominating headlines.
Harrowing stories have emerged of death, starvation and abuse at the hands of people smugglers. And from the world's new and continuing conflict zones, there have been new mass movements, across borders and within states.
Half a million Yemenis have been internally displaced since March. One hundred thousand Burundians have fled into neighbouring countries since April.
The statistics can be numbing - 7.6 million Syrians, homeless inside their own country, now make up a fifth of all internally displaced people (IDPs) in the world.
Are more people on the move than ever before?
Today's map of the world is a complex spider's web of movement. Our map only represents the larger recent trends.
But it helps to explain why, in 2013, there were 232 million "international migrants" in the world (defined by the UN as people who have lived a year or longer outside their country of birth).
This figure includes refugees, asylum seekers and economic migrants - anyone who has crossed a border, legally or illegally, to escape disaster or persecution or simply to pursue a better life.
And it's almost certainly an under-estimate.
Where do international migrants live?
Half of all international migrants live in just 10 countries. The largest number (46 million) reside in the United States. By 2013, the US was host to 13 million people born in Mexico, but the fastest growth was among recent arrivals from China (2.2m) and India (2.1m).
Russia's second place is a result of Moscow's strong ties to former states of the Soviet Union, particularly Ukraine and Kazakhstan.
In Europe, Germany and France host some of the largest migrant populations (from Turkey and Algeria respectively), while vast numbers of migrant workers from southern Asia still live and work in Saudi Arabia and the Gulf.
In the UAE, international migrants make up a staggering 84% of the population.
Deadly crisis in the Mediterranean
Dramatic scenes from the Mediterranean have captured headlines for the past two years.
Before the fall of the Libyan dictator, Muammar Gaddafi, numbers of migrants making the perilous crossing were actually declining.
Oil-rich Libya offered employment opportunities and Gaddafi was persuaded by the EU to limit onward movement.
But the year of his violent ouster, 2011, saw a sudden spike, and Libya's descent into chaos since 2012 has had a dramatic effect.
In 2014, more than 170,000 migrants arrived in Italy, the largest influx into one country in EU history.
Perilous routes through Africa to Europe
The spider's web is at its most complex here. Some of these journeys are epic, with sub-Saharan and West African migrants crossing two perilous seas, one of sand and one of water, before arriving in Europe.
These journeys can take weeks or years to complete, with young men from Gambia, Senegal and Nigeria passing through several countries and relying heavily on people smugglers.
Among the largest groups crossing from Libya this year: thousands of Eritreans fleeing long-term conscription, as well as large numbers of Somalis and Nigerians.
In the eastern Mediterranean, huge numbers of Syrians cross from Turkey to Greece, accompanied by Afghans and Iraqis.
Syria: A displaced nation
Syria's civil war has now uprooted half the country's pre-war population. More than four million Syrians are refugees in neighbouring countries, with a much larger number internally displaced.
Syria is the main country of origin of asylum seekers in the industrialised world. This huge, growing exodus is one big reason why the number of forcibly displaced people in the world is now higher than it's been at any time since World War Two.
It also helps to explain why, when it comes to housing refugees, the burden falls more and more heavily on developing countries (86%, up from 70% a decade ago).
In the hands of people smugglers
Graphic scenes of the suffering experienced by refugees afloat in the Andaman Sea have drawn international attention to another desperate story of people smuggling and human deprivation.
The numbers are smaller than the Mediterranean, but the issues are similar.
Friday's meeting in Bangkok will attempt to grapple with this latest migrant crisis, but hopes are not high for any kind of action plan.
Journeys north through Mexico
The Mexico-Texas border remains the world's largest migration corridor. Mexicans are still the largest single group apprehended by US border officials but last year, for the first time, they were outnumbered by the combined total of other Central Americans.
Mexican migration has dropped, thanks to Mexico's improved economic circumstances, but worsening security situations have prompted large numbers of Hondurans, Salvadoreans and Guatemalans to journey north along a series of well-travelled routes.
The recent arrivals have included tens of thousands of unaccompanied children.
Growing global population
The share of international migrants in the world population has remained constant in recent years, hovering around 3%.
But as the world's population expands rapidly, so too does the raw number of people living outside their place of birth.
There are even more internal migrants: the figure of 740m is almost certainly a conservative estimate. It's hard to keep track of the millions of Chinese peasants who continue to converge on urban centres every year.
Thousands of people are forced from their homes each year by natural disasters, this woman is in a makeshift camp after the recent earthquake in Nepal
And the numbers of internal migrants fluctuate wildly: it's thought half a million Iraqis were displaced in a matter of weeks in June 2014.
Then there are natural disasters, which displace an average of more than 27m people every year.
Global migration fuels political debate, tests alliances and resources and keeps legions of statisticians very busy.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:13:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Great Barrier Reef status at risk</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-australia-32911084#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Australia holds its breath as Unesco decides status</Description>
        <MainBody>Unesco reconsidering Great Barrier Reef heritage status
By Saffron Howden Sydney, Australia
29 May 2015
comments
The world's largest coral reef system is the blessed with breathtaking beauty
Australia faces a dent to its reputation and a potentially devastating blow to its tourism industry should one of the country's most iconic natural wonders, the Great Barrier Reef, be listed as "in danger" by the United Nations.
Tony Fontes loves diving the waters around Queensland's Whitsunday Islands.
In a career spanning three decades, the diving operator has introduced countless others to the magical underworld that is the Great Barrier Reef.
But he has also watched its decline.
Divers like Tony Fontes have witnessed a noticeable decline in the reef's health
The waters are now milkier and the coral quality poorer. Increasing attacks by crown-of-thorns starfish have left swathes of reef brown and lifeless.
"There'll always be reef but it's not what it once was," he told the BBC.
Like many others, he is waiting to hear if the reef - which gained World Heritage status in 1981 - will be listed as "in danger" by UN cultural agency Unesco.
The reef is one of more than 1,000 sites on Unesco's World Heritage List considered to be of such outstanding value that the world has an obligation to look after them.
Danger point
Unesco believes the Australian site is worth saving because it contains the world's largest collection of coral reefs, along with 1,500 species of fish and 4,000 types of molluscs.
But it is worried that threats to the reef's health - from overdevelopment, pollution and climate change - have reached a dangerous point.
The reef system has lost 50% of its coral in the past 30 years.
* The Great Barrier Reef  includes 3,000 coral reefs and 600 islands
* It is the world's largest marine park
* It receives about two million tourists each year.
* The region contributes A$6bn ($4.6bn; 3bn) a year to the Australian economy
In pictures: Great Barrier Reef
Late on Friday, Unesco will receive a draft recommendation about whether to place the reef on its "in danger" list.  A final decision will be made at a Unesco World Heritage Committee meeting in Germany in late June.
Few expect the international body to take this step - in part because of a flurry of activity by the Australian and Queensland governments to tighten development regulations along the Queensland coast, as well as heavy diplomatic lobbying by the Federal government.
An "in danger" listing would prove problematic for plans to open more coal mines in Queensland and proposals for more coal ports along its coast.
But environmentalists and scientists remain concerned about the reef's long-term fate.
Damage to tourism
Climate change, pollution, coastal development, fishing and dredging for shipping channels have wrought significant damage on the 348,000-sq km World Heritage Site, which stretches from the tip of Queensland to the city of Bundaberg.
There is no question the reef is in danger, says World Wildlife Fund Australia (WWF) marine programme manager, Richard Leck.
"If we'd lost 50% of the Taj Mahal, we wouldn't even question whether it was in danger," he told the BBC, referring to the loss of coral cover.
Coral bleaching, invasive starfish and pollution are damaging the reef system
But WWF does not want the reef's heritage status changed.
"We know the impact that will have on Australia's international standing," says Mr Leck.
He says it would deliver a heavy blow to tourism and the coastal communities who rely on it.
Government promises
Submissions to a 2014 Australian parliamentary inquiry into the reef back that view.
As the Whitsunday Charter Boat Industry Association explained: "It has taken a long time to build the brand that is the World Heritage Great Barrier Reef, and making the wrong decision could ruin that reputation."
State and federal governments have taken note of Unesco's scrutiny.
The Queensland government has pledged to forbid new dredge spoil - the sand, silt and rock dug out of the sea floor to create deeper ports - from being dumped in reef waters or on nearby wetlands.
There are also government plans to reduce pollution from fertilisers and pesticides used in coastal farming.
The Abbot Point port near the Reef will service a giant new coal mine in Queensland
Just this week, the Queensland Government announced it would introduce laws limiting port development adjacent to the reef.
The federal government is so worried about a potential listing that officials from its Environment Department have spent A$100,000 travelling overseas to lobby World Heritage Committee members.
Officials have visited 19 of the 21 member countries of the World Heritage Committee in recent months in a bid to avoid a highly embarrassing "in danger" listing.
A spokesperson for Federal Environment Minister Greg Hunt  told the BBC the government makes "absolutely no apology" for defending the reef's reputation.
The government says also that more than A$2bn will be spent on the reef over the next decade.
"This is a significant investment and it's on top of the A$2.6bn we're spending to tackle climate change - one of the major long term threats to the reef," said the spokesperson.
Fish kills
Still, concerns remain that the flurry of government reports, plans and promises generated over the past few years will not be enough if the watchful eye of Unesco moves on.
Some Australians are concerned about the expansion of coal ports near the Reef
And a lot of damage has already been done.
A 2012 study by the Australian Institute of Marine Sciences found the reef had lost half of its coral cover in less than 30 years.
A year before, there were reports of large-scale disease among fish and crabs in Gladstone harbour, one of the four major ports inside the world heritage area.
Simon Whittingham, from Gladstone Fish Markets, told the 2014 parliamentary committee that turtles, dolphins and dugongs were washing up dead.
Dugong habitats are at risk from overdevelopment and boat traffic, among other things
"Fish kills were occurring throughout the harbour. Something was terribly wrong," he said.
But as politicians, scientists, and conservationists debate the reef's future and Australia awaits the World Heritage Committee's decision, the reef itself continues to quietly divulge its secrets.
Three years ago, the Catlin Seaview Survey photographed a large crop of coral 125m under water that had never been seen before.
"We don't even know when the deeper reef formed," survey executive director Richard Vevers says.
"There's a lot of the Great Barrier Reef that has never been explored," he adds.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Fri May 29 05:54:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Handing over the reins of power in Nigeria</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32924530#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Muhammadu Buhari prepares to take on Nigerian presidency</Description>
        <MainBody>Handing over the reins of power in Nigeria
By Will Ross BBC News, Abuja
29 May 2015
From the section Africa
They may not have been slapping each other's backs and smiling ear-to-ear but as Goodluck Jonathan welcomed the man who defeated him in the election, he did give Muhammadu Buhari a sneak preview of the presidential villa and presented him with a box containing the outgoing president's handover notes.
"Since that famous telephone call you made, you have changed the course of Nigeria's political history," Muhammadu Buhari said.
He was referring to the moment President Jonathan conceded victory and put paid to the daunting prospect of a disputed and probably violent aftermath to the election.
It was the first time ever in Nigeria's history that an opposition politician had won an election and both men were ready for the historic transition.
'Not paid'
Many Nigerians have huge expectations of their next head of state, but one man who has worked for three different presidents including the former military ruler Sani Abacha says Muhammadu Buhari needs to be aware that it is easy to get cut off from reality once ensconced in "The Villa".
Nigerians have huge expectations of Mr Buhari, the first opposition presidential candidate to win an election
"As cocooned as Abacha was, I remember he was very fond of talking to the gardener. He would ask him 'Danzaria, what is happening in town?'" former minister Dr Aliyu Modibbo Umar told the BBC.
"'Today there are a lot of queues at the fuel stations', Danzaria would say or 'We have not been paid our salary'," said Dr Modibbo recalling the early 1990s when he was a special advisor in the presidency.
"If you are taciturn like some of the heads of state it is very easy to be in a cocoon and to only listen to a few people," Dr Modibbo said, adding that another President, Olusegun Obasanjo, was one of the few former heads of state to have kept his finger on the pulse of the country.
He put this down to his exuberant and outgoing nature.
'Cocooned'
As well as working as a minister under President Obasanjo, Dr Modibbo was also in Umaru Musa Yar'Adua's government.  He believes that like Mr Yar'Adua, Goodluck Jonathan had also allowed himself to become isolated with just a few officials around him.
Former minister Dr Aliyu Modibbo Umar (left) has worked with numerous presidents including Sani Abacha (right) during the 1990s
A huge weight of expectation will rest on the new president's shoulders
"How could you come out and not believe the Chibok girls had been kidnapped if you were not cocooned?" he said, referring to the fact that the president and his ministers were at first reluctant to admit that more than 200 schoolgirls had been seized by jihadists in April 2014.  The 219 girls are still missing.
Corruption issues
Some analysts suggest Goodluck Jonathan may be slightly relieved to be handing over, given the challenges facing the country.
The fact that Muhammadu Buhari has been head of state before may alert him to some of the dangers he is likely to face but he will be in no doubt as to how difficult it will be to deliver the changes so many Nigerians are craving.
Even on his way to the inauguration he is likely to see the fuel queues snaking for kilometres across Abuja - the latest sign that oil production and fuel importation are in need of a major overhaul.
As well as tackling jihadist extremism and helping create jobs, fighting corruption is the loudest call on the streets.
Numerous world leaders have arrived in Nigeria for Friday's inauguration
General Abacha keep in touch by speaking to his gardener
But will the new administration go after corrupt individuals in the outgoing government? This is a key factor which could affect Nigeria's stability after the handover.
At a newspaper stand in Abuja the headlines have prompted some fierce debate with arguments over whether all former governments should be investigated, or just Mr Jonathan's, or none at all.
"Jonathan urges Buhari not to be selective with probes," says This Day newspaper.
"Don't probe me alone - Jonathan tells Buhari," is the front page of the Daily Trust.
"It is good if he investigates the previous government because any money that he recovers from them he can use on the infrastructure like roads, electricity and so on," says one reader, James Isaac, as he scans the headlines.
But others are not so sure.
"If we say he should start investigating all the previous leaders, his whole tenure will finish before he settles down to work on Nigeria's issues," says another man joining the debate.
Muhammadu Buhari in focus:
Gen Buhari has finally got a kiss of approval from voters
Age 72
First opposition candidate to win a president election
Military ruler of Nigeria from 1984 to 1985
Deposed in a coup
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:46:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How gang violence is spreading fear in El Salvador</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-32913749#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Gang violence on the rise again in El Salvador</Description>
        <MainBody>How gang violence is spreading fear in El Salvador
By Katy Watson BBC News, San Salvador
29 May 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
All of the skeletons at San Salvador's Institute of Legal Medicine belong to victims of violence
Dr Oscar Quijano picks up a bone and excitedly explains how, just by looking at its texture, he knows how old the person was when they died.
Every day, he says, is a learning curve.
The forensic anthropology department of San Salvador's Institute of Legal Medicine feels like a history museum.
Laid out neatly on the tables are skeletons, each bone labelled and placed in position.
But these bones I am being shown do not tell me about El Salvador's history - they tell me more about what is happening right now.
Violent deaths
Some of these skeletons are no more than a year old.
Dr Quijano says the bones are either handed in after people stumble across them, or they are given to police by criminal gangs as part of a sort of plea bargain.
Each one of them belongs to someone who died in a violent manner.
One skull had to be carefully pieced together because the victim had her face smashed in.
Another skull has several bullet holes.
Many of the skulls bear bullet holes
Dr Quijano takes me to one table and picks up some vertebrae, pointing out that this victim was dismembered - most probably alive.
"Each different group or clique kills people in a different way," he tells me.
"Dismembering or strangling. Or a blow to the head. They all have their own execution style."
Crumbling truce
Dr Quijano says his team is struggling under all the work they are being given.
Many bodies are still awaiting identification in the morgue in San Salvador
In recent months, more and more bones have been brought to him to investigate.
El Salvador is on track to become one of the most violent countries in the world, and much of that violence is down to the country's biggest gangs.
The Mara Salvatrucha and the 18th Street Gang both trace their origins to Los Angeles, where they were founded by Central American immigrants.
Gang graffiti shows who controls the neighbourhood
After many of their members were deported back to their home countries, they now control entire neighbourhoods in El Salvador.
In 2012, El Salvador's main gangs agreed a truce which initially reduced murder rates by 40%.
But the truce has all but crumbled and killings have now soared.
March was the deadliest month in a decade and there has been little let-up since.
'Hard life'
The family of Pedro Valladares Martinez knows this too well.
Pedro Valladares Martinez (in the picture) was killed while working as a bus driver
Last month, the father of five was at work as a bus driver when he was shot in the head.
Just a few days earlier, Mr Valladares had told his wife Margarita that his job was getting too dangerous.
He said he wanted to find something else.
"He came home at eight in the evening, he had dinner and watched a bit of sport on the TV," she tells me.
"When it finished, he called our five children over and said please behave, we live in such a violent place, even just looking at somebody you can get into trouble you might not think it, but life is hard."
'No truce'
Critics say that the truce only served to expand the power of the gangs.
President Salvador Sanchez Ceren, who took office in June, has not recognised the truce and is opposed to negotiations with gang members as a way of tackling crime.
President Sanchez Ceren has ruled out negotiating with the gangs
But with homicide rates on the rise, many Salvadoreans fear the country may be facing another civil war.
They argue that gang warfare has replaced the guerrilla warfare and death squads which wracked the country from 1980 to 1992, when Marxist rebels of the Farabundo Marti National Liberation Front (FMLN) fought the government.
"Today, the problem El Salvador is facing is no longer an issue that's just between gangs," explains Raul Mijango, a former FMLN leader who helped broker the truce between the gangs three years ago.
Raul Mijango helped negotiate the truce between the gangs
"Now, what you have is a problem between gangs and the state."
With 70,000 active members and more than four times as many people in some way connected to or dependent on the gangs, this is not a problem the government can ignore, he argues.
"Around 11% of Salvadoreans are involved in the violence that this country faces, so you can't try and resolve a problem of this size just through clamping down on them."
Failed strategy
Police are increasingly becoming the target of attacks.
An anti-gang police force has been created, but murder rates have not gone down
A new anti-gang force has been created but so far it has not been able to reverse the upward trend of homicides.
So is a new truce the answer?
Deputy National Police Commissioner Howard Augusto Cotto says the iron-fist tactic has not worked in El Salvador, but negotiating with gangs is "a difficult subject".
"It's a strategy that cannot provide results," he argues.
Mr Cotto argues that negotiations with groups that have an ideology or a political vision have been successful.
Deputy Police Commissioner Howard Augusto Cotto thinks prevention would be best
"But here we're talking about a criminal activity," he says.
The police chief says there needs to be another solution, one that prevents crime in the first place.
But resources here are tight. And these gangs have just as much - if not more - firepower than the authorities they are fighting.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:53:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pilgrimage to the mountains</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-32888643#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The festival that brings thousands to the Andes</Description>
        <MainBody>Pilgrimage to the mountains
29 May 2015 Last updated at 01:53
Photographer Timothy Allen climbs high into the Peruvian Andes for Qoyllur Rit'i - the Snow Star Festival.
Every year, a week before the Christian feast of Corpus Christi, tens of thousands of pilgrims climb high into the Peruvian Andes where the Sinakara Valley hosts Qoyllur Rit'i - the Snow Star Festival. Held under a full moon, the Catholic celebrations are infused with pre-Christian traditions. (Image 1/20) (Photography by Timothy Allen)
The pilgrims tend to come from rural communities and include dancers and musicians. The Catholic side of the festival dates from the late 1700s, when an image of Jesus is said to have appeared on a boulder after the death of a young shepherd boy. The pre-Christian elements are partly based on reverence for the Pleiades star constellation, which disappears and reappears in the Southern Hemisphere at this time of the year and is linked to hopes of an abundant harvest. (Image 2/20)
The main camp, known as the Sanctuary, is in the upper region of the Sinakara Valley. It is 4,700m above sea level and many pilgrims prepare for the change in altitude by drinking coca tea or chewing coca leaves. Above the valley sit sacred glaciers on Mount Qullqip'unqu. (Image 3/20)
The route up to the Sanctuary is dotted with crosses where Christian pilgrims show reverence by lighting candles and saying prayers. (Image 4/20)
The use of whips at Qoyllur Rit'i is common. Elders give out ceremonial punishment to young pilgrims who break the strict rules of the religious festival. Groups also take part in ritualistic whip fights. (Image 5/20)
The masked machulas represent the nawpa machus - the mythical first inhabitants of the Andes. Speaking in squeaky, high-pitched voices, their split personalities swing between playing the role of jesters and policemen - joking with pilgrims one minute then reprimanding those who forget to follow festival rules the next. (Image 6/20)
When the pilgrims arrive at the Sanctuary, a huge tented village springs up, with food stalls and restaurants. Even fresh fish is available, carried up to the site live in barrels of water on the backs of donkeys. (Image 7/20)
At the Sanctuary, pilgrims can visit the unorthodox Albacitas market where they can buy piles of fake money or miniature replicas of things they would like to manifest in real life. (Image 8/20)
Divided into so called "nations", the groups that come to the Sinakara Valley are invited by the Brotherhood of the Lord of Qoyllur Rit'i, a volunteer body that organises the event and imposes strict rules for attendees - alcohol is banned. (Image 9/20)
For the Christian participants of Qoyllur Rit'i, the highlight comes when the crosses are carried up even higher to the sacred glaciers above the valley. This is done by a group dressed as Ukukus - mythical half-man-half-bear characters. (Image 10/20)
The Ukukus dress in dark woollen clothes and masks. Regulars are quick to point out the decline in the size of the glaciers in recent decades, and say the ice has receded considerably. (Image 11/20)
In days gone by, Ukukus wore football boots to stop them slipping on the ice but nowadays professional climbers with ropes and crampons assist them. (Image 12/20)
Crosses are placed in the glacier and left overnight, traditionally surrounded by a candlelit shrine. But in recent years, as a nod to the receding glaciers, large candles have been banned. (Image 13/20)
After leaving their crosses in the ice, groups of Ukukus descend to the base of the glacier to spend the night together huddled around candles. (Image 14/20)
Dawn breaks and the Ukukus climb back up to retrieve their crosses. In procession, they then head back to the waiting crowds in the valley. Pilgrims used to cut chunks of ice from the glacier to use in church fonts as holy water but the practice has been banned because of the shrinking glacial mass. (Image 15/20)
At first light, the arrival of the crosses back at the Sanctuary is cause for great celebration. Pilgrims must then prepare themselves for a day-long procession to Tayancani. (Image 16/20)
After a morning mass, the procession leaves the Sanctuary and makes its way for seven hours or so, past lagoons and through valleys, until it reaches the small settlement of Yanacocha. Most groups rest there for three or four hours until nightfall. (Image 17/20)
The journey from Yanacocha to the church in the village of Tayancani must be undertaken in the dark. The light from the pilgrims' torches snakes through the mountains for eight hours under the stars. (Image 18/20)
Just before dawn, the pilgrims stop outside Tayancani and wait for the first rays of sunlight to break over the horizon - a sun-greeting ceremony is performed by those who celebrate old Incan spiritual beliefs. (Image 19/20)
In its colourful, eclectic, contemporary incarnation, today's Qoyllur Rit'i festival honours not only Jesus, but also the mountain gods (or apus) that South Americans worshipped long before Christianity's arrival on the continent. These photos were taken in 2014 - this year's festival will be held at the beginning of June. (Image 20/20) (Photography by Timothy Allen - all images subject to copyright)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
