<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Breaking News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Suicide bomber kills 4 people in attack on Shiite mosque, Saudi officials say - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/suicide-bomber-kills-4-people-in-attack-on-shiite</Link>
        <Description>Suicide bomber kills 4 people in attack on Shiite mosque, Saudi officials say - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>Suicide bomber kills 4 people in attack on Shiite mosque, Saudi officials say - @AP
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Myanmar's navy seizes boat with 727 migrants off the coast of Myanmar, government says - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/myanmars-navy-seizes-boat-with-727-migrants-off-t</Link>
        <Description>Myanmar's navy seizes boat with 727 migrants off the coast of Myanmar, government says - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Myanmar's navy seizes boat with 727 migrants off the coast of Myanmar, government says - @Reuters
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Fire reported at the Kenya Central Bank in Burundi's capital Bujumbura - @ArchieHenry2</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/fire-reported-at-the-kenya-central-bank-in-burundi</Link>
        <Description>Fire reported at the Kenya Central Bank in Burundi's capital Bujumbura - @ArchieHenry2</Description>
        <MainBody>Fire reported at the Kenya Central Bank in Burundi's capital Bujumbura - @ArchieHenry2
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Video: Scene of car explosion near a Shi'ite mosque in Dammam, Saudi Arabia - @alaashehabi</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/alaashehabi/status/604223763501207552</Link>
        <Description>Video: Scene of car explosion near a Shi'ite mosque in Dammam, Saudi Arabia - @alaashehabi</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>Car explodes near a Shi'ite mosque in Saudi Arabia's Dammam, killing 2 people, witness says - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/car-explodes-near-a-shiite-mosque-in-saudi-arabia</Link>
        <Description>Car explodes near a Shi'ite mosque in Saudi Arabia's Dammam, killing 2 people, witness says - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Car explodes near a Shi'ite mosque in Saudi Arabia's Dammam, killing 2 people, witness says - @Reuters
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Flood flood emergency declared from Garland to Allen, Texas until 7:15am CDT - @weatherchannel</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/flood-flood-emergency-declared-from-garland-to-all</Link>
        <Description>Flood flood emergency declared from Garland to Allen, Texas until 7:15am CDT - @weatherchannel</Description>
        <MainBody>Flood flood emergency declared from Garland to Allen, Texas until 7:15am CDT - @weatherchannel
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Muhammadu Buhari is sworn in, first Nigerian to oust a sitting president at the polls - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/muhammadu-buhari-is-sworn-in-first-nigerian-to-ou</Link>
        <Description>Muhammadu Buhari is sworn in, first Nigerian to oust a sitting president at the polls - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>Muhammadu Buhari is sworn in, first Nigerian to oust a sitting president at the polls - @AP
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>No immediate reports of damage following strong earthquake off the Alaskan coast - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/no-immediate-reports-of-damage-following-strong-ea</Link>
        <Description>No immediate reports of damage following strong earthquake off the Alaskan coast - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>No immediate reports of damage following strong earthquake off the Alaskan coast - @AP
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Total of 10 confirmed MERS cases in South Korea but no sustained human-to-human spread, WHO says - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/total-of-10-confirmed-mers-cases-in-south-korea-bu</Link>
        <Description>Total of 10 confirmed MERS cases in South Korea but no sustained human-to-human spread, WHO says - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015, 09:41 AM GMT
(
)
Total of 10 confirmed MERS cases in South Korea but no sustained human-to-human spread, WHO says - @Reuters
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>World Health Organization says it's not recommending any screening of passengers or travel or trade restrictions in South Korea due to MERS - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/world-health-organization-says-its-not-recommendi</Link>
        <Description>World Health Organization says it's not recommending any screening of passengers or travel or trade restrictions in South Korea due to MERS - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015, 09:33 AM GMT
(
09:33
)
World Health Organization says it's not recommending any screening of passengers or travel or trade restrictions in South Korea due to MERS - @Reuters
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Residents at an apartment complex in Grand Prairie, Texas, being evacuated over flooding - @Saulgarzafox4</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/Saulgarzafox4/status/604208309730594816/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Residents at an apartment complex in Grand Prairie, Texas, being evacuated over flooding - @Saulgarzafox4</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>South Korean traveler in China diagnosed with MERS, Chinese officials say - @YonhapNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/south-korean-traveler-in-china-diagnosed-with-mers</Link>
        <Description>South Korean traveler in China diagnosed with MERS, Chinese officials say - @YonhapNews</Description>
        <MainBody>South Korean traveler in China diagnosed with MERS, Chinese officials say - @YonhapNews
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>Hong Kong woman taken to hospital after exhibiting MERS-like symptoms - @SCMP_News</title>
        <Link>http://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/1812136/hong-kong-woman-rushed-hospital-mers-symptoms</Link>
        <Description>Hong Kong woman taken to hospital after exhibiting MERS-like symptoms - @SCMP_News</Description>
        <MainBody>Get 2 Riedel glasses for only HK$95 when you register with Wine Circle today!
The woman was quarantined at Princess Margaret Hospital on Friday. Photo: Felix Wong
A Hong Kong woman was rushed to hospital today showing symptoms of deadly Middle East respiratory syndrome (Mers) after she shared a flight to the city with a Korean man confirmed to havethe virus.
The man, who arrived in Hong Kong on a flight from South Korea on Tuesday before travelling by bus to mainland China,tested positive for the disease, the South Korean health ministry saidthis afternoon after it was notified by Chinese authorities.
The middle-aged woman, wearing full protective gear including a mask and cap, was seen being transported by ambulance from Sham Shui Po to the infectious disease centre at Princess Margaret Hospital at noon, according to a source. Healthcare staff who accompanied her to the hospital in Lai King were also clad in full protective gear.
The source said the woman was transported to the infectious disease centre for further examination after showing symptoms of the disease, but doctors are yet to confirm whether she has the virus.
READ MORE:South Korean man in China tests positive for Mers virus
Passengers who travelled to mainland China on the same bus as the Korean man would be difficult to track down as the bus company did not keep detailed records, its assistant manager said.
Speaking to a radio station this morning, Vivien Lee Lai-wa, assistant general manager of Eternal East Cross-border Coach Management said it was not the companys policy to acquire full details when selling tickets to passengers.
It would be simple for airlines as they must have personal details of their passengers. But our bus tickets dont contain personal details of our riders, she told RTHK.
Lai was speaking of measures the cross-border bus company had taken after it was revealed the man travelled from Hong Kong to Huizhou in Guangdong using her companys service. She said her company could only provide records about the number of people on the bus.
She later told the South China Morning Post that the company could also provide the arrival and departure time of the bus and when it crossed the border.
Hopefully nailing it down to when the bus passed immigration would help, she said.
The 44-year-old Korean, the son of a 76-year-old man believed to be the first to contract the deadly virus in South Korea, tested positive for Mers at a Huizhou hospital. His elder sister, who is in South Korea, also contracted the deadly virus.
The man was placed under medical surveillance by the South Korean government last week but ignored travel warnings and flew into Chek Lap Kok airport at 1pm on Tuesday.
There were 158 passengers on the Asiana Airlines flight. They included 80 Koreans, 73 Chinese, other foreigners and eight Korean flight crew.
Despite being intercepted for showing signs of fever, he later took the cross-border bus, run by Eternal East, to Huizhou. About 10 people were on the bus.
Lee said cleaning and sanitisation work had been carried out on the bus,with the Hong Kong driver now being asked to stay at home.
They advised the driver not to go out, even if he wasnt feeling unwell or if he didnt show symptoms, Lee told DBC radio, citing what officials from the Health Department told the driver. She added that the driver and a colleague from the mainland, who later drove the bus before it was sanitised, had been put on leave for seven days.
Meanwhile, a microbiologist from the University of Hong Kong said inconsistent information provided by the South Korean authorities had made the local health authoritys job more difficult.
For example, the date given to the Centre for Health Protection that the Korean mans father was first admitted to hospital was different to that the World Health Organisation received, Professor Ho Pak-leung said. This had made the tracking process difficult, he said.
He said when it came to defending Hong Kongs border from the virus, the city also relied on its counterparts in South Korea.
Mers, which has killed more than 400 people in Saudi Arabia since 2012, is considered a deadlier but less infectious cousin of the Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (Sars) virus that killed 299 people in Hong Kong in 2003.
South Koreas health ministry said earliertoday it hadconfirmed two othernew cases of Mers. That bringsthe total number of people infected with the virus there to at least10, including the man who travelled to Hong Kong.
Eight of the total had been linked to the first case confirmed last week, a 68-year-old man who had traveled to Bahrain in April and May, and returned to South Korea.
Professor Yuen Kwok-yung, a microbiologist at HKU, said the chance of a major outbreak of Mers in Hong Kongwas very low. He said the public health system should be able to quickly test those with symptoms of fever and respiratory problems, adding that it was quite unnecessary to isolate every Korean visitor with minor symptoms.
Additional reporting by Elizabeth Cheung and Associated Press
Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>Approximately 56,140 customers without power in Texas based on reporting by power companies - @NBCNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/approximately-56140-customers-without-power-in-te</Link>
        <Description>Approximately 56,140 customers without power in Texas based on reporting by power companies - @NBCNews</Description>
        <MainBody>Approximately 56,140 customers without power in Texas based on reporting by power companies - @NBCNews
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>FIFA's Sepp Blatter addresses congress audience in Zurich, says 'I am appealing to unity and the team spirit, so we can move forward together'</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/fifas-sepp-blatter-addresses-congress-audience-in</Link>
        <Description>FIFA's Sepp Blatter addresses congress audience in Zurich, says 'I am appealing to unity and the team spirit, so we can move forward together'</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015, 07:49 AM GMT
(
07:49
)
FIFA's Sepp Blatter addresses congress audience in Zurich, says 'I am appealing to unity and the team spirit, so we can move forward together'
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Protesters chanting 'Free football, free Palestine' outside FIFA soccer congress in Zurich - @owen_g</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/owen_g/status/604182251358785536/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Protesters chanting 'Free football, free Palestine' outside FIFA soccer congress in Zurich - @owen_g</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>No tsunami threat for California or the West Coast following Alaska 6.8 earthquake, National Weather Service says - @NWSBayArea</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/no-tsunami-threat-for-california-or-the-west-coast</Link>
        <Description>No tsunami threat for California or the West Coast following Alaska 6.8 earthquake, National Weather Service says - @NWSBayArea</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015, 07:15 AM GMT
(
07:15
)
No tsunami threat for California or the West Coast following Alaska 6.8 earthquake, National Weather Service says - @NWSBayArea
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>Magnitude 6.8 earthquake strikes off the coast of Alaska - USGS</title>
        <Link>http://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/eventpage/pt15149050</Link>
        <Description>Magnitude 6.8 earthquake strikes off the coast of Alaska - USGS</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>16-year-old boy arrested on suspicion of murder of James Attfield and Nahid Almanea in Colchester, England - @EssexPoliceUK</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/16-year-old-boy-arrested-on-suspicion-of-murder-of</Link>
        <Description>16-year-old boy arrested on suspicion of murder of James Attfield and Nahid Almanea in Colchester, England - @EssexPoliceUK</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015, 06:59 AM GMT
(
)
16-year-old boy arrested on suspicion of murder of James Attfield and Nahid Almanea in Colchester, England - @EssexPoliceUK
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
