<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbc">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 09:02:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sepp Blatter seeks another term as FIFA leader despite emerging scandal</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/sports/soccer/sepp-blatter-seeks-another-term-as-fifa-leader-despite-emerging-scandal-1.3092351?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Sepp Blatter seeks another term as FIFA leader despite emerging scandal
Jordanian Prince Ali bin al-Hussein challenger in Friday's election
The Associated Press Posted: May 29, 2015 2:02 AM ET Last Updated: May 29, 2015 5:46 AM ET
FIFA President Sepp Blatter speaks Friday during the 65th FIFA Congress in Zurich, Switzerland, as he seeks re-election for a fifth term.  (Patrick B. Kraemer/Keystone via Associated Press)
FIFA Women's World Cup trophy arrives in Vancouver amid controversy
The worst corruption crisis in soccer history stems from the governing body's decision to award Russia and Qatar the next two World Cup tournaments, FIFA President Sepp Blatter said Friday.
Blatter spoke at the FIFA congress hours before the presidential election in which he is a seeking a fifth term. He has refused calls to resign after FIFA was targeted by U.S. and Swiss authorities in separate corruption investigations.
In 2010, Russia was chosen to host the 2018 World Cup and Qatar was awarded the 2022 tournament amid widespread allegations of wrongdoing.
FIFAsoccer officials arrested as U.S., Switzerland probe corruption
"If two other countries had emerged from the envelope, I think we would not have these problems today," Blatter said. "But we can't go back in time. We are not prophets. We can't say what would have happened."
The United States was one of the losing bidders for the 2022 World Cup. On Wednesday, U.S. authorities indicted 14 people on bribery, racketeering, fraud and money-laundering charges going back to the 1990s.
Seven of the officials  including two serving FIFA vice presidents  were arrested in Zurich on Wednesday ahead of the congress.
The two criminal investigations have cast a new shadow on Blatter's 17-year reign as president of FIFA. The 209 FIFA member nations will decide later Friday whether to stick with the 79-year-old Blatter or vote for Prince Ali bin al-Hussein of Jordan.
Amid the dramatic build up to the election, UEFA president Michel Platini appealed to Blatter to immediately step down  calls the president has rejected.
"I am willing to accept the president of FIFA is responsible for everything but I would at least like to share that responsibility with everyone," Blatter said in a presidential address on Friday morning. "We cannot constantly supervise everyone in football ... you cannot ask everyone to behave ethically."
FixingFIFAnot an easy goal
Blatter also cautioned that "it will take some time" to rebuild FIFA's reputation.
"The events of Wednesday have unleashed a storm and there was even questioned whether this congress would be organized or change the agenda," Blatter said. "Today I am appealing to unity and team spirit so we can move forward together. That may not always be easy but it is for this reason that we are here together today."
A two-thirds majority would be enough for Blatter or Prince Ali to win the secret presidential vote, or a simple majority in a second round of voting. Just forcing the ballot to a second round could represent a victory of sorts for Blatter's critics, denying the incumbent president an emphatic mandate in his next term.
Blatter's opening address to the congress was briefly disrupted by a pro-Palestinian activist, who held up a red card and shouted "Red card to racism." The protest was to draw attention to a campaign that aims to stop Palestinian players from being detained by Israeli security forces.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why Europe can't let Greek economy crumble: Don Pittis</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/why-europe-can-t-let-greek-economy-crumble-don-pittis-1.3089249?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Greece raids reserves to make IMF debt payment
While Greece's leaders willsuffer if the country accidentally collapses, the reputationaldamage for the European Union willbe much worse.
And worst of all, the only ones who will benefit if it happens are thosefinancial vultures betting fortunes on bond spreads and other derivatives that will make them a pile if everything goes sour.
"A precarious situation in Greece is getting worse and the probability of an accident in which governments both in Greece and the rest of Europe lose control is high," said well-known economic commentator MohamedEl-Erian on the business TV networkCNBC earlier this month.
Playing chicken
When two sides in a financial negotiation are playing chicken, there is always a possibility that both will think the other will giveway at the last minute. Accidents do happen.
Graffiti crumbles along with the wall of an abandoned house in Athens, the capital of a country that has also lost its economic way. (Petros Giannakouris/Associated Press)
This time, neither side can afford it.
You can see why the Europeans have been reluctant to cave in. It is a classic case of moral hazard, where, if a person, business orcountry gets away with something once, there is nothing to stop them from doing the same thing again.
In this case, the idea is that Greeks ran up huge debts. Greeks, through their governments, made deals to borrow even more money to keep their economy afloat. The moral hazard argument would say that if Greeks don't keep to their side of the deal, they should be made to suffer the consequences.
For the EU, the moral hazardcase goes far beyond Greece. It is only one of 28 countries in the union. Anything Brusselsdoes for one member country becomes a precedent for what it may be asked todo for other members in the future.
The gloomiest of the Europeans fear a wave of copycat defaults as more countries elect governments to repudiate debts and demand relief.
Default risk 70%
The financial press has been playing up the technical side of the negotiations, discussing drop dead dates and timelines for IMF payments. One such article on the financial websiteZerohedgequotes Deutsche Bank as saying "The Greek Endgame is Here" and that chances of a default are now at 70 per cent.
If European politiciansleave people who think like that in charge the chances of a Graccidentwill become seriously worse.
Whilelegalisms are the tools and pressure pointsof any negotiation, the real issues go to the heart of European politics and what it means to be a member of a union.
Economically, Greece has lost its way. Austerity has not worked. More austerity will not improve things. Its citizens are outraged.
The Greek economy continues to shrink, money continues to flood out, its banks are in danger of collapse.Piling more debt onto its future bill is absurd. Climbing out from under such a burden is completely unlikely.
Stripping its elderly of their pensions, as one solution required, is un-European. Condemning its children to poverty isworse because it destroys the future. This is not what Europeans want to be seen doing.
When disaster strikes
According to recent statistics from Eurostat, the Greek economy only represents between one and two per cent of Europe's. By the standards of the entire union, its debts are tiny.
From the standpoint of moral hazard, the hardship Greece has seen may beuseful. It is hard to seeother European countrieswanting to go though the same financial ringer. 
When disaster strikes one member of a union, whether it is an earthquake, flood or financial trouble, it is essential for the rest of the members of that union to step forward and nurse the battered one back to health.
In the case of Greece it will not be easy. It is not a short-term project. But if anyone on Earth has the smarts and the wealth to bring the Greek economy back from the brink, it is the Europeans.
The details need to be worked out, the negotiations should be tough. But the European politicians have to clearly state that ultimately they will back Greece.
They must stand on the principle that when memberstates get into trouble, they will not be sent nakedinto the desert to live or die alone, and as each one falls, leavethe vultures to pick their bones.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 10:12:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japan's Mount Shindake erupts, forcing evacuation order</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/japan-s-mount-shindake-erupts-forcing-evacuation-order-1.3092358?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Japan's Mount Shindake erupts, forcing evacuation order
Officials worry about further eruptions but say human life isn't endangered
Thomson Reuters Posted: May 29, 2015 3:12 AM ET Last Updated: May 29, 2015 6:52 AM ET
A video grab from the Japan Meteorological Agency's live camera image shows an eruption of Mount Shindake on Kuchinoerabujima island, Kagoshima Prefecture, on Friday.   (Japan Meteorological Agency via Reuters)
Related Stories
Mount Ontake volcano: Most of the dead likely struck by rocks
A volcano on the remote southern Japanese island of Kuchinoerabujima erupted suddenly on Friday, blasting plumes of black smoke high into the sky, prompting authorities to start evacuating the island and airlines to re-route flights.
A pyroclastic flow of super-heated gas and rock flowed down the side of Mount Shindake and reached the ocean after the mountain's "explosive" eruption, but officials said there was no danger to human life.
"There was a huge bang and black smoke rose up immediately," Nobuaki Hayashi, an island official, told NHK television, adding that residents were gathering to await evacuation.
One 72-year-old man suffered burns to his face after being caught in the pyroclastic flow, but there were no reports of other injuries among the island's 137 residents, whose only access to the outside world is by boat.
Watchful residents gathered on the roof of an evacuation centre, its parking lot packed with cars, as the peak continued to spew out smoke and ash. Ash blanketed part of the mountain's lower slopes and fell on the main harbour, turning it grey.
Smoke billowed some 9,000 metres into the sky and officials warned of the risk of continuing, possibly large-scale eruptions, calling for "extreme caution".
The volcano erupted suddenly on Friday, blasting plumes of black smoke high into the sky, prompting authorities to order the evacuation of the island's residents and forcing airlines to divert some flights.   (Japan Meteorological Agency/Reuters)
Japan's All Nippon Airways said it would divert some flights to Okinawa and Southeast Asia as a precaution, but didn't plan to cancel any. Japan Airlines (JAL) said it did not have any plans to change any of its flights.
A ferry from Yakushima, the closest neighbouring island about one hour sail east, had arrived and aimed to evacuate residents around 3:00 p.m., said Tatsuya Terada, a government official on Yakushima.
"We will need to verify safety conditions and check lists of names, but that's currently the plan," he said.
A Coast Guard ship was standing by off the island.
Kuchinoerabujima island is about 130 kilometres south of Japan's southernmost main island Kyushu, and roughly 1,000 km southwest of Tokyo.
It was not immediately clear if the eruption would affect the restart of Kyushu Electric Power's Sendai nuclear plant, which on Wednesday cleared the last step of the nuclear regulator's stringent safety hurdles introduced after the Fukushima Daiichi disaster in 2011.
Island the site of many eruptions in past
The company said an internal analysis showed the erupting volcano posed no risk to the Sendai plant on Kyushu island, and volcanologists agreed.
The island has been the site of several previous eruptions, including one in 1933 that killed several people.
Mount Shindake erupted last summer and the area where that pyroclastic flow occurred has been off limits since then.
Japan is one of the world's most seismically active nations and there has been an upsurge in volcanic activity in recent weeks, which volcanologists said may have been ushered in by the massive March 11, 2011 earthquake.
In September 2014, 63 people were killed when Mount Ontake in central Japan erupted without warning while packed with hikers.
A longer view of the eruption on Mount Shindake. Japan was hit last year by a volcano that killed 63 people. (Japan Meteorological Agency/Reuters)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 07:25:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gay feminist teen blows the internet up with her yearbook quote</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/trending/gay-feminist-teen-blows-the-internet-up-with-her-yearbook-quote-1.3091963?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Gay feminist teen blows the internet up with her yearbook quote
17-year-old Caitlyn Cannon wins love from around the world after her powerful yearbook quote hits the web
ByLauren O'Neil, CBC News Posted: May 29, 2015 12:25 AM ET Last Updated: May 29, 2015 12:29 AM ET
A photo of Caitlyn Cannon's senior yearbook quote has been reblogged on Tumblr more than 132,000 times since Tuesday, earning the 17-year-old feminist coverage in media outlets all over the world. (Twitter.com/@casualnosebleed/@C_to_the_Cizzle)
Related Stories
Why do women earn less than men?
If yearbook quotes were performed live on stage, in front of the entire world  as opposed to written down and then published months later for a few hundred students  17-year-oldCaitlyn Cannon could very wellhave dropped the mic after sharing hers. 
Instead, she's experiencing thedigital equivalent of making a stadiumerupt with her words: Going viral.
Cannon, who recentlygraduated from Oak Hills High School in California, is the toast of the web this week for penninga powerfulyearbook quote that somehow fusesfeminism, the wage gap, gay rights and humour in just one sentence:
"I need feminism because I intend on marrying rich and I can't do that if my wife and I are making .75 cent for every dollar a man makes."
this is all I honestly care about right now pic.twitter.com/5J0YauhezN
 @casualnosebleed
A photo of Cannon's yearbook photo and quote was tweeted by a friend on Tuesday with the caption "this is all I honestly care about right now."
It has since been retweetednearly 10,000 times, favourited more than 13,500 times,and picked up by news outlets all over the world.
After sharing the photo on her own Tumblrblog Wednesday, itracked up awhopping 132,000 reblogs more in less than 24 hours.
"I was tired of seeing the same old quotes from popular books and movies and authors," said Cannon, who describes herself as "feminist" and"really gay" inher Twitter bio, viaemail to TheHuffington Post."I wanted to call attention to a problem that women face."
If her goal was to callattention to the specific problem of the gender pay gap  which sees Canadian women earning between 73 cents and 82 cents for every dollar a man earns, according to theCCPAshe certainly achieved it.
The new graduate's yearbook quote has sparked quite a debate on Twitter about the issue, and aside from some " wage gap truthers ,"the majority of people appear supportive of her message.

@ZooeyDeschanel has seen my story and put a freaking heart now I've lost it  This has been quite the experience! pic.twitter.com/XYwUAo2YSR
 @C_to_the_Cizzle
When asked about what inspired her yearbook quote, Cannon told the Huffington Post that she had seen a similar message on Tumblr pertaining to men, but that she changed the words to reflect her own identity.
"I've never really been ashamed to say that I am gay," she said. "So the LGBT aspect was simply who I am."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Toronto-based mining firm paid bribes in Congo, whistleblower tells RCMP</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/magindustries-probed-by-rcmp-over-bribery-allegations-in-congo-1.3091035?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>MagIndustries probed by RCMP over bribery allegations in Congo
Toronto-based mining firm accused of paying bribes to pave way for potash mine
ByDave Seglins, Pete Evans, CBC News Posted: May 29, 2015 5:00 AM ET Last Updated: May 29, 2015 6:51 AM ET
Jun Tian, middle, is named as a suspect in the RCMP documents. He is shown in this photo with Congo mining minister Pierre Oba, left, and company chairman Simon Liang, right. (MagIndustries)
Related Stories
Arthur Porter's rights violated in Panama prison: UN report
The Mounties are investigating allegations from a whistleblowing accountant at TSX-listed mining company MagIndustries that his bosses paid bribes to officials in the Republic of Congo to winapprovals tied to apotash mine development in that country.
According to newly unsealed court documents , the RCMP's sensitive and international investigations unit raided the Toronto offices of MagIndustries in January. The company has beendeveloping a $1.5-billion potash mine and processing facilityin the West African country for several years.
Got a tip on this story or others? EmailDave Seglins here
Search warrant materials obtained by CBC News tell a cautionary tale about the company, which is registered in Toronto but controlled by Chinese interests since a takeover in 2011.Those investors and managers are now ensnaredin an international police bribery investigation.
The RCMP believe four top executives with the company, including CEO Longbo Chen who took over in 2012, ignored warnings from Canadian financial advisers and signed off on a string of illegal payments to Congolese officials.
None of the allegations contained in thesearch warrant have been tested in court, and the RCMP has not laid any charges.
When asked for comment for this story, the company and its officials declined.
Whistleblower fired
RCMP began "Project Aloes" in late 2013 after a lead accountant on MagIndustries' Mengo potash projectin Pointe Noir, Congo, contacted Canadian Embassy officials. The Canadian accountantalleges his new Chinese bosses at MagIndustries ignored his refusals to pay out $12,000in cash to government officials.
The accountant believes the money was to help win permission to expropriate290 hectares of land to build a seaside shipping terminal near the company's new potash processing facility. Canadian prosecutors involved in the case blanked out portions of the unsealed search warrant, including the names of the accountant and the Congolese officials involved, citing the need to protect the ongoing investigation.
MagIndustries CEO Longbo Chen, second from left, and the company's vice-president of mining development Fuliang Wang, second from right, shown with other employees are both named suspects by the RCMP.   (MagIndustries)
MagIndustires was working closely with various Congolese officials including Pierre Oba, mining minister, and Pierre Mabiala, minister of land ownership, the warrant states. Neither of those men are accused of doing anything wrong in the public portions of the RCMPsearch warrant.
The accountant told the RCMP in a videotaped statement that ultimately he was terminated for his refusal to approve the illegal payments, after being told by a company official "that it was the way to conduct business in Africa."
2 sets of books
The cash payments flagged by the whistleblower, it turns out, were not the first of theirkind. In March 2014, the RCMPseized MagIndustries' emails from the company's internet service provider. Thosecommunications reveal auditors and company executives were wrestling with what is described ininternal emails asfive "black money" payments made in 2012 to government tax officials.
The company, using the subsidiary Eucalpytus Fibre Congo, agreed to a series of"under the table" payments to unnamed tax officials totalling $102,000. In exchange, the company was granted a deep discount in the amount of tax it had to officially pay to Congolese authorities, the warrant alleges.
Eucalpytus kept two sets of books with one company official explainingthey agreed to the payoffs "in exchange for cost efficiency," the court documents state. TheRCMPwarrant also cites evidence the companybelieved only Chinese employees should work in the finance department.In 2012,MagIndustrieshired an outside "governance specialist," consultant Michael Gunns, who began sounding alarm bells andadvising executives the scheme could be in violation of Canada's Corruption of Foreign Public Officials Act.
In August 2013, Gunns travelled to Congo where he met with the whistleblowing accountant. Gunns began asking questions, and a month laterhe too was terminated. The RCMP warrant materials cite a Sept. 22, 2013, email from risk manager Kevin Stephens to MagIndustries CEO Longbo Chen, expressing worry the situation was handled poorly and that the accountant "for the past two years had been privy to some sensitive and confidential company information such as per diem payments made to certain members of the Congolese government, tax and other financial issues."
The RCMPdocumentstates"Stephens emphasized that they needed to avoid any possibility that [name redacted] might release anything of a sensitive nature to the Congolese government, or worse, the Canadian government."
Cost of doing business?
Forensic auditor Peter Dent works with corruption watchdog Transparency International. In an interview, he said the Republic of Congo is ranked asone of the most corrupt countries in the world.
While he stresses he's not familiar with the specifics of this particular story, he rejects the notion that allegations such as the ones laid out above can merely be dismissed as the cost of doing business in some of the world's more shadowy jurisdictions.
If there is a cost, it's to be more scrupulous, he said."One of thecosts of doing business in one of the most corruptregions of the world would be to have very robust compliance programs," he said. "The risks are much higher and therefore the due diligence that's going to be required on the businessis likely going to be more expensive as well."
He notesthere are numerousexamples of foreign companies taking over a Canadian company and then using Canada's stellar business reputation as they operate abroad.
"It does give them perhaps a degree of credibility that they would not otherwise have had operating from theirhome jurisdiction," he said.
MagIndustries launched an internal probe in January after theRCMP raided its Toronto headquarters. Ontario securities regulators have been keeping a close eye on the company ever since, and as part of an order from the Ontario Securities Commission, the company must file a report on the probe by June 1 or riskan immediate halt on the trading of MagIndustries shares on the TSX.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 07:41:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Asian countries meet to grapple with growing number of trafficked migrants</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/thailand-to-allow-help-of-u-s-planes-to-spot-boats-smuggling-migrants-1.3092341?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Thailand to allow help of U.S. planes to spot boats smuggling migrants
Summit taking place in Bangkok
The Associated Press Posted: May 29, 2015 12:41 AM ET Last Updated: May 29, 2015 12:51 AM ET
Thai Foreign Minister Thanasak Patimaprakorn speaks at the "Special Meeting on Irregular Migration in the Indian Ocean" regarding the Rohingya and Bangladeshi migrant crisis, early Friday in Bangkok.   (Charles Dharapak/The Associated Press)
Related Stories
Inside the big business of people smuggling
Thailand's Foreign Minister said Friday that the upsurge of boat people in Southeast Asia has reached an "alarming level," and called for governments in the region to address the root causes of the crisis  a reference to the swelling number of refugees who have fled persecution in Burma.
Speaking at the opening of a regional meeting in Bangkok aimed at tackling the issue, Foreign Minister Thanasak Patimaprakorn said that "no country can solve this problem alone."
Asian nations have been struggling in the face of growing waves of desperate migrants who are landing on the shores of Indonesia, Malaysia and Thailand in growing numbers. In the last few weeks alone, at least 3,000 people have washed ashore or been rescued by fishermen.
Malaysia finds 139 graves, signs of torture at human trafficking camps
Some are Bangladeshis who left their impoverished homeland in hope of finding jobs abroad. But many are minority Rohingya Muslims who have fled persecution in predominantly Buddhist Burma  also known as Myanmar  which has denied them basic rights, confined more than 100,000 to camps, and denies them citizenship. There are more than one million Rohingya living in Myanmar.
"The influx of irregular migrants in the Indian Ocean has reached an alarming level," Thanasak said. But "while we are trying to help those in need, we must stop the outflow of irregular migrants and combat transnational crime and destroy their networks."
He also added: "The root causes that motivated these people to leave must also be addressed."
Friday's meeting includes representatives from 17 countries directly and indirectly affected by crisis, as well as others such as the United States and Japan, and officials from international organizations such as the UN refugee agency and the International Organization for Migration.
Thailand's deputy minister said it will allow the United States to fly surveillance planes from its territory to identify boats carrying migrants.
U.S. Assistant Secretary of State Anne Richard had said earlier that the United States had made a request to fly such missions, as an intergovernmental meeting on the regional migrant crisis got under way in Bangkok.
"Yes, we are permitting it, it is starting today," Thailand's Deputy Prime Minister General Tanasak Patimapragorn told Reuters on the sidelines of the meeting.
Rohingya have fled Myanmar and for years, and Southeast Asia has quietly ignored the issue. The problem has attracted international attention amid increased media scrutiny in recent months.
Thailand launched a crackdown on human trafficking last month, prompting smugglers to abandon their boats, leaving what aid groups estimated were thousands of migrants stranded at sea. Survivors, including women and children, came ashore with first-hand accounts of beatings, ransom kidnappings by traffickers and near-starvation.
Pressure on Burma needed, according to rights groups
The director-general of the IOM, William Lacy Swing, said on the eve of the meeting that one important result was already achieved in getting the countries to agree to talk. He said that there needed to be some kind of a follow-up mechanism to make regional governments continue to work closely on the issue.
Human rights groups have urged those involved in the talks to find a better way of saving the people still stranded at sea, and to put pressure on Myanmar to end its repressive policies that drive Rohingya to flee.
Migrant crisis: Burma refuses to accept blame
Swing said a long-term, comprehensive policy has to be put together, and that no single element by itself is going to solve the issue. But he said Myanmar was a key. "I think Myanmar has to be engaged in any solution involving any of the groups, absolutely," he said.
Malaysia and Indonesia agreed last week to provide the migrants with one-year shelter. Indonesia says Rohingya can stay for a year while Bangladeshis will be repatriated. It is unclear what happens after a year, and both countries have called on the international community to help with resettlement options.
Thailand has offered humanitarian help but not shelter. More than 100,000 refugees, mostly from Myanmar's other ethnic groups, have been living in border camps for decades, and Thailand says it cannot afford any more.
With files from Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 06:18:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Can you spell 'scherenschnitte'? Scripps national spelling bee ends with a tie</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/scripps-national-spelling-bee-ends-in-a-tie-for-the-1st-time-in-52-years-1.3092310?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Scripps National Spelling Bee ends in a tie for the 1st time in 52 years
The final 2 words were scherenschnitte and nunatak
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 11:18 PM ET Last Updated: May 29, 2015 6:02 AM ET
Vanya Shivashankar, left, 13, of Olathe, Kan., and Gokul Venkatachalam, 14, of St. Louis, hold up the championship trophy as co-champions after winning the finals of the Scripps National Spelling Bee on Thursday. (Andrew Harnik/The Associated Press)
Related Stories
They couldn't be rattled. They couldn't be denied. Gokul Venkatachalam and Vanya Shivashankar had worked too hard and come close too many times not to win the Scripps National Spelling Bee.
So they shared the title on Thursday, making history in two different ways.
The bee hadn't ended in a tie for 52 years  until last year. Now it's happened for an unprecedented two years running.
Vanya, 13, of Olathe, Kansas, is the first sibling of a past champion to win. Her sister, Kavya, won in 2009.
2014: 2 boys declared co-winners of Scripps National Spelling Bee
Vanya's final word was "scherenschnitte," which means the art of cutting paper into decorative designs. After being informed he'd be the co-champion if he got the next word right, Gokul didn't even bother to ask the definition before spelling "nunatak." For the record, it means a hill or mountain completely surrounded by glacial ice.
"I knew it right away," he said. "I didn't want to keep everyone waiting."
Gokul, 14, of Chesterfield, Missouri, finished third last year, behind the two co-champions. He had a gruff onstage demeanor, confirming a word's roots and definition before chugging through the letters as if he had dinner plans.
Underneath his blue-and-white button-down shirt, Gokul wore the jersey of his idol, LeBron James.
"I wasn't nervous," he said.
Gokul hopes to attend Stanford and become an entrepreneur or stockbroker. But his immediate priority is to watch the NBA Finals.
While Gokul wowed the crowd with his machinelike efficiency, Vanya has been the darling of the bee since she made her debut as a vivacious 9-year-old in 2010. Also an actress, she was poised and graceful, smiling and nodding when she got a word she knew instantly  which was nearly every time.
Both are eighth-graders, so it was their last chance. Vanya was competing in the bee for the fifth and final time. Her sister, Kavya  now a sophomore at Columbia University  competed four times, which means the Shivashankar family has made the trip nine of the past 10 years.
"I'm so, so proud and in awe of my sister," Kavya said.
3 Canadians compete
Vanya, who also acts and plays the tuba and piano, dedicated her victory to her late grandmother, who died in 2013.
"Everything takes hard work and passion," Vanya said. "That's definitely what I put in and I know Gokul put that into this endeavor as well."
Vanya aspires to be a cardiac surgeon. In the meantime, she hopes to devote more time to acting and persuade her family to take a Caribbean cruise this summer.
"It's definitely going to be weird not doing spelling in high school," she said.
Proving their superiority over even their toughest competitors, Vanya and Gokul went head-to-head for 10 rounds before the list of 25 championship words was exhausted.
The words included: bouquetire, caudillismo, thamakau, scytale, Bruxellois and pyrrhuloxia. Vanya appeared to struggle only with the Fijian-derived thamaku, which is a type of outrigger canoe.
"It was on our list," said Mirle Shivashankar, Vanya's father and spelling coach. "But I couldn't remember it."
Before the bee began, executive director Paige Kimble predicted it would be another 50 years before it ended in a tie. Now she's thinking differently.
"I think it's time to consider that the bee may be entering a new era where the level of competition is so intense that we need to entertain this as a possibility every year," she said.
The last 10 winners of the bee, and 14 of the past 18, have been of Indian descent, a run of dominance that began in 1999 with Nupur Lala's victory, which was later featured in the documentary "Spellbound."
Vanya and Gokul each will receive more than $37,000 in cash and prizes, and while they held up the trophy together as they were being showered with confetti, each will get one to take home. Fourteen-year-old Cole Shafer-Ray of Norman, Oklahoma, making his first appearance in the finals, finished third.
There were three Canadians entrants: Rehana Lalani of Burlington, Ont., Thomas Duck of Halifax and Greta Warner of St. John's.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:40:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Michael Jackson's Neverland Ranch up for sale at $100M</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/michael-jackson-s-neverland-ranch-valued-at-100m-1.3092190?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Michael Jackson's Neverland Ranch valued at $100M
King of Pop's fantasy-land home goes up for sale
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 9:40 PM ET Last Updated: May 29, 2015 2:39 AM ET
In 1995, Michael Jackson and Lisa Marie Presley walk with children who were invited guests at his Neverland Ranch home, in Santa Ynez, Calif. He would move away from the playtime palace 10 years later following his acquittal on charges he sexually abused children there.  (Associated Press)
Related Stories
Michael Jackson: Recalling the King of Pop 5 years after his death
Michael Jackson's Neverland Ranch is up for sale.
The Santa Ynez Valley property that once served as the late pop star's home and personal fantasy land is being listed at $100 million US, according to the Wall Street Journal.
Michael Jackson: Recalling the King of Pop 5 years after his death
The 1,100-hectare ranch, which features a train station, six-bedroom house and 50-seat movie theatre, has been in limbo since Jackson's death in 2009.
Jackson paid $19.5 million for the property in 1988 and rechristened it Neverland after Peter Pan's island dwelling.
The real estate company Colony Capital LLC bailed out Jackson in 2008 after he defaulted on the $24.5 million that he owed on the property.
Jackson distanced himself from Neverland after his 2005 acquittal on charges that he molested children at the ranch, opting to live elsewhere.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:41:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin signs law banning publication of peacetime military casualties</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/putin-signs-law-banning-publication-of-peacetime-military-casualties-1.3091950?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Putin signs law banning publication of peacetime military casualties
Move comes as evidence mounts of Russian troops in Ukraine
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 6:41 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 6:41 PM ET
Russian President Vladimir Putin, seen addressing a business forum in Russia on Tuesday, signed a decree Thursday that makes it a crime to report Russian military losses in peacetime. (Alexei Nikolsky/RIA Novosti/ AP)
Related Stories
Russia's Vladimir Putin brandishes the nuclear option
President Vladimir Putin has signed a decree to make losses of Russian troops in peacetime a state secret.
The decree published on the official government website and signed by Putin on Thursday makes it a crime to publish information about peacetime losses of Russian troops in "special operations."
Russia's Vladimir Putin brandishes the nuclear option
The decree comes as evidence of Russian involvement in the conflict in eastern Ukraine is mounting.
Ukraine last week captured two men who it said were Russian officers operating on the side of the separatists in eastern Ukraine. The Russian defence ministry said the two are no longer active servicemen. However, the men insisted in several video interviews they were in Ukraine on their commanders' orders.
The measure brought strong criticism from Amnesty International and the United States.
"Not only is this decree a blatant attack on freedom of expression, it also has sinister undertones that will intensify speculation President Putin has something to hide  specifically losses incurred by Russia's military in Ukraine," John Dalhuisen, Amnesty's Europe and Central Asia director, said in a statement.
U.S. State Department spokesman Jeff Rathke said in Washington, "We see this as a misplaced effort to cover up what everyone knows, and that is that Russian active-duty military personnel are fighting and dying in eastern Ukraine and that the Russian government is denying it."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 06:38:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former U.S. House Speaker indicted over alleged hush money payments</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/dennis-hastert-ex-speaker-of-the-house-indicted-in-chicago-1.3092324?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Dennis Hastert, ex-Speaker of the House, indicted in Chicago
Allegedly agreed to pay $3.5M to compensate for past misconduct against an Illinois native
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 11:38 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 11:38 PM ET
In this Aug. 17, 2007, file photo, former House Speaker Dennis, Hastert, R-Ill., announces that he will not seek re-election for a 12th term. Federal prosecutors have indicted Hastert on Thursday.   (Brian Kersey/The Associated Press)
Related Stories
Aaron Schock, Republican congressman, resigning amid spending scandal
Former U.S. House Speaker Dennis Hastert agreed to pay $3.5 million US in hush money to keep a person from the town where he was a longtime high school teacher silent about "prior misconduct" by the Illinois Republican who was once second in line to the U.S. presidency, according to a federal grand jury indictment handed down Thursday.
The indictment, which doesn't describe the alleged misconduct by Hastert, charges the 73-year-old with one count of evading bank regulations by withdrawing $952,000 in increments of less than $10,000 to skirt reporting requirements. He is also charged with one count of lying to the FBI about the reason for the unusual withdrawals.
Each count of the indictment carries a maximum penalty of five years in prison and a $250,000 fine.
Hastert did not return email and phone messages from The Associated Press seeking comment on the allegations. Hastert, who had worked as a lobbyist in Washington, D.C., since shortly after he left Congress in 2007, resigned from Dickstein Shapiro LLC, a spokesman for the lobbying and law firm said Thursday.
The indictment alleges Hastert withdrew a total of around $1.7 million in cash from various bank accounts from 2010 to 2014, then provided the money to a person identified in the indictment only as "Individual A." Hastert allegedly agreed to pay the person $3.5 million, but never apparently paid that full amount.
It notes that Hastert was a high school teacher and coach from 1965 to 1981 in suburban Yorkville, about 80 kilometres west of Chicago. While the indictment says Individual A has been a resident of Yorkville and has known Hastert most of Individual A's life, it doesn't describe their relationship.
The indictment says Hastert agreed to the payments after multiple meetings in 2010. It says that "during at least one of the meetings, Individual A and defendant discussed past misconduct by defendant against Individual A that had occurred years earlier" and Hastert agreed to pay $3.5 million "in order to compensate for and conceal his prior misconduct against Individual A."
Withdrawals just under $10K raised suspicion
The indictment says that between 2010 and 2012 Hastert made 15 $50,000 withdrawals of cash from bank accounts at Old Second Bank, People's State Bank and Castle Bank and gave cash to Individual A around every six weeks.
Around April 2012, bank officials began questioning Hastert about the withdrawals, and starting in July of that year, Hastert reduced the amounts he withdrew at a time to less than $10,000  apparently so they would not run afoul of a regulation designed to stop illicit activity such as money laundering, according to the indictment.
Among the focuses of the FBI investigation was whether Hastert, in the words of the indictment, was "the victim of a criminal extortion related to, among other matters, his prior positions in government." The court document does not elaborate.
Legal experts said extortion cases can be tricky.
In mulling over whom to charge, prosecutors often must decide who is the greater victim: the person being extorted or the person who's doing the extorting, said Chicago-based attorney and former federal prosecutor Phil Turner.
Jeff Cramer, a former federal prosecutor and head of the Chicago office of the investigation firm Kroll, said investigators could have concluded Hastert's alleged misconduct was "more egregious than the extortion."
Investigators questioned Hastert on Dec. 8, 2014, and he lied about why he had been withdrawing so much money at a time, the indictment alleges. He told investigators he did it because he didn't trust the banking system, the indictment says.
"Yeah ... I kept the cash. That's what I am doing," it quotes Hastert as saying.
Latest Illinois politician to be ensnared
Hastert, who also maintains a home in the Chicago suburb of Plano several miles northwest of Yorkville, was a little-known lawmaker from suburban Chicago when chosen to succeed conservative Newt Gingrich as speaker. Hastert was picked after favoured Louisiana Rep. Bob Livingston resigned following his admission of several sexual affairs.
As speaker, Hastert pushed President George W. Bush's legislative agenda, helping pass a massive tax cut and expanding Medicare prescription drug benefits.
He retired from Congress in 2007 after eight years as speaker, making him the longest-serving Republican House speaker. He was second in line to the presidency during those years after the vice president.
David Corwin of Yorkville said his son, Scott, wrestled for Hastert in high school, then later became a wrestling coach himself.
"You won't get anyone to say anything bad about him out here," said David Corwin. "Everybody loved him. The kids loved him, and they still do."
Illinois has a long history of politicians getting in legal trouble.
Former U.S. Rep. Jesse Jackson Jr. served a year and a half for illegally spending $750,000 in campaign funds on furs, vacations and other luxury items. Two successive governors in the 2000s, Republican George Ryan and Democrat Rod Blagojevich, were convicted on corruption charges.
In the Hastert case, it's not clear whether the money was paid in relation to his former position in government. Hastert started making the payments to the person in about 2010, according to the indictment.
Reached by telephone after the announcement, former Gov. Ryan described Hastert as an effective legislator.
"I'm just surprised if this is true," said Ryan, who has lived in Kankakee, Illinois, since his release from prison.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:24:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Texas family horrified as flood waters engulf their home</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/videos/texas-family-horrified-as-flood-waters-engulf-their-home-1.3092141?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Video
Texas family horrified as flood waters engulf their home
CBC News Posted: May 28, 2015 8:24 PM ET Last Updated: May 29, 2015 6:32 AM ET
Related Stories
Texas flood: Record rainfall eases long-running drought
The home video only lasts for 2 minutes and35 seconds, but captures in graphic detail the fear felt by a Texas couple as the Blanco River swept through their home in Wimberley, Texas, on Sunday.
Ernie and Sarah Perezwatched in horror from the second floor of their home as the river's record surge  which, at its peak reached the height of a four-storey building  roared through their home.
Texas flood: Record rainfall eases long-running drought
"Oh, no!" Sarah moans more than once as family photographs and furniture swirl beneath them, all captured on a mobile phone.
But the Perez family was lucky  they survived. Nine other people remain missing following the devastation of the "large wall of water that came down the Blanco River and destroyed everything in its path," Hays County Commissioner Will Conley said on Monday..
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 29 06:49:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Republican nominee field grows to include longshot George Pataki</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/george-pataki-former-new-york-governor-launches-longshot-presidential-bid-1.3092333?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>George Pataki, former New York governor, launches longshot presidential bid
Pataki has been out of politics since 2006
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 11:49 PM ET Last Updated: May 29, 2015 12:58 AM ET
Republican presidential candidate and former New York Governor George Pataki greets supporters after formally announcing his candidacy Thursday in Exeter, N.H. (Dominik Reuter/Reuters)
Related Stories
Ted Cruz, presidential bids, and why being 1st is worst
George Pataki, the 9/11-era New York governor who achieved electoral success as a Republican in a heavily Democratic state, announced his candidacy for the presidential nomination Thursday, offering himself as a unifying figure in a divided nation.
Just as he was overshadowed after the 2001 terrorist attacks by Mayor Rudy Giuliani in New York City and President George W. Bush, Pataki opened his 2016 campaign in the shadow of better known rivals. Out of office since 2006, he's a clear underdog in a bustling pack of favourites and longshots.
Pataki told about 150 supporters that an increasingly intrusive government is jeopardizing the freedoms past generations fought for, and he will fight to get government out of people's way.
ANALYSIS I Crowded Republican field ramps up the paranoia
"It is to preserve and protect that freedom that this morning I announce I'm a candidate for the Republican nomination for president of the United States," he said.
The low-key Republican moderate flirted with presidential runs in 2008 and 2012 but stopped short. Now he hopes to reignite the bipartisan unity born in the trauma of 2001.
"While I saw the horrors of September 11 first hand, in the days, weeks and months that followed, I also saw the strength of America on display," he said. And "I completely reject the idea that we can only come together in adversity."
Pataki said Americans, with a government that does not restrain freedom, "will once again astonish the world with what we can accomplish."
Political comity is a tall order in a nation  and a party  fraught with division. But Pataki invokes his record working with Republicans and Democrats alike as a three-term governor who in 1994 defeated Mario Cuomo, the liberal stalwart and celebrated orator many Democrats wanted to see run for president.
Pataki, 69, declared his candidacy in a YouTube video, set in a New York skyscraper, and his rhetoric seemed to echo sentiments of the 9/11 aftermath. "We are all in this together," he said. "And let us all understand that what unites us is so much more important than what might seem superficially to divide us."
Shift from the centre
Without Bush's bullhorn or Giuliani's in-your-face crisis management and eloquence, Pataki worked solidly with them to steady a devastated city. He quickly mobilized New York Army and Air National Guard troops. By the evening of Sept. 11, 750 troops had already reported to armouries in New York City to support the massive security and rescue efforts.
As governor, he said, "My vision was not a partisan vision, it was a vision about people, about what we could accomplish together."
He's been a frequent visitor to New Hampshire and set his announcement event in Exeter because it was the state capital during the Revolutionary War and claims to be the birthplace of the Republican Party.
Despite his centrist leanings, he's spent recent months promoting his conservative credentials, as those running for the Republican nomination invariably do.
He's campaigned against President Barack Obama's health care law and Obama's executive order to offer protections against deportation to millions of immigrants living in the country illegally. In his announcement speech, he criticized Democratic candidate Hillary Rodham Clinton for claiming to represent aspirations of the middle class.
"We are the party of the middle class, unless by middle class they mean someone who left the White House dead broke and 10 years later had $100 million," he said of Bill and Hillary Clinton. "That's their party's candidate. She speaks for the middle class? They are the party of privilege."
Pataki didn't directly compare himself with other GOP rivals. But his wife, Libby, acknowledged the challenge her husband faces in a field that includes sitting senators, several current and former governors, business leaders and a renowned neurosurgeon.
"Are we prepared for a struggle and an uphill battle?" she asked. "We are absolutely prepared to enter the fray and fight the good fight."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:04:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS fighters fall back as Kurdish troops retake towns in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/kurdish-troops-retake-cities-in-syria-from-isis-1.3091682?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Kurdish troops retake cities in Syria from ISIS
Motivated by revolutionary fervour, Kurds succeed where Iraqi army fails
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 5:04 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 5:04 PM ET
A young Kurdish fighter battles last fall in the retaking of Kobani, Syria. The Kurds, motivated by a desire for their own homeland and backed by U.S.-led airstrikes, have now retaken more than 200 cities from ISIS fighters. (AP file photo)
Related Stories
Iraq lacks will to fight, U.S. says
In contrast to the Iraqi army's failures, Kurdish fighters in Syria are on the march against ISIS, capturing towns and villages in an oil-rich swath of the country's northeast under the cover of U.S.-led airstrikes.
As the Kurds close in on Tel Abyad, a major commercial centre on the Turkish border, their advance highlights the decisive importance of combining air power with the presence of a cohesive and motivated ally on the ground  so clearly absent in Iraq.
Iraq lacks will to fight, U.S. says
In Syria, a country now split mostly between al-Qaeda-style militants and forces loyal to embattled President Bashar al-Assad, the United States has found a reliable partner in the country's main Kurdish fighting force, known as the YPG. They are moderate, mostly secular fighters driven by revolutionary fervour and deep conviction in their cause.
Since the beginning of May, they have wrested back more than 200 Kurdish and Christian towns in northeastern Syria, as well as strategic mountains seized earlier by ISIS militants. Along the way, they have picked up ammunition, weapons and vehicles left behind by jihadists.
Key link
The push has got them closer to Tel Abyad, a major avenue for commerce for the extremist group through which it smuggles foreign fighters and sells black-market oil to help fund its conquests. The city is also a key link between Turkey and the northern Syrian city of Raqqa, the Islamic State group's de-facto capital in its self-declared caliphate.
"The YPG doesn't lack a will to fight, like soldiers in the Syrian army or soldiers in the Iraqi army who mostly fight for a salary," said Wladimir van Wilgenburg, a Middle East analyst at the Jamestown Foundation in Washington. "The YPG is much more motivated than other forces in the region, and doesn't lack cohesion and doesn't have co-ordination problems.
The Iraqi military has struggled to make gains after its humiliating defeats last year, when it virtually crumbled in the face of the militant onslaught in northern Iraq. Poor training, corruption and sectarian politics have all been cited as reasons for the military's shortcomings.
The U.S. spent billions of dollars training Iraqi forces from 2003 to 2011, but much of that training did not reach the foot soldiers battling the Islamic State group today.
Last week, U.S. Defence Secretary Ash Carter criticized the Iraqi army following the fall of Ramadi, the strategic capital of the country's largest Sunni province of Anbar, saying the Iraqi military lacked the "will to fight."
'The YPG doesn't lack a will to fight, like soldiers in the Syrian army or soldiers in the Iraqi army who mostly fight for a salary.'
- Wladimir van Wilgenburg, Middle East analyst
Within days, ISIS fighters had also dealt a major blow to Assad's forces in Syria, seizing the historic city of Palmyra, a major crossroads linking the capital, Damascus, with territory to the east and west. In images reminiscent of the Iraqi defeat in Ramadi, Syrian soldiers fled the city, leaving behind tanks and ammunition.
By contrast, Syria's Kurds have shown remarkable cohesiveness. Spurred by ideology and nationalistic fervour, they fought ferociously to claw back territory after ISIS fighters captured the Kurdish town of Kobani and dozens of surrounding villages last fall. The ISIS descent on Kobani led the U.S. to widen its air campaign from Iraq into Syria to assist the Kurds.
Despite the fact that ISIS had heavy weapons and far more fighters, the Kurds resisted the offensive on Kobani, conducting fierce street battles until the U.S. air-dropped weapons and intensified the airstrikes.
In January, the YPG liberated Kobani from the Islamic State militants and began a wide offensive in which they regained much of the territory they had lost.
On May 6, the Kurdish fighters and their allies launched an offensive from the northeastern province of Hassakeh and in less than three weeks captured the strategic Mount Abdul-Aziz along with 221 Kurdish and Christian villages that were held by ISIS.
The Kurds are now closing in on Tel Abyad with fighters moving east from Kobani and west from Hassakeh  an offensive that, if successful, would open a direct line between Kurdish-controlled territory along the border with Turkey. Such a move is likely to anger Turkey, which sees the YPG as part of the Kurdish PKK movement that has waged an anti-government insurgency in southeastern Turkey for years.
Kurdish troops were able retake Kobani, Syria, last year with the help of U.S.-led airstrikes. Now they're reclaiming more towns lost to ISIS fighters. (Associated Press file photo)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:57:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Car bombs kill 10 near major Baghdad hotels</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/car-bombs-kill-10-near-major-baghdad-hotels-1.3092126?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Car bombs kill 10 near major Baghdad hotels
Thomson Reuters Posted: May 28, 2015 8:57 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 8:57 PM ET
Smoke and flames rise from the site of car bomb attack in Baghdad on Thursday night. (Ahmed Saad/Reuters)
Related Stories
Car bombs exploded in the parking lots of two heavily fortified five-star hotels in central Baghdad late on Thursday, killing at least 10 people, police and medical sources said.
A further 30 people were wounded in the blasts, which were detonated about seven minutes apart.
Iraq lacks 'will to fight,' U.S. says
The first bomb targeted the Babylon hotel, where government officials often hold meetings and news conferences, and the second hit the Meridian.
Iraqi authorities lifted a decade-old night-time curfew on Baghdad early this year, seeking to restore a sense of normality to the capital as security forces battle ISIS militants who have overrun large parts of the country.
However, the rate of bombings in Baghdad has increased since then.
In recent days, the insurgents seized the city of Ramadi, west of Baghdad,in the most significant military setback to the government since a U.S.-led coalition launched a campaign of airstrikes against the jihadists last August.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 29 09:38:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pete Townshend honoured by Bruce Springsteen, others at MusiCares event</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/pete-townshend-honoured-by-bruce-springsteen-others-at-musicares-event-1.3092354?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Pete Townshend honoured by Bruce Springsteen, others at MusiCares event
Roger Daltrey, Joan Jett, Billy Idol also on hand in tribute to The Who guitarist
The Associated Press Posted: May 29, 2015 2:38 AM ET Last Updated: May 29, 2015 3:16 AM ET
After describing his failed attempts to recreate The Who's violent stage act as a teen,  Bruce Springsteen, left, joined Roger Daltrey and Pete Townshend onstage in New York. (Andrew H. Walker/Getty Images)
Related Stories
New-look U2 with Chris Martin, Springsteen performs at AIDS benefit
Bruce Springsteen called Pete Townshend "the greatest rhythm guitarist of all-time," told a story about attending his first Who concert as a pimply-faced teenager, and joined Townshend and surprise guest Roger Daltrey onstage for a rocking set.
The rock icons attended the MusiCares MAP Fund benefit in New York City on Thursday night, where Townshend and longtime Who manager, Bill Curbishley, were honoured for their charitable efforts.
Springsteen, Daltrey and Townshend joined forces for My Generation at the Best Buy Theater in Times Square. They closed the event with Won't Get Fooled Again, and were joined by Billy Idol and Willie Nile, who both hit the stage for solo sets earlier in the night.
"It's gonna be good. It's gonna be bad, but good-bad," Townshend said before the finale.
Springsteen presented Townshend with the Stevie Ray Vaughan Award for his commitment to the MusiCares MAP Fund, which provides members of the music community access to addiction recovery treatment regardless of their financial situation.
Pete Townshend, seen arriving at the MusiCares event in New York on Thursday, extolled the beneifts of 30 years of sobriety. (APTN/The Associated Press)
The Boss said The Who was the first rock concert he saw in the late '60s when the English band first toured America.
"All I knew was for some reason this music and the demolishing of these perfectly fine instruments filled me with incredible joy," Springsteen said.
Springsteen said he was so inspired he imitated The Who's set as a 16-year-old in the band The Castiles when he performed in the basement of St. Rose of Lima Catholic for a school dance.
"I went out and I bought a smoke bomb and I bought a strobe light and I brought them to the gig.  At the end of the night, I lit the smoke bomb in the Catholic school basement, I turned on the strobe light and I climbed on top of my Danelectro amplifier holding a vase of flowers I'd stolen from one of the upstairs classrooms," he said.
"As the nuns looked on with horror, I reached up and smashed them onto the dance floor."
Springsteen earned rousing applause from the crowd, but also got serious in his near eight-minute speech.
"Pete, I'm here to say `congratulations, well deserved.' And thanks, not just for Who's Next or Who Are You, but for who I am," he said.
Townshend, who turned 70 this month, told the crowd about smoking weed as an art student, tripping on LSD and turning to alcohol after using drugs.
"I was doing like three bottles of brandy a day ... and I think I don't look too bad for someone that drank cognac for 15 years," he said to laughs from the audience.
"But the secret for me to be able to do this tour with The Who, this 50th anniversary tour, and still kind of put on a reasonable show ... has been [because of] the 30 years I've been clean," he added to loud cheers.
Elton, Jagger pay tribute in videos
The night was a mix of laughable moments from the rock stars to high volume performances. Joan Jett rocked out in her signature black ensemble and Nile was energetic on the guitar. Daltrey was excited onstage, and enticed the crowd with his signature windmill effect with the microphone. Idol matched his energy: He danced, waved his tongue and stuck half of his microphone down his pants while he clapped as the band began playing "Who Are You," which earned Idol a standing ovation.
Elton John, Mick Jagger, Ronnie Wood and Joe Walsh appeared in videos and offered kind words to Townshend. Daltrey, 71, first appeared in a video he said was taped Thursday in England, but later surprised the crowd when he jumped onstage after Curbishley accepted the From the Heart Award.
"It's not easy to find an honest manager in this business," Daltrey said to laughs, "especially in our period. Some of the artists will tell you."
Curbishley said he was grateful that The Who has performed at benefit events like "12-12-12: The Concert for Sandy Relief" and "The Concert for New York City" in response to the Sept. 11 attacks.
Thursday's event marked the 11th annual MusiCares MAP Fund benefit concert. The organization raised $26,000 US in 1992, but raised more than $37 million last year.
A 1962 guitar that Townshend bought from Daltrey was auctioned for $41,000; both performers autographed it.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
