<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="express">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mediterranean migrants: Libya to COUNTER-ATTACK if 'colonial' EU uses military force</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/iNFJ41S4lOs/Mediterranean-migrants-crisis-Libya-counter-attack-colonial-EU-military-force</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Mediterranean migrants: Libya to COUNTER-ATTACK if 'colonial' EU uses military force
LIBYA is ready to launch a counter-attack against any military action ordered by "colonial" European Union leaders as they attempt to stop migrants crossing the Mediterranean.
10:12, Fri, May 29, 2015
| UPDATED: 10:24, Fri, May 29, 2015
PA
Around 60,000 migrants have been rescued this year alone
The North African country's Prime Minister, Khalifa al-Ghawi, today likened any forceful action co-ordinated by Brussels to the "colonial mentality" of Libya's Italian occupiers in the 20th century.
Warning of his country's "ability to defend our sea and our land", Mr al-Ghawi said the deployment of European armed forces during the ongoing migrant crisis is "completely unacceptable in the modern world".
His comments come as Britain and its European partners attempt to deal with the huge increase in refugees making the perilous, and often fatal, journey from Africa and war-torn Middle East to southern Europe, using Libya as a transit point.
The EU is currently considering the options in response to the crisis, which include sinking smuggling boats and carrying out armed operations in Libya to tackle human-trafficking gangs.
Desperate migrants are charged extortionate prices by traffickers to make the journey to Europe in perilous boats, the reason many drown, while they are often treated badly by gang members.
Getty
Migrants are making the dangerous journey with their young families
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 10:52:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japan Volcano: Terrifying moment Mount Shindake erupts forcing locals to flee paradise </title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/dKyD7A-oHWk/Japan-volcano-Mount-Shindake-erupts-forcing-locals-flee-paradise-Pacific-island</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Japan Volcano: Terrifying moment Mount Shindake erupts forcing locals to flee paradise
A REMOTE Japanese island has been completely evacuated today after the volcano at its heart suddenly erupted in spectacular fashion.
08:52, Fri, May 29, 2015
| UPDATED: 10:15, Fri, May 29, 2015
REUTERS
Mount Shindake erupted unexpectedly this morning
Mount Shindake blew its top unexpectedly this morning, sending thick plumes of choking black smoke high into the sky and deadlypyroclasticflows ofhot gas and rocksurging down its slopes.
More than 100 residents had to be ferried away on boats from the tiny tourism island of Kuchinoerabujima, around 70 miles off Japan's southern coast.
An airline was forced to divert flights around the huge plume of smoke, but officials said that there was no immediate danger to human life.
AP
Mount Sindake lies at the heart of a paradise Pacific island off Japan
REUTERS
The spectacular eruption, at 1am this morning, was caught on TV cameras
REUTERS
The eruption sent a huge pyroclastic flow hurtling down the mountainside
A 72-year-old man suffered burns to his face after being caught in the pyroclastic flow but there were no reports of other injuries among the island's 137 residents, whose only access to the outside world is by boat.
Many gathered on the roof of an evacuation centre and watched on as ash from the eruption blanketed the island's main harbour, turning it grey.
Thick smoke billowed 9,000 metres into the sky as seismologists called for "extreme caution", warning that the first eruption could spark a flurry of larger seismic events.
The huge eruption happened at around 10am local time, prompting the Japan Meteorological Agency to raise the island's alert level to five - the highest on its scale.
Japan's All Nippon Airways said it would divert some flights to Okinawa and Southeast Asia as a precaution, but that there are no plans at this stage to cancel any planes.
There were also concerns that the eruption may affect the restart of a nearby nuclear power plant, which is due to be brought back into service four years after being shut down in the wake of the Fukushima disaster.
REUTERS
The eruption could be seen for miles around
AP
The island is largely reliant on its thriving tourism and fishing businesses
AP
Seismologists have warned that the eruption could spark further volcanic activity
Nobuaki Hayashi, a local village chief, said most of the island's residents had now reached the evacuation centre.
He said: "There was a really loud, 'dong' sound of an explosion, and then black smoke rose, darkening the sky. It smelled of sulphur."
Island official Nobuaki Hayashi said only a handful of locals were still unaccounted for and that efforts to track them down were under way.
Describing the moment the volcano erupted, he added: "There was a huge bang and black smoke rose up immediately."
The island has been the site of several previous eruptions, including one in 1933 that killed several people.
Mount Shindake also erupted as recently as last summer and the area where that pyroclastic flow occurred has been off limits since then.
Japan sits atop the Pacific 'Ring of Fire' group of underwater volcanos and is frequently jolted by earthquakes.
AP
Most of the island's residents gathered at an evacuation centre to watch the eruption
REUTERS
Officials said there was little danger posed to human life by the eruption
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 10:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA corruption: Ex-vice president Jack Warner whisked out of jail for 'exhaustion'</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/lY7FllIaGzk/FIFA-corruption-Ex-vice-president-Jack-Warner-jail-exhaustion</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
FIFA corruption: Ex-vice president Jack Warner whisked out of jail for 'exhaustion'
FIFA's ex-vice president Jack Warner was whisked out of jail by ambulance yesterday - a day after he was charged with millions of pounds worth of fraud and racketeering.
08:23, Fri, May 29, 2015
| UPDATED: 10:21, Fri, May 29, 2015
Reuters
Jack Warner left jail in an ambulance after complaining about exhaustion but later gave a speech
The 72-year-old had complained of exhaustion and was not able to face questions from reporters, who had been waiting for several hours outside the jail on the Caribbean island of Trinidad where he lives.
However, a short while later Mr Warner - who was forced out of FIFA in 2011 over a bribery scandal he denies - donned a cap and a garland of flowers to give a lengthy speech before a crowd of raucous supporters in the district he represents as an opposition member of Parliament.
He said: "If I have been thieving FIFA money for 30 years, who gave me the money? How come he is not charged?
"Why only persons from third world countries have been charged?"
His speech was met with hoots and applause from supporters wearing green shirts - the colour of his Independent Liberal Party.
Mr Warner handed himself into the Trinidadian police on Wednesday and was granted a 258,000 bond but spent the night in jail.
He faces eight counts in the US, including conspiracy to defraud and to engage in racketeering, which covers money laundering, extortion and bribery.
The politician had not yet entered a plea and is expected to appear in court in July and has been ordered by a judge to surrender his passport and report to police twice a week until then.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 08:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tragedy as woman calls police to help her suicidal boyfriend – and they shoot and kill him</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/PESKyo6_59Q/Justin-Way-suicidal-Kaitlyn-Christine-police-St-Augustine-Florida-US-suicide-by-cop</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Tragedy as woman calls police to help her suicidal boyfriend and they shoot and kill him
A WOMAN who called police to get help for her suicidal boyfriend has been left distraught after the officers who turned up shot and killed him.
06:04, Fri, May 29, 2015
| UPDATED: 10:08, Fri, May 29, 2015
FACEBOOK
Justin Way was reportedly suicidal after losing his job
Kaitlyn Christine picked up the phone after her partner Justin Way threatened to kill himself while lying in bed with a large knife, in St John's County, Florida.
Mr Way had recently lost his job and had been drinking, Ms Christine told American website the Daily Beast.
She then tried to get him a place at a local hospital.
But when officers armed with assault rifles arrived at their home and stormed his room, rather than saving Mr Way they reportedly shot and killed him.
The police claimed in a report to the boyfriend's father George Way that his son tried to attack the officers with a knife.
His father said: If Justin was coming after them with a knife, at 6-foot-4, wouldnt there be blood splattered all over the room?
Mr Ways parents also allege that a detective told them they shot him because "thats what we do" and suggested that Mr Way had committed "suicide by cop".
When asked if officers usually respond to suicidal person calls with weapons, local police spokesman said that "if the deputies feel that that is the appropriate weapon system to use, then yes".
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:43:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Incredible moment woman sees dead brother's face on another man's body</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/PWhASIx4_6k/Face-transplant-woman-sees-dead-brothers-face-another-man-s-body-surgery</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Incredible moment woman sees dead brother's face on another man's body
THIS is the emotional moment a woman whose brother died in a tragic car crash saw and touched his face again - on another man's body.
02:43, Fri, May 29, 2015
| UPDATED: 03:03, Fri, May 29, 2015
IG
Rebekah touches Richard's new face
Rebekah Aversano's 21-year-old brother Joshua died in a horror car accident in 2012, but thanks to groundbreaking life-saving transplant surgery, she was able to look at his face once more.
Her family agreed to give Joshua's face to Richard Norris, 39, who was left horribly disfigured almost 18 years ago when he accidentally blew most of his face off with a shotgun.
Mr Norris, from Virginia, underwent one of the most complex and face transplants of all time, receiving a teeth, jaw and even tongue from his donor.
The incredible footage shows Mr Norris thanking Ms Aversano and her family for "saving my life".
SPLASH
Richard Norris with his new face
Wow, this is the face I grew up with
Rebekah Aversano
As the pair met for filming of 60 Minutes on Nine, Ms Aversano asked: "Do you mind if I touch it?"
She then stepped back in amazement and said: "Wow, this is the face I grew up with".
Mr Norris' accident left him so disfigured he had battled with suicidal thoughts.
He had undergone more than 30 operations to try and correct the damage and restore his features.
But three years ago the Aversano family offered him hope - and a chance to transform his life.
Joshua's mother Gwen Aversano said: "We can definitely see our son in him. Some of the facial features would definitely be our son, so we could see similarities, very much so.
"We are just so pleased we have been able to help him, even though we had such a tragic loss, we are able to give someone else the benefit of our son.
IG
Joshua Aversano died in a tragic car crash
"I asked him if it really was worth the risk, he said 'absolutely', even though there was a 50 per cent chance it would fail".
But the complex surgery has not been an easy journey for Mr Norris.
He suffered with severe sunburning and spent three weeks recovering in hospital after surgery.
And before the 36-hour controversial surgery he was warned he had a 50 per cent chance of survival - but now he has a new life.
Eduardo Rodriguez, the doctor who performed the operation at the Maryland Medical Centre, said:" He never really thought about himself in all of this.
"He's always thought about helping the wounded warriors and the other people and providing hope. He's a remarkable man."
IG
The pair embrace during the emotional meeting
The world's first partial face transplant of this kind was performed in France in 2005 on a woman who was mauled by her dog.
Of 27 other transplants that followed, four people have died.
Mr Norris' mother, Sandra has been behind her son every step of the way.
"We looked at Richard and we told him we loved him the way he was and it didn't matter to us, but it was his life.
"That as what he wanted to do and we supported him," she added.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EXCLUSIVE: Holidaymakers warned they risk returning to UK with deadly CAMEL FLU virus</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/HOySC7wU7yM/MERS-outbreak-Holidaymakers-warned-risk-returning-UK-DEADLY-VIRUS</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
EXCLUSIVE: Holidaymakers warned they risk returning to UK with deadly CAMEL FLU virus
HOLIDAYMAKERS have been warned they risk returning home with a deadly virus after a new outbreak of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) saw British patients tested.
02:47, Fri, May 29, 2015
| UPDATED: 03:03, Fri, May 29, 2015
GETTY
MERS is spread through camels and humans
Authorities in the Middle East are being urged to do more to stop the infection spreading between camels, which then pass it on to humans.
MERS  also dubbed camel flu  has been spreading among those in the region since it was first discovered in 2012.
While the majority of cases have been recorded in Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Ermirates and surrounding nations, cases have also been reported in Britain, France, Holland, Austria and Italy, with a Briton tested as recently as three weeks ago.
Starting off as flu-like symptoms, victims can then suffer pneumonia and kidney failure, and nearly 40 per cent of those contaminated end up dying.
It then spreads to those in close contact, such as relatives and hospital workers.
Jonathan Ball, a professor in virology at the University of Nottingham, said: Anything that increases the amount of travel is going to increase the chance you see sporadic infections.
GETTY
Tighter rules on the testing of camels are needed in the Middle East
People going on holiday could be at risk
Jonathan Ball
People going on holiday could be at risk. Travel isnt a great thing as it helps the virus spread but thankfully its not the most infectious virus.
If you are out to ride a camel in Saudi Arabia in particular, yes, you could be at risk. 
The disease has now spread as far as South Korea with seven elderly people infected within two weeks.
Authorities have isolated more than 70 people to try and stop the spread. But one man, aged 44, has travelled against advice to China for a business trip a day after his father was diagnosed.
All infected are connected to a 68-year-old man who was diagnosed two weeks ago after a trip to Bahrain in Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates.
His 63-year-old wife has now tested positive, as has a 76-year-old man who shared a hospital room with him.
GETTY
Muslim pilgrims arriving at Mecca's Grand Mosque for the Hajj festival poses risk of spreading MERS
In Britain patients have also been tested.
Professor Ball said: Just three weeks ago in Nottingham we had someone who had travelled to the Middle East and had severe respiratory problems. The first thing they agreed was a MERS test.
"Public Health England has measures in place.
"People in primary healthcare situations are aware that someone with severe respiratory problems need to be asked whether they have travelled to the Middle East.
There is also a risk of increased infection in Britain as people make the annual pilgrimage to Mecca in Saudi Arabia to mark the Muslim festival of Hajj in September.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Start of WW3? Putin could force the West to use NUCLEAR WEAPONS against Russia, warns NATO</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/vb84PHWfwT8/Vladimir-Putin-NATO-nuclear-weapons-Russia-Ukraine</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Start of WW3? Putin could force the West to use NUCLEAR WEAPONS against Russia, warns NATO
VLADIMIR PUTIN could seize power of the three ex-Soviet Baltic states in just TWO DAYS, forcing the West to use NUCLEAR WEAPONS against Russia, a top NATO general has warned.
02:45, Fri, May 29, 2015
| UPDATED: 06:11, Fri, May 29, 2015
GETTY
Vladimir Putin could force the West to use nuclear weapons against Russia
Europe and the United States are "embarrassingly" unprepared for Russian aggression, claimed General Petr Pavel.
The warning comes amid concerns the Russian president is massing military firepower and troops close to the Ukrainian border.
Today Putin banned revealing information about troop deaths in "special operations" during peacetime, as the Kremlin continues to rebuff accusations its soldiers are fighting in Ukraine.
Czech general Pavel, next chairman of the NATO Military Committee, issued a warning to Western leaders expressing his concern they are not ready for military action by Putin.
He said: "Russia could seize the Baltic countries in two days.
"NATO wouldn't be able to react to the situation in that time."
The Alliance would be forced to "weigh its positions regarding whether it would start a war - maybe even a nuclear war - against Russia for the Baltic states," he said.
Lithuania, Latvia and Estonia were all incorporated into the USSR by Stalin in June 1940, but are now members of NATO and the EU.
GETTY
The Ukraine-Russia crisis continues
Russia could seize the Baltic countries in two days. NATO wouldn't be able to react to the situation in that time
General Petr Pavel
General Pavel added that measures taken by Europe against threats from Russia, including Islamic State, were "embarrassingly ineffective".
He warned that NATO was hit by "weaknesses" such as a "complicated decision-making process" because it requires the agreement of 28 member states.
He said: "Russia on the other hand can make decisions very quickly, in a couple of hours."
EPA
The warning comes amid concerns the Russian president is massing military firepower near Ukraine
Putin was last year quoted as boasting: "If I wanted, Russian troops could not only be in Kiev in two days, but in Riga, Vilnius, Tallinn, Warsaw or Bucharest, too."
The warning comes as reports have pointed to a massing of Russian equipment close to the Ukraine border.
Hundreds of pieces of weaponry including mobile rocket launchers, tanks and artillery at a makeshift have been spotted.
Many vehicles have removed number plates and identifying marks, while servicemen have taken insignia off their fatigues.
AP
Putin pictured swimming. He previously boasted about marching Russian troops into Kiev
AP
A NATO general warned the West are not ready for military intervention by Vladimir Putin
The scene at the base on the Kuzminsky firing range - only 30 miles from the Ukrainian border - is said to offer "some of the clearest evidence to date of what appeared to be a concerted Russian military build-up in the area".
Ukraine and the West insist Russia has not only armed and equipped rebels, but also sent in troops to spearhead fighting against Kiev's forces.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hope for people with amnesia as scientists make breathrough into retrieving lost memories</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/oEYLqa0i8nE/Amnesia-treatment-scientists-retrieve-lost-memories-light-mice</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Hope for people with amnesia as scientists make breathrough into retrieving lost memories
HOPES for patients with severe amnesia have been raised after scientists discovered the use of LIGHT could retrieve lost memories.
22:25, Thu, May 28, 2015
| UPDATED: 22:30, Thu, May 28, 2015
GETTY
Mice were used in the experiment into the treatment of amnesia
Research carried out on mice has discovered that a lost memory is still stored within the brain cells even though the animal had apparently lost the ability to retrieve it.
In a series of experiments involving a technique called optogenetics, when blue light is used to activate a specific nerve cell in the brain, scientists found that the mice's memory was jogged.
Susumu Tonegawa of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in Cambridge, Massachusetts, said: "The majority of researchers have favoured the storage theory, but we have shown in this study that this majority theory is probably wrong.
"Amnesia is a problem of retrieval impairment."
This could be a breakthrough in the widely-discussed treatment of amnesia, as scientists have long debated its nature, with some suggesting the problem lies within the storage of the memory rather than an inability to retrieve a lost memory.
The majority of researchers have favoured the storage theory, but we have shown in this study that this majority theory is probably wrong
Susumu Tonegawa of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in Cambridge, Massachusetts
However, amnesia comes in many forms.
In some cases people have trouble forming memories after sustaining a brain injury, while others are unable to recall the events that led up to a brain injury.
The latter is called retrograde amnesia, a condition which occurs after traumatic injury, stress or disease such as Alzheimer's, which is due to the damage of the brain cells involving memory retrieval rather than where the memories are stored.
The study, published in the journal Science, discovered that the storage of the memory is caused by building new connections between nerve cells in the brain.
While the ability to retrieve the memory involves the strengthening of these connections, which can be blocked when the brain is damage by injury or disease.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Restaurant staff surprise as customer leaves £1,300 tip for £60 meal</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/mF7uOrC9H8M/Washington-DC-diner-1300-tip</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Restaurant staff surprise as customer leaves 1,300 tip for 60 meal
RESTAURANT staff got more than they bargained for when they got a 1,300 tip for a customer's 60 meal.
22:18, Thu, May 28, 2015
| UPDATED: 22:22, Thu, May 28, 2015
GOOGLE MAPS
Staff at this small diner got a 1,300 tip
Waiters and waiteresses got the extra bonus after a customer, believed to be a regular at the eatery, had a three-course meal with a friend.
The pair had eaten fried chicken and gumbo and drank Old Chub Scotch Ale before leaving.
And it was only as workers at the restaurant started to get ready to close that bartender Laura Dally made the amazing discovery.
She picked up the holder of the bill, which contained a credit card slip which showed the man making a tip for $2000 - the equivalent of 1,300.
And on the slip was a note saying "thank you for the gumbo".
Ms Dally told the Washington Post: "I was in utter shock.
"I was completely speechless. I had to do a double take."
CHRISTOFER NARDELLI
The tip given to staff at Blue 44
This is the kind of stuff you see in the restaurant business that happens to some guy in the Midwest or the West Coast.
Christofer Nardelli
Having seen the tip, she went to speak to restaurant owner Christofer Nardelli, who runs the Blue 44 eatery in Washington, US.
Mr Nardelli, who has run the business since 2011, said that he didn't want to name his benefactor.
He said: "This is the kind of stuff you see in the restaurant business that happens to some guy in the Midwest or the West Coast.
"You think, who are these people who give these extraordinarily generous tips that just made a server or bartenders day? And then sure enough, it happened to us."
The patron, who has been in regular contact with the diner about recipe ideas and suitable beers to go with food, left instructions as to how his gift should be split up.
He wanted Ms Dally and Mr Nardelli to both get $500 (326) each and for chef James Turner to get $1,000 (652).
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First picture of tragic toddler pushed in swing by mother for hours while dead</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/WhUsuEWS7lU/Picture-dead-American-toddler-JiAire-Lee-pushed-swing-mother-Romechia-Simms</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
First picture of tragic toddler pushed in swing by mother for hours while dead
THIS is the first picture of a toddler who was found dead in a swing being pushed by his dazed mother.
21:23, Thu, May 28, 2015
| UPDATED: 21:43, Thu, May 28, 2015
FACEBOOK
Ji'Aire was found dead in a swing being pushed by his mother in a park
Romechia Simms, 24, was found by police swinging her dead son Ji'Aire Lee, three, for what investigators described as a "unusual amount of time".
Detectives think she may have been there all night.
She will not be charged in relation to the incident and is being treated at a local hospital.
Her mother Vontasha Simms said her daughter would never do anything to hurt her son as she spoke for the first time since the discovery last Friday in Maryland, United States.
It is understood the family were homeless and living in a hotel. Ms Simms's mother said she was diagnosed with depression about three months ago while struggling to care for her son.
She said: "[Romechia] would never harm my grandson in any type of way. You know, I just believe she had some type of mental illness, some type of mental break that came upon her where she wasn't able to get herself out of that situation.
WUSA
Police believe Ji'Aire and his mother may have been in the park all night
WUSA
Tributes have been left at the park
That's my little man - he loved having fun just like me
James "Donnell" Lee
"I don't want people to look down upon her I want people to use the situation as an opportunity to grow, learn from it. Like I said, help your neighbour, if you suffer from mental issues and you need help, don't be afraid to reach out to somebody."
It is understood Ji'Aire was at the centre of a custody battle between Ms Simms and father James "Donnell" Lee.
He said he felt angry that a court judge didn't look closer at Ms Simm's issues.
He said he was due to see Ji'Aire for the first time in a month on Saturday. But as he tried to call her over the Wednesday and Thursday he became concerned.
He said: "That's my little man - he loved having fun just like me.
He'll always be - that's my little man."
Two GoFundMe pages have been set up to pay for Ji'Aire's funeral, raising more than $10,000 between them.
GOFUNDME
Ji'Aire's dad James Donnell Lee revealed he had recently lost a custody battle
One explains how they want to give their "angel" a "proper homecoming.
The other writes: "He was adored by a huge family including a brother, grandparents, aunts, uncles, and cousins. He loved being outdoors, sports especially basketball, pizza, McDonald's french fries, the color red, and was the center of attention at social gatherings."
Police are still compiling a full timeline of events to work out how Ji'Aire came to his death.
A post-mortem examination has been conducted but findings are incomplete as toxicology tests are still to be returned.
Diane Richardson, of the Charles County Sherrif's Office, said: "This is a top priority for us.
"This is a three-year-old boy that's deceased. We don't know the cause of death. There are no obvious signs of trauma, but he is deceased and our detectives are working around the clock trying to put information together to answer the question as to how this child died."
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
