<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="FOX News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:54:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As bailout talks stall, Greek bank deposits fall to lowest level in more than a decade</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/_KzN_EjUlJo/</Link>
        <Description>Greek bank deposits have fallen to their lowest in more than a decade, new statistics show, as Greeks worried about their new government's painfully slow negotiations with creditors withdraw savings.</Description>
        <MainBody>As bailout talks stall, Greek bank deposits fall to lowest level in more than a decade
Published May 29, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
ATHENS, Greece  Greek bank deposits have fallen to their lowest in more than a decade, new statistics show, as Greeks worried about their new government's painfully slow negotiations with creditors withdraw savings.
Figures from the European Central Bank published Friday showed more than 5 billion euros ($5.5 billion) were withdrawn in April.
That leaves household deposits at the end of the month at 139.4 billion euros ($151.9 billion), down from 145 billion euros in March. The figure is the lowest since November 2004, when deposits stood at 137.2 billion euros.
Athens has insisted in recent days it is close to a deal, indicating an agreement could come as soon as this weekend that would unlock desperately needed funds from its international bailout. But European officials have said much remains to be done.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:07:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Madagascar parliamentarians seek to oust president in renewal of political turmoil</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/hMtSntPRIrw/</Link>
        <Description>Political instability is looming in Madagascar, where lawmakers voted this week to impeach the country's president for what they say are his repeated violations of the constitution.</Description>
        <MainBody>Madagascar parliamentarians seek to oust president in renewal of political turmoil
Published May 29, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
ANTANANARIVO, Madagascar  Political instability is looming in Madagascar, where lawmakers voted this week to impeach the country's president for what they say are his repeated violations of the constitution.
The parliamentarians say they secured a two-thirds majority required for an impeachment motion, which now goes to the constitutional court for review. However, President Hery Rajaonarimampianina says they fell short of the majority and that the lawmakers are bitter about not being granted certain perks such as new vehicles.
Relations between parliament and the president have been strained for months.
Madagascar endured political turmoil and economic deterioration after a 2009 coup. Rajaonarimampianina took office after elections at the end of 2013.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:00:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France and Morocco vow to strengthen counterterrorism cooperation after diplomatic rift</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/qTTqeL7rJQc/</Link>
        <Description>France and Morocco have vowed to strengthen counterterrorism cooperation, four months after they resumed judicial cooperation following a year-long diplomatic rift.</Description>
        <MainBody>France and Morocco vow to strengthen counterterrorism cooperation after diplomatic rift
Published May 29, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
PARIS  France and Morocco have vowed to strengthen counterterrorism cooperation, four months after they resumed judicial cooperation following a year-long diplomatic rift.
After meeting with French president Francois Hollande on Friday, Moroccan Prime Minister Abdelilah Benkilane said: "We had a difficult year of course, now it's behind us, and (relations) are resuming as if nothing had happened."
French authorities say counterterrorism and the fight against radicalization were at the top of the agenda for the meeting.
Both countries are deeply concerned by the large numbers of citizens leaving to fight with the Islamic State group in Syria and Iraq.
Morocco suspended judicial cooperation in February 2014 after French police attempted to arrest the visiting head of Moroccan intelligence. Cooperation resumed in January.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:59:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italy's rising Northern League leader champions anti-migrant themes in regional elections</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/PIwqwW7ySZE/</Link>
        <Description>The community's hostility is veiled, but palpable.</Description>
        <MainBody>Italy's rising Northern League leader champions anti-migrant themes in regional elections
Published May 29, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
In this picture taken on Wednesday, May 27, 2015, Issa Konate, from Mali, attends an interview with The Associated Press past election posters near a migrant holding center in Baone, near Padua, northern Italy Housing migrants who continue to flood Italy, many risking death in Mediterranean crossings, has become a contentious campaign issue in Italian regional elections set for Sunday. It has unleashed a wave of anti-migrant resentment that Matteo Salvini, the up-and-coming leader of the populist Northern League, has both benefited from and fomented. (AP Photo/Antonio Calanni)(The Associated Press)
In this picture taken on Wednesday, May 27, 2015, Issa Konate, from Mali, walks past election posters near a migrant holding center in Baone, near Padua, northern Italy. Housing migrants who continue to flood Italy, many risking death in Mediterranean crossings, has become a contentious campaign issue in Italian regional elections set for Sunday. It has unleashed a wave of anti-migrant resentment that Matteo Salvini, the up-and-coming leader of the populist Northern League, has both benefited from and fomented. (AP Photo/Antonio Calanni)(The Associated Press)
In this picture taken on Wednesday, May 27, 2015, a migrant walks past a migrant holding center in Baone, near Padua, northern Italy. Housing migrants who continue to flood Italy, many risking death in Mediterranean crossings, has become a contentious campaign issue in Italian regional elections set for Sunday. It has unleashed a wave of anti-migrant resentment that Matteo Salvini, the up-and-coming leader of the populist Northern League, has both benefited from and fomented. (AP Photo/Antonio Calanni)(The Associated Press)
In this picture taken on Wednesday, May 27, 2015, a migrant works in a migrant holding center in Baone, near Padua, northern Italy. Housing migrants who continue to flood Italy, many risking death in Mediterranean crossings, has become a contentious campaign issue in Italian regional elections set for Sunday. It has unleashed a wave of anti-migrant resentment that Matteo Salvini, the up-and-coming leader of the populist Northern League, has both benefited from and fomented. (AP Photo/Antonio Calanni)(The Associated Press)
In this picture taken on Wednesday, May 27, 2015, the Rev. Luca Favarin, second left, poses for pictures with migrants in a migrant holding center in Baone, near Padua, northern Italy.  Favarin runs the Percorso Vita charity, which has been trying to find private homes for new arrivals in Padua province. He says the province took in just 500 new migrants last year, less than half of its 2014 quota, despite the availability of EU funds. Housing migrants who continue to flood Italy, many risking death in Mediterranean crossings, has become a contentious campaign issue in Italian regional elections set for Sunday. It has unleashed a wave of anti-migrant resentment that Matteo Salvini, the up-and-coming leader of the populist Northern League, has both benefited from and fomented. (AP Photo/Antonio Calanni)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
RIVODOLMO, Italy  The community's hostility is veiled, but palpable. When the young migrants from Nigeria and Gambia venture away from their house in this hilltop idyll south of Padua, they say neighbors come out and snap their photos in a gesture of intimidation. They have been pressured to stop using the local soccer field, accused of taking the pitch away from Italian kids.
Housing migrants who continue to flood Italy, many risking death in Mediterranean crossings, has become a contentious campaign issue in Italian regional elections set for Sunday. It has unleashed a wave of anti-migrant resentment that Matteo Salvini, the up-and-coming leader of the populist Northern League, has both benefited from and fomented.
Salvini's anti-immigrant, anti-Europe party is poised to be the second largest vote-getter in seven regional votes this weekend, including the wealthy Veneto region where Padua is located. The provocative leader has backed Padua's Northern League mayor in his opposition to a program by Rome officials to seek private homes to shelter the migrants.
"We don't know who we are putting next-door," Salvini told The Associated Press by telephone from Sicily, where he was campaigning. "There are no controls, no guarantees, not even for health. ... It is a problem of safety and cohabitation. There are 4 million Italians without work, and millions more living under the poverty level. I don't think we can give housing to half the world."
He is unapologetic about fears that such rhetoric could encourage racism. He says Italy's 5 million legally resident migrants are "welcome" and noted that Britain's conservative Prime Minister David Cameron won elections in Britain "saying he wouldn't even take one immigrant," referring to Britain's refusal to take part in a proposed EU quota system for distributing asylum-seekers around Europe.
Salvini hopes to ride the anti-establishment wave evident in recent elections in Poland and Spain. He called the results "a slap in the face for Europe, the common currency and migration." The Northern League, under Salvini, is seeking to become the rallying point for Italy's nationalist right, venting its anger at Brussels in a bid to widen its appeal beyond its traditional secessionist base with roots in northern Italy. Despite his attempt to moderate some of the Northern League's past rhetoric, particularly against southern Italy, he still riles public opinion in campaign stops across the country.
Political analysts say the major electoral concern among Italian voters remains the economy, as the country weakly pulls itself out of recession. But in Veneto the race between the Northern League's incumbent Gov. Luca Zaia and the Democratic Party candidate Alessandra Moretti is also being shaped by the emotional migrant issue. Italy has been struggling to deal with the huge inflows of migrants, with more than 26,500 landings this year through the end of last month, on top of last year's total of 170,100. And the Northern League has found fertile ground for its message in Veneto, once the powerhouse behind the Italian economic miracle of the 1960s, which now has fallen on hard times.
"The number one priority is lack of jobs, which generates frustration and anger, the desire for change, along with indecision and polarization," said Roberto D'Alimonte of Rome's LUISS University. Experts are projecting high levels of absenteeism.
Polls indicate the results could catapult the Northern League to second place in the overall regional vote count, behind Premier Matteo Renzi's Democratic Party, which would make the Northern League the main opposition party. It would allow Salvini's camp to overtake Beppe Grillo's anti-establishment 5-Star Movement as the principal lightning rod for disaffected voters. But Salvini is setting his ambitions higher: He wants to take command of Italy's center-right  which has suffered a void as former Premier Silvio Berlusconi has found himself crippled politically by a tax fraud conviction.
Europe was shocked into devising a plan to accommodate the migrants, and ease pressure on Italy, after more than 800 people were believed to have drowned an April shipwreck. The result is a proposed national quota system aimed at helping Italy and Greece manage the massive influx of migrants  and oblige reluctant EU partners to share the burden.
But the Rev. Luca Favarin, who runs the Percorso Vita charity, which has been trying to find private homes for new arrivals in Padua province, says the province took in just 500 new migrants last year, less than half of its 2014 quota set by the Interior Ministry, despite the availability of EU funds. He is currently working with the national prefect in Padua on getting approval to put migrants in 23 homes on the grounds that keeping migrants in smaller groups spread through the territory created a more familial environment and made it easier for locals to get to know them, and help them with their trauma.
He acknowledges that the plan  by spreading migrants over a wider area  "makes more people unhappy."
In Rivadolmo, a total of 22 migrants are living in a spacious house that belongs to a man serving prison time for pedophilia. Favarin said the reaction of neighbors has been "borderline racist."
Amadu Jatta, a 30-year-old Gambian, said he was photographed as he walked down the street earlier this week. He said he believed it was for posting on a community Facebook page that includes comments, often derogatory, on the migrants' presence. The page includes complaints that the migrants had taken over the local soccer field, displacing a group of 11 and 12-year-olds who had been playing for an hour. The entry is titled "Here is the integration of our ... political refugees!"
"Maybe they are against us," Jatta said, adding that the photo-taking made him uncomfortable. "We are not afraid. We don't do anything. We just walk."
Favarin said he also has been abused by residents: "When I go down the street, people spit on me, they accuse me, they use vulgar language."
The migrants pass the time waiting for their asylum applications to be processed, learning woodwork and tending a small garden. They make occasional trips to the police station to process their requests, and to the train stations to meet newcomers. Sometimes they go on cultural outings. Favarin said they have created no disturbances during their stay.
"We believe that welcoming the migrants is a value that you cannot debate," Favarin said. "You can debate the methods, you can debate the timing and the resources, but taking them in, from a human and Christian point of view, cannot be a matter of debate."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:54:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Correction: Norway-Myanmar-Rohingya story</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/nda_9vWFXP4/</Link>
        <Description>In a story May 28 about Nobel Peace Prize winners calling for an end to persecution of Myanmar's Rohingya Muslims, The Associated Press reported erroneously that the appeal came at the end of a three-day conference organized by the Norwegian Burma Committee.</Description>
        <MainBody>Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
COPENHAGEN, Denmark  In a story May 28 about Nobel Peace Prize winners calling for an end to persecution of Myanmar's Rohingya Muslims, The Associated Press reported erroneously that the appeal came at the end of a three-day conference organized by the Norwegian Burma Committee. There were two conferences over the three days, one organized by a coalition of international groups and the other by the Norwegian Burma Committee. The appeal by the Nobel Peace Prize winners was made Tuesday during the conference organized by the international groups, but not announced until they put out a statement Thursday.
A corrected version of the story is below
COPENHAGEN, Denmark (AP)  Several Nobel Peace Prize winners have called for an end to the persecution of Myanmar's Rohingya Muslims, describing it as "nothing less than genocide," and appealed for international help for them in Rakhine state.
The appeal followed two conferences in the Norwegian capital where participants witnessed video addresses from Nobel Peace Prize laureates, including from South Africa's retired Archbishop Desmond Tutu, Iranian human rights activist Shirin Ebadi and former East Timor President Jose Ramos-Horta.
"What Rohingyas are facing is a textbook case of genocide in which an entire indigenous community is being systematically wiped out by the Burmese government," the final statement said.
Held at the Nobel Institute in Oslo, the conference urged the international community "to take all possible measures to pressure" the Myanmar government to "immediately end its policies and practices of genocide."
Philanthropist George Soros, who escaped Nazi-occupied Hungary, said that there were "alarming" parallels between the plight of the Rohingya and the Nazi genocide.
Pro-democracy icon Aung San Suu Kyi hadn't been invited to the event, organized by several international organizations. During her 15 years under house arrest, the Nobel Peace Prize laureate won admiration for her fiery speeches and scathing criticism of the military regime that ruled Myanmar, or Burma, at the time. Her critics note she is carefully choosing her battles, in part because she has presidential ambitions.
In recent weeks, thousands of Rohingya have fled persecution and landed on the shores of Indonesia, Malaysia and Thailand, often abandoned by human traffickers or freed after their families paid ransoms. There are approximately 1.3 million Rohingya Muslims.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:53:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Twin car bombings in Baghdad kill at least 15 </title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/nYipTPGeVYw/</Link>
        <Description>The death toll from bombings that targeted two prominent hotels in Baghdad a day earlier rose to 15 people, with another 42 wounded, Iraqi authorities said on Friday, as a lawmaker warned that the capital is vulnerable to more attacks.</Description>
        <MainBody>Twin car bombings in Baghdad kill at least 15
Published May 29, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
May 29, 2015: Civilians and security forces inspect the aftermath of a car bomb attack in the parking lot of Babil hotel in Karrada neighborhood, Baghdad, Iraq. (AP Photo/Hadi Mizban)
The death toll from bombings that targeted two prominent hotels in Baghdad a day earlier rose to 15 people, with another 42 wounded, Iraqi authorities said on Friday, as a lawmaker warned that the capital is vulnerable to more attacks.
The double bombing occurred late Thursday when two separate car bombs went off in the parking lots of the Cristal, formerly Sheraton, and Babil hotels. Initial reports said 10 people were killed and 27 wounded, but the casualty figures rose overnight.
The two explosions shattered windows of the recently renovated hotels and destroyed several cars. Baghdad's top hotels are usually crowded on Thursday nights with people attending wedding celebrations or parties.
The twin attacks targeting heavily secured buildings in the heart of Baghdad demonstrate the boldness and freedom with which militants have been able to operate inside the capital.
Police said a third car bomb found near the Babil Hotel was discovered and defused early Friday. A police officer blamed the infiltration on the negligence of the hotel guards and the weak security measures adopted by police in Baghdad.
All officials spoke on condition of anonymity because they are not authorized to speak to the media.
Sameer al-Shwaili, a spokesman for government's Anti-Terrorism Apparatus, said that more attacks on Baghdad are expected as military operations continue in an effort to drive out ISIS militants from the Sunni-majority provinces of Anbar and Salahuddin.
"The situation is directly related to operations in Anbar, and operations in Tikrit. Iraq is in a state of war and what happened in Baghdad is a product of that war," al-Shwaili told The Associated Press in a telephone interview.
Nobody has claimed responsibility for the attacks, but al-Shwaili placed the blame on ISIS.
"Car bombs and bombs are typically used by Daesh in a way to create fear among the citizens of Iraq," he said, using the Arabic acronym for the terror group.
Iraq witnesses almost daily attacks that have been frequently claimed by ISIS, which seized large swaths of the country during a blitz last year and recently overran the city of Ramadi, provincial capital of Anbar province.
Fighting also continues in several parts of Salahuddin province, where government forces -- backed by Shiite militias and airstrikes from the U.S.-led coalition -- took back the city of Tikrit from IS militants earlier this year.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:44:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rocky road: A look at key milestones in Britain's troubled ties to the European Union</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/KUifCaYhOII/</Link>
        <Description>The British people will get another chance to decide on their European future by the end of 2017 &amp;mdash; marking one more milestone in a long-troubled relationship.</Description>
        <MainBody>Rocky road: A look at key milestones in Britain's troubled ties to the European Union
Published May 29, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
FILE - In this March 10, 1961 file photo, France's President, Charles De Gaulle speaks at the French General Assembly, in Paris. Britains ambitions to become a member of the European Economic Community were twice dealt a blow in the 1960s when de Gaulle vetoed the countrys applications. Non, he said, claiming that Britain could bring about the end of what was then commonly referred to as the common market. (AP Photo/Levy, File)(The Associated Press)
FILE - In this Oct. 19, 1972 file photo, European leaders pose for a photograph, at the European Common Market summit conference, with French President Georges Pompidou fourth from right stands next to Britain's Prime Minister Edward Heath, third from right, at an Elysee Palace luncheon, in Paris. Britain finally joined the "common market' at the start of 1973 after Heath managed to douse concerns in Europe. Britains cause was helped by the resignation of French President Charles de Gaulle in 1969. His successor Pompidou proved far more amenable to Britains membership. (AP Photo/Michel Lipchitz, File)(The Associated Press)
FILE - In this Oct. 15, 1984 file photo, Britain's Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher greets France's Jacques Delors, the then president-elect of the European Commission, inside 10 Downing Street, London. Though Thatcher had been a prominent supporter of  British membership of the European Economic Community in the 1975 referendum her 11-year premiership became increasingly dominated by her opposition to it. In fact, it was her vocal antipathy to the growing integrationist tendencies in Europe, epitomized by Delors, that contributed to her downfall in 1990.  (Pool Photo via AP,  File)(The Associated Press)
FILE - In this Dec. 9, 1991 file photo European leaders pose during a summit in Maastricht, Netherlands including Britain's Prime Minister John Major, front second right. Margaret Thatchers successor as prime minister, Major, tried to mend fences with Britains partners in Europe. Perhaps the most notable achievement of his premiership was the opt-out he managed to secure for Britain from joining the euro in Maastricht in 1991. However, his Conservative government soon descended into internecine warfare over Europe. (AP Photo/Pfeil, File)(The Associated Press)
FILE - In this Tuesday, June 17, 1997 file photo,  Britain's Prime Minister Tony Blair foreground mounts a bike, along with European leaders in the Dutch city of Amsterdam.  One of Blairs ambitions after his Labour Party won a landslide election victory in May, 1997, was to put Britain at the heart of Europe. However, his decision to join the U.S.-led war in Iraq in 2003 put him at odds with many in Europe, notably French President Jacques Chirac. And any hopes he may have had of Britain joining the euro were doused by his finance minister and subsequent successor, Gordon Brown. (AP Photo/Hermann Knippertz, File)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
LONDON  The British people will get another chance to decide on their European future by the end of 2017  marking one more milestone in a long-troubled relationship.
The planned referendum on Britain's membership in the 28-country European Union following a renegotiation of some of the terms of the country's membership is a key element of the new Conservative government's program.
Prime Minister David Cameron was Friday on the second day of a whistle-stop tour of European capitals, trying to convince leaders to offer concessions, including limits to welfare benefits EU migrants can claim.
Europe's been a source of contention for decades in Britain. The British may love Alpine skiing, the horrors of Scandi-noir drama and the late-night hotspots on the Spanish island of Ibiza, but they have often been ambivalent over being part of a political and economic union with Europe.
Many reasons have been cited for the complex relationship.
Maybe it's to do with Britain's "special relationship" with the United States. Maybe it's just to do with the fact that the British are an island people, wary of the entanglements and shifting alliances that have played out on the European continent since the Norman conquest of 1066, through the Spanish Armada, the Napoleonic Wars and two world wars.
Ironically, it was former British leader Winston Churchill who called for "a kind of United States of Europe" in the grim aftermath of World War II.
But when the fledgling European Coal and Steel Community launched in 1951, Britain was nowhere to be seen. It also opted against joining the six founding nations of what was then the European Economic Community in 1957.
Britain has seemed a land apart, even after it joined in 1973.
Here are some memorable events in Britain's relationship with Europe.
___
De Gaulle Says Non  Twice
Though Britain was absent at the EEC's formation, it soon changed its mind. Its ambitions, though, were twice rejected by a former ally  the French president, General Charles de Gaulle.
"Non," he said in 1963, and again in 1967.
De Gaulle, who spent much of World War II in London when France was under occupation, warned his five EEC partners  Belgium, the Netherlands, Luxembourg, Italy and West Germany  that Britain had a "deep-seated hostility" to European integration that could bring about the end of what was then commonly referred to as the "common market." He also worried that in crunch times, Britain would always side with the United States over its continental neighbors.
___
1975 Referendum: The People say Yes
Edward Heath, who became Conservative prime minister in 1970, made membership of the EEC a key objective. De Gaulle's successor, Georges Pompidou, was far more amenable to British membership and by 1973 Britain finally joined. However, with the opposition Labour Party increasingly conflicted over Europe, accession would not be smooth.
Labour's leader, Harold Wilson, thought a referendum following a renegotiation would overcome the cracks in his party. That referendum in June 1975, Britain's first-ever national plebiscite, was held after Labour's return to power. A majority of 67 percent said "yes" to the question: Do you think that the United Kingdom should remain part of the European Community?
Though membership was secured, the divides within Labour didn't go away, with many leading Cabinet ministers viewing the EEC as incompatible with the aims of socialism. That fissure, among others, would weaken Labour and pave the way for the election in 1979 of Margaret Thatcher's Conservatives.
____
Thatcher's Party Splits over Europe
Thatcher was a keen backer of the 'yes' campaign, even venturing to wear a sweater with the flags of the member countries sewed in. However, her 11 years in Downing Street were marked by growing opposition to Europe.
Though her government backed the creation of the single European market in the mid-1980s, she became increasingly hostile to the move to further integrate European countries.
The appointment of French socialist Jacques Delors to head the executive European Commission, added fuel to her fire. Thatcher and a growing part of the Conservative Party were aghast at Delors' ambition for a single currency.
In a 1988 speech, Thatcher rejected the prospect of a "European super-state exercising a new dominance from Brussels." Not everyone in her party was that hostile, and Thatcher's growing antipathy to Europe prompted the 1990 resignation of her foreign secretary and led to a leadership battle. Thatcher's time was up.
Her successor, John Major, sought to mend fences with Europe, even while keeping Britain out of the single currency  Game, Set and Match, he claimed. His government would soon after descend into conflict over Europe.
___
Blair on a Bike
When Tony Blair won in a landslide in 1997, he made Labour a decidedly pro-European party. Britain, he said, would be at the "heart of Europe." He even indicated a willingness to join the euro, which launched in 1999. The image of the young premier on a bike in Amsterdam a few weeks after his election triumph with other European leaders symbolized the new approach.
Blair built bridges initially, but his decision to back the U.S.-led war in Iraq in 2003 put him at odds with French President Jacques Chirac and German Chancellor Gerhard Schroeder. Plans to join the euro stalled and Blair's European enthusiasm hit a roadblock.
____
Referendum Redux
With Blair's departure in 2007, pro-Europeans lost a key voice. His successor, Gordon Brown, was more lukewarm while the opposition Conservatives morphed into a primarily Euroskeptic party. In 2011, Prime Minister David Cameron vetoed an EU treaty designed to help stabilize the euro, which was struggling following a debt crisis.
And with the U.K. Independence Party making headway with its demand for a fresh vote on Britain's membership, and its assertion that Britain had ceded too much sovereignty to Brussels, Cameron felt compelled to promise a referendum to bind his party together.
The Conservatives' recent surprise victory has put that referendum in motion. That vote will take place by the end of 2017.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:35:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US says China has artillery vehicles on artificial island in South China Sea</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/mjqBpS_-tH8/</Link>
        <Description>U.S. officials say that two large artillery vehicles have been detected on one of the artificial islands that China is creating in the South China Sea.</Description>
        <MainBody>US says China has artillery vehicles on artificial island in South China Sea
Published May 29, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
SINGAPORE  U.S. officials say that two large artillery vehicles have been detected on one of the artificial islands that China is creating in the South China Sea.
The discovery, made at least several weeks ago by the United States, underscores ongoing concerns that China will try to use the land reclamation projects for military purposes.
Pentagon spokesman Brent Colburn says the U.S. was aware of the artillery, but he declined to provide other details, saying it is an intelligence matter. The revelation comes as Defense Secretary Ash Carter visits several Asia Pacific nations.
Another defense official described the weapons as self-propelled artillery vehicles. The official was not authorized to discuss the matter publicly so spoke on condition of anonymity.
The sighting was first reported by the Wall Street Journal.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:30:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mistress, now wife, of ex-Czech PM, 3 spy agency officials acquitted of abuse of power charges</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/pvUCEmDvlRM/</Link>
        <Description>A Prague court has acquitted the wife of former Czech Prime Minister Petr Necas of abuse of power charges in a case that brought down his government.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mistress, now wife, of ex-Czech PM, 3 spy agency officials acquitted of abuse of power charges
Published May 29, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
PRAGUE  A Prague court has acquitted the wife of former Czech Prime Minister Petr Necas of abuse of power charges in a case that brought down his government.
Jana Necasova, formerly Jana Nagyova, was charged along with two former heads of the military intelligence agency, Ondrej Palenik and Milan Kovanda, and intelligence agent Jan Pohunek.
Prosecutors charged that Nagyova  then Necas' chief of staff and mistress  ordered the military intelligence agency to spy on Necas' estranged wife in 2012.
Necasova and the three pleaded not guilty.
The Prague 1 district court ruled Friday to acquit them. The verdict is not final, and prosecutors can appeal.
After his government fell in June 2013, Necas admitted his affair with Nagyova and divorced his first wife.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:29:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ahead of presidential election, Blatter says vote for Russia and Qatar the root of FIFA crisis</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/8NcEz5kWRvk/</Link>
        <Description>The worst corruption crisis in soccer history stems from the governing body's decision to award Russia and Qatar the next two World Cup tournaments, FIFA President Sepp Blatter said Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ahead of presidential election, Blatter says vote for Russia and Qatar the root of FIFA crisis
Published May 29, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
FIFA president Joseph S. Blatter, right, walks past Prince Ali bin al-Hussein, left, and UEFA President Michel Platini, center, during the 65th FIFA Congress held at the Hallenstadion in Zurich, Switzerland, Friday, May 29, 2015, where he will run for re-election as FIFA head. (Walter Bieri/Keystone via AP)(The Associated Press)
FIFA president Joseph S. Blatter delivers a speech during the 65th FIFA Congress held at the Hallenstadion in Zurich, Switzerland, Friday, May 29, 2015, where he will run for re-election. (Walter Bieri/Keystone via AP)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
ZURICH  The worst corruption crisis in soccer history stems from the governing body's decision to award Russia and Qatar the next two World Cup tournaments, FIFA President Sepp Blatter said Friday.
Blatter spoke at the FIFA congress hours before the presidential election in which he is a seeking a fifth term. He has refused calls to resign after FIFA was targeted by U.S. and Swiss authorities in separate corruption investigations.
In 2010, Russia was chosen to host the 2018 World Cup and Qatar was awarded the 2022 tournament amid widespread allegations of wrongdoing.
"If two other countries had emerged from the envelope, I think we would not have these problems today," Blatter said. "But we can't go back in time. We are not prophets. We can't say what would have happened."
The United States was one of the losing bidders for the 2022 World Cup. On Wednesday, U.S. authorities indicted 14 people on bribery, racketeering, fraud and money-laundering charges going back to the 1990s.
Seven of the officials  including two serving FIFA vice presidents  were arrested in Zurich on Wednesday ahead of the congress.
The two criminal investigations have cast a new shadow on Blatter's 17-year reign as president of FIFA. The 209 FIFA member nations will decide later Friday whether to stick with the 79-year-old Blatter or vote for Prince Ali bin al-Hussein of Jordan.
Amid the dramatic build up to the election, UEFA president Michel Platini appealed to Blatter to immediately step down  calls the president has rejected.
"I am willing to accept the president of FIFA is responsible for everything but I would at least like to share that responsibility with everyone," Blatter said in a presidential address on Friday morning. "We cannot constantly supervise everyone in football ... you cannot ask everyone to behave ethically."
Blatter also cautioned that "it will take some time" to rebuild FIFA's reputation.
"The events of Wednesday have unleashed a storm and there was even questioned whether this congress would be organized or change the agenda," Blatter said. "Today I am appealing to unity and team spirit so we can move forward together. That may not always be easy but it is for this reason that we are here together today."
A two-thirds majority would be enough for Blatter or Prince Ali to win the secret presidential vote, or a simple majority in a second round of voting. Just forcing the ballot to a second round could represent a victory of sorts for Blatter's critics, denying the incumbent president an emphatic mandate in his next term.
Blatter's opening address to the congress was briefly disrupted by a pro-Palestinian activist, who held up a red card and shouted "Red card to racism." The protest was to draw attention to a campaign that aims to stop Palestinian players from being detained by Israeli security forces.
After calling for security, Blatter announced: "I would ask you to please check the access points of this room."
___
Rob Harris can be followed at www.twitter.com/RobHarris
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
