<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Global News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:55:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Officials monitor river levels in Texas, with focus on Houston area</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024560/officials-monitor-river-levels-in-texas-with-focus-on-houston-area/</Link>
        <Description>Officials are closely monitoring the levels of rivers in Texas engorged by the deluge of last weekend.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015 6:55 am
Officials monitor river levels in Texas, with focus on Houston area
By   Juan A. Lozano And Seth Robbins The Associated Press
Wilber Albarenga, left, and Alfredo Chavez, pump water from the United Orthodox Synagogues of Houston, which suffered extensive damage by flooding from a recent storm Wednesday, May 27, 2015, in Houston.
Gary Coronado/Houston Chronicle via AP
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
HOUSTON  Officials are closely monitoring the levels of rivers in Texas engorged by the deluge of last weekend.
The Colorado River in Wharton and the Brazos and San Jacinto Rivers near Houston are the focus of attention for officials as floodwaters from North and Central Texas move downstream toward the Gulf of Mexico.
The death toll continued to rise as search teams dig through debris piles along rivers that raged through Central Texas and the Houston area. The confirmed death toll Friday was at least 24, with 20 in Texas alone, and at least 14 others missing.
Homecoming Queen dies in Texas floods while driving home from prom
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:22:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>King Willem-Alexander, Queen Maxima of the Netherlands visit Toronto today</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024545/king-willem-alexander-queen-maxima-of-the-netherlands-visit-toronto-today/</Link>
        <Description>King Willem-Alexander and Queen Maxima of the Netherlands will be in Toronto today as part of their three-day trip to Canada.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
King Willem-Alexander and Queen Maxima of the Netherlands will be in Toronto today as part of their three-day trip to Canada.
The visit comes on the helm of the 70th anniversary of the Liberation of Holland, where Canadian troops fought to end the Dutch oppression under the Nazis during the Second World War.
The two countries have had a close tie ever since.
During their first official state visit to the city, Willem-Alexander and Maxima will visit several Toronto landmarks including Queens Park, the Art Gallery of Ontario and the MaRs discovery district.
The pair will also unveil a gift on the Toronto Islands  seven orange Tulpi chairs that sit alongside the waterfront overlooking the city.
Willem-Alexander and Maxima also visited Ottawa this week where they laid a wreath at the National War Memorial and met with Canadian veterans.
They were officially invited by Gov. Gen. David Johnston.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:59:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter blames FIFA scandal on Russia and Qatar world cup bids</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024518/blatter-blames-fifa-scandal-on-russia-and-qatar-world-cup-bids/</Link>
        <Description>The worst corruption crisis in soccer history stems from the governing body's decision to award Russia and Qatar the next two World Cup tournaments, FIFA President Sepp Blatter said Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015 5:59 am
Blatter blames FIFA scandal on Russia and Qatar world cup bids
By   Rob Harris The Associated Press
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WATCH:FIFAs Sepp Blatter vows to stay at helm of world soccer
ZURICH  The worst corruption crisis in soccer history stems from the governing bodys decision to award Russia and Qatar the next two World Cup tournaments, FIFA President Sepp Blatter said Friday.
Blatter spoke at the FIFA congress hours before the presidential election in which he is a seeking a fifth term. He has refused calls to resign after FIFA was targeted by U.S. and Swiss authorities in separate corruption investigations.
READ MORE: A look at the voting blocs in the FIFA president balloting
If two other countries had emerged from the envelope, I think we would not have these problems today, Blatter said. But we cant go back in time. We are not prophets. We cant say what would have happened.
The United States was one of the losing bidders for the 2022 World Cup. On Wednesday, U.S. authorities indicted 14 people on bribery, racketeering, fraud and money-laundering charges going back to the 1990s.
Seven of the officials  including two serving FIFA vice-presidents  were arrested in Zurich on Wednesday ahead of the congress.
The two criminal investigations have cast a new shadow on Blatters 17-year reign as president of FIFA. The 209 FIFA member nations will decide later Friday whether to stick with the 79-year-old Blatter or vote for Prince Ali bin al-Hussein of Jordan.
READ MORE: Canada will not vote for Sepp Blatter in FIFA presidential election
Amid the dramatic build up to the election, UEFA president Michel Platini appealed to Blatter to immediately step down  calls the president has rejected.
I am willing to accept the president of FIFA is responsible for everything but I would at least like to share that responsibility with everyone, Blatter said in a presidential address on Friday morning. We cannot constantly supervise everyone in football  you cannot ask everyone to behave ethically.
Blatter also cautioned that it will take some time to rebuild FIFAs reputation.
The events of Wednesday have unleashed a storm and there was even questioned whether this congress would be organized or change the agenda, Blatter said. Today I am appealing to unity and team spirit so we can move forward together. That may not always be easy but it is for this reason that we are here together today.
READ MORE: Should soccer parents be concerned about the FIFA corruption scandal?
A two-thirds majority would be enough for Blatter or Prince Ali to win the secret presidential vote, or a simple majority in a second round of voting. Just forcing the ballot to a second round could represent a victory of sorts for Blatters critics, denying the incumbent president an emphatic mandate in his next term.
Blatters opening address to the congress was briefly disrupted by a pro-Palestinian activist, who held up a red card and shouted Red card to racism. The protest was to draw attention to a campaign that aims to stop Palestinian players from being detained by Israeli security forces.
After calling for security, Blatter announced: I would ask you to please check the access points of this room.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:40:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Loblaw expands recall of President’s Choice hummus and dips</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024513/loblaw-expands-recall-of-presidents-choice-hummus-and-dips/</Link>
        <Description>More than a dozen hummus and dip flavours are being recalled because they could contain a toxin and have caused reported illnesses.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015 5:40 am
Loblaw expands recall of Presidents Choice hummus and dips
By Natalie van Rooy Web Writer Global News
Loblaw Companies Limited is recalling President's Choice brand hummus and dip products from the marketplace because they may contain the toxin produced by Staphylococcus bacteria.
CFIA
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
Loblaw Companies Ltd. has expanded its recall of Presidents Choice hummus and dip after it was found the products could contain the toxin produced by Staphylococcus bacteria.
The Canadian Food Inspection Agency says there have been reported illnesses from eating the recalled products.
Loblaw says the products have been removed from store shelves and customers can return the recalled hummus for a full refund.
Story continues below
Initially, Loblaw recalled PC Moroccan-Style Hummus on Tuesday . The recall has now been expanded to include a dozen more flavours of hummus and dip.
Food contaminated with Staphylococcus toxin may not look or smell spoiled andis not easily destroyed at normal cooking temperatures.
If ingested, common symptoms ofpoisoning includenausea, vomiting, abdominal cramping and fever. In severe cases of illness, headache, muscle cramping and changes in blood pressure and pulse rate may occur.
The recalled product includes:
PC Butterbean &amp; Roasted Garlic Hummus 280 g
PC Caramelized Vidalia Onion Hummus 227 g
PC Chickpea Dip and Spread Hummus 227 g and 454 g
PC Garlic Hummus 227 g and 454 g
PC Moroccan-Style Hummus 280 g
PC Olive Tapenade Hummus 280 g
PC Red Harissa Hummus 280 g
PC Roasted Garlic Red Pepper and Cumin Hummus 280 g
PC Roasted Pepper and Paprika Hummus 280 g
PC Roasted Red Pepper and Chipotle Hummus 280 g
PC Spicy Hummus 227 g and 454 g
PC Sweet Potato and Harissa Dip 280 g
With files from the Canadian Press
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:25:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Relentless heat wave across India drives death toll to more than 1,800</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024512/relentless-heat-wave-across-india-drives-death-toll-to-more-than-1800/</Link>
        <Description>Dizzying temperatures caused water shortages in thousands of Indian villages and killed hundreds more people over the past day, driving the death toll from a weekslong heat wave to at least 1,826, officials said Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015 5:25 am
Relentless heat wave across India drives death toll to more than 1,800
By   Staff The Associated Press
A young Indian child pours water on himself as he tries to cool himself off in New Delhi on May 28, 2015. More than 1,100 people have died in a blistering heatwave sweeping India, authorities said, as forecasters warned searing temperatures would continue.
MONEY SHARMA/AFP/Getty Images
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
HYDERABAD, India  Dizzying temperatures caused water shortages in thousands of Indian villages and killed hundreds more people over the past day, driving the death toll from a weekslong heat wave to at least 1,826, officials said Friday.
Meteorological officials called the heat wave severe and warned that it would continue for at least two days across a huge swathe of the South Asian country from Tamil Nadu in the south to the Himalayan foothill state of Himachal Pradesh.
Stifling summer temperatures leave at least 1,100 dead in India
Most of those killed by heat-related conditions including dehydration and heat stroke have been in the southern states of Andhra Pradesh and Telangana, where 100 people died just on Thursday as temperatures hovered about 43 degrees Celsius (109 degrees Fahrenheit).
Thousands of water tankers were delivering supplies to more than 4,000 villages and hamlets facing acute water shortages in the central state of Maharashtra, state officials told the Press Trust of India news agency.
PHOTOS: Its so hot in India the roads are melting
People across India were reporting scorched crops and dying wildlife, with some animals succumbing to thirst.
Indians were doing whatever they could to beat the heat, including staying in the shade, plunging into rivers, and drinking buttermilk, onion juice and plenty of water.
But many farmers and construction workers struggling with poverty were still working outdoors despite the risks. They along with the impoverished elderly were among the most vulnerable, without access to air conditioners or sometimes even shade-giving trees.
Cooling monsoon rains were expected next week in the south before gradually advancing north.
Indians seek any shelter, relief as blistering heatwave continues
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:15:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>6.7 magnitude earthquake strikes off Alaska coast; no tsunami threat</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024504/6-7-magnitude-earthquake-strikes-off-alaska-coast-no-tsunami-threat/</Link>
        <Description>A strong earthquake has struck in a remote region off the coast of Alaska and officials say there is no tsunami threat or immediate report of damage.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015 5:15 am
6.7 magnitude earthquake strikes off Alaska coast; no tsunami threat
By   Staff The Associated Press
An airplane flies over Cook Inlet in Anchorage, Alaska, U.S., on Wednesday, Nov. 5, 2014.
David Ryder/Bloomberg via Getty Images
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
ANCHORAGE, Alaska  A strong earthquake has struck in a remote region off the coast of Alaska and officials say there is no tsunami threat or immediate report of damage.
The U.S. Geological Survey says the magnitude-6.7 quake was centred in the ocean about 35 miles (55 kilometres) beneath the seabed and some 400 miles (640 kilometres) southwest of Anchorage, a remote and lightly populated Aleutian Island region.
The National Tsunami Warning Center says there is no tsunami danger.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:00:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain’s Cameron in Poland to support on EU reform</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024502/britains-cameron-in-poland-to-support-on-eu-reform/</Link>
        <Description>British Prime Minister David Cameron pressed his case for renegotiating his country's relationship with the European Union Friday in Poland, where resistance is stiff to any changes that would limit the rights of the many Polish migrants living in the U.K.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015 5:00 am
Britains Cameron in Poland to support on EU reform
By   Staff The Associated Press
Prime Minister David Cameron leaves 10 Downing Street, London, as he heads for Buckingham Palace for an audience with Queen Elizabeth II to confirm his second term as Prime Minister following his party's General Election victory on May 8, 2015.
AP Photo
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WARSAW, Poland  British Prime Minister David Cameron pressed his case for renegotiating his countrys relationship with the European Union Friday in Poland, where resistance is stiff to any changes that would limit the rights of the many Polish migrants living in the U.K.
Ahead of the visit, the Polish minister for European affairs, Rafal Trzaskowski, told the Rzeczpospolita daily that he expected the talks to be very difficult and that Poland would not agree to changes that would discriminate against Poles.
Story continues below
Hundreds of thousands of Poles have settled in Britain since Poland joined the EU in 2004.
Cameron and Polish Prime Minister Ewa Kopacz held a working breakfast early Friday in the Palace on the Isle, a historic palace in the royal Lazienki park, but did not make any public statements.
Following the victory for his Conservative party this month, Cameron has pledged to hold a referendum that could take Britain out of the European Union by the end of 2017. Cameron says he will campaign to stay in the EU, if he wins concessions including curbing benefits, such as the right to claim tax credits, for EU migrants. He also wants to limit welfare benefits to migrants.
As part of a four-country tour meant to win support for his changes, Cameron visited the Netherlands and France before visiting Poland. Germany is the next stop later Friday.
Polands government, led by the Civic Platform party, is staunchly pro-European. The partys former leader and prime minister, Donald Tusk, is now the head of the European Council in Brussels.
However, the country has just elected a new president, Andrzej Duda, who hopes to recalibrate Warsaws relationship to Brussels. He stood for the nationalistic and right-wing Law and Justice party, which has long fought for greater national sovereignty within the EU. Dudas victory has given the party new momentum and raised its chances of winning parliamentary elections this fall.
Cameron did not meet Duda during his brief visit to Warsaw.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:42:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Muhammadu Buhari sworn in as Nigeria president</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024499/muhammadu-buhari-to-be-sworn-in-as-nigeria-president/</Link>
        <Description>Nigerians celebrated their newly reinforced democracy Friday, dancing and singing songs and praises as Muhammadu Buhari was sworn in, the first candidate to beat a sitting president at the polls.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015 4:42 am
Updated: May 29, 2015 6:06 am
Muhammadu Buhari sworn in as Nigeria president
By   Michelle Faul The Associated Press
Nigeria's President-elect Mohammadu Buhari speaks after receiving his certificate of return from Independent Nigeria Electoral Commission (INEC) in Abuja, on April 1, 2015. Nigeria's president-elect Muhammadu Buhari today sought to reconcile past differences with incumbent Goodluck Jonathan, extending a hand of friendship to his beaten election opponent.  AFP PHOTO / STRINGER
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
ABUJA, Nigeria  Nigerians celebrated their newly reinforced democracy Friday, dancing and singing songs and praises as Muhammadu Buhari was sworn in, the first candidate to beat a sitting president at the polls.
As Buhari finished taking the oath of office, the crowd at Eagle Square in Nigerias capital roared its approval.
Change has come to Nigeria! the announcer had declared, echoing the election slogan as Buhari arrived for the ceremony resplendent in traditional robes and an embroidered cap.
Who is Nigerias presidential election winner Muhammadu Buhari?
Nigerians are hopeful that Buhari  the only leader believed not to have lined his pockets from the state treasury  can curb the graft that keeps a rich nation impoverished.
With Nigeria so broke its borrowing money to pay government workers, Buhari intends to retrieve ill-gotten gains to fund programs from education for girls to job creation for young people  seeking to address the roots of Boko Harams northeastern insurgency. Nigerian newspapers are carrying unconfirmed reports that some politicians already have returned millions of dollars, in hopes of currying favour and avoiding scrutiny.
Buhari, the first Nigerian to oust a sitting president at the polls, has a wealth of international goodwill. Some 50 heads of state are expected at Fridays inauguration along with U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry, looking to mend fences broken under the discredited administration of Goodluck Jonathan.
The inauguration is being held in Abuja at Eagle Square, where a 2010 twin car bombing and grenade attack by oil militants killed 12 people at Independence Day celebrations. Buhari must decide how to deal with the militants who are threatening to renew attacks if he does not continue an amnesty program that has them paid to guard the installations they once attacked.
Jonathan, who allowed Boko Harams nearly 6-year-old insurgency to flourish unhindered until this year and was seen as uncaring of the suffering it has imposed in the northeast of the country, won acclaim at home and abroad for graciously conceding defeat. There were fears of the kind of electoral violence that killed more than 1,000 people in the mainly Muslim north when Jonathan defeated Buhari in 2011 elections.
You have changed the course of Nigerias political history, Buhari told Jonathan when he handed over the report of his administration Thursday. For that you have earned yourself a place in our history, for stabilizing this system of multiparty democracy and you have earned the respect of not only Nigerians but world leaders.
Political science professor Richard Joseph of Northwestern University said Buharis victory has hopeful international implications.
The world desperately needs a victory against cultist jihadism. Nigeria (under Buhari) can provide it, he said. In no other large country, with an almost equal number of Muslims and Christians, is such a process conceivable.
Buhari was a major general when he defeated another homegrown Nigerian Islamic group in the 1980s.
Jonathan was forced to accept an international intervention from neighbouring countries to curb Boko Haram this year as its uprising spread across Nigerias borders. His government also hired foreign mercenaries to help train troops even as it halted a U.S. military training program last year.
Buhari has criticized the need for foreign troops in Nigeria, which has Africas largest standing army, albeit demoralized and under-resourced by some plundering officers. The answer to defeating Boko Haram begins and ends with Nigeria, he has said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:33:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japanese volcano erupts spewing ash 9 kilometres into the sky</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024496/japanese-volcano-erupts-spewing-ash-9-kilometres-into-the-sky/</Link>
        <Description>A volcano erupted in spectacular fashion on a small island in southern Japan on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015 4:33 am
Updated: May 29, 2015 5:45 am
Japanese volcano erupts spewing ash 9 kilometres into the sky
By   Elaine Kurtenbach The Associated Press
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WATCH:Mount Shindake erupts on Japanese island
TOKYO  A volcano erupted in spectacular fashion on a small island in southern Japan on Friday, spewing out rocks and sending black clouds of ash 9 kilometres (5.6 miles) into the sky. Authorities told people on the island to evacuate.
One person was reported to have suffered minor burns from falling debris after Mount Shindake erupted about 10 a.m. (0100 GMT), sending dense pyroclastic flows of rock and hot gases seaward, the Japan Meteorological Agency reported.
The injured man, another person who was feeling unwell and a third person were airlifted to nearby Yakushima island, the Fire and Disaster Management Agency said.
Another 133 people were evacuated on a Coast Guard vessel and town-operated ferry and fishing boats.
Ash was just raining down from the sky, said one elderly woman as she disembarked at Yakushimas port, wearing a safety helmet.
The agency raised the volcano alert level for Kuchinoerabu island, where Shindake is located, to five, the highest on its scale. Shindake also erupted in August last year for the first time since 1980.
A military helicopter was sent to survey the island and assess damage, as the government pledged to do all it can to ensure the islanders safety.
There was a really loud, dong sound of an explosion, and then black smoke rose, darkening the sky, Nobuaki Hayashi, a local village chief, said as he and dozens of others gathered at a shelter before leaving the island.
There was a really loud, dong sound of an explosion, and then black smoke rose, darkening the sky, he told the national broadcaster NHK. It smelled of sulfur.
Kuchinoerabu is 50 miles (80 kilometres) southwest of Japans main southern island of Kyushu. A heavily forested, mountainous island bordered mostly by rocky cliffs, it is a national park supported mainly by tourism and fishing.
About two hours after the eruption, footage from NHK showed the mountain shrouded in light grey ash as the clouds from the eruption cleared.
Kuchinoerabu usually can be reached only by a once-a-day ferry from Yakushima, 12 kilometres (about 7 miles) to the east, which has an airport and a population of more than 13,000 people.
Japan, which sits atop the Pacific Ring of Fire, has dozens of volcanoes and is frequently jolted by earthquakes.
In March 2011, a magnitude-9 earthquake rocked northeastern Japan, triggering a tsunami that killed more than 18,500 people and ravaged much of the northern Pacific coast.
Authorities recently closed part of a popular hot springs about 80 kilometres (50 miles) from Tokyo because of fears of an eruption from Mount Hakone, which is southeast of Mount Fuji.
The eruption last September of another volcano, Mount Ontake in central Japan, killed 57 people.
Setsuya Nakada, a professor at Tokyo University, told NHK that the eruption on Kuchinoerabu was stronger than Mount Ontakes.
Since the 2011 disasters, this sort of activity has continued, Nakada said, when asked if more eruptions were likely on the island. Probably the eruptions will continue.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:22:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Ontario deputy minister to be sentenced for child porn-related offences</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024492/former-ontario-deputy-minister-to-be-sentenced-for-child-porn-related-offences/</Link>
        <Description>A man who once was deputy education minister in Ontario and Manitoba should find out today how long he'll spend behind bars after pleading guilty to three child pornography-related charges.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
TORONTO  A man who once was deputy education minister in Ontario and Manitoba should find out today how long hell spend behind bars after pleading guilty to three child pornography-related charges.
Benjamin Levin, 63, was originally charged with seven child porn-related offences.
Court has heard Levin used to frequent an online website with numerous chatrooms for the discussion of sexual activities.
Among the people he chatted with were an undercover officer in Toronto, one in London, Ont., and one in New Zealand  all posing as women interested in sexual activities with children.
Levin was arrested in July 2013 when a search warrant was executed at his home. He was a university professor at the time.
His lawyer is seeking a sentence of two years in a penitentiary, while the Crown is seeking up to three years and eight months behind bars.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
