<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Google">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:54:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Speaker of US House of Representatives Dennis Hastert Indicted - NBCNews.com</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHYEOimuvP1bSCgsaC9aKKAMBy1Lw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778858675452&amp;ei=cUdoVZDELaKEaY7lgNgC&amp;url=http://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/former-speaker-u-s-house-representatives-dennis-hastert-indicted-n366276</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 7:12 pm ET
Former Speaker of U.S. House of Representatives Dennis Hastert Indicted
by Phil Helsel
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_wil_hastert_charged_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Former Speaker of the U.S. House of Representatives J. Dennis Hastert was indicted on federal charges Thursday for allegedly structuring the withdrawal of over $950,000 in cash in a way to avoid reporting requirements, and then lying to the FBI about it.
Hastert allegedly took out the cash and handed it over to a Yorkville, Illinois, resident "in order to compensate and conceal his prior misconduct" against that person, according to the indictment.
Hastert, 73, of Plano, Illinois, is charged with one count each of structuring currency transactions to evade currency transaction reports and making a false statement to the FBI, the U.S. Attorney's Office for the Northern District of Illinois said.
Hastert, a Republican, served as speaker of the House of Representatives from 1999 to 2007. Hastert resigned from Congress in 2007, and has been working as a lobbyist since 2008, according to the government.
The indictment alleges that Hastert withdrew $1.7 million from 2010 to 2014 and gave it to the unidentified person, referred to in the indictment as "individual A."
advertisement
The indictment does not specify what the acts were or when they happened, only that they occurred "years earlier." The indictment says "individual A" has known Hastert for most of his or her life, but does not elaborate on the relationship. The indictment says Hastert was a high school teacher and coach in Yorkville from 1965 to 1981.
Hastert is accused of withdrawing $952,000 of that $1.7 million in increments of less than $10,000 so as to avoid regulations that require banks to report withdrawals over that amount.
Hastert agreed in 2010 to pay "individual A" a total of $3.5 million in compensation, according to the indictment.
Hastert at first made larger withdrawals, taking out $50,000 at a time on 15 occasions between June 2010 and April 2012, but scaled back the withdrawals to less than $10,000 at a time after bank officials questioned him about the larger amounts, according to the indictment.
When asked about the withdrawals by the FBI in December, Hastert allegedly told agents, "Yeah ... I kept the cash. That's what I'm doing," when he was actually giving the money to "individual A" as part of the agreement.
advertisement
Under the alleged agreement, Hastert handed over $50,000 cash payments to "individual A" every six weeks. In 2014, the former congressman began paying that person $100,000 every three months, according to the indictment.
The FBI began investigating Hastert in 2013, partly because investigators wanted to know if he was the victim of an extortion scheme, court documents said.
Each of the two criminal charges carries a maximum penalty of 5 years in prison and a $250,000 fine, the U.S. Attorney's Office said. A court date has not yet been set.
Hastert served as a U.S. Representative from 1987 until his resignation on Nov. 26, 2007.
Hastert spent 16 years as a teacher of history, economics and government at Yorkville High School, where he also coached football and wrestling, according to his biography on the Wheaton College website, where he earned a bachelor's degree in 1964.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:23:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crisis-Hit FIFA Prepares to Vote on Whether to Keep Sepp Blatter as Chief - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFKPpeaN-e6sWZb-FWJS6vzv0KaqA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778855010755&amp;ei=cUdoVZDELaKEaY7lgNgC&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/30/sports/soccer/fifa-soccer-sepp-blatter-congress-vote.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:54:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Millionaire mother, who killed her 8-year-old autistic son, sentenced to 18 years - The Indian Express</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGOcyD-YN0c--BnMHA6u2C9U2Au2g&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778858212875&amp;ei=cUdoVZDELaKEaY7lgNgC&amp;url=http://indianexpress.com/article/world/americas/millionaire-mother-who-killed-her-8-year-old-autistic-son-sentenced-to-18-years/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Jude Law choses work over newborn baby girl
But Manhattan Supreme Court Judge Charles Solomon dismissed the notion that her nearly mute, autistic child was repeatedly abused, noting time and again that no credible evidence on the record substantiated those claims.
All of her money, all of her resources, she decided to kill him, he said. There were so many things she could have done.
Though charged with murder, a jury in November found her guilty of a lesser manslaughter charge, deciding she was under extreme emotional disturbance when she gave Jude Mirra the fatal dose of Ambien and Xanax, believing killing him was the only way to save him.
Solomon also said he didnt believe her suicide attempt was genuine and admonished her for giving an interview to the Dr. Phil Show while the jury was deliberating. And he wondered why she wasnt more repentant.
Jordan, 54, has spent the past five years jailed on Rikers Island, the time that will count toward her prison term. Prosecutors had sought a 25-year sentence.
Her attorneys said they were disappointed in the lengthy prison term.
Jordan never pursued a plea deal because she wanted to take the stand to tell her story, an account the jury apparently accepted when it convicted her of the lesser charge, said one of her attorneys, Ron Kuby, after the proceeding.
The judge in the guise of paying lip service to the jurys decision went about trying to undo it, he said.
Before she was sentenced, Jordan, wearing a white pantsuit, haltingly and through tears detailed reports describing her sons various medical conditions that she believed pointed to sexual abuse.
The 54-year-old woman, estimated to be worth $40 million, left her career to find treatment for her son, who was initially diagnosed autistic, visiting medical experts at universities across the countries.
Prosecutors have argued the killing was intentional and carried out because Jordan could no longer care for the needs of her son. In a statement, Manhattan District Attorney Cyrus R. Vance Jr. hailed the sentence.
The poisoning and killing of an 8-year-old boy is a premeditated act of continued 
First Published on: May 29, 2015 12:11 pm Single Page Format
Do you like this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:38:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US says China has placed mobile artillery on reclaimed island - Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFMGm-ncAxbpqzzsrJJFeKuGGtxSQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778858137274&amp;ei=cUdoVZDELaKEaY7lgNgC&amp;url=http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/05/29/us-asia-security-island-idUSKBN0OE12T20150529</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>U.S. says China has placed mobile artillery on reclaimed island
SINGAPORE
SINGAPORE The United States said on Friday that China had placed mobile artillery weapons systems on a reclaimed island in the disputed South China Sea, a development that Republican Sen. John McCain called "disturbing and escalatory."
Brent Colburn, a Pentagon spokesman traveling with Defense Secretary Ash Carter, said the United States was aware of the weapons.
McCain, chairman of the Senate's Armed Services Committee, said the move would escalate tensions but not lead to conflict.
"It is a disturbing development and escalatory development, one which heightens our need to make the Chinese understand that their actions are in violation of international law and their actions are going to be condemned by everyone in the world," he said at a news conference in Ho Chi Minh City.
"We are not going to have a conflict with China but we can take certain measures which will be a disincentive to China to continue these kinds of activities," he said.
In Beijing, China's foreign ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying said she had no information on the weapons.
U.S. officials say Chinese dredging work has added some 2,000 acres to five outposts in the resource-rich Spratly islands in the South China Sea, including 1,500 acres this year.
It has released surveillance plane footage showing dredgers and other ships busily turning remote outcrops into islands with runways and harbors.
Carter called on Wednesday for an immediate halt to land reclamation in the South China Sea and was expected to touch on the issue of maritime security and freedom of navigation again on Saturday in a speech at the Shangri-La Dialogue security conference in Singapore.
China says the islands are in sovereign Chinese territory.
 Pentagon officials said efforts by China and other claimant countries to turn reefs into islands in the Spratlys undermines international law and raises questions about their future plans and intentions.
"It creates an air of uncertainty in a system that has been based on certainty and agreed-upon norms," said Colburn, the Pentagon spokesman. "So anything that steps outside of the bounds of international law we see as a concern because we don't know what the ... motivations are behind that. We think it should concern everyone in the region."
Asian military attaches and analysts said the placement of mobile artillery pieces appeared to be a symbol of intent, rather than any major development that could tilt any balance of power.
"It is interesting and a point to watch. But it should be remembered theyve already got potentially a lot more firepower on the naval ships that they routinely move through the South China Sea," one military attache said.
China claims most of the South China Sea. The Philippines, Vietnam, Malaysia, Brunei and Taiwan also claim parts of the vital trade route. All claimants except Brunei have military fortifications in the Spratlys.
(Reporting by David Alexander in Singapore, Mai Nguyen in Hanoi, Sui-Lee Wee in Beijing and Greg Torode in Hong Kong; Writing by Raju Gopalakrishnan ; Editing by Nick Macfie )
The alleged on-going land reclamation of China at Subi reef is seen from Pagasa island (Thitu Island) in the Spratlys group of islands in the South China Sea, west of Palawan, Philippines, May 11, 2015.
Reuters/Ritchie B. Tongo/Pool
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Can you spell co-champions? National Spelling Bee ends in tie. - Washington Post</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFgn1vQioO1gZ6tjTW1YkoFEQKb6g&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778857819331&amp;ei=cUdoVZDELaKEaY7lgNgC&amp;url=http://www.washingtonpost.com/local/at-the-national-spelling-bee-just-10-top-spellers-remain/2015/05/28/5a28f0a8-0543-11e5-a428-c984eb077d4e_story.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>By Joe Heim May 28 at 11:58 PM Follow @JoeHeim
All sorts of history was made at the National Spelling Bee on Thursday night.
Vanya Shivashankar and Gokul Venkatachalam duked it out to a tie and were named co-winners of the annual contest. It marked the second year in a row that co-champions were named and only the fifth time in the history of the bee.
With her share of the victory, Shivashankar, a 13-year-old from Olathe, Kan., joined her sister Kavya as the only siblings to have won the bee. Kavya took the title in 2009.
Shivashankar and Venkatachalam, 14, of Chesterfield, Mo., battled it out for 30 minutes before they were both crowned champs. Back and forth they went, correctly spelling words such as scherenschnitte, pyrrhuloxia, thamakau, caudillismo and a slew of other words mere mortals would never be able to decode.
A roar erupted from the crowd as Venkatachalam correctly spelled nunatak to ensure that the victory would be shared.
When Vanya Shivashankar, 13, spelled scherenschnitte correctly and Gokul Venkatachalam, 14, nailed nunatak, it meant the duo would share the title of 2015 Scripps Spelling Bee champion. (Reuters)
This is a dream come true, said Shivashankar, who was making her fifth trip to the national bee. Ive wanted this for such a long time. She dedicated her win to her late grandmother. I hope I make her happy with this, she said.
I wasnt nervous at all, said Venkatachalam, standing on a stage littered with confetti and facing a sea of cameras. It was the culmination of all the hard work of the past six years. Im finally happy to have success.
His one word to describe his win? Ridiculous.
In the packed ballroom, parents, grandparents, siblings and friends of all the spellers sat nervously through each attempt, willing the contestants to nail their words. Media from around the country and the world chronicled each correct  and incorrect  letter. There was a lot on the line. In addition to bragging rights, the winner stood to take home $35,000 in cash prizes. And a trophy big enough to hold the money. (Good news for the winning pair: They wont have to split the cash or the trophy.)
The victory by Venkatachalam and Shivashankar also marked the eighth straight year in which Indian Americans have won the national bee. Seven of the 10 finalists were kids of South Asian descent.
The domination of the bee by Indian American spellers over the past 15 years has created some backlash, including an ugly outburst of racial insults on social media last year. Paige Kimble, the longtime director of the bee, said that she was approached Thursday and asked whether any Americans made it to the finals.  Yes, theyre all Americans, I told them, Kimble said. We obviously still have a long way to go.
There were similarly ugly comments on Twitter on Thursday night, but it was impossible to measure the breadth or depth of the response.
View Graphic
Try your hand at correcting these silly sentences.
After a grueling three days of competition that began with 283 spellers, just 10 made it to the final round of the bee held at the Gaylord National Resort and Convention Center at National Harbor, Md. But it didnt take long for that number to shrink.
Sylvie Lamontagne was the first to exit the final round on Thursday night. She spelled cerastes incorrectly. Thats not right, she said as soon as she uttered the last letter and before the bell had even rung. And then the Coloradan exited the stage.
Minutes later, she was followed out of the contest by Siyona Mishra, at 11, the youngest speller in the finals. She misspelled the word hacek. Before the round, she admitted to some nerves about going up against the older spellers.
The plan now, she said, is to take a long, long, long break from spelling.
Paul Keaton, 14, of Pikeville, Ky., was out next. He tied for 13th place last year and was making his last visit as a contestant to the bee. Virginias Tejas Muthusamy and Californias Snehaa Ganesh Kumar also spelled their words incorrectly before the first hour was completed. Dev Jaiswal and Siddharth Krishnakumar soon followed. Cole Shafer-Ray hung on a little while longer before succumbing. At 9:25 p.m., there were just two contestants left: Venkatachalam, who finished third last year, and Shivashankar.
Each misspelling was greeted with the ding of the judges bell and a small gasp from the crowd and then loud and sustained applause. Sweetest, perhaps, was the standing ovation given by the other contestants to their departed cohorts. The bee can sometimes feel less like a competition and more like a giant support group.
Jacques Bailly, now in his 13th year as announcer, was a voice of calm for the nervous spellers.
I try to make eye contact and elicit a smile before we go into the business of the word, he said, as he prepared for Thursday nights finals. I think of myself as the spellers ally  even if they dont always think that.
Earlier in the day, the 10 finalists battled a slew of taxing words to survive the elimination rounds.
Venkatachalam correctly spelled bordereau (paper describing reinsured risks).
Mishra handled emmetropia (refractive condition of the eye) without trouble. And Lamontagne carefully considered hanswurst (burlesque character in German comedy) before nailing it.
Shafer-Rays late father, Neil, a physicist, always wanted him to compete in the bee, he said after learning that he had made it to the final group. His father died in 2012, and Cole has thought of him this week.
I think hed be proud of me, he said.
Mirle and Sandy Shivashankar also had reason to be proud. Theyre now the parents of two children who have won spellings top prize.
Vanya showed the flair and the confidence tonight, said Mirle, who was wearing a shirt with The Beefather emblazoned on it. She was in the zone.
There were, according to bee organizers, about 11 million spellers who took part in school, local and regional bees that eventually led to Thursdays final rounds. It would take a math bee champion to calculate those odds, but its fair to say that win or lose, the kids who made it to the Maryland Ballroom for last nights finale are the cream of the spelling crop.
Read more:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:45:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Latest on flooding: EMS rescues 21 from houseboat in Austin - Washington Post</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEpHixX4XOie5o9WPAiwlmhRV1gOg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778859124237&amp;ei=cUdoVZDELaKEaY7lgNgC&amp;url=http://www.washingtonpost.com/national/latest-on-flooding-2-dead-5-missing-in-blanco-county/2015/05/28/dbe9f6cc-0599-11e5-93f4-f24d4af7f97d_story.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Comments 0
From left to right, Cara Hewitt, Linda Balas, Kathy Bullard and Doreen Crow look at the spot in Wimberley, Texas, on Thursday May 28, 2015, where eight of their friends from Corpus Christi were swept away in a flood. (Jay Janner/Austin American-Statesman via AP) AUSTIN CHRONICLE OUT, COMMUNITY IMPACT OUT, INTERNET AND TV MUST CREDIT PHOTOGRAPHER AND STATESMAN.COM, MAGAZINES OUT (Associated Press)
By Associated Press May 29 at 6:44 AM
3:30 a.m. (CDT)
Emergency personnel have rescued the occupants of a houseboat that was adrift in Lake Travis in Austin.
Austin-Travis County EMS says the 21 occupants of the boat rescued Friday were not injured.
Responders say the houseboat broke free from Sandy Creek Marina earlier in the day. The area has been blighted by days of relentless rains. Emergency personnel used three boats to attach the houseboat to the dock at the marina.
The National Weather Service issued a flash flood warning for parts of Travis, Williamson and Bastrop counties until 4:45 a.m.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Continue reading
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:22:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>All said and done, Google I/O 2015 left us wanting more - Firstpost</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGP4Iw8aT8VYLIy8cHMT0IDB-DbDw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778855205727&amp;ei=cUdoVZDELaKEaY7lgNgC&amp;url=http://tech.firstpost.com/news-analysis/all-said-and-done-google-io-2015-left-us-wanting-more-268884.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>35
By Nash David / 29 May 2015 , 14:50
There are several reasons why anything Google announces is news. Given the sheer dominance and clout it commands in the technology space, it is difficult to ignore any message received from Googleplex. Add Android, Maps, Chrome and the bouquet of tools by Google, and you cannot help but sit back and pay attention.
A few years ago, at Google I/O 2012, there was a jaw dropping, pushing-you-out-of-your-seat kind of a demo. It could beat any Hollywood thriller for the sheer stunt that was pulled off. Complete with a live skydive out of a plane, on to the roof of the Moscone centre, rappelling to the ground, on to bikes to the stage at Moscone where Sergey Brin was onstage to demo a true invention which was making sci-fi a reality. You can watch this exciting demo here .
Yes, its Google I/O 2015, and were stuck at 2012. Thanks to the benchmark set by Google. As someone who has followed the developer space for quite a while, we must add, we deeply appreciate the contribution Google has made in terms of tools, languages and support for the open web and software development ecosystem. Having said that, the expectations of innovation are undeniably high.
So when we latched on to the mandatory Google I/O chatter this year, we were a bit underwhelmed. Volume control was an announcement. Like really? Sounds more like an update. We dont intend to be a naysayer here. Is that a major announcement? We couldnt say the same about Apple, because then wed probably have to think whether were setting the volume the right way, or our ears functioning properly. Google gives users the freedom, and is associated with the freedom to choose, hence the surprise about volume controls being so significant. May be it is, and were just not seeing it through. But till then it seems like it could have just been a minor OTA. Sure, to those who love Google and their work with Android, we share the passion. Its a brilliant product. If it werent itd not be among the two mobile operating systems to dominate the globe.
Android Auto
We were expecting a lot around automobiles. Its been a zone that has been attracting a lot of attention in the recent wave of interest around Internet of Things. Nonetheless, a mention at least. Increasing and exciting partnerships, a driverless SDK or something similar is what wed have loved to see. Wed stay content with the 35 brand partnerships that have been announced for now.
We wonder if the Google Car would ever become a practical reality for consumers, or would stay put within the Googleplex neighbourhood? Especially considering automotive companies such as the Nissan-Renault alliance working on autonomous drive vehicles with the target of launching one for consumers by 2020. Whats the roadmap ahead when it comes to Auto? Does QNX-powered Apple CarPlay have more or less in store, and effectively determine what Googles way forward is going to be? Was it just supposed to be Google Maps and Hangouts on a new screen size? An Android phone with an effective Voice Assistant would accomplish the same tasks.
Android Wear
A passing reference to Android Wear. Especially given that Apple Watch has picked on really well. Bringing on new partners for Android Wear ought to have been the sought after announcement. But instead a massive 4000 apps was more important. On the sidelines of the Google I/O event, Lenovo seemed to have a more stylish hardware announcement with the Magic View smartwatch sporting an innovative Virtual Interactive Design.
Lenovo Magic View smartwatch with a unique Virtual Interactive Display. Image: gagadget.com
What we now seem to have though, is preference. Those who prefer square dials could opt for Apple Watch and then transition to iOS. Those who love round dials could opt for the Moto 360 et al. and use Android. Thats pretty much what the wearable space has come down to, rather than emerging as a new philosophy of extending the users access to useful information.
To Googles credit, one must add, the emphasis on polish and stability is much needed given Androids history . Effectively it does become important for the developer community in the Android ecosystem to focus on more optimised ways of garbage collection and clean up so your Android device doesnt lag a few months after you begin using it. Given the fragmentation within the Android base, a focus on performance and stability is the much needed direction Google needs to focus on. Were still hopeful of seeing more hardware and device based announcements, for thats where the fun lies! In closing, it seems like a few others also seem to have expected more from Google I/O 2015, as mentioned in this Quora discussion that began immediately after the Google I/O keynote .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:01:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Five things to know about Martin O'Malley - CBS News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHQq8nZv79gCrvngmLkOapBKx-Gyg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778857905427&amp;ei=cUdoVZDELaKEaY7lgNgC&amp;url=http://www.cbsnews.com/news/election-2016-five-things-to-know-about-martin-omalley/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>ByJake MillerCBS NewsMay 29, 2015, 6:00 AM
Five things to know about Martin O'Malley
Shares
Former Maryland Gov. Martin O'Malley is expected to formally declare his 2016 presidential bid on Saturday at a rally in Baltimore , his home for decades and the city he once served as a councilmember and mayor.
He's been laying the groundwork for a bid for some time, stepping up his visits to early voting states and building the campaign infrastructure he'll need to compete against Democratic frontrunner Hillary Rodham Clinton. This week, some of his political allies launched "Generation Forward," a super PAC dedicated to supporting his candidacy .
The O'Malley team's case for his candidacy is heavily generational. They say the country needs new leadership for the 21st century, and it's a natural argument for O'Malley, who's 52 years of age, compared with the other two Democratic candidates - Clinton, who is 68 and Bernie Sanders, a spry 73.
Still, most analysts consider O'Malley's bid a long shot at this point. A Quinnipiac poll released Thursday showed him at one percent among Democratic primary voters nationwide. But that could change as voters get to know him: A CBS News poll earlier this month found that 11 percent of Democrats would consider supporting O'Malley for the nomination. Seventeen percent said they would not consider him, and 72 percent said they don't know enough to decide.
Here are five things you need to know about Martin O'Malley:
The Clintons are a conflict for him
In a bid to disrupt Hillary Clinton's domination of early Democratic primary polls, O'Malley has positioned himself as the true progressive in the race - the counterpoint to the frontrunner, who has been running as a populist, but has had her centrist moments. (The contrast with Bernie Sanders also makes her look more centrist)
O'Malley has soft-pedaled his criticisms of Clinton thus far, but you get the sense that a more damning indictment is lurking just offscreen, waiting for the right moment to emerge.
"We can be the party that leads our country into the future," O'Malley told CBS News' "Face the Nation" in April. "But we won't do it unless we offer ideas for the future and break with things like bad trade deals, the systematic deregulation of Wall Street that many Democrats were complicit in and helped get us into this mess."
Former Maryland Gov. Martin OMalley talks about the lack of competition in the Democratic presidential primaries and discusses whether hell mou...
As evidence of his progressive bona-fides, O'Malley has cited his decision to sign a same-sex marriage bill in 2012 and a bill allowing undocumented immigrants to receive drivers licenses in 2013. Clinton now shares those positions, but she arrived at them more recently than O'Malley - and he wants to make sure voters know it.
"I'm glad Secretary Clinton's come around to the right positions on these issues," O'Malley said in April during an event at Harvard's Institute of Politics. "I believe that we are best as a party when we lead with our principles and not according to the polls...Leadership is about making the right decision, and the best decision before sometimes it becomes entirely popular."
When it comes to Clinton's husband, O'Malley's views are harder to pin down. This year, O'Malley has advanced a dim view of "triangulation," a political strategy associated with former President Bill Clinton during the 1990s to position his administration in the ideological center between the two major parties.
"Triangulation is not a strategy that will move America forward," O'Malley said in February, according to the New York Times . "History celebrates profiles in courage, not profiles in convenience."
In 2007, however, O'Malley was feeling nostalgic for "the success of the last centrist president," he said in a Washington Post op-ed with former Rep. Harold Ford of Tennessee. He wrote admiringly, "Bill Clinton ran on an agenda of sensible ideas that brought America a decade of peace and prosperity. He was the only Democrat to be elected and reelected president in the past seven decades, and he left office more popular than almost any other president in recent memory."
And as recently as 2013, O'Malley said that the model for his own presidential run would be Bill Clinton.
But now, he is seeking a toehold in a race that could once again pit a Bush against a Clinton, and O'Malley has suggested he plans to campaign against the power of political dynasties.
"The presidency of the United States is not some crown to be passed between two families," he told ABC News in April. "It is an awesome and sacred trust to be earned and exercised on behalf of the American people."
He's been criticized on criminal justice issues
After Baltimore erupted in protests when a young black man named Freddie Gray died in police custody last month, O'Malley called for criminal justice reform in a Huffington Post op-ed , urging policymakers to rethink old ideas about race and policing
"We must continue to work constantly to improve policing and the way we police our police," he said. "Public trust is essential to public safety. Public trust is essential for officer safety. Enlightened police chiefs across our country understand this."
The Department of Justice is investigating the Baltimore Police Department after six officers were charged in the killing of an unarmed suspect, ...
As mayor of Baltimore, O'Malley oversaw a dramatic reduction in the city's violent crime rate, pushing a "zero tolerance" approach to law enforcement that embraced tough-on-crime police tactics. The Washington Post notes that while O'Malley was in office, "The overall crime rate (the number of crimes per 100,000 people) fell by 48 percent during that decade, more than any other large police agency in the country. Specifically for violent crimes, the Baltimore City Police Department saw the third highest drop (behind Los Angeles and New York City) during the period."
Critics, though, have said some of O'Malley's tactics are partly to blame for the tensions between police and minority communities in Baltimore today . He "probably had the best of intentions, but boy, was it foreseeable," Joe Margulies, a visiting professor at Cornell Law School, told CBS News. "When you are so unrelenting in your stops -- and every officer on the street would tell you this -- you can predict with absolute certainty that you're going to breed a lot of animosity."
"The stake through the heart of police procedure in Baltimore was Martin O'Malley," David Simon, a Baltimore native and the creator of HBO's "The Wire" told The Marshall Project last month . "What happened under his watch as Baltimore's mayor was that he wanted to be governor. And at a certain point, with the crime rate high and with his promises of a reduced crime rate on the line, he put no faith in real policing."
He's a bit of a numbers geek
One of O'Malley's signature initiatives, both as mayor and as governor, was a data-driven approach to governing that used computer programs to measure and track government performance on a wide variety of metrics.
As mayor, he pioneered a program called CitiStat that monitored everything from pothole maintenance to city employee attendance and the deployment of police resources.
Gov. Martin O'Malley D-Md. spoke with CBS News political director John Dickerson on if the country is better off compared to four years ago and h...
Matthew Gallagher, the program's former director, told the Washington Post in March that CitiStat was a "fundamental bedrock" of O'Malley's approach to governance and something he's "rightfully proud of."
And when O'Malley was elected governor of Maryland, he implemented a statewide version of the program called StateStat.
"There's not a doubt in my mind that this is the new way of governing and getting things done," he said of his emphasis on quantitative data during a March speech at the Brookings Institution. "This is the way our federal government should operate. . . . The larger the human organization, the more important performance-based measurement becomes."
That's not the kind of scintillating rallying cry that typically rouses crowds on the stump, but O'Malley has suggested it will resonate nonetheless.
"I think people are actually far more interested in a functioning government and effective governance and people with executive experience than we might give them credit for," he said during the speech at Brookings.
He inspired a character on HBO's "The Wire"
One of the most acclaimed shows on television between 2002 and 2008 was HBO's "The Wire," which took a gritty, unflinching look at life in inner city Baltimore. The show included perspectives from the city's police force and some of its criminal elements. It also included the view from City Hall, and one of the show's characters, Tommy Carcetti, bore a striking resemblance to O'Malley.
Like O'Malley, Carcetti was a charismatic, young politician who held a seat on the Baltimore City Council. Like O'Malley, he staged an unlikely but ultimately successful bid for mayor, becoming a white mayor of a majority-black city. Like O'Malley, Carcetti followed his stint as mayor with a stint as governor of Maryland.
Of course, Carcetti, as his name suggests, was an Italian-American, and O'Malley is an Irish-American. But the actor who played Carcetti, Aidan Gillen, is Irish.
The parallels are striking, but show creator David Simon has said O'Malley was only one of several politicians that influenced Carcetti's character.
Carcetti wasn't always the most morally upstanding player in the show, though, which limits the upside of the comparison a little for O'Malley. In one plot line, Carcetti cooked the city's crime statistics to make it seem like he'd achieved drastic reductions in crime in Baltimore. The story echoed complaints from O'Malley's critics that his data-tracking program StateStat effectively fudged crime statistics to tell a misleading story about progress .
"O'Malley's tenure was as destructive a mayoralty to causes of crime and punishment as Baltimore has ever seen and, by that standard, Tommy Carcetti makes him look good," Simon told the Daily Beast in 2013 .
He's in a Celtic rock band
While he usually plays the part of a fairly unassuming politician, O'Malley has an edgier side as well: he's actually the frontman and lead guitarist for "O'Malley's March," a Celtic rock band.
The band was formed in 1988, according to the Washington Post , and it's seen a host of members cycle through during the last few decades. But even as O'Malley has continued his rise up the political ladder, the band hasn't been discarded. If anything, it's actually risen in prominence thanks to the increased prominence of its frontman.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:00:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds expected for Mohammed cartoon contest outside Phoenix mosque - CNN</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFEdtqEA4pNt5FGi3d5MBNWRMYoMw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778856056008&amp;ei=cUdoVZDELaKEaY7lgNgC&amp;url=http://www.cnn.com/2015/05/29/us/mohammed-cartoon-contest/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>The "Freedom of Speech Rally" will be held outside the Islamic Community Center in Phoenix
It's scheduled to start about the time evening prayers are taking place inside
Phoenix (CNN)
Jon Ritzheimer is a former Marine and he has no middle ground when it comes to Islam.
A T-shirt he wears pretty much says it all:  "F--- Islam."
Ritzheimer is the organizer of Friday's "Freedom of Speech Rally" outside the Islamic Community Center in Phoenix.
It's the same mosque where Elton Simpson and Nadir Soofi attended for a time.  They're the men who drove from Arizona to a Dallas suburb to shoot up a Prophet Mohammed cartoon contest there.  Both were killed by police early this month.
Many Muslims consider any depiction of Mohammed to be blasphemous and banned by the Islamic holy book, the Quran.
The rally
"This is in response to the recent attack in Texas where 2 armed terrorist(s), with ties to ISIS, attempted Jihad," the event's Facebook page said .
Some 600 people say they're attending.
It's scheduled to start at 6:15 p.m., about the time evening prayers are taking place inside the center.  And one other thing, the rally features another cartoon contest.
"I think the whole thing, the cartoon contest especially, I think it's stupid and ridiculous," Ritzheimer said, "but it's what needs to take place in order to expose the true colors of Islam."
D.C. Metro ending issue ads after Mohammed ad submission
Cartoon ads
The rally comes a day after the Washington Metro board voted to stop showing issue ads throughout its system.
The decision was made after Texas activist and conservative blogger Pamela Geller requested the system place ads showing cartoons of the Prophet Mohammed.
She wanted to show the winning cartoon her group's contest in Texas.  The one where Simpson and Soofi were killed by police.
A worried community
Events like this one and other developments have Muslims in the area scared, said Imraan Siddiqi with the Council on American-Islamic Relations.
"Recently the mosques here in Phoenix actually received threatening letters -- very specific threats, saying that we are going to massacre your congregations," he said.
Ritzheimer anticipates possible problems because of the rally and says people should bring their guns.
"People are also encouraged to utilize (their) second amendment right at this event just (in case) our first amendment comes under the much anticipated attack," the event's Facebook page says.
Bikers will be there too, according to the post.
Siddiqi calls it the "intersection of Islamaphobia and (the) gun culture."
"When we see these two things ... then obviously it becomes more of a concern," he said.  "We're advising people ... it's better to stay clear from the event, don't engage with these people."
&lt;div id="ad_rect_atf_01" class="ad-ad_rect_atf_01"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
More from US
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:11:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Volcano erupts 30000 feet into sky in Japan - Washington Post</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFVpLR6juiGBgNT2C7AsbCczvko0Q&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778858876673&amp;ei=cUdoVZDELaKEaY7lgNgC&amp;url=http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2015/05/29/volcano-erupts-30000-feet-into-sky-in-japan/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>By Lindsey Bever and Nick Kirkpatrick May 29 at 6:06 AM Follow @lindseybever Follow @n_kirkpatrick
Images from a live camera show an eruption of Mount Shindake on Kuchinoerabujima island. ( Japan Meteorological Agency via AP,EPA,Reuters)
A volcano erupted Friday morning on the small Japanese island Kuchinoerabu, sending billowing clouds of black smoke nearly 30,000 feet into the sky and prompting authorities to evacuate the islands residents and re-route airline flights, according to reports .
There was a really loud, dong sound of an explosion, and then black smoke rose, darkening the sky, Nobuaki Hayashi, a local village chief, told the national news broadcaster NHK, according to the Associated Press . It smelled of sulfur.
The man had burns on his face, according to CBC News , but no other injuries have been reported.
Nagata Elementary School shows schoolchildren at Nagata Elementary School on Yakushima Island looking towards volcanic ash rising from Mt. Shindake on Kuchinoerabu Island, about 12 km west of UNESCOs World Heritage Yakushima Island in Kagoshima Prefecture, southwestern Japan, 29 May 2015. (KATSUNORI NAGASAKI/NAGATA ELEMENTARY via EPA)
Smoke billowed about 5.5 miles into the sky, forcing Japans All Nippon Airways to divert flights after a volcano on a southern Japanese island erupted Friday. Authorities warned there could be more to come. (Reuters)
Mount Shindake erupted about 10 a.m. local time, prompting Japans meteorological agency to put the island on the highest alert. The islands 140 residents were ordered to evacuate.
Japans prime minister Shinzo Abe launched an emergency response team and told authorities to do everything possible to keep people safe, the Guardian reported .
Kuchinoerabu is located about 50 miles from main Japanese island of Kyushu. Islanders can reach Kyushu only by a ferry sent from Yakushima, a small island 12 miles east.
A video grab photo from the Japan Meteorological Agency shows four eruptions of Mount Shindake on Kuchinoerabu Island in Kagoshima Prefecture, southwestern Japan on May 29, 2015. (JAPAN METEOROLOGICAL AGENCY VIA JIJI PRESS/AFP/Getty Images)
By the afternoon, the ferry had arrived from Yakushima, Tatsuya Terada, a government official on Yakushima, told CBC News . A coast guard vessel was waiting nearby.
We will need to verify safety conditions and check lists of names, but thats currently the plan, Tatsuya Terada told CBC News. Hayashi said a few were still missing.
Mount Shindake also erupted in August 2014  for the first time since 1980.
 Oh!kawa@ (@TAKUYAbluewhale) May 29, 2015
Lindsey Bever is a national news reporter for The Washington Post. She writes for the Morning Mix news blog. Tweet her: @lindseybever
Nick Kirkpatrick is a digital photo editor at The Washington Post. Follow him on Instagram or on Twitter .
Continue reading
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
