<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Huffingtonpost">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:27:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Muhammadu Buhari, First Candidate To Beat A Sitting Nigerian President At The Polls, Sworn In</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/29/muhammadu-buhari-sworn-in_n_7467428.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>ABUJA, Nigeria (AP) — Nigerians celebrated their newly reinforced democracy Friday, dancing and singing songs and praises at the inauguration of Muhammadu Buhari, the first candidate to beat a sitting president at the polls.</Description>
        <MainBody>Muhammadu Buhari, First Candidate To Beat A Sitting Nigerian President At The Polls, Sworn In
| By                                                                      MICHELLE FAUL
reddit
PIUS UTOMI EKPEI via Getty Images
ABUJA, Nigeria (AP)  Nigerians celebrated their newly reinforced democracy Friday, dancing and singing songs and praises at the inauguration of Muhammadu Buhari, the first candidate to beat a sitting president at the polls.
As Buhari finished taking the oath of office in traditional robes and an embroidered cap, the crowd at Eagle Square in Nigeria's capital roared its approval. The former general then inspected troops in the plaza, decked out in colors of Nigeria's green and white flag, from the back of an open vehicle and waved at supporters.
A 21-gun salute boomed over Eagle Square during the handover of power which is a turning point in Nigeria's democratic evolution. Security was tight. In 2010, two car bombs and a grenade blast triggered by militants from Nigeria's oil patch killed 12 people at Independence Day celebrations.
Buhari has a wealth of international goodwill. A phalanx of African leaders attended the inauguration along with France's Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius and U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry, looking to mend fences broken under the discredited administration of Goodluck Jonathan.
Some nervous politicians fear Buhari's promise to retrieve ill-gotten gains for coffers emptied by massive corruption. Nigerian newspapers carried unconfirmed reports that some politicians already have returned millions of dollars in hopes of avoiding scrutiny.
"We see him as our only hope against this crippling corruption," said Efo Okorare, curator of an open-air exhibition of Nigerian leaders, pointing out the many in military uniforms. Buhari ruled briefly as a military dictator in the 1980s. The 72-year-old says that as a "born-again democrat" he can heal the woes of Africa's biggest nation, economy and oil producer.
Buhari inherits leadership of a nation plagued by an Islamic uprising has killed more than 13,000 people driven more than 1.5 million people from their homes. Nigeria is also $63 billion in debt and is borrowing to pay government workers.
Jonathan allowed the nearly 6-year-old Islamic insurgency to flourish before agreeing to an international offensive with troops from neighboring countries this year. His perceived indifference to the suffering caused by the uprising also hurt him. Presidents of neighboring countries have complained of lack of cooperation from Nigeria's government and military in the offensive against Boko Haram, the Nigerian Islamic extremist group.
Buhari, a Muslim from the north, was first installed as president after a military coup on New Year's Eve 1983. In August 1985, he was himself deposed because his fight against corruption and the life-long jail terms for politicians found guilty by military tribunals proved too draconian even for the coup plotters, who felt threatened.
Political science professor Richard Joseph of Northwestern University said Buhari's victory has hopeful international implications.
"The world desperately needs a victory against cultist jihadism. Nigeria (under Buhari) can provide it," he said.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:31:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World's Oldest Murder Case Uncovered In Spain's 'Pit Of The Bones'</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/29/oldest-murder-case_n_7466222.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>Call it "CSI: Prehistory."</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Call it "CSI: Prehistory."
Scientists have uncovered what may be the world's oldest murder case . The victim was bashed in the head -- twice -- and then tossed into a pit deep inside a cave system in Spain. And it happened 430,000 years ago, during the Middle Pleistocene era.
Here's a look at the evidence, examined by a team of researchers led by paleontologist Nohemi Sala of Madrid's Centro Mixto UCM-ISCIII de Evolucion y Comportamiento Humano.
(Story continues below image.)
As seen in the image, there are two cracks in the skull above the left eye.
 Either one of them could have been lethal because they would have penetrated the brain, paleoanthropologist Rolf M. Quam of Binghamton University told The New York Times. The fact that there were two fractures seems to imply an intention to kill.
Indeed, the scientific abstract published in PLoS ONE reads more like a coroner's report:
"The type of injuries, their location, the strong similarity of the fractures in shape and size, and the different orientations and implied trajectories of the two fractures suggest they were produced with the same object in face-to-face interpersonal conflict. Given that either of the two traumatic events was likely lethal, the presence of multiple blows implies an intention to kill. This finding shows that the lethal interpersonal violence is an ancient human behavior and has important implications for the accumulation of bodies at the site, supporting an anthropic origin."
In other words, we humans have been killing each other for a very long time.
"This represents the earliest clear case of deliberate, lethal interpersonal aggression in the hominin fossil record," the research team wrote.
The skull of the victim, a young adult of unknown gender, was found in 52 pieces and then put back together by the research team. Using modern forensic techniques, including contour and trajectory analysis, the team determined that the fractures were made by two separate blows from the same object, each with a slightly different trajectory , according to a news release.
Sala told Reuters that the murder weapon was likely a wooden spear, stone spear tip or stone hand axe. The researchers are still missing a motive, but that might be a little tougher to determine.
"Unfortunately, the intentions do not fossilize so it is impossible to interpret the motivation of the killing," Sala told the news agency. " Not even Sherlock Holmes could help us in that ."
The skull was among 28 sets of remains discovered in Spain in what's known as Sima de los Huesos or the "Pit of the Bones." The pit lies inside a cave system in the Atapuerca Mountains and at the bottom of a shaft more than 40 feet deep.
Scientists believe the ancient murder victim was dead on arrival as falling accidentally might cause one crack in the skull but not two nearly identical fractures. Since the victim didn't fall, the body must've been dumped there.
"The only possible manner by which a deceased individual could have arrived at the SH site is if its cadaver were dropped down the shaft by other hominins," the researchers wrote.
That would make it the earliest known example of funerary behavior in the human fossil record in addition to being the world's oldest crime scene.
Sala told the Los Angeles Times that the other remains are being examined for potential evidence of ancient crimes.
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 09:07:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India Heat Wave Tests Water Supply; Death Toll Over 1,800</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/29/india-heat-wave_n_7466292.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>HYDERABAD, India (AP) — Dizzying temperatures caused water shortages in thousands of Indian villages and killed hundreds more people over the past day, driving the death toll from a weekslong heat wave to at least 1,826, officials said Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>India Heat Wave Tests Water Supply; Death Toll Over 1,800
Posted:
reddit
ASSOCIATED PRESS
HYDERABAD, India (AP)  Dizzying temperatures caused water shortages in thousands of Indian villages and killed hundreds more people over the past day, driving the death toll from a weekslong heat wave to at least 1,826, officials said Friday.
Meteorological officials called the heat wave "severe" and warned that it would continue for at least two days across a huge swathe of the South Asian country from Tamil Nadu in the south to the Himalayan foothill state of Himachal Pradesh.
Most of those killed by heat-related conditions including dehydration and heat stroke have been in the southern states of Andhra Pradesh and Telangana, where 100 people died just on Thursday as temperatures hovered about 43 degrees Celsius (109 degrees Fahrenheit).
Thousands of water tankers were delivering supplies to more than 4,000 villages and hamlets facing acute water shortages in the central state of Maharashtra, state officials told the Press Trust of India news agency.
People across India were reporting scorched crops and dying wildlife, with some animals succumbing to thirst.
Indians were doing whatever they could to beat the heat, including staying in the shade, plunging into rivers, and drinking buttermilk, onion juice and plenty of water.
But many farmers and construction workers struggling with poverty were still working outdoors despite the risks. They along with the impoverished elderly were among the most vulnerable, without access to air conditioners or sometimes even shade-giving trees.
Cooling monsoon rains were expected next week in the south before gradually advancing north.
However, forecasting service AccuWeather warned of prolonged drought conditions, with the monsoon likely to be disrupted by a more active typhoon season over the Pacific.
"While there will be some rainfall on the region, the pattern could evolve into significant drought and negatively impact agriculture from central India to much of Pakistan," senior meteorologist Jason Nicholls at AccuWeather said in a statement.
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 07:53:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran is America's de-facto ally in the war against ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/raghida-dergham/iran-is-americas-de-facto_b_7466066.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>Surprises are increasing in the Arab region against the backdrop of the geopolitical transformation taking place in the Middle East, mainly in the direction of developing a US-Iranian relationship that goes beyond mere appeasement. This is while the US-Israeli relationship remains one of quintessential alliance regardless of the signs of disagreement, and while the US-Arab relationship continues with various titles from the Gulf to Africa, through the Orient and its torn countries. The Americans want to say that the US public opinion does not care about what is happening in the Arab region and that the talk about American roles in the terrible changes that have played out there for years is part of "conspiracy theories". As for the Arabs, from various affiliations and orientations, they seem "certain" that it is US policy that is manipulating the Arab region, and leading it to partition and fragmentation. </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Surprises are increasing in the Arab region against the backdrop of the geopolitical transformation taking place in the Middle East, mainly in the direction of developing a US-Iranian relationship that goes beyond mere appeasement. This is while the US-Israeli relationship remains one of quintessential alliance regardless of the signs of disagreement, and while the US-Arab relationship continues with various titles from the Gulf to Africa, through the Orient and its torn countries. The Americans want to say that the US public opinion does not care about what is happening in the Arab region and that the talk about American roles in the terrible changes that have played out there for years is part of "conspiracy theories". As for the Arabs, from various affiliations and orientations, they seem "certain" that it is US policy that is manipulating the Arab region, and leading it to partition and fragmentation.
What is clear is that there is a decline in the trust and increase in suspicions in the US-Arab relationship, in parallel with the realignment of the Islamic Republic of Iran in the direction of becoming a reliable partner for the United States. The Obama administration has a big appetite for Iranian offers and for upgrading the bilateral relationship. However, developments on the ground sometimes raise questions about whether the silent US blessing of the Iranian role in the Arab countries is an endorsement of Iranian ambitions or an attempt to implicate Iran in a way that would make Syria and perhaps even Iraq the "Vietnam" of the Islamic Republic of Iran and its allies.
What ISIS is doing in Syria is astonishing, but equally astonishing is how the Iraqi army and the Syrian regime army have handed over to ISIS extremely important areas in both countries. The entry of the Popular Mobilization forces, which are sometimes called Shiite militias, to the Anbar province alongside the Iraqi army to repel ISIS is a dangerous development that exacerbates concerns and suspicions. However, what is happening in Iraq and Syria is not completely separate from what is happening in Yemen, where the Arab coalition led by Saudi Arabia is fighting the Iranian influence represented by the Houthis and their current ally former President Ali Abdullah Saleh. And from the cracks created by the sectarian and tribal wars in the Arab region, the projects for fragmentation and partition are returning to the fore, with talk about cohesive "Petromstan" and Shiastan, independent Kurdistan, and fragmented Sunnistan.
Among the most important statements to be made in public this week following ISIS' takeover of Ramadi, the capital of Anbar province, were those made by Iranian General Qasem Soleimani, the top Iranian Revolutionary Guards commander. Soleimani quoted his message with criticism of the United States, which he said did nothing to help the Iraqi army against ISIS, has no will to fight, and is establishing false alliances as he put it. However, the most important message he sent out was when he said that only the Islamic Republic of Iran can fight ISIS.
Soleimani's message is important because it means that Tehran wants to convince Washington that it is the only party able to repel ISIS and not the Arab, international or Sunni coalition. What Tehran wants is to be the only de facto ally of the United States, which has made the war against ISIS a top priority. Tehran wants to tell Washington that it must not oppose its presence in Iraq or Syria, directly or through Shiite militias in Iraq and Hezbollah in Syria and Lebanon. Only in a ground battle, Tehran says, not through aerial bombardment, can ISIS be defeated; and there are no Saudi or Gulf forces on the ground.
Subsequently, one of Iran's priorities is to convince Washington that regional Iranian ambitions are not expansionist but necessary.
Washington seems almost convinced of the Iranian narrative. Washington believes it is in its interests to ignore the expansionist goals of the Islamic Republic and focus on partnership with Iran against ISIS. Especially so when Tehran sees the ISIS project as an existential threat to its so-called Shiite Crescent project.
That project had emerged during the tenure of former US President George W. Bush at the hands of the neoconservatives, who believed US strategy must be based on supporting that crescent because it served US and Israeli interests. The neocons believed that partitioning the Arab countries was an indispensable necessity to allow the creation of "Petrostan" from the Eastern Province of Saudi Arabia to Iran to parts of Iraq, with corridors to Syria, Lebanon, and Israel. In the view of the neocons ten years ago or so, the tools for achieving this partition include roles to be played by al-Qaeda and similar groups, like ISIS now, to carry out sabotage in Saudi Arabia and help partition and fragment Iraq and Syria.
US President Barack Obama for his part underwent two phases: The first at the start of his tenure when he adopted the idea of mainstreaming the Turkish model with the Muslim Brotherhood taking power in Egypt and other Arab countries. Obama believed this would encourage "moderate" Islam against Islamic extremism. In the second phase, Barack Obama decided that the US interest requires a dtente with the mullahs in Tehran, and so he complied with all their conditions under the title of encouraging "moderation in Iran, as the Iranian regime sold it through Hassan Rouhani.
What is common between the Obama administration and the neocons in the Bush administration is that they both agree on the project for a Petrostan/Shiastan, and what this requires in terms of strengthening Iran, weakening the Arab states that are confronting it, and partitioning the Arab countries. This is a shared interest for Iran, Israel, and Turkey, because removing the Arabs from the regional balance of power suits all three countries.
Therefore, the Arab interest definitely requires that none of the leaders in Saudi Arabia, Egypt, and the UAE make a strategic mistake that would end up weakening this important axis trying to restore the Arab part in the regional balance of power. In this regard, the Egyptian media - and not just the Egyptian leadership and the public - must not slip into arrogance, one-upmanship, or petulance with regard to the Gulf contribution to saving Egypt and empowering it. For their part, the Gulf states must be alert to Egyptian sensitivities, including history, to understand the causes of Egyptian hesitation with respect to the war in Yemen, which has shaken Gulf trust in the Egyptian partner. This is not a time for accountability, but a time for a realistic review of the requirements of the Gulf-Egyptian partnership and protecting it against erosion or collapse. The responsibility falls on the shoulders of all those concerned with the partnership.
What the Gulf leaders heard at the Camp David summit two weeks ago with President Barack Obama regarding Yemen was not encouraging and did not show understanding of the importance of the war in Yemen from the Arab, Gulf, or Saudi perspective. The opinion of Obama's advisers in this issue is that Iran is not a key player in Yemen, and that Iran does not interfere in Yemen's internal affairs. The opinion of Obama and his advisers is that Saudi Arabia and its allies in the Arab coalition have exaggerated the Yemeni threat, and that it was necessary for them to become involved as a party in this war. If Yemen ends up being a quagmire for the Arab coalition, then they would have no one else to blame but themselves, according to the US thinking, which is radically at odds with the Saudi and Arab thinking. The latter holds that the war in Yemen was extremely necessary to stop the Iranian encroachment on the Arab countries, and that there is zero room for defeat in Yemen, as this would threaten Saudi national security.
What happened when the Gulf leaders visited Washington and Camp David is that they found the US president fully focused on the Iranian priority, and that his main message was that no one would be allowed to sabotage his main strategy of Iran, Iran, Iran.
According to sources, Barack Obama did not hear the language of decisiveness that the Gulf leaders had pledged to use. The Gulf leaders did not call for establishing, for example, a no-fly zone in Syria in order to bring about a quantum leap in the support for the moderate armed Syrian opposition. They only listened to Barack Obama say that his priority is repelling ISIS at any cost, that his support for moderate opposition forces will not be upgraded, and that he will not become involved.
The opinion of Obama's advisers is that if the Islamic Republic of Iran, the Revolutionary Guards, and Hezbollah are the instrument by which ISIS can be expelled then so be it. Obama will not become involved in Syria. Let Hezbollah fight the war on ISIS, and let them both perish, after they exhaust the Assad regime and fragment Syria, because Washington no longer cares.
The US policy on Iraq, as the Gulf leaders heard it, is that priority there too is for repelling ISIS at the hands of no matter whom. The Obama administration has decided to ignore the danger of enabling the Popular Mobilization at Iran's hands. For this reason, Washington decided to ignore the fact that the Iraqi army handed over Ramadi without fierce resistance would inevitably lead to calls for help from the Shiite militias in the capital of Sunni-majority Anbar. In other words, Iran has entered Anbar, and this will have very serious implications.
ISIS's adventures in Iraq and Syria raises questions because of the ease at which it is making its sweeping gains. Indeed, the mysterious organization may have been born in Syrian and Iraqi prisons, and was subsequently unleashed by Bashar al-Assad and former Iraqi PM Nuri al-Maliki - both allies of Iran - to tarnish the Syrian revolution. After that, ISIS became ISIS Inc., and a cocktail of intelligence agencies are exploiting ISIS for both divergent and convergent objectives. What is strange, however, is that all these parties do not seem to be concerned by ISIS, which has otherwise spread terror and panic in ordinary hearts.
The Arab region will undergo a difficult and complex period ahead. The mistakes made by Arab leaders are major mistakes. The Iranian ideas have found a sponsor with Barack Hussein Obama.
If only federalism could make its way to realistic Arab strategies. This is the best scenario compared to projects for partition and fragmentation in the Arab region.
Translated from Arabic by Karim Traboulsi
Follow Raghida Dergham on Twitter: www.twitter.com/raghidadergham
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:47:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japanese Volcano Mount Shindake Erupts On Kuchinoerabu Island</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/mount-shindake-volcano-_n_7465596.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>TOKYO (AP) — A volcano erupted on a small island in southern Japan on Friday, spewing black clouds of ash and rock towering into the sky and prompting authorities to tell residents to evacuate the island.</Description>
        <MainBody>Japanese Volcano Mount Shindake Erupts On Kuchinoerabu Island
Posted:
reddit
TOKYO (AP)  A volcano erupted on a small island in southern Japan on Friday, spewing black clouds of ash and rock towering into the sky and prompting authorities to tell residents to evacuate the island.
No injuries were reported after Mount Shindake erupted about 10 a.m. (0100 GMT) in spectacular fashion, sending dense pyroclastic flows of rock and hot gases seaward, the Japan Meteorological Agency reported.
The agency raised the volcano alert level for Kuchinoerabu island, where Shindake is located, to five, the highest on its scale. Shindake also erupted in August last year for the first time since 1980.
A military helicopter was sent to survey the island and assess damage. Chief government spokesman Yoshihide Suga told reporters in Tokyo that the Coast Guard had dispatched a ship to help evacuate the residents.
Nobuaki Hayashi, a local village chief, said about 120 of the island's 137 residents were gathered at a local evacuation facility.
"There was a really loud, 'dong' sound of an explosion, and then black smoke rose, darkening the sky," he told the national broadcaster NHK.  "It smelled of sulfur."
Hayashi said a few people on the island were still unaccounted for. One person, who lives in an area that is generally off-limits, was to be evacuated by boat as he could not travel safely to the shelter by land.
"The skies here are blue, but smoke is still rising to the west," he said.
Kuchinoerabu is 50 miles (80 kilometers) southwest of the main southern island of Kyushu. A heavily forested, mountainous island bordered mostly by rocky cliffsides, it is a national park supported mainly by tourism and fishing.
Footage from NHK showed the mountain shrouded in light gray ash as the clouds from the eruption cleared.
Kuchinoerabu usually can be reached only by a once-a-day ferry from Yakushima island, 12 kilometers (about 7 miles) to the east, which has an airport and a population of more than 13,000 people.
Japan, which sits atop the Pacific "Ring of Fire," has dozens of volcanoes and is frequently jolted by earthquakes.
In March 2011, a magnitude 9 earthquake rocked northeastern Japan, triggering a tsunami that killed more than 18,500 people and ravaged much of the northern Pacific coast.
Authorities recently closed part of a popular hot springs about 80 kilometers (50 miles) from Tokyo because of fears Mount Hakone, which sits to the southeast of Mount Fuji, might erupt.
The eruption last September of another volcano, Mount Ontake in central Japan, killed 57 people.
Setsuya Nakada, a professor at Tokyo University, told NHK that the eruption on Kuchinoerabu was stronger than Mount Ontake's.
Since the 2011 disasters, "this sort of activity has continued," Nakada said, when asked if more eruptions were likely on the island. "Probably the eruptions will continue."
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:49:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'What Happened To The Yazidis Is Nothing But Genocide,' Kurdish Rep Says</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/yazidis-genocide-isis_n_7463034.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON -- When the Obama administration began military action against the Islamic State back in August 2014, </Description>
        <MainBody>'What Happened To The Yazidis Is Nothing But Genocide,' Kurdish Rep Says
Posted:
reddit
WASHINGTON -- When the Obama administration began military action against the Islamic State back in August 2014, one of its stated goals was to defend Iraq's Yazidi religious minority from mass killings by the militant group. Almost a year later, hundreds of thousands of Yazidis have fled their historic homes in northwestern Iraq to escape what many argue is a genocide perpetrated by the Islamic State.
After successfully conquering the Yazidi areas of Iraq in August, the Islamic State, also known as ISIS, summarily executed hundreds of Yazidi men over the age of 14 and took hundreds of women as hostages. The United Nations suggested in March that the group's extremist behavior showed that it intended to carry out a religiously motivated genocide to wipe out the Yazidis.
The Huffington Post spoke with Bayan Sami Abdul Rahman, the Kurdistan region's representative in the U.S., about the actions of ISIS and the current status of the Yazidis.
"What happened to the Yazidis is nothing but genocide," Rahman said. "Anybody who denies that, I think, is just using political maneuvering, which is shameful and despicable in my book."
Rahman is a representative, not a formal ambassador, since the Kurdistan region is a part of Iraq and not an independent state. She took up her post in January, after serving as the region's representative to the U.K.
Though the Yazidis are usually distinguished by their religious identity -- their faith being a distinctive mix of ancient Assyrian, Zoroastrian, Christian and Islamic beliefs -- they are considered ethnically Kurdish. That binds them to the Muslim Kurds in Iraq, Turkey and Syria, who have been involved in defending the minority group against the Islamic State onslaught. As a result of the mass killings by ISIS, more than 400,000 Yazidis are now living as internally displaced persons in Iraq's northeastern Kurdistan region.
The U.N. report argued that the Islamic State's actions constituted a genocide because of their focus on the Yazidis' religious identity. ISIS killed male Yazidis even if they had agreed to convert -- in contrast to its treatment of other religious minorities, whom the group has instead forced to convert or to pay special taxes. Weeks after their massacres, the extremists again highlighted the Yazidis' identity in a chilling piece of propaganda saying that Islamic law required captured women who were non-believers to be treated as concubines and slaves.
"There are women and girls who are being held as sex slaves or sold in the open markets," Rahman said. "It's actually just so horrific to think that today in the 21st century, this still goes on -- that there are people who do the selling and that there are people who do the buying."
Accounts have since emerged of the women's treatment at sex slavery markets, their suffering in the homes of their new "owners" and their efforts to escape their plight -- from reaching out to relatives via hidden mobile phones to slashing their own wrists.
The regional government of Kurdistan, which Rahman represents, is working to recover those enslaved Yazidis. It revealed last month that it has paid Iraqi residents of Islamic State-controlled areas to "buy" Yazidi women and liberate them.
Rahman maintains that what the Yazidis went through should be considered a genocide. Her government has pushed for the U.N. and the U.S. Congress to pass resolutions declaring as much, even though she explained why it would be politically difficult to make that kind of statement.
"Genocide internationally has legal obligations on everybody," she said. "All of us, internationally, by law, are obliged to prevent genocide."
Rahman underscored the importance of this recognition by referring to a prominent Yazidi political leader, the Iraqi parliamentarian Vian Dakhil, who said in Washington earlier this year that the Yazidis' suffering should be classified as a genocide.
"[Dakhil] said that in Yazidi oral history -- it's an oral tradition -- there have been 73 episodes of genocide. But there's no written record, there's nothing to say that this happened, other than what the Yazidis pass on to their children."
"This time, the world witnessed it," Rahman continued, "and for the Yazidis, it's important that not only they and their children recognize this as genocide but also the international community does so."
This is the first installment in The Huffington Post's new "Ambassadors Unplugged" series, which will interview prominent diplomats on important global issues.
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:13:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mystery Saiga Antelope Die-Off Stumps Scientists</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/antelope-die-off_n_7463206.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>Endangered, adorable </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Endangered, adorable Saiga antelope are dying off at a terrifying rate in Kazakhstan -- and nobody knows why.
More than a third of the world's population of saigas has died off in the past month. The cause has stumped scientists and sparked conspiracy theories.
A month ago, Kazakhstan was home to 250,000 saigas. The population was considered a conservation success story. Now, the United Nations has confirmed that 120,000 saigas are dead , and the number may continue to rise.
Biologist EJ Milner-Gulland told The Guardian that the evidence points to a highly contagious disease. The U.N. statement said the bacteria Pasteurella and Clostridia are contributing to the die-off. But both bacteria are opportunistic, meaning they only kill animals with weakened immune systems.
Nobody's sure why so many saigas have succumbed. Kazakh environmentalists blame toxic Russian rocket fuel that may have rained down on the plains after rockets exploded during their launch from a Kazakh site, The Guardian reported.
Saigas are compellingly strange-looking creatures with a distinctive long nose. Male saigas use their capacious nostrils to produce a "nasal roar" during mating season.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:11:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The IRS Data Theft and Putin's Red Notice</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/harlan-green/the-irs-data-theft-and-pu_b_7464490.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>It has to be more than a coincidence that the </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
It has to be more than a coincidence that the recent cyber theft of IRS tax data has been traced to Russian criminals.  IRS investigators believe the identity thieves who stole the personal tax information of more than 100,000 taxpayers from an IRS website are part of a sophisticated criminal operation based in Russia, two officials told the Associated Press.
"The information was stolen as part of an elaborate scheme to claim fraudulent tax refunds, IRS Commissioner John Koskinen told reporters. Koskinen declined to say where the crime originated," said the AP report.
In fact, the connection between fraudulent tax refunds and actual officials of the Russian government has been well-documented by former Russian Hedge Fund Manager Bill Browder in his new book, Red Notice, which provides evidence of how Russian government officials were able to steal back $230,000,000 in taxes paid by his hedge fund, Hermitage Capital, which managed $4.5 billion in assets at the time.
This happened in Russia.  Russian officials have stolen from their own government.  It was Russia's FSB Secret Police, successor to their KGB, that stole actual tax receipts, according to Browder.  They had raided his Russian offices, and confiscated the corporate seals and legal documents of corporations he managed that had paid $230 million in taxes the year before President Putin kicked him out of Russia in 1995.
When Russian officials found they couldn't confiscate his assets--he had been able to sell all his Russian assets--they literally changed the ownership of his corporations and re-filed fraudulent tax returns.  The refiled returns then reported sufficient losses that they could claim a refund for all of the $280 million in taxes his companies had paid to the Russian government.
This was so blatant a financial fraud that we can be sure our IRS must be aware of Russian government complicity.  How?  Because Browder was able to document the fraud, which resulted in a new U.S. law, the Sergei Magnitsky Rule of Law Accountability Act ,  which named the actual perpetrators of the tax theft --some 35 Russian government officials at last count--from ever entering the U.S. and freezing their assets.
Yet it seems even the IRS can be fooled.
"In 2012, the IRS sent a total of 655 tax refunds to a single address in Lithuania, and 343 refunds went to a lone address in Shanghai, according to a report by the agency's inspector general. The IRS has since added safeguards to prevent similar schemes, but the criminals are innovating as well, said the AP report.
The amount of rampant criminal fraud in Russia cannot have happened without Putin's knowledge or assent.  We know this because the very same perpetrators of the Browder-Hermitage Capital tax fraud were awarded medals by Putin for their 'heroism' in the scheme, believe it or not.
The Russian government then charged Bill Browder with the theft, which resulted in a call for his arrest by Interpol, and the resulting Red Notice--a notice the Russian government put out to Interpol for his arrest.  They have put out a Red Notice 3 times to date, and 3 times Interpol has rejected their request because of the overwhelming evidence that the Russian government was behind the theft.
This shows the lengths corrupt officials have gone to cover up their thefts.  That's why we should have no illusion about the IRS tax return thefts.  It's a new cold war, of sorts.  Putin's Russia will want to continue stealing tax refunds from US taxpayers as they have done in Russia.
We also know this because Sergei Magnitsky , Bill Browder's Russian attorney, was imprisoned and beaten to death by the same perpetrators for his refusal to recant the evidence of theft that defrauded the Russian people.
Harlan Green  2015
Follow Harlan Green on Twitter: www.twitter.com/HarlanGreen
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:46:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sweden Is About To Give New Fathers A Third Month Of Paid Paternity Leave</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/sweden-paternity-leave_n_7463530.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>Sweden is a great place to be a dad, and the country is about to make things even better for soon-to-be fathers.</Description>
        <MainBody>5 Countries With No Maternity Leave
of


New parents in the U.S. are entitled to a measly 12 weeks of job-protected time off under the 1993 Family Medical Leave Act, though with no cash benefits. And the 12-week rule only covers those who work for companies with 50 employees or more. Unfortunately for expectant parents, a full 96 per cent of businesses in the United States have fewer than 50 workers on the payroll.  Some states do offer paid leave, along with more enlightened companies, including Google, which gives new parents 22 weeks plus $500 in cash to cover baby-related expenses.  Yahoo CEO Marissa Mayer increased paid leave for moms from eight weeks to 16; the company also gives dads eight weeks off.
In this tiny nation, nestled within South Africa, life expectancy is just 52 years, three-quarters of the country's two million people are subsistence farmers, and 42 per cent of women are unemployed.
Also located in southern Africa, Swaziland is an impoverished nation where 60 per cent of the population lives on less than $1.25 a day.  It also has one of the highest rate of HIV infection among adults aged 15 to 49: 26 per cent. Among pregnant women between the ages of 30 and 24, that spikes to a heart-wrenching 54 per cent.  Not surprisingly, the country is in the bottom 10 when it comes to life expectancy, which is just 47 years.
This island just north of Australia remains one of the least explored places in the world. The majority of Papua New Guinea's seven million inhabitants still live in traditional societies and speak 820 indigenous languages. Most women are illiterate and have an average of 3.3 children (compared to 1.89 in the U.S.).
The West African nation of Liberia was colonized by black Americans in the 1820s, mostly by freed slaves, who ruled for 130 years.  In 1980, they were overthrown in a military coup that led to bloody civil wars that killed 250,000 people and brought Charles Taylor to power. Taylor was himself overthrown after yet another horrific conflict.  In 2005, a Harvard-trained economist named Ellen Johnson Sirleaf came to power in Liberia's first fair election. Africa's first female president won the Nobel Peace Prize in 2011. So there's hope that Liberia will be surpassing the U.S. on maternity leave sometime soon.
Maternity Leaves From Around The World
Length Of Maternity Leave: 52 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid:  55 per cent at 17 weeks for maternity leave, and the additional 35 weeks can be taken by either parent. Wages also depend on province.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 3 Months Percentage Of Wages Paid: 80
Length Of Maternity Leave: 14 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 14 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 67
Length Of Maternity Leave: 14 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 14 Weeks Paid, 38 Weeks UnpaidPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 14 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 80
Length Of Maternity Leave: 12 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: No national program but cash benefits may be provided at the state level.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 15 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 82 per cent for the first 30 days and 75 per cent for the remaining period.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 105 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 70
Length Of Maternity Leave: 105 Days Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 16 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 16 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 112 Days Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 16 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 16 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 16 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 119 Days Percentage Of Wages Paid: 50
Length Of Maternity Leave: 18 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: Each parent can take up to 12 months of leave, of which 18 weeks are paid.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 126 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 126 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 126 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 126 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 126 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 85
Length Of Maternity Leave: 120 to 150 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: Parental benefits paid at 100 per cent for the shorter duration of leave and 80 per cent for the longer option
Length Of Maternity Leave: 140 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 20 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 140 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 5 MonthsPercentage Of Wages Paid: 80
Length Of Maternity Leave: 135 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid:90
Length Of Maternity Leave: 24 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 70
Length Of Maternity Leave: 26 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 80
Length Of Maternity Leave: 28 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 60
Length Of Maternity Leave: 28 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 55
Length Of Maternity Leave: 9 MonthsPercentage Of Wages Paid: Not found.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 36 to 46 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: Parental benefits paid at 100 per cent for the shorter duration of leave and 80 per cent for the longer option.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 365 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 80 per cent prior to birth and for 150 days after and 50 per cent for the rest of the leave period. Albanian Prime Minister Sali Berisha shown here.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 1 YearPercentage Of Wages Paid: 82 per cent for the first 30 days and 75 per cent for the remaining period.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 1 YearPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 52 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 52 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
52 Weeks 90 (p)
Length Of Maternity Leave: 420 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 80
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:46:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Will Putting Silk Road Founder Ross Ulbricht Behind Bars Accomplish Anything?</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/stefanie-jones/ross-ulbricht-silk-road-sentence_b_7464438.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
Friday Silk Road founder Ross Ulbricht will be sentenced. He faces the possibility of between 20 years to life behind bars because drugs were bought and sold on his website. The prosecution is painting him as a major drug dealer and blaming him for the deaths of six people who overdosed (without acknowledging that our current drug policies lead to 35,000 accidental overdose deaths per year).
On the eve of his sentencing, it's worth considering: what will we actually accomplish by putting this man away?
The fact is, the existence of Silk Road proved something we all know to be true: millions of people around the world want to use and buy drugs. As many have argued, including my former colleague Meghan Ralston and Phil Smith on Alternet , Silk Road's online marketplace actually reduced the harms of drugs in several key ways.
Silk Road reduced the potential violence associated with buying drugs. By taking away the need for face-to-face interaction, Silk Road reduced the violence commonly associated with drug purchases. It also took power away from cartels.
It allowed for better knowledge about content and purity. One of the greatest dangers of drug use is that it's very difficult to know if you're getting what you intend to get, especially with today's rapidly diversifying synthetic market. Using a review system similar to what you'd see on Yelp or other sites, a seller who was not representing his or her product accurately would not have customers long, and a user could be sure about his or her purchase.
It encouraged harm reduction among users. Silk Road had a whole section of its site devoted to safer drug use practices. It's relevant and important that this kind of content reach people at the very place where they are making purchases.
Ulbricht's defense recognized this and included these arguments in their memo to Katherine Forrest, the judge handing down the sentencing. If nothing else, a shorter sentence might help acknowledge the reality that no matter what your opinion about drug sales, Silk Road served as harm reduction for these marketplaces.
Friday, the path of Ulbricht's life will be determined. But his sentencing will have little to no impact on those millions of people who will still buy and use drugs. Other online drug marketplaces will arise and the violent, wasteful drug war will carry on unchecked.
Unless we end 40 years of failure, and consider the lessons from Silk Road, and think about a new approach to drug use and sales.
Stefanie Jones is the nightlife community engagement manager for the Drug Policy Alliance.
CORRECTION: A previous version of this post incorrectly stated that Ross Ulbricht may be facing 30 years to life in prison.
This piece first appeared on the Drug Policy Alliance Blog .
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:29:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FINALLY: Science Figured Out Where The Holes In Swiss Cheese Have All Gone</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/swiss-cheese-holes-gone-science_n_7462942.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>New research is poking holes in old thinking about Swiss cheese. Namely: Where do cheese holes come from, and where have they all gone?</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
New research is poking holes in old thinking about Swiss cheese. Namely: Where do cheese holes come from, and where have they all gone?
Those questions have plagued Swiss cheese producers who, in the last 15 years, have seen the signature holes in their product decrease for no apparent reason. Thanks to Agroscope, a government-funded Swiss agriculture institute, we now know it all comes down to hay.
In a report released Thursday, Agroscope and the Swiss Federal Laboratories for Materials Science and Technology revealed microscopic hay particles are believed to be responsible for the creation of holes in cheeses such as Emmental and Appenzell.
Cleanliness has increased in cheese-making facilities in the last 15 years, virtually eliminating the possibility for outside particles to enter the milk before it's converted into cheese and stored. That, in turn, has prevented Swiss cheese from developing its characteristic holes.
Agroscope spokesman Regis Nyffeler told The Telegraph the primary difference in cheese manufacturing methods has been "the disappearance of the traditional bucket" used during milking. Before, small amounts of hay would have entered the bucket; now, sealed milking machines send the milk straight to a filter.
Agroscope arrived at their newest hay-pothesis after taking multiple CT scans of cheese as it developed over a 130-day period, reports the Swiss Broadcasting Corporation . The research overturns a prior theory , held since at least 1917 , that concluded the holes were created by bacteria that produced carbon dioxide bubbles.
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:19:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why UN Peacekeeping Needs Global Support More Than Ever</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/herve-ladsous/why-more-than-ever-un-pea_b_7464110.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>Eighteen  months ago, Bentiu, like most towns in South Sudan, was bustling with the  restlessness of markets, people trading and children going to school.  </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Eighteen  months ago, Bentiu, like most towns in South Sudan, was bustling with the  restlessness of markets, people trading and children going to school. UNMISS, the UN Mission in South Sudan , was  busy supporting development and growth in the world's youngest nation.
Today,  a visitor to the UN Mission's base outside Bentiu, in Unity State, would see a  sea of blue-and-white tarpaulin tents and hastily erected stalls. The base has  become temporary home to some 63,000 civilians seeking protection from the  cataclysm of violence that has gripped the new state of South Sudan since the  outbreak of the political crisis in December 2013. The town of Bentiu itself remains  deserted, its main dirt road lined with the grim evidence of an ongoing war in  the absence of a final peace agreement between government and opposition  forces.
The  story is repeated across the country. Today, more than 130,000 are being  protected by UN peacekeepers in seven bases, with civilians continuing to arrive  at UN protection sites as they flee unimaginable suffering and grave human  rights violations.
As  we mark the International Day of UN Peacekeepers , the reality is that our peacekeepers  are often the only hope for a better life for the civilians they are mandated  to serve. In other places where peacekeeping missions are deployed today, there  is little peace to keep. In some of the harshest conditions on Earth, UN  personnel must negotiate complex threats each day amid political instability,  with large, often terrified populations to protect. In these places they work to provide  security while pursuing a political solution to ongoing  conflict.
This  is the case in Mali, where peacekeepers strive to bring stability while bearing  the brunt of violent attacks from armed groups. Since the establishment of the United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in Mali in July  2013, 36 peacekeepers have been killed, and more than 170 others have been  wounded in hostile incidents alone. It is also the case in the Central African  Republic , where we are seeing encouraging signs following the 2013 breakdown in  law and order and widespread ethnically motivated violence. Here, 10,000 UN  troops, police and civilians are on the ground, supporting efforts to bring the  country back onto the path of peace, good governance and stability. Earlier in  May, the country adopted a peace pact that reflects the people of the Central  African Republic's aspirations to put the conflict behind them once and for  all. Our peacekeepers battle inhospitable terrain and an almost complete lack  of infrastructure every day to react quickly to flare-ups of violence that, if  left unchecked, could threaten this fragile peace.
Over the course of nearly seven decades,  UN peacekeeping has proven itself to be a legitimate, reliable and effective means  of protecting civilians and facilitating the transition from conflict to peace.  In countries like Liberia, Timor-Leste and Bosnia Herzegovina, peacekeeping has  played a critical role in helping stabilize countries as they seek to rebuild.  Today, more than 125,000 military, police and civilian staff carry on this work  in 16 peacekeeping operations worldwide, our largest deployment in history,  serving as a testament to the international community's faith in peacekeeping  as a tool for bringing peace and security.
But  for UN peacekeeping to continue responding effectively and robustly to the  conflicts of today and tomorrow, it needs a strengthened international  partnership and the willingness of all to share the burden and risk. In  environments where peacekeepers are directly targeted, where widespread  violence is ongoing, or where thousands of civilians need protection from  unthinkable acts of violence, peacekeeping operations must remain fit for  purpose. Our missions require well-trained and skilled troops from a broad  array of countries. When crises erupt, they must be ready to deploy more  quickly to where they are most needed. And to confront the unique challenges of  this century, peacekeepers require the tools and capabilities of this century.  In the Democratic Republic of the Congo , unarmed, unmanned aerial vehicles are  being used to improve situational awareness, serve as a deterrent to armed  groups and improve mandate delivery and the safety and security of our  personnel. In Mali, an innovative Information Fusion Cell is improving the  information-gathering efforts of the peacekeeping mission as it confronts determined  non-state actors and armed groups. As we honor the 126 peacekeepers who died  in 2014 , these tools help our Blue Helmets better protect themselves and  vulnerable populations.
A  renewed engagement of all member states of the United Nations is critical. This  process has already begun and will receive a major boost in the margins of this  year's General Assembly, where the secretary-general and several world leaders  will co-host a summit on UN peacekeeping. For its part, UN peacekeeping is  determined to be more innovative, more flexible and more cost-effective. With  an annual budget of just under $8.5 billion -- less than one half of 1 percent of global  military spending -- we are working to increase our value for money and using  new approaches to implement our mandates more effectively and efficiently.
Peacekeeping  missions deliver because they represent a convergence of interests that is the  fundamental concept behind the United Nations. At a moment in history where new  crises and conflicts emerge constantly, the stakes for peacekeeping are higher,  and the consequences of failure are dire. The people of Bentiu, like the  populations protected by missions around the world, today deserve a UN  peacekeeping institution that is an effective tool of international peace and  security. More than ever, today, UN peacekeeping needs global support.
Find out more at www.un.org/peacekeeping .
Follow Herv Ladsous on Twitter: www.twitter.com/UNPeacekeeping
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:15:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>10 Children's Books That Paved The Way For A New Queer Protagonist</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/lgbtq-childrens-books_n_7462250.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
In Kendrick Daye and Myles E. Johnsons Large Fears, Jeremiah Nebula may not be a bullfrog. But he is the queer, black protagonist of a childrens picture book -- a genre traditionally dominated by heterosexual, cisgender, white characters. Although the politics of representation is an issue for all literary forms, parent sensitivity has made materials for young readers particularly resistant to plots that question gender, sexuality or the institution of the family.
Daye and Johnson were frustrated with those age-old patterns, so they decided to create new ones. Their recent Kickstarter campaign casts the project as both subtle and radical. Jeremiah, they say coyly, is just a boy who loves pink. But they also stress how his queer, black identity makes him a character that defies gender roles, race politics, sexuality, and his fears.
Jeremiahs story builds on over 30 years of childrens books that portray LGBTQ characters, translating complex issues of gender and sexuality to an accessible, picture-heavy format. These books, though, reveal far more than cutesy anecdotes. They are instructional, cathartic, and ethical, explaining different family models, connecting children with LGBTQ identities or parents to fictional counterparts, and teaching values of acceptance at impressionable ages.
Jenny Lives with Eric and Martin by Susanne Bsche (1981)
This black-and-white Danish photobook was arguably the first to feature gay characters. Two men raise their daughter, Jenny, whose biological mother lives nearby and visits from time to time. Most events are normal childrens books fare like laundry-folding and surprise birthday parties. But the characters also deal with a homophobic comment from a stranger in the street.
Heather Has Two Mommies by Lesla Newman and Diana Souza (1989)
Like Bsches story, this one follows a child with same-sex parents. New plot points include artificial insemination and an inclusive discussion at Heathers playgroup about different family structures. In real-life playgroups, the response to this book was far less benign: the story rocked the U.S., and the resulting controversy led to extensive parodies including a "Simpsons" version: Bart Has Two Mommies.
Ashas Mums by Rosamund Elwin, Michele Paulse and Dawn Lee (1990)
Asha needs to get a permission slip signed by her mother, but she is perplexed when she must decide which of her two moms to ask. While Heather was lucky enough to have an accepting playgroup, Asha confronts a far less hospitable school -- and world. Its a tale for anyone whose family does not fit into educational bureaucracy, and Ashas African-Canadian identity marks a decisive step away from lily-white characters.
Daddys Roommate by Michael Willhoite (1991)
You might recognize the name from the 2008 presidential campaign when it came out that Sarah Palin, back in her 1995 councilwoman days, had said the book should not be permitted in public libraries. Why? Theres a gay relationship between the the father and his new roommate-actually-boyfriend, Frank. Plus it all starts off with a divorce and arrives at a pretty clear message: Being gay is just one more kind of love.
King &amp; King by Linda De Haan and Stern Nijland (2002)
Originally published in Dutch, this book offered both a new take on the royal marriage story, with a gay child rather than just gay parents. I've never cared much for princesses, says the princely protagonist, as he finds a series of potential wives paraded in front of him by his wedding-hungry mother. Then, he spots one of the princesses brothers. They are soon crowned King and King, and the story ends with a subversive same-sex kiss -- which launched a series of conservative campaigns to ban the book.
One Dad, Two Dads, Brown Dad, Blue Dads by Johnny Valentine and Melody Sarecky (2004)
Instead of focusing on a single storyline, the book features two kids comparing different paternal figures. Blue, it turns out, is a not-so-subtle euphemism for gay, and the children slowly come to the realization that all skin-colors and sexual identities are equally valid. (Bonus points for the enchanting Seussical rhyming scheme.)
And Tango Makes Three by Justin Richardson, Peter Parnell and Henry Cole (2005)
A tale of two male penguins who are chick-less until a zookeeper helps them adopt Tango from a heterosexual couple. Animals are always one of the easier ways to discuss unconventional storylines, but that didnt stop Singapore from banning the book along with two others last year. In fact, its ranked third on ALAs list of  Most challenged books of the 21st century , which is hard to explain considering how heartwarming these polar birds are. Did we mention its based on real gay penguins at the Central Park Zoo ?
10,000 Dresses by Marcus Ewert and Rex Ray (2008)
Bailey is a boy by day who, at night, dreams of cross-dressing. His night-time escapades are rebuked by his family, until he finds a seamstress in playmate Laurel. Baileys story is an early forerunner to Jeremiahs, for it broke from the gay-character plot to examine what it meant to be a gender-queer child.
My New Mommy by Lilly Mossiano and Sage Mossiano (2012)
Who says transgender identity cant be explained to young children? Four-year-old Violet has a transitioning father who carefully walks her -- and us -- through the process. Like Daye and Johnson, Mossiano was frustrated with the lack of childrens materials, so she took matters into her own hands. She challenged herself to make the content accessible to a young audience, but the real challenge is the one she posed to traditional portrayals of gender in children's books.
Call Me Tree by Maya Christina Gonzalez (2014)
The third in a trilogy that opted for gender neutral pronouns, providing what the writer called a much needed break from the constant boy-girl assumptions and requirements. Gonzalez took another decisive step away from the gay parent trend and gave us an unambiguously ambiguous gender-queer character. Her engagement with the Chicano identity also departed from the classic whiteness of LGBTQ childrens characters.
Morris Micklewhite and the Tangerine Dress by Christine Baldacchino and Isabelle Malenfant (2014)
Like Bailey, Morris has a penchant for gender-queer behavior. He loves to wear the titles orange garment but his fashion choices leave him open to relentless teasing from his classmates. Tensions escalate, and Morris becomes physically ill from the psychological pain. Though his imagination helps him triumph in the end, the books real triumph is that it gives a harsh and realistic account of queer bullying.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:07:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Here's More Proof That We Shouldn't Stereotype Dogs By Breed</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/pit-bull-bans-ireland_n_7450400.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>If you're hoping that restricting dogs by breed will lead to fewer dog bites, well, you're barking up the wrong tree, according to the author </Description>
        <MainBody>

Robbybad:Vicious pitbull has my baby cornered.  No wait, she's using her as a recliner never mind.
Stacy Bove-Fulgenzi:Sweet, Gentle and Loving
Terrence Greene:
johnalcock:
Whitney Pflanzer:Starla and Sienna were both found as strays in Indianapolis. After being adopted from the city shelter, they now spend their days as happy girls and love everyone they meet.
Jill Tyler McDaniels:My foster dogs!
Katie Griffith:Capone loves his turtle :)
Adam Mangel:She was mistreated from her previous owners, but patience and a flood of love have brought her back to trust.
Justin Moreno:Our 5 Year old Pitty Marley with her little sister Penny the french bulldog
Krista Hickman:Giving my godson love in the morning!
craigkaos:Piggy Roo, the Pit Bull, and Lucy, the Australian Cattle Dog, have helped raise over 50 Pit Bull foster puppies through Richmond-based Ring Dog Rescue over the past three years.
Megan Lovejoy:This adorable girl is up for adoption through Love-A-Bull, a non profit rescue in Austin, TX. She was rescued from a sad life, which can negatively effect some dogs, but what about this girl? Nope! She is delighted to be friends with EVERYONE. All she wants is non stop tummy rubs, and her favorite little pink stuffed owl toy.
Chris Loveless:Joker and Daphne - Daphne (grey and white) has just met Joker after being brought home from the SPCA. She spent two years as a neglected, starved, and abused dog.
Nomsnotbombs:Mona is a rescue pit mix who hasn't let  her early life experiences deter her from loving life...or every single person she meets. Her appetite for snuggles is insatiable, and she fancies herself to be a 55 pound lapdog.
Megan Lovejoy:Betty the pit bull, Bushi the pit mix, and Polly the teacup pit bull (really chihuahua/peke mix) having a ferocious naptime.
Megan Lovejoy:Betty the wonder-bull!
Candi Diamond:Grandma's cuddle muffin and protector follows her everywhere!
Melissa Sue HutJo:
Angie Laurusaitis:Daisy adored my mother who had Alzheimers. Daisy knew mom was special and kept very close to her
Jamie Delgado:My niece and her Cane Corso/American Bulldog 9 month old "puppy"
AVSmartz:A boy &amp; his dog.  Dog's remind us to stay young and release our inner child. Not a day goes by that Einstein doesn't take me outside to play. Something I would not do every day if not for his friendship.
amy5167:We rescued Emmitt from the county pound on his euthanasia day.  He is a great dog...
Robert Andrade:Petunia and Moby adopted siblings napping
PitBullMomma:Dixie, at the time a 1 year old American Pit Bull Terrier, is best friends with her human sister, Hadley.
Heather DeWitt:
Ashley Endres:Petunia always gets tuckered out at sleepovers with my godchildren.
Brandi Hyatt:His christmas present one year. He kept handing it to my barely one year old daughter Seraphina to "throw" lol
HarkShark:Our Pit Bull Pearl loves to curl up on the pillow on the couch.
Danielle Bauman:Um, excuse me but that looks like a hot dog you're holding. May I pleeeeeeaaase?
Jennifer Flees:
Brandy Lehto:Suvi and Ramsey live peacefully with their chihuahua brother.
Brian Martin:Pierre and KrazyKat snuggling up for a nap.
rappublicist:Pit Bulls can be super heroes
PitBullMomma:Dixie, a 2 year old American Pit Bull Terrier, is best friends with her human sister, Hadley.
Brandy Lehto:Suvi lives at home with her sister Ramsey (a doberman) and her brother Pablo (a chihuahua). They work day and night to advocate for misunderstood breeds!
ILLJWILL11:
Sam Goodwin 1:Eliza is 2 years old &amp; was rescued by her previous owners from an owner that had her locked in a closet where she only had drywall to eat. She adopted me when they had to move &amp; their new landlord was scared of pit bulls.
Rich Wyckoff:Allie and Brody are both rescues. Allie is teaching her little brother the ins and outs of what faces you need to make to sucker their owners into giving them treats. It's working.
westophervan:All smiles.
Riah Day:My little brother and I taking a nap with freckles (Fatty)
Fayclis: 3 Girls and a Boy
Laura Bobrowsky:Bubba keeping watch on his baby girl
Jill Tyler McDaniels:
woolysock:Mini is a rescue dog. We call her our pit-belle ;-)
Chloe
ILLJWILL11:The nicest, BIGGEST, (100 lb) lap dog I've ever had or seen!
peebo:Child and cop friendly!
Adam Mangel:This is my boy. Had him since he was a little sausage.  He's 10 years old in April and he's never attacked anyone.
Jill Tyler McDaniels:
mmmchelsea:
Chrysta Cherrie:Our buddy, rescued by the Michigan Humane Society, is happily tuckered out after an afternoon playing in the yard.
Our handsome pit at the dog park! His favorite game is chased, only he's the one that likes to be chased. :)
Stevie Manning:Hank loves people and pets of all shapes and sizes!
Justin Moreno:Marley, the 5 year old Pitt bull hanging out with her favorite people in the entire world
the1Murdoc:
Heather DeWitt:
Rick Minyard:I have one each of the top two breeds on the list.  And am all the better for it.
terriecro:Ella just loves to snuggle on the couch
doutsiderd:"Rocky" is a beautiful 18 month old pure pitbull, with 2 different eye colors! She positively thinks that she is human, uses the TOILET!,sleeps under the covers with my son and his girlfriend, has her own seat in the car, and as you can see, loves to dress cool! She is adorable, loveable, great listener, talks to you intelligently, and is such an added family member! She is also gentle and kind with my 8 year old grandson, and loves to open his bedroom door with her paws when she is closed out from him! We love her!!!
Hannah Hilgeford:This is a photo of one of my three pitbulls adopted from a shelter!  She had less than a week before she would be put down due to her breed when Adore-A-Bull Rescue stepped in and saved her.  She is now an irreplaceable part of my family.  And as you can see here she has the most gentle touch and loving intentions while sitting with my Grandmother.
KChance:She will attack you with her tongue.
Kate6917:Bella my 8yr old Pitbull with my 1yr old being used as a couch by my 1yr old 3lb Chihuahua, Fiona
Sharon Brown84:Rub my belly!! Star is a Stafforshire Terrier/Pit Bull
Cindy Parks Ross:
Kristina Gale:Our pups Louie and Nina, having a playdate with Mitzi
HuffPost Blogger Rayya Elias:
michellejacobson:
BeMoreDog:Zoey, a 2 year old rescued pitty/coon hound mix, would much rather cuddle then hurt a fly!
terriecro:Spencer's life was devoted to bringing joy to everyone and loved to give kisses!
Kimberly McClain:We found Hank wandering in the desert while we were camping. Skinny and lethargic but sweet as can be, he loves everyone and everything (kitties included). Now spends his days sleeping, eating, and playing with our two other dogs!
Here's Louie, our Pit/Newfoundland mix. He was acting very guilty this afternoon so I immediately went on a hunt to figure out what he'd done.
Laura Filtness:Brooklyn and Boss are both rescue dogs. Brooklyn was rescued in TN and has helped many people see just how fun loving the breed can be. Boss was rescued by Animal Rescue Corps as part of Operation Forgotten Angels and now has high hopes of becoming a therapy dog.
Della Earley:
HuffPost Blogger Rayya Elias:
rappublicist:Found on street with truck chain padlocked to neck. Look at him now!
Kathy Mc:This adorable girl was abandoned on the streets of NYC more than 3 years ago, and spent a year in foster care before she came to us. She loves sunshine and snuggling, even on a hammock!
CrazyDogLady4:
CourtneyColeman:Swami doing what pit bulls do best: being a couch potato.
bednarluck:
Si Sa:
Michelle Oosterloo:My bull terrier mix Poker. We got him through a rescue 3 years ago and he is the best dog I have ever known. He shares his home with 3 kids, a Boston Terrier and 4 cats. In this pic, my then 5 year old daughter had the flu. He stayed with her all night. Didn't even get up for his dinner.
Sabrina Reichstein Carey:Everyone wants to be on dad's lap so they piled on :)
SamanthaBlake14:My nine year old Ozzy posing like a pin up girl.
Ashley Pie:
Wtebb001:Dexter is a rescue from VA Beach ACAC. He loves his people and playi8ng outdoors.
Cm123803:Raoul Duke giving kisses to his Aunt Greta.
Candi Diamond:The very best dogs on the planet!
Melissa LeBender:Party Animal
Rebecca Mis:Amelia, an American Staffordshire Terrier, enjoying time with her squeaky ball.
Jamie Delgado:Paulie is a sweet 8 month old pitbull found in an abandoned car behind a restaurant.  He has exhuberant energy and will chase balls all day long and learn tricks for yummy treats.  He is available for adoption at the Grass Valley Animal Control shelter in CA.
Noir Dfault:Pancho is a rescue pup that has changed my life and lives of everyone he meets.  He is a true example of the breed and the love of my life.
Michael Brozovic:My boy Petey.
Michael Brozovic:Just loungin' around.
Jamie Delgado:Paulie is a sweet 8 month old pitbull found in an abandoned car behind a restaurant.  He has exhuberant energy and will chase balls all day long and learn tricks for yummy treats.  He is available for adoption at the Grass Valley Animal Control shelter in CA.
Jamie Delgado:Popeye was found as a stray being attacked by 2 other dogs, he just hid under a car.  He is loves to chew on balls like they are gum and is learning how to sit still for doggie "cookies" He is available for adoption right now at the Grass Valley Animal Control shelter in CA.
mipadre:
Eh653198:We adore all of our dogs!!!!!
Athena Scheidet:Peewee and Bella Mia enjoying a swell cuddle
s s s s:Rory &amp; Cy, pit bull mixes, live in harmony with little sister Cookie and 2 cats!
Diana DeGarmo:One of our failed foster, pit mixes. The Face of Boe, Bowie for short, is the biggest baby of a dog you'll ever meet. He was found on Christmas eve, tied to a fence by two policemen in NYC. I simultaneously want to shake his former owners for abandoning him and hug them because I'm so glad he's mine. Mostly shake though because Bowie was definitely not treated well previously. He's living the good life now.
Sabrina Reichstein Carey:Boxie the pibble loves her kitty and doggy friends :)
Heather Farquhar:Smudge at his book club
sampista:A ball and some grass--pure bliss.
Ashley Thibault:Best dog in the world.  My Dot, she's 10.  Pictured with her brothers Redgie and Bagpuss.
Robin Weissbohn Barnes:
Wtebb001:Dexter and our other rescue Winter
Robs Raven:Daddy's Girl
Meagan Jane:My Pit mix and my new boxer pup
Souhaila El-Souki:Sweet Alice's favorite spot to cuddle up and relax-my bed
Souhaila El-Souki:My sweet Alice showing grandma love
Souhaila El-Souki:My sweet Alice in her favorite comfy chair with my mom
jlgclassof2000:Gemma at Guardian Pit Bull Rescue's Kissing Booth
gow81:My girls and their dogs, Ace our cocker spaniel and Kitty our pitbull.
Laura Filtness:rooklyn and Boss are both rescue dogs. Brooklyn was rescued in TN and has helped many people see just how fun loving the breed can be. Boss was rescued by Animal Rescue Corps as part of Operation Forgotten Angels and now has high hopes of becoming a therapy dog.
Gurpreet Sandhu:Stella
Eva Lagudi-Devereux:Our beautiful Rescue! We are constantly trying to overturn the stereotype of aggressive dangerous pit bulls. She may cuddle you to death.... but I think thats it!
Azsa Hanson:
gow81:Always looking out for her.
Fred Aguirre:Sam and Mali garden keepers
Rachel Harrison Massa:Shea spent the first year of his life passed around from shelter to foster home, and we still can't understand why no one wanted him.  Aside from being the sweetest most loving dog, he is the absolute best friend to our 3 year old son.  His only problem is - he thinks he is a lap dog!
Sarah Miller Ross:Bauzy Boo Bear - the sweetest, most gentle baby boy ever :)
Pj Kendrick:Juneau is a ten month old rescued pit bull mix. She also happens to me the best friend a girl could ever hope for.
Sarah Miller Ross:They love to snuggle, even when they don't quite fit ;)
Vicki Gramm:Taking a break from all the fun.
Kim Wangnoo:My grandson Jaylen and his BFF, Rylee.  Sweetest dog in the world.  I was leery when my daughter got a Pit but Rylee changed my heart 100%
DunkNorris:MooMoo is a beautiful rescued pit bull. She loves to enjoy the warm summer sun on her face.
Lizz Rockford:MOMMMYYYYY are you still fueling up the car I can't see you
Lindsay Henson:Roxy our rescue posing with her hat on July 4th.
Ashley Duesler:Bailey (brown) 8 years old &amp; Lola, 10 months old are the best of friends and snuggle buddies with my two boys!
Jill Spinello:
Shannon Westphal Kubenez:Mr. Jack!
Rebecca Cohen Clayter:Two rescued pit bulls = two VERY spoiled babies!  Beau was only 5 months old and roaming the streets of Philadelphia when we adopted him.  Halo is a pure breed American Staffordshire Terrier whose family never registered her microchip!  She's our "foster failure"!
Heather Feamster:
nvtribefan:
Claudiagsb:The most amazing companions our family can have!Pita, Lilo and Rocky , rescued from a high kill shelter in FL, they now enjoying their days sunbathing or on the sofa!
David Von Eschen:Madison as a puppy
Eileen Finn:Our girl, Sunshine, has the cutest, goofiest grin ever.
Jake McGee:Teddy in Shades
ChristopherCharles:Baby was kept on a chain in a backyard for three years, She recently got her Canine Good Citizen certificate and is now training to be a therapy dog!
bcarmic:Patty the Pet Bull  bobcarmichael.com
Cage LaCapitan:Stewie does not like to get out of bed. He'd rather snuggle than get up.
casaroonc:The best dog that has ever been part of our family. My boys could do anything to him when they were younger &amp; he would tolerate it &amp; give back love. He also understood over 100 words, he was very smart.  He was truly a forever dog. He is greatly missed.
RonJRoy:First day home and so excited!
Kristine Genovese:Blue is a 5 yr old rescued Pit/Rhodesian Ridgeback X who loves dressing up in costumes and playing with his 6 yr old human brother and border collie sister. He is the most mellow dog we've ever had, and at 80 lbs is a big lap dog/cuddle bunny!
Mags226:Benny the Pit Bull has four brothers who are all cats. They are best friends and take turns adoring each other.
Stacy Lusk:Juniper visiting the beach for the first time. We rescued her from a local shelter in July of this year.
CJ Osburn:Acey lounging with his Dad
Si Sa:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:56:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A Guide to Slovenia's Best Craft Breweries</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/inga-batur/a-guide-to-slovenias-best-craft-breweries_b_7447918.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>Despite its size of 20.273 square kilometers, Slovenia is home to roughly around 28 breweries, making it a perfect destination for any beer connoisseur. The two major brands are Union and Lasko, recently bought by Heineken. Avoid getting sucked into the local debate on which of these two is better and rather give these small microbreweries a chance. These are the true stars of Slovenia's beer renaissance.</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Despite its size of 20.273 square kilometers, Slovenia is home to roughly around 28 breweries, making it a perfect destination for any beer connoisseur. The two major brands are Union and Lasko, recently bought by Heineken. Avoid getting sucked into the local debate on which of these two is better and rather give these small microbreweries a chance. These are the true stars of Slovenia's beer renaissance.
Bevog Brewery
It's technically produced in Austria, just a few kilometers away from the Slovenian border, but it's owned by a Slovenian. The microbrewery is dedicated to making beers of top fermentation, better known as ales. The owner Vasja Golar claims: "Despite the English roots of ales, we here at Bevog are very creative and do not stick to the established norms. We design our beers in our own way, the way we know is right."
With all the awards they have recently received for both beer and the design of their labels they are apparently doing it right. You can give all their beers a chance at the brewery or get some to take home.
Try: Pale ale Tak -- very tasty and aromatic. It's just a bit bitter at the end, and then it mellows down, beginning for another sip.
Reservoir Dogs
This is one of the youngest microbreweries in Slovenia, located in Nova Gorica. In their case the saying: curiosity trumpets experience, definitely holds true, because despite being young they are certainly making their mark. They've named their beer after the four horsemen of the apocalypse -- a force of nature to be reckoned with, just like their Grim Reaper, IPA and Warriors Pale Ale. As the horsemen, they deliver a blow.
Try: Grim Reaper starts off with an aroma of tropical fruit and then the sweet bitterness takes over.
Mali Grad
A married couple Anja and Urban Florjancic have established their own microbrewery in Kamnik, a few kilometers away from Ljubljana. While husband is in charge of the recipes, they try to further improve them together. In their case being small is not necessarily a disadvantage because they've managed to turn it into a lead, as they pay special attention to the ingredients they use and don't rush the whole process. The results are very delicious bottles of beer.
Try: India Pale Lager (special edition), with a lovely taste full of citruses and it finishes with a bitter bang.
Human Fish
They claim to be the leading family-owned microbrewery in Slovenia. Their glass of IPA was actually my first sample of Slovenian craft beer. You could say I have them to thank for getting hooked and I know for a fact I am not the only one. Their microbrewery is based in Vrhnika, just a few kilometers out of the capital. It is worth mentioning since they offer tours of their place and you can check for yourself to see how the job is being done. They have a wide variety of different beers and are constantly experimenting and trying something new. So, the visit will definitely be inspirational.
Try: Their IPA, which they named "SIPA" (meaning "squid" in Slovenian), hazy orange color of the beer, delicious aroma and a bitter jolt.
Carniola
Rok Rutar is the owner of the Carniola Brewery and he pays special attention to the ingredients he uses. And if you want a uniquely Slovenian experience give his drinks a go, since he primarily uses Slovenian hops. What will also immediately capture your imagination are the pretty cool labels.
Try: ESB, light and refreshing, making it just ideal for the summer.
Pelicon
Voters of Ratebeer website voted them the best beer and brewery in Slovenia in 2014. Matej Pelicon and Anita Lozar opened their microbrewery in the heart of the Vipava valley in Ajdovscina. They launched their first pale ale beer Pally in the November 2013.
Try: They are most famous for their India pale ale beer called the 3rd Pill. But just to make sure how good they are and check if the awards are well deserved you can try the others as well, because their list is getting longer.
This post originally appeared on coolkidzcooltrips.com.
Follow Inga Batur on Twitter: www.twitter.com/Coolkidzcooltri
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
