<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nbcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:53:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Major Flash Flooding Hits Texas, Dozens Rescued</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46c03fa1/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cweather0Ctexas0Efloods0Edozens0Erescued0Estate0Estruggles0Erecord0Erain0En366436/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dozens of people were rescued from flash flooding in Texas early Friday, as emergency responders struggled to cope with the wettest May on record.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_gut_texas_flooding_nod_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Dozens of people were rescued from flash flooding in central Texas early Friday, as emergency responders throughout the state struggled to cope with the wettest May on record.
Flood alerts extended nearly 800 miles from southern Texas to central Missouri, according to The Weather Channel's Justin Abraham. He highlighted "major flash flooding issues around Dallas" after up to 6 inches of rain fell overnight.
advertisement
At 5:10 a.m. local (6:10 a.m.), NBC Dallas-Fort Worth's Ellen Bryan reported that authorities said cars were "still trapped in high water."
Tarik Hawkins, a 30-year-old who works for a Dallas freight company, said he became stranded while trying to drive to work.
Flash #flood emergency from Garland to Allen Texas until 7:15 am CDT. Travel has become impossible in many areas. pic.twitter.com/QeDUL1Yp05
 The Weather Channel (@weatherchannel) May 29, 2015
Speaking to NBC News from the side of the road, he said it had taken him two hours to drive about a mile and described the situation on the road as "very chaotic."
advertisement
He added: "It's extremely dangerous out there. I drive a Mustang and in some areas the water has been coming up to the hood. The people who have tried to drive through have become stuck, so there are tow trucks and fire trucks rescuing people.
"I've never seen anything like this before. I have seen some severe weather, but this extremely dangerous."
5 cars submerged in water on Northwest Hwy at Harry Hines Blvd. @NBCDFW pic.twitter.com/tO0ZWugiO9
 Ellen Bryan (@EllenBryanNBC5) May 29, 2015
Tow-truck driver Robert Levtzow, was stranded on a flooded Dallas street after responding to a police call.
advertisement
"I was trying to put in reverse to get out and it died off and the water started rising immediately," he told The Weather Channel. "I was scared, didn't know really what to do [so] I called my wife immediately."
Israel Ramos, 32, a tower inspector at a communications company in Dallas, said there was 3 inches of water inside his home and the street outside resembled "a river."
He said his neighbor called the police after seeing an SUV floating down the street with a person trapped inside. "They had to be rescued by the fire department," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:41:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Flood Gushed Into Home 'Like a Freight Train'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46c12935/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cweather0Cviral0Evideo0Etexas0Eflood0Ecame0Ehome0Efreight0Etrain0En366456/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Perez family, who filmed dramatic footage of their holiday home being inundated by the Texas floods, have recounted the "terrifying" ordeal.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_roker_flood_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A dad who captured dramatic footage of his family's vacation rental home being inundated by the Texas floods recounted the "terrifying" moment a torrent of water gushed into the building.
"It was like a flood gate opened into your living room," Ernie Perez told NBC News, recalling the flood waters coming through the window of the property in Wimberly, Texas, on Saturday night.
Perez, whose wife, daughter, brother and sister-in-law were all in the house at the time, said the water was "pretty terrifying" and came in "as fast as a freight train."
His wife, Sarah Perez, added: "I was in shock, it was something that was crazy. It was very scary."
Texas has been battered by flooding during record rainfalls this month.
Gabe Gutierrez
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:03:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Allies Fall but FIFA Boss Looks Destined for Re-Election</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46c0fc6f/sc/12/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cfifa0Ecorruption0Escandal0Cfifas0Esepp0Eblatter0Elooks0Edestined0Ere0Eelection0Edespite0Escandal0En366441/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>FIFA's beleaguered president Sepp Blatter was expected to be re-elected for a fifth term despite this week's corruption scandal.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=a_101_seppscandals_150527" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
FIFA's beleaguered president Sepp Blatter was expected to be re-elected for a fifth term Friday, despite this week's scandal that saw several of his closest allies arrested for alleged corruption on his watch.
Blatter, 79, was not mentioned in the 165-page federal indictment unsealed by U.S. officials Wednesday that alleged FIFA executives received more than $150 million in kickbacks over more than two decades.
However, soccer governing bodies in the United States, Canada and Europe have come out in support of Blatter's only opponent, Jordan's Prince Ali bin Al Hussein. They cited the need for change after the biggest crisis in FIFA's 111-year history .
advertisement
Among the most high-profile figures to call for Blatter to step down was Michel Platini, the powerful head of Europe's governing body UEFA. Platini told reporters Thursday that he had asked the FIFA president to quit "with tears in my eyes"  but conceded that Blatter had declined.
The FIFA president has made a series of bullish statements and speeches since the scandal broke. He denied he had any knowledge that some of his most high-ranking deputies were involved in wrongdoing , and in a speech to FIFA's congress ahead of Friday's vote called for "unity and team spirit so we can move forward together."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:59:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Slain Reporter Was Bystander Used as Human Shield: Kin</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46c043b0/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcwashington0N0Cnews0Clocal0CCharnice0EMilton0EYoung0ELocal0EReporter0EKilled0Ein0ESoutheast0EDC0E30A53825710Bhtml0D0Iosource0FSocialFlowTwt0IDCBrand/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The parents of a 27-year-old reporter who was gunned down in Washington, D.C., say she was a bystander used as a human shield.</Description>
        <MainBody>Close
Embed this video
&lt;script type="text/javascript" charset="UTF-8" src="http://www.nbcwashington.com/portableplayer/?cmsID=305416521&amp;videoID=vrmaaiFsFPhQ&amp;origin=nbcwashington.com&amp;sec=news&amp;subsec=local&amp;width=600&amp;height=360"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
More videos (1 of 9)
 
Charnice Milton, the 27-year-old reporter gunned down in Southeast D.C. last night, was remembered today for her devotion to covering neighborhoods east of the Anacostia River. (Published Thursday, May 28, 2015)
Updated at 11:33 PM EDT on Thursday, May 28, 2015
A 27-year-old reporter was gunned down in Skyland in Southeast D.C. last night -- and her parents were told their daughter was a bystander used as a human shield.
Charnice Milton was shot by a man on a dirt bike about 9:40 p.m. Wednesday on the 2700 block of Good Hope Road SE, D.C. Police Chief Cathy Lanier said. The gunman riding in a group of dirt bike riders was trying to shoot someone in another group of riders, police said.
Local Reporter Killed While Being Used as Human Shield
A local reporter was killed while being used as a human shield at a D.C. bus stop. News4's Derrick Ward spoke to the people who knew her best. (Published Thursday, May 28, 2015)
"At 9:28, she texted me and said, 'I'm on my way home,'" the victim's mother, Francine Milton, said. "So, I was waiting for her to text me back and let me know if she needed me to pick her up, if she needed us, where she was. And we never got that text last night."
Milton, who was a contributor for Capital Community News, was taking the bus home after covering a story on Capitol Hill at the time of the shooting,her parents told News4's Derrick Ward. She was rushed to a hospital, where she died.
"She was on her way home doing what she did every single day," Lanier said at a briefing this afternoon.
Ward 8 resident advocate Nikki Peele said she admired Milton's devotion to covering D.C. neighborhoods east of the Anacostia River.
"The story was being told by people who did not live here, and it took those citizen journalists like Charnice ... who gave the true story," Peele said. "She ate with us, she shopped with us, she worshipped with us."
Milton began working for CCN, which publishes East of the River News and Hill Rag, in August 2012, editor Andrew Lightman said.
"We lost one of our own yesterday," he said. "Charnice really loved doing community stories. She loved talking to people."
Milton attended Ball State University and earned a master's degree in journalism from Syracuse University, her Linkedin page says.
Police described the suspect as a male in his late teens with long dreadlocks, last seen speeding away on a dirt bike or moped.
Lanier made an impassioned plea for witnesses to come forward with anonymous tips.
"Help us get to the person who would be so reckless as to take this life in the manner it was taken," she said. "We need closure for this girl, for this community."
Anyone who has information regarding this case is asked to call police at 202-727-9099. Information can also be submitted to the Metropolitan Police Department's text tip line by text messaging 50411.
Published at 5:23 PM EDT on May 28, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:34:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dozens Rescued From Rising Floodwaters in Texas</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46c04c0d/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cweather0Crising0Efloods0Etrap0Etexas0Eresidents0Estate0Estruggles0Erecord0Erain0En366436/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dozens of people were rescued from flash flooding in Texas early Friday, as emergency responders struggled to cope with the wettest May on record.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_gut_texas_flooding_nod_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Dozens of people were rescued from flash flooding in central Texas early Friday, as emergency responders throughout the state struggled to cope with the wettest May on record.
Flood alerts extended nearly 800 miles from southern Texas to central Missouri, according to The Weather Channel's Justin Abraham. He highlighted "major flash flooding issues around Dallas" after up to 6 inches of rain fell overnight.
advertisement
At 5:10 a.m. local (6:10 a.m.), NBC Dallas-Fort Worth's Ellen Bryan reported that authorities said cars were "still trapped in high water."
Tarik Hawkins, a 30-year-old who works for a Dallas freight company, said he became stranded while trying to drive to work.
Flash #flood emergency from Garland to Allen Texas until 7:15 am CDT. Travel has become impossible in many areas. pic.twitter.com/QeDUL1Yp05
 The Weather Channel (@weatherchannel) May 29, 2015
Speaking to NBC News from the side of the road, he said it had taken him two hours to drive about a mile and described the situation on the road as "very chaotic."
advertisement
He added: "It's extremely dangerous out there. I drive a Mustang and in some areas the water has been coming up to the hood. The people who have tried to drive through have become stuck, so there are tow trucks and fire trucks rescuing people.
"I've never seen anything like this before. I have seen some severe weather, but this extremely dangerous."
5 cars submerged in water on Northwest Hwy at Harry Hines Blvd. @NBCDFW pic.twitter.com/tO0ZWugiO9
 Ellen Bryan (@EllenBryanNBC5) May 29, 2015
Tow-truck driver Robert Levtzow, was stranded on a flooded Dallas street after responding to a police call.
advertisement
"I was trying to put in reverse to get out and it died off and the water started rising immediately," he told The Weather Channel. "I was scared, didn't know really what to do [so] I called my wife immediately."
Israel Ramos, 32, a tower inspector at a communications company in Dallas, said there was 3 inches of water inside his home and the street outside resembled "a river."
He said his neighbor called the police after seeing an SUV floating down the street with a person trapped inside. "They had to be rescued by the fire department," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:19:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA Scandal: We're Accused of Nothing, Nike Says</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46c04c0e/sc/13/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cfifa0Ecorruption0Escandal0Cnike0Efifa0Ecorruption0Escandal0Ewere0Eaccused0Enothing0En366431/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Nike Inc said on Thursday that charging documents regarding the FIFA bribery scandal do not allege the company is engaged in criminal conduct.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_30_nn_alexanderfifa_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Nike Inc said on Thursday that charging documents regarding the FIFA bribery scandal do not allege the company is engaged in criminal conduct.
U.S. authorities said on Wednesday nine soccer officials and five sports media and promotions executives faced corruption charges involving more than $150 million in bribes . Swiss police arrested seven FIFA officials who are now awaiting extradition to the United States.
The criminal indictment also mentioned an unnamed sports company that appeared to be Nike.
advertisement
"The charging documents unsealed yesterday in Brooklyn do not allege that Nike engaged in criminal conduct," Nike said in a statement. "There is no allegation in the charging documents that any Nike employee was aware of or knowingly participated in any bribery or kickback scheme."
Nike, which is not a FIFA partner but is challenging Adidas' dominance in soccer by sponsoring many of the world's top players and teams, had earlier said it was cooperating with authorities.
Sponsors such as Visa Inc expressed concern over the FIFA scandal after customers attacked them on social media, threatening to boycott the brands associated with the game.
Visa told FIFA that it could end its sponsorship if soccer's governing body does not restore the reputation of the game.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Farmers Leave Nearly $100M Worth of Apples to Rot</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46c03fa5/sc/28/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cwashington0Efarmers0Edump0Emillions0Eapples0Eafter0Eports0Edispute0En366426/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A record crop of apples, coupled with the West Coast port slowdown earlier this year, is taking a toll on Washington apple growers.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29 2015, 4:08 am ET
Washington Farmers Dump Millions of Apples After Ports Dispute
by The Associated Press
advertisement
SPOKANE, Wash.  A record crop of apples, coupled with the West Coast port slowdown earlier this year, is taking a toll on Washington apple growers.
Nearly $100 million worth of apples that cannot be sold have been dumped into fields across central Washington, the nation's most productive apple region. The apples are being left to rot and compost in the hot sun, an unusual occurrence for an industry that has found ways to market ever-growing crops.
"If we wouldn't have had the port slowdown, we wouldn't have needed this," Todd Fryhover, president of the Washington Apple Commission in Wenatchee, said of the dumping.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nc_microwave_ports_150214" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
He estimated that apple exporters lost at least three weeks of their season because of labor problems at West Coast ports. Along with a record supply of apples, that created surpluses that could not be shipped profitably to markets or processors, Fryhover said.
The Washington State Tree Fruit Association estimated $95 million in lost sales because of apples that could not ship, a figure Fryhover considers low.
Washington is by far the nation's largest producer of apples, a crop worth about $2 billion a year to the state's farmers. The 2014 crop totaled a record 150 million boxes, which weigh about 40 pounds each. About a third of the apples each year are exported to more than 60 countries.
The labor dispute that hobbled international trade through West Coast seaports earlier this year didn't officially end until last week, when the union representing dockworkers announced its members had ratified a five-year contract.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 10:57:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Bulge in This Thief's Pants Was an Assault Rifle</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bfa84c/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcmiami0N0Cnews0Clocal0CStore0EOwner0ETackles0EThief0EWho0EStuffed0EAssault0ERifle0EDown0EPants0E30A54129610Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A Florida store owner took matters into his own hands, tackling a would-be thief outside of his store. And it wasn't your everyday shoplifter.</Description>
        <MainBody>Close
Embed this video
&lt;script type="text/javascript" charset="UTF-8" src="http://www.nbcmiami.com/portableplayer/?cmsID=305418911&amp;videoID=h4vpcMhU8nF4&amp;origin=nbcmiami.com&amp;sec=news&amp;subsec=local&amp;width=600&amp;height=360"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
More videos (1 of 9)
 
A store owner in Davie took matters into his own hands, tackling a would-be thief who tried to steal a rifle by stuffing it down his pants. (Published Thursday, May 28, 2015)
Updated at 11:39 PM EDT on Thursday, May 28, 2015
A Florida store owner took matters into his own hands, tackling a would-be thief outside of the Davie shop, and this wasn't your everyday shoplifter.
The thief was trying to walk out of the Public Pawn and Gun at 6798 Stirling Road with an assault rifle stuffed down his pants .
Man Caught Stuffing Assault Rifles Down Pants
"By the time he left I noticed a bulge in his pants, so I followed him out," said owner, Kevin Hughes. "I didn't want to have an altercation in the store... too many customers and employees here."
Surveillance video shows the 19-year-old suspect, Marlon Alvarez, inspecting the three-foot long firearm inside the store for quite some time before stuffing it down his pants and under his sweatshirt.
Father Charged After 3-Year-Old Son Shoots Sister
Hughes said the suspect first tried to get away with another AK-47. He placed the firearm down his pants, but then changed his mind, putting it back on the display rack and attempted to get away with the other assault rifle.
Alvarez then spent a few more minutes in the store and employees said they thought he was acting suspicious.
"He really was more interested in being left alone, or looking for an opportunity to do what he was doing I guess," said Alan Weiner, an employee at the store.
When Alvarez walked out the door Hughes followed him, unsure if the firearm was loaded.
"Anybody can load it especially if he's putting it down his pants he could've put one in the chamber yes," Hughes said. "That's why I got on top of him, you don't have time to react, it can be scary, you just react."
Alvarez eventually gave up the gun. Hughes took him to the ground but Alvarez got away  running through the parking lot shirtless.
Davie Police officers caught up with him a few blocks away. Hughes said he was happy to have the $900 rifle back, but not because of the money.
"If he took that gun and killed 20 kids tomorrow at a school, I'm responsible for that, so that's not happening on my watch," Hughes said.
Alveraz was charged with grand theft and held on $25,000 bond. The judge later revoked bond for a May 15 arrest on theft and drug possession charges in Pembroke Pines, Florida Department of Law Enforcement records showed.
Published at 10:28 PM EDT on May 28, 2015
News breaks at inconvenient times. 
Download one of the NBC6 mobile apps and have the news come to you. Watch live streaming newscasts, receive  critical push notifications on the go and stay in touch with your city  around the clock.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 07:22:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japanese Island Evacuated as Volcano Erupts</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bdff69/sc/32/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Csmall0Ejapanese0Eisland0Eevacuated0Evolcano0Eviolently0Eerupts0En366381/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Japanese authorities said all of the estimated 137 people on a small island were confirmed safe.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29 2015, 12:22 am ET
Small Japanese Island Evacuated as Volcano Violently Erupts
by M. Alex Johnson and Arata Yamamoto
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_japanvolcano_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Japanese authorities ordered all of the estimated 137 people on a small island to evacuate after a volcano erupted Friday morning in a towering plume of thick, black smoke almost six miles high and a shower of fiercely hot rock and toxic gases.
Japan's main government spokesman, Chief Cabinet Secretary Yoshihide Suga, told reporters that all 137 people believed to be on the southern island of Kuchinoerabu were confirmed safe. Prime Minister Shinzo Abe set up a task force to coordinate operations.
The national broadcaster NHK broadcast a bulletin showing smoke billowing over Mount Shindake, which the Japanese Meteorological Agency said erupted violently at 9:59 a.m. (8:59 p.m. ET):
advertisement
At a news conference late Friday morning, Sadayuki Kitagawa, director of the Meteorological Agency's volcanology division, characterized the eruption as one of "explosive power," with a smoke plume rising 9,000 meters, or almost 30,000 feet, from the crater.
Kitagawa said a pyroclastic flow  a fluidized mixture of blazing rock fragments and toxic gases  was flowing from the volcano and had reached the island's northwest coast.
He said the alert level of 5, the highest on the scale, was being maintained because more powerful eruptions are possible.
advertisement
Japan Meteorological Agency volcano director Sadayuki Kitagawa describes the power of the eruption Friday of Mount Shindake.THOMAS PETER / Reuters
Kuchinoerabu is part of the remote Ryukyu archipelago south of the mainland. Access to the island is only possible by boat, and a nearby ferry service is expected to be diverted to begin evacuating the island's residents.
NBC News' Arata Yamamoto reported from Tokyo.
M. Alex Johnson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 07:02:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gay-Marriage Study Author Admits to Lies, Mag Says</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bdf1d3/sc/32/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cscience0Cscience0Enews0Cgay0Emarriage0Estudy0Eauthor0Eadmits0Elies0Escience0Ejournal0Esays0En366266/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The journal Science has now formally retracted the study that said a person's view on gay-marriage could be changed by a short conversation.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
The study reported that people's views on same-sex marriage could be changed by short one-on-one conversations with gay canvassers.
It came under scrutiny after a Stanford University research team tried and failed to replicate the findings and tipped off the lead author, Donald Green, to the irregularities. They said the firm LaCour supposedly hired to carry out the field work didn't know anything about the project.
Green said that when LaCour was confronted, he refused to turn over contact information for the survey respondents and claimed the raw data had been accidentally deleted.
Since then, LaCour's lawyer has confirmed two false statements in the published study: that survey respondents were given cash incentives to participate, and that funding was provided by a number of well-known non-profits.
"In addition to these known problems, independent researchers have noted certain statistical irregularities in the responses," Science said . "LaCour has not produced the original survey data from which someone else could independently confirm the validity of the reported findings."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 06:04:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>National Spelling Bee Ends in Tie for 2nd Year in a Row</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bdc17d/sc/13/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cnunatak0Enational0Espelling0Ebee0Eends0Etie0E2nd0Eyear0Erow0En366371/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The bee hadn't ended in a tie for 52 years — until last year. Now it's happened for an unprecedented two years running.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 11:04 pm ET
National Spelling Bee Ends in Tie for 2nd Year in a Row
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_os_beechamps_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
OXON HILL, Md.  They couldn't be rattled. They couldn't be denied. Gokul Venkatachalam and Vanya Shivashankar had worked too hard and come close too many times not to win the National Spelling Bee.
So they shared the title, making history in two different ways.
Vanya Shivashankar, 13, left, of Olathe, Kan., and Gokul Venkatachalam, 14, right, of St. Louis.Andrew Harnik / AP
advertisement
The bee hadn't ended in a tie for 52 years  until last year. Now it's happened for an unprecedented two years running.
And Vanya is the first sibling of a past champion to win. Her sister, Kavya, won in 2009.
Vanya's final word was "scherenschnitte." After being informed he'd be the co-champion if he got the next word right, Gokul didn't even bother to ask the definition before spelling "nunatak"  which means a hill or mountain that has been completely encircled by a glacier.
Gokul finished third last year.
Vanya Shivashankar, left, 13, of Olathe, Kan., and Gokul Venkatachalam, 14, of St. Louis, hold up the championship trophy as co-champions after winning the finals of the Scripps National Spelling Bee, Thursday, May 28, 2015, in Oxon Hill, Md.Andrew Harnik / AP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 29 05:38:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beer Giant Stops Production to Give Water to Storm Victims</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46be2a13/sc/10/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Canheuser0Ebusch0Ehalts0Ebeer0Eproduction0Eprovide0Ewater0Etexas0Eoklahoma0Estorm0En366361/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Anheuser-Busch says it has stopped beer production at a Georgia brewery to produce thousands of cans of water for the American Red Cross.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_gut_texas_flooding_nod_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
"Oklahoma and Texas are in an unprecedented situation," Scott said. "There are a lot of folks in need and everyone's coming forward to help out."
Scott said the additional drinking water would be "critical" to relief efforts in the area.
Heavy storms and floods in Texas and Oklahoma this week have left at least 25 people dead, more than a dozen missing , and thousands of homes damaged. The rainfall was enough to fully reverse a drought afflicting the area for the last five years, according to meteorologists.
Anheuser-Busch has 12 breweries in the United States and is the maker of several major brands including Budweiser, Michelob ULTRA, Beck's, Kirin and O'Doul's.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 29 05:23:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heartwarming Photo of Young Cancer Patients Goes Viral</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46c0439f/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cwatch0Cnbc0Enews0Echannel0Cfighting0Ecancer0Etogether0Ephoto0Egoes0Eviral0E45270A739560A8/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Mother's snapshot of her 5-year-old daughter embracing another young cancer patient quickly goes viral. WPXI's Lisa Sylvester reports.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:17:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bowe Bergdahl Not Accused of Sexual Harassment: Officials</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bdc96d/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cbowe0Ebergdahl0Ereleased0Csexual0Eharassment0Eallegation0Eagainst0Ebowe0Ebergdahl0Eunfounded0Eofficials0En36630A6/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Army officials seek to tamp down "false reports" about Bergdahl, charged with desertion after he left his post and was held captive by the Taliban.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Army Sgt. Bowe Bergdahl, who's charged with desertion after he left his post in Afghanistan in 2009 and was held captive by the Taliban for five years, has not been accused of sexual harassment, according to Army officials seeking to tamp down "false reports."
The officials told NBC News on Thursday that while a female specialist at Fort Sam Houston in Texas made an unofficial complaint in February that Bergdahl had harassed and stalked her, she never accused Bergdahl specifically of sexual harassment.
In an informal inquiry, the two soldiers' commanding officer found that the allegations weren't true, the officials said. The female soldier accepted the informal findings and didn't file a formal complaint, they said.
The woman also accused Bergdahl of "unwanted contact and stalking, including leaving origami at her barracks door and showing up at her door in a gorilla suit and hanging around her while she was on staff duty."
The informal inquiry found that Bergdahl would often leave origami for his fellow soldiers and at times would don a gorilla suit in the barracks.
advertisement
In one instance, the Army specialist claimed Bergdahl was stalking her one evening and watching her through her office window at Fort Sam Houston. But the inquiry found that Bergdahl was actually at dinner off-base with soldiers who have been assigned as his escorts when he leaves the base.
Bergdahl had been assigned to administrative duties at Fort Sam Houston in, San Antonio, last summer after a reintegration process following his release by the Taliban.
A frame grab from the Taliban propaganda video released Dec. 25, 2009, purportedly showing U.S. soldier Bowe Bergdahl taken from a video made available by IntelCenter. IntelCenter via AP file
Bergdahl is scheduled to appear for an Article 32 hearing at the base on charges that he deserted his post in Afghanistan in June 2009. He was captured and held hostage by the Taliban and Haqqani terrorist network for five years before he was released in exchange for five high-ranking Taliban prisoners released from the U.S. detention center at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, in May 2014.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:39:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Heartbreaking': Search for Texas Flood Victims Goes On</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bae551/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Ctexas0Efloods0Erivers0Erising0Emore0Erain0Eway0Esearch0Emissing0Egoes0En3660A56/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Rescue crews have already pulled more than 100 people from rushing floodwaters in Texas, some of them swept downstream more than 10 miles.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_fh_dpatricktxflooding_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
The rushing waters swept people many miles away  one dead body was found at least 30 miles downstream, he said, and a person who survived was found 12 miles downstream.
And huge debris and heavy brush are making it hard for crews to know where to look, Patrick said.
"It's heartbreaking," he said.
Sarah Perez of Hays County posted dramatic video of Blanco River floodwaters rushing through her home and submerging the entire first floor. She and her family had to flee to the second floor, where rescuers found them late Wednesday.
advertisement
President Barack Obama offered thoughts and prayers to families in Texas and said the federal and state governments were working well together on disaster relief.
"They appear to have the assets they need at this stage," he said. "There's going to be a lot of rebuilding, and we as a nation are going to have to help, the same way we do any time that folks are affected by these natural disasters."
People were still cleaning up Thursday in Wimberley, where the Blanco left a landscape of tree limbs and shattered houses.
"I wake up in the morning sometimes and I'm thinking, no, this was all just a dream," Chuck Criswell told NBC News.
A restroom building was nearly submerged Thursday at Lake Somerville State Park near Brenham, Texas.Texas Parks and Wildlife
During the worst of the flood, on Saturday night and Sunday morning, "I shined my light out there and it looked like the water was going 500 miles an hour," he said. "The debris just flying by."
On Thursday, an estimated 14 million people in Nebraska, Kansas, Oklahoma and Texas were at risk of more severe weather, and flood watches were posted again for Texas and Oklahoma. A line of thunderstorms rumbled through Oklahoma City on Thursday morning.
5:07 PM: This storm is capable of quarter size hail and winds to 60 mph #txwx https://t.co/cXls60y6cF
 NWS Midland (@NWSMidland) May 28, 2015
A powerful tornado touched down Wednesday afternoon in the town of Canadian, in the Texas Panhandle, injuring three people, authorities said. One of them, a man who was impaled through the abdomen, remained in serious condition at University Medical Center in Lubbock, the hospital said Thursday.
M. Alex Johnson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:37:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dog Walker Finds Body in Suitcase in Pennsylvania</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bd3720/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcphiladelphia0N0Cnews0Clocal0CBody0ESuitcase0ETinicum0E30A53832510Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A dog walker discovered a suitcase with a human body inside Thursday not far from Philadelphia International Airport, authorities say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Close
Embed this video
&lt;script type="text/javascript" charset="UTF-8" src="http://www.nbcphiladelphia.com/portableplayer/?cmsID=305418981&amp;videoID=zh5539wdqhUy&amp;origin=nbcphiladelphia.com&amp;sec=news&amp;subsec=local&amp;width=600&amp;height=360"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
More videos (1 of 9)
 
A body was stuffed into a suitcase just steps away from Philadelphia International Airport. Police are trying to figure out who the victim is and what happened to him. NBC10's George Spencer reports from Tinicum Township. (Published Thursday, May 28, 2015)
Updated at 11:56 PM EDT on Thursday, May 28, 2015
A dog walker made a grisly discovery in Delaware County Thursday afternoon.
The person was walking in the area of the old Westinghouse plant near 2nd Street in Tinicum, Pennsylvania -- not far from Philadelphia International Airport -- when he saw the suitcase, said the Delaware County District Attorneys Office.
Psychiatrist: Colorado Theater Shooter "Knew What He Was Doing"
The man called police who came out and unzipped the suitcase to discover the mans body stuffed inside the large brown case. The man appeared to be in his 20s, said investigators.
Jim Martin -- who walks his dog in the area called "Back Road" that sits just below flights paths -- said that he saw the case in the weeds a few days back and he noticed something strange about it.
Breaking Emergency Bridge Repairs on Area Interstate
"I smelled a smell -- you mentally think something, then you're like pause, pause it's my imagination," said Martin.
It wasn't and it's possible the suitcase had been there for weeks. The investigation into the case continued late Thursday.
Published at 5:22 PM EDT on May 28, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:27:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Argentine Judge Orders Arrest of 3 Executives in FIFA Scandal</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bd7894/sc/13/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cfifa0Ecorruption0Escandal0Cargentina0Ejudge0Eorders0Earrest0E30Eexecutives0Efifa0Escandal0En366296/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A judge in Argentina said Thursday that he had ordered the arrest of three businessmen named in a corruption scandal engulfing world soccer.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 7:27 pm ET
Argentine Judge Orders Arrest of 3 Executives in FIFA Scandal
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_30_nn_alexanderfifa_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
BUENOS AIRES  An Argentine judge said on Thursday he had ordered the arrest of three businessmen named in a corruption scandal engulfing world soccer and facing U.S. extradition requests, though he acknowledged he did not know if they were in the country.
Alejandro Burzaco, Hugo Jinkis and his son Mariano Jinkis, all Argentine citizens, are among five defendants who have apparently not been detained or arrested a day after the U.S. Department of Justice named them as among those facing corruption charges.
The U.S. Justice Department alleges that Burzaco, Hugo Jinkis and his son conspired to win and keep hold of lucrative media rights contracts from regional soccer federations through the payment of up to $110 million in bribes.
Related: FIFA Corruption Scandal: How Sepp Blatter Runs Soccer 'Like a Chicago Politician'
The three are among nine football officials and five sports media and promotions executives hit with U.S. corruption charges involving more than $150 million in bribes. Swiss police arrested seven of the senior soccer officials on Wednesday, plunging FIFA into its worst crisis in its 111-year history.
Of the remaining seven, two have been detained. Former FIFA vice-president Jack Warner surrendered to police in Trinidad and Tobago on Wednesday. Aaron Davidson, the U.S. head of Brazilian sports marketing firm Traffic Group, was arrested in Miami by the FBI on Wednesday.
U.S. officials are trying to extradite the defendants who remain outside the United States.
advertisement
In this May 14, 2015 photo, Conmebol delegate Roger Bello of Bolivia, left, talks with Boca Juniors goalkeeper Agustin Orion, center, and Alejandro Burzaco, right, president of Torneos y Competencias, moments before canceling the Copa Libertadores soccer match between Boca Juniors and River Plate in Buenos Aires, Argentina. A US Justice Department indictment was announced Wednesday, May 27, 2015, against nine FIFA officials and several corporate executives for racketeering, conspiracy and corruption. Burzaco is one of the sports marketing executives charged.Victor R. Caivano / AP
Burzaco is president of Argentine sports marketing firm Torneos y Competencias (Torneos), while Hugo and Mariano Jinkis are controlling principals of Full Play, another sports media and marketing business headquartered in Argentina.
The indictment states that Burzaco and the Jinkis' led their companies to form a new entity known as Datisa, which entered into a $317.5 million contract with CONMEBOL to obtain exclusive worldwide rights to the 2015, 2019 and 2023 Copa America tournaments.
Datisa later entered into a $35 million contract with the Confederation of North, Central America and Caribbean Association Football, CONCACAF, to acquire rights for another tournament, the Copa America Centenario.
Torneos on Wednesday denied any involvement in corrupt schemes to win contracts and said it was willing to work with judicial authorities.
Full Play did not immediately respond to an e-mailed request for comment on the U.S. allegations. Attempts to reach the three indicted men through the companies were unsuccessful.
Argentina's Cabinet Chief Anibal Fernandez said the country's tax authority would pursue any money owed to it.
"Illegal acts also pay taxes and in this case if it is proven that kickbacks were paid then they will have to pay an income tax of 35 percent," Fernandez said.
Contributor Reuters and Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:21:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>This May Explain Why DOD Accidentally Sent 'Live' Anthrax</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bc4190/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Chealth0Chealth0Ecare0Ctough0Espores0Emay0Eexplain0Eanthrax0Eblunder0Eexperts0Esay0En366151/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Hard-to-kill anthrax spores may explain why the Department of Defense accidentally sent out "live" samples of the bacteria, experts say.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 7:21 pm ET
Tough Spores May Explain Anthrax Blunder, Experts Say
by Maggie Fox
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_snow_anthrax_scare_folo_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Hard-to-kill anthrax spores may explain why the Department of Defense accidentally sent out "live" samples of the bacteria, experts say.
The spores are so tough, and so tiny, that the irradiation procedure used to deactivate the spores might not have killed every single one.
John Peterson, a microbiology professor who works with anthrax at the University of Texas Medical Branch, says the X-rays or gamma rays used to kill anthrax spores might not get every little one.
"They were most likely inactivated but that the inactivation process may not have been complete," he told NBC News. Anthrax spores are only about 1 micron in diameter and a sample could contain 10 billion individual spores, he said.
"They are very difficult to kill."
advertisement
"If a procedure kills 99.999 percent of the bacteria, there would still be 100,000 spores left viable," he says. "They are very difficult to kill."
That's why, even though anthrax is not terribly infectious and is not fatal if it gets treated in time, is considered a potential biological weapon. The tough spores can be dispersed into the air and linger for months or even years, putting people at risk of infection.
The DoD is trying to explain how and why live anthrax spores were sent to labs in nine states and to an Air Force base in South Korea in recent months. At least 26 people who handled or were near the samples are taking antibiotics just in case they breathed in any of the spores.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=a_flashback_anthrax_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
Officials say the investigation is focusing on the irradiation process used to inactivate the spores.
Anthrax bacteria  the scientific name is Bacillus anthracis  live in the soil normally. They make spores when living conditions get tough, for instance, if it gets very dry. "When conditions improve, everything it needs to live again is there," Peterson said. "It can sense nutrients."
In nature, that would mean a rainfall, for instance. But if a spore landed in a lung, that could also signal for it to germinate and multiply.
"It only takes a very small number. A single spore will cause the culture to become positive."
A Maryland lab that received one of the shipments first notified DoD about the live spores. Peterson said the lab was almost certainly doing a validation test, which involves putting the spores into a nourishing broth that would encourage them to grow.
advertisement
"It only takes a very small number. A single spore will cause the culture to become positive," Peterson said.
But a single spore cannot cause an infection, Peterson said. "It is not the most virulent agent," he said. Studies of anthrax show it takes 2,500 to 50,000 spores to infect.
Even if lab workers thought the anthrax was completely dead, they would have handled it carefully and it would have been packaged in a way to fully contain the spores, Peterson and other experts agreed. Defense officials and the Centers for Disease control and Prevention say there is no risk to the public.
Officials said the government labs that received the potentially live anthrax samples were at the Army's Edgewood Proving Ground in Maryland and the Naval Surface Warfare Center in Virginia. The Pentagon has declined to identify the other labs.
Maggie Fox
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:20:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How to Surf the Web Safely at 30,000 Feet</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bd3fd6/sc/28/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnightly0Enews0Chow0Esurf0Eweb0Esafely0E30A0E0A0A0A0Efeet0En366226/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Unthinkable just a few years ago, Internet access is now widely available on planes in flight. But it carries the same risks as on the ground.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 7:20 pm ET
How to Surf the Web Safely at 30,000 Feet
by Tom Costello
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_cos_plane_wifi_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Chances are, you've already done what was unthinkable just a few years ago: Surfed the web from a plane.
But security experts warn that logging on to a plane's WiFi system carries the same risks as logging on to any public hotspot. The bottom line is that sophisticated hackers and crooks can intercept your internet activity and gain access to your digital life.
"It even doesn't matter if these networks are encrypted or not," said James Lyne, the head of security at Sophos Security. "When you connect to them, you're handing over your destiny of your internet connection to some unknown stranger."
To safeguard your digital privacy, Sophos Security suggests taking some basic precautions:
Treat every public WiFi as an open door to your computer.
Avoid accessing your bank account information via public WiFi. If someone is watching, they can quickly grab your username, password and account balances.
If you're concerned about email security, wait until you're on ground and using a trusted internet connection to check your inbox.
And depending on your level of paranoia, you may want to also avoid logging on to any social media websites where you keep personal information or photos.
Anytime you're using a public WiFi, even while flying across the country, there's a chance someone is watching.
The nation's largest provider of inflight WiFi access, Gogo, says its connection to access Wi-Fi is secure  but once users start surfing the web, the connection is not encrypted.
"The connection through which users purchase Gogo is an SSL-encrypted link and is secure. However, following the purchase, due to the many users of our Inflight Wi-Fi access point, Gogo does not provide an encrypted communication channel between our Inflight Wi-Fi access point and the user's computer."
advertisement
"Past the purchase point, GoGo operates similar to any public WiFi hotspot on the ground," the company said.
Gogo, along with many security experts, suggest customers use a Virtual Private Network (VPN) for the best security. A VPN takes your information, puts it into a bubble and encrypts it, protecting the data from being intercepted.
Another good security practice involves ensuring that file-sharing is not enabled while accessing the Internet from an un-encrypted public network and that laptops have firewall and other protection against malware.
"The reality is, cyber crime is entirely opportunistic and every time you connect to the internet, you are a target," Lyne said.
Tom Costello
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
