<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="news24">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:04:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 12 Australian women have tried to join ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/12-Australian-women-have-tried-to-join-ISIS-20150529-2</Link>
        <Description>At least 12 Australian women from one city have attempted to join ISIS, police say, warning of a trend towards a 'romanticised view' of violent jihadists.</Description>
        <MainBody>12 Australian women have tried to join ISIS
2015-05-29 12:04
Abbott: Australia to strip citizenship for terror links
Melbourne - At least 12 Australian women from one city have attempted to join ISIS, police said on Friday, warning of a trend towards a "romanticised view" of violent jihadists.
More than 100 Australians have left the country to support ISIS in Syria and Iraq, raising concerns about radicalisation and whether they pose a security threat on return, the authorities have said. At least 30 have been killed overseas.
Victoria Police assistant commissioner Tracy Linford said those attracted to ISIS were mostly young, isolated people swayed by slick social media propaganda.
In the case of women, they often had a romantic idea of what life would be like under ISIS control, she said, adding that at least 12 had attempted to join from Melbourne, Victoria's capital city.
"We've got five [women] that we know are over there," Linford said, adding that two more were unaccounted for, four were turned back outside Australia and one was stopped at the airport before leaving.
"But we also suspect that there are probably more than 12," she told reporters.
Linford's comments came just days after a Sydney mother reportedly abandoned her two children and fled to Syria for a new life under ISIS.
Social media
"We think that the young women particularly get a romanticised view of what actually exists for them if they travel to the conflict zones," she said.
"There is a reach-back from people who are already in the conflict zone telling them, 'Come over... you will be well looked after, you will have an important position in growing the caliphate, bearing jihadi children in the future, growing the Islamic State'.
"And I think they think they are going to be put on a pedestal and treated very well once they are overseas, but the reality is, that's not the case."
Linford said some women were forced into arranged marriages and others pushed into sexual servitude, while living in often squalid conditions and on rations, with their movements heavily restricted.
"One of things we know about ISIS is that their social media skills are well advanced, and their reach through social media is obviously paying dividends for them," she said, using another acronym for the jihadists.
Earlier this week Prime Minister Tony Abbott said dual nationals linked to terrorism would be stripped of their Australian citizenship.
Australia raised its threat level to high last September and has since carried out a series of counter-terrorism raids, with several alleged plots foiled this year.
Read more on:  isis | australia | security
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:04:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | UN aid chief makes final appeal to end Syria's despair</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/UN-aid-chief-makes-final-appeal-to-end-Syrias-despair-20150529</Link>
        <Description>Outgoing UN aid chief Valerie Amos has made a final appeal to world powers to take action to end Syria's four-year war, saying it had brought more despair than ever thought possible.</Description>
        <MainBody>UN aid chief makes final appeal to end Syria's despair
2015-05-29 12:04
Valerie Amos. (File, AP)
Syrian army raid kills 140 ISIS fighters
New York - Outgoing UN aid chief Valerie Amos made a final appeal on Thursday to world powers to take action to end Syria's four-year war, saying it had brought more despair than ever thought possible.
In her final report to the Security Council, Amos presented a list of atrocities, from the bombing of a market to attacks on medical facilities, blocked aid deliveries and the use of chlorine to terrorize civilians.
"For more than four years, we have watched Syria descend into deeper depths of despair, surpassing what even the most pessimistic observers thought possible," said Amos.
"I know that there are no easy answers or quick fixes," she told the 15-member council.
"We cannot leave Syrians abandoned to hopelessness and further despair."
In the months leading up to her departure, Amos has repeatedly voiced frustration with the Security Council's failure to unite behind measures to ease the suffering of civilians and chart a course for a political solution.
The British diplomat is stepping down after more than four years in one of the most challenging jobs at the United Nations as demands for humanitarian aid have surged in conflicts worldwide.
Set aside differences
With more than 12.2 million people in urgent need of aid, more than half of the country's population Syria has been the UN official's top priority and Amos repeated that more needs to be done.
Peace initiative
"For the sake of Syria and its future generations, this council must set aside its political differences and come together to find a solution to what appear to be intractable problems," she said.
The death toll from the war has surpassed 220 000, but the Security Council has remained deadlocked over how to address the conflict despite three resolutions adopted last year.
Amos noted that 422 000 people are living under siege in Syria, under dire conditions, and that UN agencies and partner relief organizations have been unable to reach those in need in besieged areas.
She took a swipe at the council, saying that if such a figure had been envisaged at the start of the conflict, council members "would not have believed it possible."
"Today we take it for granted," she said.
UN peace envoy Staffan de Mistura opened consultations in Geneva earlier this month to gauge support for a full-fledged peace initiative after two previous UN efforts failed.
Syrian Ambassador Bashar Jaafari told the council that the crisis in Syria will end when support for "foreign terrorist fighters" is cut off, in a reference to US, Turkish and Gulf support for opposition armed groups.
Amos will be replaced by fellow Briton Stephen O'Brien, a former MP who worked as Prime Minister David Cameron's envoy for the Sahel.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:03:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 7 magnitude quake strikes offshore Alaska</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/7-magnitude-quake-strikes-offshore-Alaska-20150529</Link>
        <Description>An earthquake with a magnitude of 7.0 has struck off the southwest coast of Alaska, the US Geological Survey reported.</Description>
        <MainBody>7 magnitude quake strikes offshore Alaska
2015-05-29 11:03
Plot of typical eartquake. (File)
6.9-magnitude quake strikes off Solomon Islands
An earthquake with a magnitude of 7.0 struck off the southwest coast of Alaska late on Thursday, the US Geological Survey reported.
The USGS said the quake's epicenter was 104km south-southeast of Ugashik and 61.7 km deep. The agency upgraded the temblor to a 7.0 after initially stating it was slightly weaker.
The Pacific Tsunami Warning Centre said that based on its available data, no tsunami was expected.
The USGS said the quake was unlikely to cause casualties and notable damage, and there were no immediate reports of such.
The area near the quake, centred some 643km southwest of Anchorage, is lightly populated, according to the USGS.
Read more on:  alaska | earthquakes
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:03:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Cameron urges 'flexible, imaginative' EU reforms</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Cameron-urges-flexible-imaginative-EU-reforms-20150529</Link>
        <Description>British PM David Cameron is preparing to lobby German Chancellor Angela Merkel for "flexible and imaginative" EU reforms, but faces an uphill battle against Franco-German plans for a more integrated eurozone.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cameron urges 'flexible, imaginative' EU reforms
2015-05-29 11:03
File: AFP
Cameron better placed to get EU deal - ex EC head
Berlin - British Prime Minister David Cameron prepared Friday to lobby German Chancellor Angela Merkel for "flexible and imaginative" EU reforms, but faces an uphill battle against Franco-German plans for a more integrated eurozone.
The second day of Cameron's European tour came as his government published a law paving the way for the controversial vote on whether Britain should leave the EU that must be held by the end of 2017.
The prime minister has moved rapidly to kickstart efforts to secure EU reforms before the referendum which he promised voters ahead of his surprise election win earlier this month.
"The status quo is not good enough and I think there are changes that can be made that can benefit not just Britain but the rest of Europe too," Cameron said before a dinner with French President Francois Hollande in Paris.
"My priority is to reform the European Union to make it more competitive and to address the concerns that British people have about our membership.
"We want to help the euro zone work better."
Hollande said that France wanted Britain to remain in the European Union, but that "it will be up to the British people to choose their future."
"David Cameron will present his proposals and we will discuss them and see how we can move forward," he added.
The British premier intends to speak to every EU leader before a summit in Brussels next month where the proposed British reforms will be discussed in more detail.
He met his Dutch counterpart Mark Rutte for lunch in The Hague on Thursday and will also meet Friday with Polish premier Ewa Kopacz.
'27 nuts to crack'
Before Cameron set off, a British official said there were "27 nuts to crack" to secure concessions.
Cameron said earlier this week he was "confident" of securing a deal, but warned there would be "lots of noise, lots of ups and downs along the way".
Cameron argues that the EU should be retreating from further integration instead of embracing it, and that Europe risks a no vote in Britain by failing to change.
However, a proposal from Berlin and Paris for a summit next week on the future of the 19-member single currency not only mentions tightening ties in the eurozone, but doing so without changing the existing treaties that govern the EU.
And in a sign of Europe's discomfort with the looming referendum, French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius warned Thursday that the vote was "very risky" and "quite dangerous".
Fabius added that you could not "join a football club and decide in the middle of the match we are now going to play rugby".
Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said there would need to be "a substantial package of reform" on Europe.
"If we are not able to deliver on these big areas of concern that the British people have, we will not win the referendum when it comes," he told BBC radio.
Among changes Cameron is seeking are tougher requirements for EU migrants to claim state benefits in Britain. He also wants Britain to be able to opt out of the commitment to "ever closer union".
"What matters is that the European Union and its 28 members are flexible and imaginative about responding to these issues," Cameron said Thursday.
If Cameron can secure the concessions he wants, he will campaign to stay in the EU. Most opinion polls currently suggest voters would also back remaining part of the bloc.
'Sooner the better'
No precise date has been set for the referendum in which British voters will be asked: "Should the United Kingdom remain a member of the European Union?"
The question emerged in the EU Referendum Bill, which was formally laid before parliament and will be debated by the House of Commons for the first time on June 9.
Europe Minister David Lidington told reporters in London that the mood in the government was "the sooner the better" but that this should not come at the expense of getting negotiations right.
While he has faced repeated questions about when he will outline a clear programme of demands, Lidington said he had advised Cameron to do no such thing.
"My advice to my boss would be on no account publish a full negotiating position because I don't think that's sensible in any sort of negotiation at all to set all that out in advance in writing," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:02:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Chile students, police clash at new protest over reforms</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Chile-students-police-clash-at-new-protest-over-reforms-20150529</Link>
        <Description>Chilean police have fired tear gas and used water cannons to disperse stone-throwing students protesting against what they call inadequate education reforms.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chile students, police clash at new protest over reforms
2015-05-29 11:02
Teen shot in Chile protest dies
Santiago - Chilean police fired tear gas and used water cannons to disperse stone-throwing students protesting on Thursday against what they call inadequate education reforms and heavy-handed crackdowns on recent demonstrations.
Thousands of students took to the streets of Santiago to condemn President Michelle Bachelet's reforms, claiming they fall short of overhauling an unequal education system inherited from the 1973-1990 dictatorship of late ruler Augusto Pinochet.
The protest began in the early morning hours as students dragged piles of rubbish into the streets and set them on fire, blocking traffic.
Demonstrators then massed outside the education ministry and state television network.
After being dispersed by police, thousands of protesters again took to the streets Thursday night. Hooded protesters gathered around a government building where they erected barricades and attempted to loot shops, police said.
Police reported four officers were hurt in the demonstrations.
"We're still a very long way from achieving our dreams. The reforms are very inadequate," student leader Claudia Arevalo told AFP.
Critical condition
The students, who have been protesting against the education system since 2011, also accused police of using excessive force to break up recent demonstrations.
An art student from Catholic University is currently in critical condition after being knocked to the ground and badly injured by a police water cannon during a protest in the port city of Valparaiso last week.
Police again used water cannons as well as tear gas Thursday as masked protesters attacked them with sticks and stones during an unauthorised march through the center of the capital.
Bachelet won a second term in 2013 with promises to launch an ambitious reform of the education system.
In January, she signed the first reform bill, opening university education to all students and banning for-profit activities at state-funded schools.
Last week, she announced a bill to provide free university education to 60% of the poorest students starting next year, reaching 70% in 2018 and 100% in 2020.
But her reform push has slowed amid a series of damaging corruption scandals, including one involving her son, that have dented her popularity - currently at 29%, her lowest rating ever.
Read more on:  chile
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:08:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Mexican president caught up in another property scandal</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Mexican-president-caught-up-in-another-property-scandal-20150529</Link>
        <Description>Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto has misrepresented to authorities the circumstances under which he acquired one of his properties, public documents show, a discrepancy that could add to the controversy surrounding his personal finances.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mexican president caught up in another property scandal
2015-05-29 10:08
Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto. (Marco Ugarte, AP)
Families of missing Mexican students promise protests
Valle de Bravo - Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto misrepresented to authorities the circumstances under which he acquired one of his properties, public documents reviewed by Reuters show, a discrepancy that could add to the controversy surrounding his personal finances.
According to an official asset declaration first made in 2013, Pena Nieto stated that he acquired the property through a "donation" or gift from his father. Pena Nieto, who made his asset declaration public in 2013 as part of a transparency and accountability push, has since updated and ratified this declaration twice.
Under a public information request, Reuters reviewed documents showing that Pena Nieto actually purchased the property in question - a 1 000 square meter piece of land in the town of Valle de Bravo in 1988 from a third party. He paid around $5 000 at the time, the registry shows. His wealth declaration lists the property as being valued at just $5 at the time.
Reuters was unable to determine why Pena Nieto's declaration mischaracterised the purchase as a gift and understated the price. The declaration lists eight other real estate properties, five of which are also listed as donations. Reuters couldn't determine if those five properties, which include houses and land, are accurately characterised.
Mexican public officials face no requirement to explain the source of any funds that were used to obtain properties they receive as gifts, but they are required to accurately declare how they acquire their properties.
The president's office, asked to explain the discrepancies in the documents, declined repeated requests to comment.
Pena Nieto has been under pressure in recent months over a series of conflict-of-interest scandals centered on properties he, his wife Angelica Rivera and finance minister Luis Videgaray acquired from government contractors.
Mexican journalist Carmen Aristegui and her colleagues reported last year that Rivera was acquiring a multi-million dollar home from a unit of a government contractor which was part of a Chinese-led consortium that had won a $3.75bn high speed rail contract. The Wall Street Journal later reported that Pena Nieto purchased a home from a developer which, the newspaper said, went on to win millions of dollars in state public works contracts.
The president has denied any wrongdoing. But the scandals have overshadowed a major economic reform drive that Pena Nieto was hoping would boost the world's 15th biggest economy.
Update coming
Pena Nieto will publish his annual asset declaration update later this week with more details, an official at the presidential palace said. He will not reveal his wife's assets, because she is neither a public servant nor financially dependent on him, the official added.
Ten lawyers and law professors at top Mexican law firms and law schools consulted by Reuters said the incorrect asset declaration could spell legal trouble for the president. The discrepancy between the registry documents and his official declaration constitute a false statement to authorities, they said.
Several lawyers pointed to the Federal Law of Public Servants' Responsibilities. Article 80 of the law lists which officials, including "even the president of the republic," must declare their wealth to authorities under oath. "The public servant whose wealth declaration lacks truth will be suspended, and when its importance merits it, removed from office and disqualified for three months to three years," the law states.
Several lawyers said they thought the president's wealth declaration should be audited given the discrepancy.
"The property is declared as a donation from the father, when it is in reality the result of a purchase," said Victor Blanco, a Mexican lawyer and academic. "It is incurring falsehood."
Officials who are unable to justify the source of their wealth can face an audit for suspected illicit enrichment. If proven, that would be a crime under Article 224 of Mexico's Federal Penal Code.
One lawyer, speaking on condition of anonymity, said he believed the president could argue that the money used to buy the property was donated to him, and that the discrepancy would not be a major worry.
Lawyers added that there are few precedents for prosecuting senior officials under these laws.
Reuters was unable to check Pena Nieto's other real estate holdings because his wealth declaration doesn't list the addresses of the properties. Mexico's opaque and decentralised property registry makes it difficult to verify the ownership and purchase details of land and buildings.
There are more than 220 public registry offices across the country, many of which lack searchable electronic databases. Even modernised registries can be of limited use.
At some public registry offices, members of the public can search an intranet of property records. However, to request a copy of a particular property registration, the user must know the number of the "folio," a compendium of paper records in which properties are originally listed. Searching on an individual's name sometimes turns up no information.
In the case of the president's property identified by Reuters, a computer search in the public registry in Valle de Bravo, a leafy upmarket retreat a two hour drive southwest of Mexico City, initially came up empty for Pena Nieto. A reporter then reviewed old paper files at the registry office, and found the president's name along with a folio number. That enabled the reporter to find the records for the Valle de Bravo property.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:09:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | German captive released in northern Afghanistan</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/German-captive-released-in-northern-Afghanistan-20150529</Link>
        <Description>A German national kidnapped by Taliban militants in Afghanistan's northern province of Kunduz has been released, police have confirmed.</Description>
        <MainBody>German captive released in northern Afghanistan
2015-05-29 10:09
(Noorullah Shirzada, AFP)
Multiple Taliban raids kill 26 Afghan police
Kunduz - A German national kidnapped by Taliban militants in Afghanistan's northern province of Kunduz has been released, police confirmed on Friday.
The German citizen, working with the development agency Deutsche Gesellschaft fur Internationale Zusammenarbeit (GIZ), was abducted by the Taliban some 45 days ago while travelling in a taxi from Kunduz to the adjacent province of Balkh, according to police officials.
"Our officers saw a man coming towards our checkpoint at 01:00," said Noorullah, a police official in Char Darah district in Kunduz.
"When the officers brought him to the checkpoint, we found out that he was not speaking Dari or Pashto [the two official languages in Afghanistan]," Noorullah told dpa.
He was taken to the provincial airport where, according to the official, "German Special Forces who had come in two helicopters from their base in Mazar-e-Sharif, took him over and moved him to Mazar-e-Sharif."
Noorullah did not know why the man had been released. The German was in good health, apart from a stomach ache, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:07:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Mexico catches 50 illegal migrants on plane</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Mexico-catches-50-illegal-migrants-on-plane-20150529</Link>
        <Description>Mexican authorities have intercepted 50 undocumented migrants from Cuba and Central America on a plane that was about to fly from Cancun to a city bordering Texas.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mexico catches 50 illegal migrants on plane
2015-05-29 10:07
(Sumeth Panpetch, AP)
Police, election offices bombed in Mexico
Cancun - Mexican authorities intercepted 50 undocumented migrants from Cuba and Central America on a plane that was about to fly from Cancun to a city bordering Texas on Thursday.
The migrants had entered Mexico illegally when they were stopped in the Caribbean coast resort city before they could reach Reynosa, said an official from the National Migration Institute.
The migrants included 18 Cubans, 23 Salvadorans, five Guatemalans, two Hondurans, one from Belize and another from the Caribbean island of Granada.
In Reynosa, organized crime controls the trafficking of migrants, who are often kidnapped and held in homes until their families pay a ransom.
Some 200 000 migrants illegally enter Mexico every year across the southern border with Guatemala.
Many have hitched rides on a freight train known as "The Beast" but are forced to find alternative routes after authorities cracked down last year.
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 10:04:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Car bombs explode near 2 Baghdad hotels</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Car-bombs-explode-near-2-Baghdad-hotels-20150529</Link>
        <Description>Car bombs have exploded near two of Baghdad’s most high-profile hotels, killing at least three people, police say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Car bombs explode near 2 Baghdad hotels
2015-05-29 09:04
At least 13 killed in Baghdad bombing
Baghdad - Car bombs exploded on Thursday near two of Baghdad's most high-profile hotels, killing at least three people, police said.
The explosions occurred just before midnight (21:00 GMT) and were heard across the city centre. According to police and an interior ministry source, at least 12 people were also wounded.
Read more on:  iraq
24.com publishes all comments posted on articles provided that they adhere to our Comments Policy . Should you wish to report a comment for editorial review, please do so by clicking the 'Report Comment' button to the right of each comment.
Comment on this story
Motorcycle deaths are on track to decline for a second year in the US thanks to a so far - on bikes - little-used road safety accessory.

US biker deaths down: What's the secret?
Pro's and con's of accredited driver-training
Juvenile pillion riders? Play safe...
Need a family ride? SA's top Mommy Cars
Traffic Alerts
Apartments / Flats R 6750000
Sponsored links
RSS feeds News delivered really simply.
Mobile News24 on your mobile or PDA
E-mail Newsletters You choose what you want
News24 on your iPhone Get News24 headlines on your iPhone.
News24 on Android Get the latest from News24 on your Android device.
SMS Alerts Get breaking news stories via SMS.
Blogs Your opinion on you, me and everyone.

 2015 24.com. All rights reserved.
There arenew storieson the homepage. Click here to see them.

Hello
Create Profile
Creating your profile will enable you to submit photos and stories to get published on News24.
Please provide a username for your profile page:
This username must be unique, cannot be edited and will be used in the URL to your profile page across the entire 24.com network.
Hello
* You must provide a display name.
Edit your avatar:
Select an image file on your computer (max 4MB):
* The image you selected could not be uploaded.
Tell us a bit about yourself:
* Your profile could not be saved at the moment. Please try again later.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 10:05:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Obama makes a surprise visit to a Cuban community church</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Obama-makes-a-surprise-visit-to-a-Cuban-community-church-20150529</Link>
        <Description>President Barack Obama has paid a surprise visit to a Miami religious shrine popular with Cuban exiles, amid moves by Washington and Havana to normalise ties after five decades of enmity.</Description>
        <MainBody>Obama makes a surprise visit to a Cuban community church
2015-05-29 09:05
President Barack Obama arrives at the Ermita de la Caridad in Miami. (Al Diaz, AP)
France's Hollande meets Fidel Castro, urges end to embargo
Miami - President Barack Obama paid a surprise visit on Thursday to a Miami religious shrine popular with Cuban exiles, amid moves by Washington and Havana to normalise ties after five decades of enmity.
"The president is visiting the Shrine of Our Lady of Charity in Miami to pay his respects to the Cuban-American diaspora that worships there," said Bernadette Meehan, National Security Council spokeswoman.
"He will honour the sacrifices that Cuban-Americans have made in their pursuit of liberty and opportunity, as well as their extraordinary contributions to our country."
The visit carries dual political significance.
The Catholic Church, up to and including Pope Francis has been deeply involved in efforts to thaw ties between Havana and Washington.
Francis will visit the White House in September.
Meanwhile, many of Miami's older, more conservative Cuban emigre population, who still play an outsized role in US electoral politics, are skeptical about Obama's moves to restore ties with the Communist island.
The White House will want to reassure them Obama's motives are noble.
Inside the shrine, Obama stood before a vast brown and cream mural depicting Jesus, the Virgin Mary, Christopher Columbus and Cuban national hero Jose Marti.
Panama
It is an "obvious attempt to show deference for the Cuban-American community, while he continues to pursue his controversial policy of engaging the Castro regime," said Sebastian Arcos, of Florida International University's Cuban Research Institute.
That policy will take a step forward on Friday, when Cuba is due to be taken off the US list of state sponsors of terrorism.
The move is part of an effort to reestablish embassies, which appeared to have stalled last week as the latest round of talks reached no deal.
"Our two governments continue to discuss the reestablishment of diplomatic relations and opening embassies in Havana, including different matters that relate to how our embassies will operate," said White House spokesperson Eric Schultz.
Obama and Cuban President Raul Castro agreed in December to seek a normalisation of relations frozen for five decades.
The pair held a historic first meeting in Panama last April.
But the island is still subject to a US trade embargo put in place in 1962, which Obama has called on Congress to lift.
Polls show a majority of Americans support Obama's efforts to improve ties.
According to a Pew survey from early this year, 63% of Americans want to re-establish diplomatic ties and 66% favour ending the embargo.
With Floridian politicians Marco Rubio and Jeb Bush running for the Republican White house nomination, ties with Cuba are sure to be a major issue come election time.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 09:09:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Millionaire mom gets 18 years for killing 8-year-old son</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Millionaire-mom-gets-18-years-for-killing-8-year-old-son-20150529</Link>
        <Description>A self-made health care millionaire who fatally drugged her developmentally disabled child has been sentenced to 18 years in prison by a judge who says he disbelieved much of her defence and scolded her for not showing remorse.</Description>
        <MainBody>Millionaire mom gets 18 years for killing 8-year-old son
2015-05-29 08:09
Gigi Jordan appears in Manhattan Supreme court in New York. (Mary Altaffer, AP)
Family in shock after US toddler shoots mom
New York - A self-made health care millionaire who fatally drugged her developmentally disabled child five years ago in a luxury New York City hotel room was sentenced on Thursday to 18 years in prison by a judge who said he disbelieved much of her defence and scolded her for not showing remorse.
Gigi Jordan, a nurse-turned-pharmaceutical-entrepreneur, claimed her son Jude Mirra had been sexually abused for years by his biological father and other men in her life. She argued she killed the boy in February 2010 to keep him safe from her ex-husband who was planning to kill her and take her money, leaving Jude defenceless to more sexual torture. She then said she tried to kill herself.
But Manhattan Supreme Court Judge Charles Solomon dismissed the notion that her nearly mute, autistic child was repeatedly abused, noting time and again that no credible evidence on the record substantiated those claims.
"All of her money, all of her resources, she decided to kill him," he said. "There were so many things she could have done."
Though charged with murder, a jury in November found her guilty of a lesser manslaughter charge, deciding she was under "extreme emotional disturbance" when she gave Jude Mirra the fatal dose of Ambien and Xanax, believing killing him was the only way to save him.
Solomon also said he didn't believe her suicide attempt was genuine and admonished her for giving an interview to the Dr Phil Show while the jury was deliberating. And he wondered why she wasn't more repentant.
Jordan, aged 54, has spent the past five years jailed on Rikers Island, time that will count toward her prison term. Prosecutors had sought a 25-year sentence.
Her attorneys said they were disappointed in the lengthy prison term.
Jordan never pursued a plea deal because she wanted to take the stand to tell her story, an account the jury apparently accepted when it convicted her of the lesser charge, said one of her attorneys, Ron Kuby, after the proceeding.
"The judge in the guise of paying lip service to the jury's decision went about trying to undo it," he said.
Before she was sentenced, Jordan, wearing a white pantsuit, haltingly and through tears detailed reports describing her son's various medical conditions that she believed pointed to sexual abuse.
The 54-year-old woman, estimated to be worth $40m left her career to find treatment for her son, who was initially diagnosed autistic, visiting medical experts at universities across the countries.
Prosecutors have argued the killing was intentional and carried out because Jordan could no longer care for the needs of her son. In a statement, Manhattan District Attorney Cyrus R. Vance Jr hailed the sentence.
"The poisoning and killing of an 8-year-old boy is a premeditated act of child abuse," he said.
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 29 09:14:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Nobel laureates appeal for Rohingya</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Nobel-laureates-appeal-for-Rohingya-20150529</Link>
        <Description>Nobel Peace Prize laureates have appealed for an end to the Rohingya persecution, which is comparable to genocide.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nobel laureates appeal for Rohingya
2015-05-29 08:14
An armed police officer stands guard as ethnic Rohingya men gather upon arrival at a temporary shelter for the migrants whose boats were washed ashore on Sumatra island on Sunday, in Lhoksukon, Aceh province, Indonesia. (Binsar Bakkara, AP)
Indonesian fishermen rescue 370 migrants
Copenhagen - Several Nobel Peace Prize winners have called for an end to the persecution of Myanmar's Rohingya Muslims, describing it as "nothing less than genocide," and appealed for international help for them in Rakhine state.
The appeal came on Thursday at the end of a three-day conference in the Norwegian capital where participants witnessed video addresses, including from South Africa's Desmond Tutu, Shirin Ibadi from Iran and former East Timor President Jose Ramos-Horta.
Philanthropist George Soros, who escaped Nazi-occupied Hungary, said that there were "alarming" parallels between the plight of the Rohingya and the Nazi genocide.
In recent weeks, thousands of Rohingya have fled persecution and landed on the shores of Indonesia, Malaysia and Thailand, often abandoned by human traffickers or freed after their families paid ransoms.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 29 08:10:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Bill Clinton hopes to keep working, whatever Hillary does</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Bill-Clinton-hopes-to-keep-working-whatever-Hillary-does-20150529</Link>
        <Description>Bill Clinton says he hopes to keep working for his foundation, regardless of what the future holds for his wife Hillary.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bill Clinton hopes to keep working, whatever Hillary does
2015-05-29 07:10
Former US President Bill Clinton. (Jacquelyn Martin, AP)
Republicans tread carefully around Hillary Clinton's age
New York - Former US President Bill Clinton made an impassioned appeal for modern health care in the Ebola-stricken countries of West Africa and told The Associated Press afterward that he hoped to keep working for the foundation he launched regardless of what happens politically with his wife, Hillary.
Clinton, whose wife is the leading Democratic presidential contender, called the Ebola epidemic in Liberia, Sierra Leone and Guinea "a man-made disaster" caused by their poor health facilities.
He told a UN conference on Thursday that he had visited Liberia earlier in May, where his foundation has worked during the Ebola crisis.
Clinton urged donor governments and organisations to earmark 15% of their aid money over the next six or seven years to build health systems not only in Ebola-hit countries, but across Africa.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 29 06:25:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | US army anthrax mistake technical</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/US-army-anthrax-mistake-technical-20150529</Link>
        <Description>The US Army chief says human error at an army lab probably was not the cause of mistaken anthrax shipments.</Description>
        <MainBody>US army anthrax mistake technical
2015-05-29 05:25
US biolab mishaps probed
Washington - The US Army's top general says human error probably was not a factor in the inadvertent shipping of live anthrax to research laboratories.
General Ray Odierno is the Army chief of staff. Odierno told reporters on Thursday the problem may have been a failure in the technical process of killing, or inactivating, anthrax samples.
He says the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention is looking at that aspect of what went wrong at Dugway Proving Ground, the Army installation in the state of Utah that sent the anthrax to government and commercial labs in nine states across the US and to an Army lab in South Korea.
The Pentagon disclosed on Wednesday that at least one of nine labs in the US that received anthrax got live rather than dead bacteria.
Read more on:  cdc | us | wmd
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:17:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Syria rebels storm city, take province</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Syria-rebels-storm-city-take-province-20150528</Link>
        <Description>A rebel coalition led by al-Qaeda's Syrian affiliate has edged into the last remaining government-held city in the northwest province of Idlib.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria rebels storm city, take province
2015-05-28 21:17
An image grab taken from an undated video uploaded on YouTube allegedly shows a member of the jihadist group Al-Nusra Front shooting blindfolded supporters of the Syrian regime at an undisclosed location in eastern Syria. (YouTube/ AFP)
ISIS executes 200+ in ancient Syrian city - monitor
Beirut - A rebel coalition led by al-Qaeda's Syrian affiliate edged into the last remaining government-held city in the northwest province of Idlib on Thursday, a monitoring group said.
The lightning offensive saw the Army of Conquest, or Jaish al-Fatah in Arabic, enter outer districts of Ariha within a matter of hours, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights told AFP.
"There was heavy shelling and rocket fire, then they stormed the city," said Observatory director Rami Abdel Rahman.
"They have entered the city and are engaged in fierce clashes on its peripheries," he added.
Ariha, which was home to 40 000 people before the conflict began, is the last remaining government-held city in Idlib province which borders Turkey.
"The march of lions has begun... Let Allah liberate Ariha," the Army of Conquest's official Twitter account posted.
The coalition, which includes al-Qaeda branch Al-Nusra Front, has won a series of victories in Idlib, including the provincial capital on March 28 and the key town of Jisr al-Shughur on April 25.
Most recently, the rebels seized the massive Al-Mastumah military base and overran a hospital complex where regime soldiers were trapped.
Many government forces retreated from these areas to Ariha, which Abdel Rahman said was heavily defended by fighters from Iran and Lebanese Shi'ite movement Hezbollah.
The Army of Conquest vowed to consolidate its control of Idlib province, where the regime still holds Ariha, the Abu Duhur military airport and a sprinkling of minority villages and military posts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:17:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Putin makes troop deaths a state secret</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Putin-makes-troop-deaths-a-state-secret-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin has banned revealing information about troop deaths during peacetime, as the Kremlin continues to rebuff accusations its soldiers are fighting in Ukraine.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin makes troop deaths a state secret
2015-05-28 21:17
Putin lauds Russian 'glory and power'
Moscow - Russian President Vladimir Putin on Thursday banned revealing information about troop deaths in "special operations" during peacetime, as the Kremlin continues to rebuff accusations its soldiers are fighting in Ukraine.
The strongman signed an amendment adding to what Russia classifies as "state secrets" any "information revealing losses of personnel... in peacetime during special operations."
The addition means that those who disclose details about the deaths of soldiers sent on operations during peacetime could be prosecuted.
The decree gives no details of what exactly is meant by a "special operation". Revealing state secrets, when it does not involve handing them to a foreign state, is a criminal offence that can be punished by up to four years in jail.
Analysts said the legal change was aimed at stamping out any leaks on Russian military losses in Ukraine after activists released a string of evidence pointing to the deaths of government soldiers across the border in the former Soviet state.
"The reason is not to reveal losses in Donbass," said military analyst Pavel Felgenhauer, referring to the war zone in eastern Ukraine, adding that the legal move was designed to "imprison or scare people".
"I've never heard a legal definition of the concept of a special operation," said Felgenhauer. "That means you could classify anything you like as this."
Troops mass on border
The Kremlin decree came as reports have pointed to a massing of Russian equipment close to the Ukraine border.
An AFP photographer in recent days saw Russian military vehicles loaded on a freight train in the southern Rostov region, around 20km from the Ukrainian border.
The photographer also saw Russian military vehicles at a training camp around 50km from the border.
The Kremlin has consistently denied government soldiers are fighting in Ukraine and claimed those fighting alongside rebels are there as volunteers.
Ukraine and the West insist Russia has not only armed and equipped the rebels but also sent in troops to spearhead fighting against Kiev's forces.
Nato has said rebels are using a lull in the fighting due to a shaky truce to bolster their forces ahead of possible new offensive.
The presence of Russian troops in east Ukraine has been backed up by reports from activists of hushed-up funerals, interviews with soldiers in the Russian media, and information gathered from relatives and social networking sites.
US-based think tank Atlantic Council released a report on Wednesday detailing "irrefutable evidence of direct Russian military involvement in eastern Ukraine" that researchers gathered from open sources.
Jail for espionage
The tightening of the state secrets act prompted an outraged reaction from Kremlin critics.
"Now the activity of looking for victims of 'special operations' in Ukraine will be a breach of state secrets," warned opposition leader and lawyer Alexei Navalny on his blog.
"Let the soldiers die and their relatives keep quiet. Those who don't agree, we'll jail for espionage."
Rights lawyer Nikolai Polozov wrote on Twitter: "If you want, you needn't bother giving relatives an insurance payout and a pension, and they won't tell anyone."
According to the latest survey by independent polling agency Levada published on May 5, only 20% of Russians believe government forces are fighting in Ukraine.
Forty-eight percent said they believed Russians were serving there as volunteers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:37:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Watchdog says 90% of declared chemical weapons destroyed</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Watchdog-says-90-of-global-stockpile-destroyed-20150528</Link>
        <Description>The chemical weapons watchdog has hailed a milestone in its mission to rid the world of poison gas and nerve agents, saying 90% of stocks declared has now been destroyed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Watchdog says 90% of declared chemical weapons destroyed
2015-05-28 18:54
Iraqi army retakes chemical weapons site from ISIS
The Hague - The Nobel Peace Prize-winning chemical weapons watchdog has hailed a milestone in its mission to rid the world of poison gas and nerve agents, saying 90% of stocks declared by its members worldwide has now been destroyed.
Ahmet Uzumcu, director-general of the Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons, announced the milestone Thursday, saying it "shows we are well on the way to ridding the world of chemical weapons."
The organisation has been thrown into the spotlight over the last two years by its efforts to oversee the destruction of Syrian chemical weapons, but the majority of stocks are Cold War-era weapons held by the United States and Russia.
Russia is scheduled to complete destruction of its stockpile by 2020 and the United States three years later.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:18:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Texas cities worry about flooding</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Texas-cities-worry-about-flooding-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Texas cities worry that rivers swollen by heavy rains this week could lead to flooding.</Description>
        <MainBody>Texas cities worry about flooding
2015-05-28 17:18
The Blanco River flows past a road around Umphery Ranch located between Wimberley and San Marcos, Texas. (Gabe Hernandez, Corpus Christi Caller-Times via AP)
Twister kills 13 in Mexico; 12 missing in Texas
Houston - Many Texas cities remain in danger though a barrage of deadly thunderstorms has tapered, as officials warn about the possibility of more flooding from rain-swollen rivers.
The storms and floods in Texas and Oklahoma this week have left at least 21 people dead and about a dozen others missing.
In suburban Houston, the rains have pushed the San Jacinto River above flood stage, and its waters were expected to cover streets in subdivisions along the west fork of the river, possibly stranding people in their homes for days if they don't leave.
In Wharton, about 80km southwest of Houston, the mayor asked residents to voluntarily evacuate about 300 homes on the west side of the city due to the predicted rise of the Colorado River. In the Parker County town of Horseshoe Bend in North Texas, officials asked about 250 residents to leave their homes as the Brazos River was expected to rise above its flood stage of 6.4m on Thursday.
Meanwhile, in Central Texas, crews continued searching for nine people feared dead after the swollen Blanco River smashed through Wimberley, a small tourist town between San Antonio and Austin, over the Memorial Day weekend.
In Houston, residents whose homes were flooded by torrential rains on Monday and Tuesday also continued their clean-up efforts.
While the Houston area got a respite from rainy weather for most of Wednesday, the heavy rains from earlier in the week were still making their way downstream. By late Wednesday, the San Jacinto was at 15m, nearly one metre above its flood stage, said Kim Jackson, a spokesperson for the Harris County Flood Control District.
In Houston, between 800 and 1 400 homes have already been damaged by the flooding. Thousands of homes were also damaged or destroyed in the central Texas corridor that includes Wimberley  744 of them in San Marcos alone.
This has been the wettest month on record for Texas, even with several days left. The state climatologist's office said Wednesday that Texas has gotten an average of 19.15cm of rain in May, breaking the old record of 16.92cm, set in June 2004.
While rain is in the forecast the next couple of days for many of the affected areas, the chances for showers are greater during the weekend.
Read more on:  us | weather | flooding
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:18:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Yemen may never emerge intact from civil war</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Yemen-may-never-emerge-intact-from-civil-war-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Yemen may never emerge as a united country from a civil war pitting a northern Shi'ite Muslim militia and its allies in the army against fighters in the mostly Sunni south.</Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen may never emerge intact from civil war
2015-05-28 17:18
Yemeni supporters of the separatist Southern Movement, loyal to the government forces, hold a position on the western outskirts of Aden during reported clashes with Shi'ite rebels. (Saleh al-Obeidi, AFP)
ISIS claims Yemen mosque attack
Cairo - Yemen may never emerge as a united country from a civil war pitting a northern Shi'ite Muslim militia and its allies in the army against fighters in the mostly Sunni south.
The latest conflict, now in its third month, has exacerbated long-standing grievances that are regional but also increasingly religious in a country whose unity has always been brittle.
Secessionist sentiment in the south, stoked by what southerners see as decades of marginalization by the north, is deepening as result of the damage inflicted upon Aden and other southern cities in assaults by the northern Houthi militia.
Sunni Muslim Arab states have maintained an air bombing campaign against the Houthis, allied to archrival Shi'ite Iran, but the Houthis retain the upper hand in battles in the south.
Southern combatants fight under the flag of their formerly independent state, and residents spurn the idea of again joining those they see as northern invaders.
"What unity could there be after the destruction we see on our streets and wars of extermination against the south? Forget it," said Saleh Hashem, a resident of Aden, a port city whose historic commercial district lies in ruins.
Once a British protectorate turned satellite state of the Soviet Union, South Yemen joined North Yemen to form a united country in 1990 under then President Ali Abdullah Saleh, who took power in the north in 1978.
Many in the south, home to most Yemeni oil facilities, felt northerners had commandeered their resources and denied them their identity and political rights. The South then sought to break away in 1994, but Saleh re-united the country by force.
Resentment has festered since the unification and has grown with the ongoing war, taking on more religious overtones.
"We want there to be one people, but in two states with open borders between their citizens," Fuad Rashed, a leader of the southern secession movement, told Reuters.
"The ongoing war has bloodied and slaughtered what little remained of the national unity that has been bungled for over two decades," he said.
Despite Saleh's overthrow during the 2011 Arab Spring protests, he and loyalists in Yemen's army have made common cause with the Houthis, helping their drive from northern strongholds into the capital Sanaa in September and further south.
Northern entente
The Houthis say their advance is part of a revolution against Sunni Islamist militants and corrupt officials. Saleh says he seeks reconciliation and denies accusations that he wants to settle old scores.
The northerners' alliance against Yemen's government, whose base of support is in Aden, may reflect a new unity of purpose in the heavily tribal north, where Shi'ite Islam's Zaydi sect, to which the Houthis belong, prevails.
"A sectarian and regional polarization is under way. When the Houthis took over Sanaa and beyond, it showed that the Zaydi tribesmen were again vying for control)," a northern Yemeni politician, who requested anonymity for security reasons, told Reuters by telephone from Sanaa.
"The majority of the military command, being northerners, quickly fell in with this agenda," the politician said.
The northern advance is firing religious zeal in the south.
"The Houthis are a Shi'ite religious movement, and the whole south is Sunni. This has caused the religious to support the idea of secession more, so that the authority remains Sunni and they avoid living in a united state run by Shi'ites," said Mahmoud al-Salmi, a history professor at Aden University.
Unstable
While the idea of secession has gained ground, a security vacuum brought on by the split of Yemen's army into pro- and anti-Houthi factions may make a viable southern state harder.
Religious hardliners may be poised to make the most gains.
After pro-Saleh troops evacuated last month, a council of conservative Sunni tribesmen and clerics emerged to govern southeastern Hadramawt province, Yemen's largest and home to the modest oil reserves that keep its finances afloat.
Residents of Hadramawt's main city, Mukalla, say the council has made a pact with al Qaeda's Yemen branch, allowing it to hold recruitment rallies, set up informal Islamic courts and carry their weapons in public.
Southern activists worry that the new prominence of the group, whose goal of attacking the Yemeni state and Western targets, could turn the region into a hotbed of strife rather than the state they seek.
"The truth is that the situation has become like an Islamic Republic, where al Qaeda operates freely to impose its deviant version of hardline Islamic Law," activist Mohammed al-Sharqi said by telephone from Mukalla.
All this will only add to the worries of the United States, which poured aid and military assistance into Yemen, including drone strikes, to counter al-Qaeda's rise but has had to scale back due to this year's conflict.
Read more on:  al-qaeda | yemen
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:18:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Myanmar restricts journalists after photos of sleeping MPs go viral</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Myanmar-restricts-journalists-after-photos-of-sleeping-MPs-go-viral-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Journalists can no longer cover Myanmar's nascent Parliament from inside the media chamber because pictures of snoozing lawmakers have been published online.</Description>
        <MainBody>Myanmar restricts journalists after photos of sleeping MPs go viral
2015-05-28 17:18
An army representative dozes off at a parliament session in Naypyitaw, Myanmar. (Khin Maung Win, AP)
Myanmar acknowledges concern over migrant exodus
Yangon - Journalists can no longer cover Myanmar's nascent Parliament from inside the media chamber because pictures of snoozing lawmakers were published online.
Reporters in the capital, Naypyitaw, were told they would have to watch proceedings on TV from the corridor. The pictures of sleeping MPs were the main reason cited by Kyaw Soe, director general of the Union Parliament, which handles administrative duties.
Other embarrassing pictures have circulated showing lawmakers using iPad devices while in session. Another appeared to show an army representative leaning over to press a voting button for a missing lawmaker.
Journalists were negotiating with officials on Thursday to restore their access. In a minor victory, they were told they could occupy a row of far-away seats. But that would be sufficient only for text reporters, not visual journalists.
Read more on:  myanmar
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
