<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Reuters">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:32:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Five more victims' remains found at Nepal crash site of U.S. helicopter</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/xtQldK5UIYs/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>NEW DELHI (Reuters) - Authorities have found DNA evidence that five more people may have been on board a U.S. military helicopter that crashed during a humanitarian relief mission after the Nepal earthquake, a U.S. military spokesman said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Five more victims' remains found at Nepal crash site of U.S. helicopter
NEW DELHI
NEW DELHI Authorities have found DNA evidence that five more people may have been on board a U.S. military helicopter that crashed during a humanitarian relief mission after the Nepal earthquake, a U.S. military spokesman said.
Investigators were exploring the possibility that the five new suspected victims of the crash were villagers picked up by the helicopter during its relief mission, a Nepali army spokesman said.
The helicopter and its crew were part of the large international aid effort after a massive earthquake and major aftershock struck Nepal on April 25 and May 12, killing more than 8,600 people and making hundreds of thousands homeless.
Six U.S. Marines and two Nepali soldiers are known to have died in the crash, the cause of which has yet to be determined.
"While no positive identification has yet been made, there is DNA evidence of five individuals in addition to the six U.S. Marines and two Nepalese soldiers who have already been identified," said Lt. Col. Rob James, a public affairs officer for the U.S. Marines, in a statement to Reuters.
The Nepal Army said the new remains were found on May 25, 10 days after the bodies of the soldiers were found among the wreckage of a U.S. Marine Corps UH-1Y helicopter that went down in the mountains northeast of the capital Kathmandu.
Earlier this week, Nepalese media reported that five people from devastated villages in Dolakha district had gone missing after boarding an unidentified aid helicopter.
A team of U.S. and Nepalese medical and forensic experts are performing DNA tests on the remains to identify all of the victims in tandem with the joint investigation by both militaries into the crash.
Brigadier General Jagadish Chandra Pokharel, spokesman for the Nepal Army, said DNA from the five would be sent to the United States for testing along with DNA samples from relatives of the missing villagers to see it there is a match.
The U.S. military did not comment on whether it had any prior indication that there may have been additional passengers on board the aircraft.
"We are all committed to ensuring all remains - whether U.S. or Nepalese - are positively identified," James said.
(Reporting by Krista Mahr in New Delhi and Gopal Sharma in Kathmandu; Editing by Frank Jack Daniel )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:18:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China land reclamation in South China Sea creates 'new facts': U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/RZLoLPhc63k/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ABOARD A U.S. MILITARY AIRCRAFT (Reuters) - U.S. Defense Secretary Ash Carter, in Washington's latest challenge of Chinese land reclamation in the South China Sea, said the scale of Beijing's activities, not the United States, was altering the status quo in the region.</Description>
        <MainBody>China land reclamation in South China Sea creates 'new facts': U.S.
ABOARD A U.S. MILITARY AIRCRAFT | By David Alexander
A U.S. Navy crewman aboard a P-8A Poseidon surveillance aircraft points to a computer screen purportedly showing Chinese construction on the reclaimed land of Fiery Cross Reef in the disputed Spratly Islands in the South China Sea in this still image from video provided by...
Reuters/U.S. Navy/Handout via Reuters
ABOARD A U.S. MILITARY AIRCRAFT U.S. Defense Secretary Ash Carter, in Washington's latest challenge of Chinese land reclamation in the South China Sea, said the scale of Beijing's activities, not the United States, was altering the status quo in the region.
Carter, speaking to reporters at the start of a 10-day trip to Asia, said the United States was trying to maintain a shared regional security structure that had advanced "prosperity for everyone" over the past 70 years.
"We've been flying over the South China Sea for years and years and years, and ... will continue to do that: fly, navigate, operate. So that's not a new fact," Carter said.
"The new facts are the reclamation and the scale on which it is being done, and that's not an American fact, that's a Chinese fact," Carter said.
The United States has publicly highlighted Chinese island-building in the disputed Spratly Islands several times in recent weeks. Carter called for an end to the land reclamation work by China and other countries on Wednesday and a halt to the militarization of the territorial dispute.
The U.S. Navy last week sent a reconnaissance plane carrying Navy and television camera crews to film the Chinese dredging work, which U.S. officials say has added some 2,000 acres to five outposts in the resource-rich Spratlys, including 1,500 this year.
The Spratlys are claimed by half a dozen countries,  including the Philippines, Malaysia, Vietnam and China.
Chinese Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying deflected criticism, saying it was the Philippines that had conducted large-scale construction activities on what she said were China's islands and reefs since the 1970s, saying China would not "recognize the illegal occupation".
"We urge the Philippines to stop making erroneous remarks and we also urge the United States, which is not a party to the South China Sea dispute, to take a responsible attitude, be prudent in words and deeds, be reasonable and calm, and stop making provocative remarks," she told a news conference.
"These types of remarks are not conducive to solving the dispute peacefully, but will further damage the region's peace and stability."
Carter, asked whether the United States would send ships to within 12 miles of the Chinese-built islands to demonstrate Washington does not accept Beijing's territorial claims, said, "The United States will ... fly, sail, operate, wherever international law allows."
He also rejected the notion that the islands, which China built on previously submerged reefs, could claim 12 miles of territorial waters.
"The 12 nautical miles that I think youre referring to does not pertain to features that were submerged and now are no longer submerged," Carter said.
(Additional reporting by Sui-Lee Wee in BEIJING; Editing by Chizu Nomiyama and Clarence Fernandez)
Track China's Leaders
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:04:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Civilians emerge as pawns in South China Sea legal chess game</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/tOFxmqb1m-o/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>HONG KONG/MANILA (Reuters) - On tiny specks in the disputed Spratly archipelago of the South China Sea, Vietnamese and Filipino children skip to school each day. Not far away, China is building lighthouses and weather stations on reclaimed land. Further north, a Chinese cruise ship takes "patriotic" tourists to a separate group of contested islands.</Description>
        <MainBody>Civilians emerge as pawns in South China Sea legal chess game
HONG KONG/MANILA | By Greg Torode and Manuel Mogato
A Filipino soldier patrols the shore of Pagasa island (Thitu Island) in the Spratly group of islands in the South China Sea, west of Palawan, Philippines, in this May 11, 2015 file photo.
Reuters/Ritchie B. Tongo/Pool/Files
1 of 2
right
The alleged on-going land reclamation of China at Subi reef is seen from Pagasa island (Thitu Island) in the Spratlys group of islands in the South China Sea, west of Palawan, Philippines, in this May 11, 2015 file photo.
Reuters/Ritchie B. Tongo/Pool/Files
2 of 2
right
HONG KONG/MANILA On tiny specks in the disputed Spratly archipelago of the South China Sea, Vietnamese and Filipino children skip to school each day. Not far away, China is building lighthouses and weather stations on reclaimed land. Further north, a Chinese cruise ship takes "patriotic" tourists to a separate group of contested islands.
Little noticed in the heated debate over the potential military use of China's holdings is a growing civilian presence across the South China Sea - a trend that potentially complicates any future armed conflict while buttressing competing claims to territory.
Such moves will be limited by the small size, exposed conditions and lack of fresh water on most islands in the typhoon-tossed waterway, but beefing up civilian features is still important for rival claimants, experts said.
"It does strengthen their legal position ... because it underscores effective administration, not just military, but civilian," said Ian Storey, a South China Sea expert at Singapore's Institute of South East Asian Studies.
"That would be important if these disputes ever went to the International Court of Justice," added Storey, referring to the United Nations' primary judicial body that can rule on territorial disputes.
Tensions in the Spratlys, in particular over China's island building and freedom of navigation through the contested waters, will dominate an Asian security forum in Singapore this weekend to be attended by U.S. Defense Secretary Ash Carter and military officials from Asia, including China.
China claims most of the South China Sea. The Philippines, Vietnam, Malaysia, Brunei and Taiwan also claim parts of the vital trade route. All claimants except Brunei have military fortifications in the Spratlys.
As China pushes ahead with the construction of at least one airstrip and other military facilities on reclaimed land in the Spratlys, Chinese officials are stressing the civilian nature of the work.
Ouyang Yujing, head of the Foreign Ministry's department of boundary and ocean affairs, told state media this week that while China had "every right" to use its Spratly holdings for military purposes, the facilities would be "primarily civilian".
He listed search and rescue, disaster prevention, scientific research and weather observation, among others. China had a groundbreaking ceremony for the building of two lighthouses on its new islands, state media said on Tuesday.
SUNSCREEN AND SOVEREIGNTY
China accelerated its South China Sea civilian push in 2012, when it made a township on Woody island in the Paracel chain, north of the Spratlys, the head of a civilian administration for its claimed islands and reefs. The Paracels, entirely occupied by China since 1974, are also claimed by Vietnam.
Now, mainland Chinese tourists can visit Woody island aboard a cruise ship called the Coconut Princess that sails from China's Hainan island.
"Setting foot onto China's most beautiful gardens is a declaration of our national sovereignty," says the website of the Hainan Airways International Travel Agency, which also warns travelers to wear sunscreen.
International tourists, meanwhile, can visit a small diving resort on Malaysia's Swallow Reef in the southern reaches of the Spratlys.
Wu Shicun, president of China's National Institute of South China Sea Studies, said he went to Woody island earlier this year and noticed that the population had risen to several hundred, forcing the building of proper roads and rubbish collection facilities.
In addition to an elementary school and a hospital, the families of fishermen had places to shop, Wu told Reuters.
It's very different on the Philippine-held island of Thitu, also known as Pagasa, in the Spratlys.
Some 135 soldiers and civilians eke out an existence, sharing a communal vegetable garden and a health clinic while the children attend a basic school.
Rovelyn Jugo, 22, moved to Manila's largest holding in the Spratlys with her husband and son a year ago.
"Everything is free, so we can save," she told Reuters during a recent media visit to the island.
JUST ROCKS
On the Vietnamese-held island of Southwest Cay, an elementary school opened this month, the third Vietnam has opened in the Spratlys in the last two years, according to state media. A health clinic on Spratly island, the biggest Vietnam occupies, is also being upgraded.
Under the U.N. Convention on the Law of the Sea, the ability of an island to sustain a civilian population and economic activity is vital to determining whether it can claim a 200 nautical mile exclusive economic zone (EEZ), international lawyers say.
Those that can't are legally considered rocks.
Clive Schofield, an Australian legal expert, said placing civilians on a reclamation was not enough for an EEZ.
"The legal character of the feature will not change no matter how large the civilian population becomes, or what economic activities take place there," he said.
While the legal nuances may be a long way from life on Thitu, China's reclamations are hard to avoid.
At night, lights are visible on Subi Reef, a Chinese reclamation 20 km (13 miles) away.
"What we hear on the radio about the situation here is frightening," said Jugo. "We are ready to leave ... In fact, our things are in plastic containers so we can take them with us."
(Additional reporting by Ho Binh Minh in HANOI; and Megha Rajagopalan in BEIJING; Editing by Dean Yates )
Track China's Leaders
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:00:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Poland sees tough talks on Britain's EU immigrant plan</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/7D0bTOmoWqk/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WARSAW (Reuters) - Poland will be very firm in its talks with Prime Minister David Cameron over the situation of Polish immigrants in Britain and would reject changing EU treaties, ministers from the Eastern European country said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Poland sees tough talks on Britain's EU immigrant plan
WARSAW
Poland's Foreign Minister Grzegorz Schetyna looks on as he listens questions during news conference after his meeting with Britain's Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond at the Foreign Ministry in Warsaw March 6, 2015.
Reuters/Kacper Pempel
WARSAW Poland will be very firm in its talks with Prime Minister David Cameron over the situation of Polish immigrants in Britain and would reject changing EU treaties, ministers from the Eastern European country said.
Cameron was in Warsaw on the second day of a whirlwind European tour to try to drum up support for EU reform. He has promised to secure a settlement before giving Britons an EU membership in-out referendum by the end of 2017.
One of Cameron's key demands in the renegotiation is cutting welfare payments to EU migrants in Britain. Around 800,000 Poles live in Britain, as well as many other Eastern Europeans.
"We want Great Britain to stay in the EU. But the interest of Poles, our citizens who live in Great Britain is important," Foreign Minister Grzegorz Schetyna Schetyna told public broadcaster TVP1 on Friday.
"It's a question of the joint market, these are basic questions. We understand the British stance. But there are also EU fundamentals on which joint Europe was forged. It will be a tough conversation, but very firm on the Polish side."
Cameron met Polish Prime Minister Ewa Kopacz on Friday morning and is then due to head to Berlin for talks with German Chancellor Angela Merkel.
"As far as treaty changes are concerned or the introduction of discriminatory measures, that would be a red line for Poland, Poland's Minister for European Affairs Rafal Trzaskowski told the BBC.
"If every country comes with a shopping list to change European Union policies, that will be the end of the European construction, it will simply implode."
Volker Treier, deputy chief executive of Germany's chamber of commerce and industry, expressed a similar view. He told the BBC Merkel should not offer Britain concessions because it would encourage other countries to demand changes to their terms of membership.
(Reporting by Adrian Krajewski and Wiktor Szary; Additional reporting by Kylie MacLellan in LONDON; Writing by Marcin Goclowski; Editing by Toby Chopra)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 08:58:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japanese island to be evacuated after volcano erupts</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/xNJhYdWSxVA/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TOKYO (Reuters) - A volcano on the remote southern Japanese island of Kuchinoerabujima erupted suddenly on Friday, blasting plumes of black smoke high into the sky, prompting authorities to start evacuating the island and airlines to re-route flights.</Description>
        <MainBody>TOKYO | By Elaine Lies
A video grab from the Japan Meteorological Agency's live camera image shows an eruption of Mount Shindake on Kuchinoerabujima island, Kagoshima Prefecture, southwestern Japan,  May 29, 2015.
Reuters/Japan Meteorological Agency/Handout via Reuters
left
1 of 6
right
A video grab from the Japan Meteorological Agency's live camera image shows an eruption of Mount Shindake on Kuchinoerabujima island, Kagoshima Prefecture, southwestern Japan,  May 29, 2015.
Reuters/Japan Meteorological Agency/Handout via Reuters
left
2 of 6
right
A video grab from the Japan Meteorological Agency's live camera image shows an eruption of Mount Shindake on Kuchinoerabujima island, Kagoshima Prefecture, southwestern Japan, May 29, 2015.
Reuters/Japan Meteorological Agency/Handout
3 of 6
right
Japan Meteorological Agency's  Senior Coordinator for volcanic affairs Sadayuki Kitagawa holds an emergency news conference following the eruption of a volcano in southern Japan, as a screen shows a map of the volcano on Kuchinoerabujima, at the agency in Tokyo May 29, 2015....
Reuters/Thomas Peter
4 of 6
right
Japan Meteorological Agency's Senior Coordinator for volcanic affairs Sadayuki Kitagawa holds an emergency news conference following the eruption of a volcano in southern Japan, as a screen shows a map of the volcano on Kuchinoerabujima, at the agency in Tokyo May 29, 2015.
Reuters/Thomas Peter
5 of 6
right
Japan's Chief Cabinet Secretary Yoshihide Suga (C) is surrounded by reporters as he holds an emergency news conference following the eruption of a volcano in southern Japan, at prime minister Shinzo Abe's official residence in Tokyo, in this photo taken by Kyodo May 29,...
Reuters/Kyodo
6 of 6
right
TOKYO A volcano erupted on a remote Japanese island on Friday, blasting black smoke thousands of meters into the sky and forcing residents to flee by boat and an airline to re-route flights.
A pyroclastic flow of super-heated gas and rock rolled down the side of Mount Shindake, on the southern island of Kuchinoerabujima, and into the ocean.
A 72-year-old man suffered minor burns to his face but there were no reports of other injuries among the island's 137 residents.
"It sounded like dynamite had exploded, and the house shook," one resident told TV Asahi.
Others described a smell of sulfur and clouds of smoke that blacked out the sky. Ash blanketed lower slopes and fell like snow on Yakushima, 12 km (7 miles) to the east.
Residents, many elderly and carrying boxes and bags,
fled by boat to the closest neighboring island of Yakushima, an hour away, where they disembarked shortly before sunset. Several struggled to control excited dogs on leads.
"All I could bring were a few emergency goods. It was utter chaos," one man told Fuji TV. "I'm really worried about things back home."
Smoke shot more than 9,000 meters (29,000 feet) into the sky and officials warned of more big eruptions and urged "extreme caution".
All Nippon Airways said it would divert some flights as a precaution but it did not cancel any. Japan Airlines said it did not have any plans to change flights.
Kuchinoerabujima is about 130 km (70 miles) south of Japan's southernmost main island of Kyushu, and 1,000 km (620 miles) southwest of Tokyo.
It was not clear if the eruption would affect the restart of Kyushu Electric Power's Sendai nuclear plant, which on Wednesday cleared the last of the nuclear regulator's safety hurdles, introduced after the Fukushima Daiichi nuclear plant disaster triggered by a March 11, 2011, earthquake and tsunami.
[ID: nL3N0YI1Q4]
The company said the volcano posed no risk to the Sendai plant on Kyushu, and volcanologists agreed.
The island has seen several eruptions, including one in 1933 that killed eight people, but Mount Shindake was dormant for 34 years until last year.
Japan is one of the world's most seismically active countries and there has been an upsurge in volcanic activity in recent weeks, which volcanologists said may be linked to the big 2011 earthquake that set off a tsunami that killed nearly 20,000 people.
In 2014, 63 people were killed when Mount Ontake in central Japan erupted while packed with hikers.
(This version of the story corrects the tense in paragraph six.)
(Additional reporting by Tim Kelly, Osamu Tsukimori Kentaro Hamada and Kaori Kaneko; Editing by Michael Perry , Robert Birsel )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 07:36:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Exclusive: Mexican president misrepresented personal land deal, records show</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/x3QLN5-LxbM/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VALLE DE BRAVO, Mexico (Reuters) - Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto misrepresented to authorities the circumstances under which he acquired one of his properties, public documents reviewed by Reuters show, a discrepancy that could add to a controversy surrounding his personal finances.</Description>
        <MainBody>Exclusive: Mexican president misrepresented personal land deal, records show
VALLE DE BRAVO, Mexico | By Simon Gardner
Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto reacts during a ceremony to sign into law a new-anti corruption legislation, at the National Palace in Mexico City May 4, 2015.
Reuters/Henry Romero
1 of 8
right
This is the first of two pages in President Enrique Pena Nieto's 2014 public declaration of his assets that assert he was donated six properties by his parents. Public registry documents show that one of those properties was not donated to him by his father, but was...
Reuters/Mexican National Registry Handout via Reuters
left
2 of 8
right
This is the second of two pages in Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto's 2014 public declaration of his assets that assert he was donated six properties by his parents. Public registry documents show that one of those properties was not donated to him by his father, but was...
Reuters/Mexican National Registry Handout via Reuters
left
3 of 8
right
A Mexican public registry document dated March 23, 2015 and obtained by Reuters details how Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto purchased a property in Valle de Bravo in 1988 from a third party and paid 11.2 million pesos at the time.
Reuters/Mexican National Registry Handout via Reuters
left
4 of 8
right
Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto and first lady Angelica Rivera wave during the military parade celebrating Independence Day at the Zocalo square in downtown Mexico City in this September 16, 2014 file photo.
Reuters/Edgard Garrido/Files
5 of 8
right
Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto looks on during the oath ceremony for new Secretary of the Public Administration Virgilio Andrade Martinez at Los Pinos Presidential house in Mexico City, in this February 3, 2015 file picture. Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto...
Reuters/Edgard Garrido/Files
6 of 8
right
Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto looks on after addressing the media about a private meeting with the relatives of the 43 missing students of Ayotzinapa Teacher Training College Raul Isidro Burgos, at Los Pinos presidential residence in Mexico City in this October 29,...
Reuters/Bernardo Montoya/Files
7 of 8
right
Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto speaks during a military parade in celebration of the 104th anniversary of the Mexican Revolution, at Campo Marte in Mexico City in this November 20, 2014 file photo. Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto misrepresented to authorities the...
Reuters /Henry Romero/Files
8 of 8
right
VALLE DE BRAVO, Mexico Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto misrepresented to authorities the circumstances under which he acquired one of his properties, public documents reviewed by Reuters show, a discrepancy that could add to a controversy surrounding his personal finances.
According to an official asset declaration first made in 2013, Pena Nieto stated that he acquired the property through a "donation" or gift from his father. Pena Nieto, who made his asset declaration public in 2013 as part of a transparency and accountability push, has since updated and ratified this declaration twice.
Under a public information request, Reuters reviewed documents showing that Pena Nieto actually purchased the property in question - a 1,000 square meter piece of land in the town of Valle de Bravo - in 1988 from a third party. He paid 11.2 million pesos, equivalent to about $5,000 at the time, the registry shows. His wealth declaration lists the property as being valued at just 11,200 "old" pesos, the equivalent to about $5 at the time.
Reuters was unable to determine why Pena Nieto's declaration mischaracterized the purchase as a gift and understated the price. The declaration lists eight other real estate properties, five of which are also listed as donations. Reuters could not determine if those five properties, which include houses and land, are accurately characterized.
Mexican public officials face no requirement to explain the source of any funds used to obtain properties they receive as gifts, but they are required to accurately declare how they acquire their properties.
The president's office, asked to explain the discrepancies in the documents, declined repeated requests to comment.
Several hours after Reuters published its story, the president's spokesman publicly released a letter on the presidential website addressed to Reuters reporter Simon Gardner.
It asserted that the property was a donation and that Pena Nieto's father had purchased it in his son's name.
Pena Nieto has been under pressure in recent months over aseries of conflict-of-interest scandals centered on properties he, his wife Angelica Rivera and Finance Minister Luis Videgaray acquired from government contractors.
Mexican journalist Carmen Aristegui and her colleagues reported last year that Rivera was acquiring a multi-million dollar home from a unit of a government contractor which was part of a Chinese-led consortium that had won a $3.75 billion high speed rail contract. The Wall Street Journal later reported that Pena Nieto purchased a home from a developer which, the newspaper said, went on to win millions of dollars in state public works contracts.
The president has denied any wrongdoing. But the scandals have overshadowed a major economic reform drive that Pena Nieto was hoping would boost the world's 15th biggest economy.
UPDATE COMING
Pena Nieto will publish his annual asset declaration update later this week with more details, an official at the presidential palace said. He will not reveal his wife's assets, because she is neither a public servant nor financially dependent on him, the official added.
Ten lawyers and law professors at top Mexican law firms and law schools consulted by Reuters said the incorrect asset declaration could spell legal trouble for the president. The discrepancy between the registry documents and his official declaration constitute a false statement to authorities, they said.
Several lawyers pointed to the Federal Law of Public Servants' Responsibilities. Article 80 of the law lists which officials, including "even the president of the republic," must declare their wealth to authorities under oath. "The public servant whose wealth declaration lacks truth ... will be suspended, and when its importance merits it, removed from office and disqualified for three months to three years," the law states.
Several lawyers said they thought the president's wealth declaration should be audited given the discrepancy.
"The property is declared as a donation from the father, when it is in reality the result of a purchase," said Victor Blanco, a Mexican lawyer and academic. "It is incurring falsehood."
Officials who are unable to justify the source of their wealth can face an audit for suspected illicit enrichment. If proven, that would be a crime under Article 224 of Mexico's Federal Penal Code.
One lawyer, speaking on condition of anonymity, said he believed the president could argue that the money used to buy the property was donated to him, and that the discrepancy would not be a major worry.
Lawyers added that there are few precedents for prosecuting senior officials under these laws.
Reuters was unable to check Pena Nieto's other real estate holdings because his wealth declaration doesn't list the addresses of the properties. Mexico's opaque and decentralized property registry makes it difficult to verify the ownership and purchase details of land and buildings. There are more than 220 public registry offices across the country, many of which lack searchable electronic databases. Even modernized registries can be of limited use.
At some public registry offices, members of the public can search an intranet of property records. However, to request a copy of a particular property registration, the user must know the number of the "folio," a compendium of paper records in which properties are originally listed. Searching on an individual's name sometimes turns up no information.
In the case of the president's property identified by Reuters, a computer search in the public registry in Valle de Bravo, a leafy upmarket retreat a two-hour drive southwest of Mexico City, initially came up empty for Pena Nieto. A reporter then reviewed old paper files at the registry office, and found the president's name along with a folio number. That enabled the reporter to find the records for the Valle de Bravo property.
FURTHER DISCREPANCIES
There are other discrepancies in Pena Nieto's declaration of assets.
 He reported the value of the Valle de Bravo property as 11,200 so-called "old pesos," when the property registry shows he originally paid 11.2 million old pesos. Mexico was gripped by a deep economic crisis in the 1980s, and in the early 1990s the peso was revalued by lopping three zeros off the hyper-inflated currency.
Pena Nieto's declaration includes two other properties registered in old pesos, which lawyers said appeared to underplay their real worth.
One of those properties is a 560 square meter piece of land containing a 492 square meter house. The president's declaration says he acquired the property in cash in 1982, when he was a 16-year-old schoolboy. The other property is a 24,000 square meter piece of farmland.
Converting the declared amounts using today's exchange rate, those two properties are valued in his declaration at a total of just $102.
Not counting these three properties, Pena Nieto declared assets totaling about $3 million in May 2014.
Pena Nieto made his first declaration of assets as president in early 2013. At that time, he listed nine properties, six of which were described as donations. He didn't report their locations or values or name any of the donors.
In May 2013, he amended his declaration to specify that the donated properties came from his mother or father, and assigned them values. Pena Nieto ratified his declaration again last year, but still withheld the location of the properties.
Shortly after filing his first asset declaration with the government, Pena Nieto followed his two immediate predecessors and made the report public. He vowed his government would be open.
"I am doing this, not just because of a legal mandate, but also as an ethical obligation ... to do with accountability," he said at the time. "Above all I reaffirm my democratic conviction to conduct myself with absolute transparency."
(Edited by Michael Williams)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
