<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="rte">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:56:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Call for Dáil recall over O'Brien controversy</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704632-denis-obrien-rte/</Link>
        <Description>Fianna Fáil leader Micheál Martin has called for the Dáil to be recalled in the light of what he claimed had been the silencing of media outlets in relation to comments about businessman Denis O'Brien by independent TD Catherine Murphy yesterday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 11.56
An Oireachtas spokeswoman said the Dil can only be recalled at the request of the Taoiseach
Fianna Fil leader Michel Martin has called for the Dil to be recalled in the light of what he claimed had been the silencing of media outlets in relation to comments about businessman Denis O'Brien by independent TD Catherine Murphy yesterday.
The subject of her remarks is at the centre of an injunction granted against RT earlier this month and cannot be reported by the broadcaster.
Mr Martin said in a statement that it was unprecedented that a matter of serious public interest raised in the Dil could not be reported on by the national broadcaster or other media outlets.
Speaking to RT, Fianna Fil spokesperson on health Billy Kelleher said the matter raises grave concern for freedom of speech and the independence of the Dil.
A spokesman for Mr O'Brien insisted that individuals, no matter who they were, had an entitlement to their good name and privacy relating to their financial affairs.
James Morrissey questioned the accuracy of what Ms Murphy had said, maintaining Dil privilege had an important role but could not be abused to have falsehoods misrepresented as facts.
Mr Morrisey said a core principle of a democracy is the right of every individual to their good name and reputation and it was important that people "stand up for democracy inside the Dil and outside the Dil".
He said Mr O'Brien had sought an injunction against RT as "a point of principle".
Responding to a request by Mr Kelleher request to recall the Dil over Ms Murphy's allegations, MrMorrissey said it was "a little bit rich from Deputy Kelleher" as Fianna Fil never did that when this country was "going down the tubes."
Mr Morrissey said: "There had always been a separation of powers but a fundamental and core principle of a democracy is the right of every individual to their good name and reputation and privacy in matters that are private."
When responding to an article that appeared in today's Guardian concerning press freedom in Ireland, Mr Morrissey said that RT was "the largest media entity in Ireland".
Mr Morrissey said if there is wrongdoing involved it should be examined and investigated, but until then Mr O'Brien was entitled to his good name.
He also pointed out Mr O'Brien's record of job creation in Ireland.
Mr Kelleher earlier told RTs Today with Sean ORourke that hehas written to the Ceann Comhairle calling for the Dil to be recalled over the allegations.
He wants the Dil to discuss the fact that what she said, under Dil privilege, cannot be reported.
He said the matter raises grave concern for freedom of speech and the independence of the Dil.
He said he would like the Dil to reassert its validity as a chamber of free speech, and a chamber that upholds democracy.
Mr Kelleher said the principle of a parliament being unafraid to speak is critically important and fundamental to any democracy.
He added that it is important that issues in the Dil can be reported by the media and he said it would be very disturbing if we now have a situation, whereby journalists cannot report and comment on the Dil.
He said that any attempt to block the reporting of something said in the Dil by a TD is an attack on the basic essence of democracy.
Mr Kelleher said the issue here is not the actual substance of the debate, but the freedom for journalists and others to be able to report exactly what is said in the Dil.
Mr Kelleher said if an issue raised by a TD turns out to be wrong or what they have raised in the Dil is not in the public interest, then sanctions should be placed on that individual by the Dil.
Renua has said it would like to express its total support to Ms Murphy.
Renua leader Lucinda Creighton said: "We wish to express grave concern over the restrictions placed on the tax-payer funded state broadcaster RTE in covering this issue.
"We wish to express grave concern over the courts definition of the public interest and what is of public interest" she continued.
'Defining moment' for media
The NationalUnion of Journalists has criticised the media for notpublishing the statement Ms Murphymade in the Dil last night.
NUJ Irish Secretary Samus Dooley warned that faith in the media would be "shattered if proprietors and editors did not challenge threats to parliamentary democracy and freedom of expression".
Mr Dooley said: "It is gravely concerning that media organisations felt constrained from publishing the comments, made under Dil privilege, by Deputy Catherine Murphy concerning financial matters relating to Mr Denis O'Brien and his alleged relationship with IBRC.
"The fact that the national public service broadcaster was constrained from broadcasting material freely available on the website of the Houses of the Oireachtas, and that other print and broadcasting organisations felt similarly constrained, raises fundamental questions about our parliamentary democracy and the right of the media to report freely on parliamentary proceedings.
"A courageous stand in defence of the right to report parliamentary proceedings would have served the public interest.Faith in the media's ability to do its job will be shattered if this challenge is not faced head on. This is a defining moment for the media in Ireland."
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:33:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Defiant Blatter set to win FIFA election</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704560-fifa/</Link>
        <Description>FIFA President Sepp Blatter remained defiant ahead of today's election defiant in the face of worldwide condemnation and a threatened revolution from UEFA.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Friday 29 May 2015 10.33
FIFA President Joseph Blatter (C) and his girlfriend Linda Gabrielian (L) arrive for the opening ceremony of the FIFA Gongress
FIFA President Sepp Blatter remained defiant ahead of todays election defiant in the face of worldwide condemnation and a threatened revolution from UEFA.
European countries are set to mount further challenges to Mr Blatters authority if, as expected, the 79-year-old wins todays vote against Prince Ali Bin Al Hussein.
Addressing the delegation at FIFA's Congress in Switzerland this morning, Mr Blatter urged the membership to remain unified.
      
"Today, I am appealing to unity and team spirit so we can move forward together," he said. "It may not always be easy but he we are here together today to tackle the problems that have been created. We are here to solve them."
"I think the important point today is to move ahead and the important point is transparency. The important point is where does FIFA stand in the world. It is the fight against corruption, against match fixing, racism and discrimination which we still have and this hurts.
      
"Let's show to the world we are able to run our institution which is FIFA we can do it together."
Speaking on RT's Morning Ireland, FAI Chief Executive John Delaney said that if Mr Blatter loved football he would do the honourable thing and step down.
Mr Delaney said Mr Blatter had lost some support due to the corruption probes launched this week by US and Swiss authorities but that he still expected him to win a fifth term.
Mr Delaney said in his tenure he has never voted for Mr Blatter and that he is not the man to lead FIFA forward.
Mr Delaney added he believes Mr Blatter views FIFA as an empire and that it has "this huge power".
"He has a big ego. When he requires you he can try flatter you but in my opinion, and many people in Europe, personality aside, he is not the person to be leading FIFA going forward." 
UEFA president Michel Platini declared "enough is enough" and demanded that Mr Blatter quit in face-to-face talks yesterday.
Mr Platini warned all options would be considered - and did not rule out a World Cup boycott - while sponsors turned up the heat on Mr Blatter.
Virgin chairman Richard Branson even called on companies to ditch their ties with the world governing body.
Dawn raids by Swiss police on Wednesday saw arrests of seven FIFA officials including Jeffrey Webb, a FIFA vice-president from the Cayman Islands who holds a British passport and fellow vice-president, Eugenio Figueredo from Uruguay.
All are challenging extradition to the USA where authorities have indicted 18 people on corruption charges.
Leading FIFA executives under investigation
Mr Blatter, however, refused to resign and tackled the crisis head on at the FIFA Congress opening ceremony, referring to "unprecedented and difficult times for FIFA" and saying corruption brought "shame and humiliation on football".
He said: "It must fall to me for the well-being of our organisation to find the way forward to fix things.
"Actions of individuals bring shame and humiliation on football and demand action and change. We cannot allow the reputation of football and FIFA to be dragged through the mud any longer, it has to stop - here and now."
Mr Platini did not rule out the possibility of a World Cup boycott but said UEFA members may follow the example of English FA vice-chairman David Gill, who said he will refuse to serve on FIFA's executive committee if Mr Blatter is re-elected.
Mr Platini said UEFA would unite behind Prince Ali and when asked if a boycott of FIFA competitions was a possibility, replied: "UEFA associations will meet in Berlin next week. We will be open to all options."
Pressed further on the prospect of a World Cup boycott, Mr Platini added: "There may be proposals. I honestly don't wish that."
He confirmed he had personally pleaded with Mr Blatter to quit. He said: "I have had enough - enough is enough, too much is too much. I am the first to be disgusted."
He also said a minimum of 45 or 46 of UEFA's 53 voting associations would back Prince Ali but warned Mr Blatter's decision to stay meant his support was still strong.
The US Department of Justice charged 18 people over alleged bribes totalling more than $150m paid for television rights, sponsorship deals and World Cup votes, with the payments allegedly transferred using American wire and banking facilities.
In a separate development, the Swiss attorney general also opened criminal proceedings over the awarding of the 2018 and 2022 World Cups, seized documents and electronic data from FIFA HQ, and police have started questioning the ten current FIFA ExCo members who voted on that tournament.
Mr Gill, the former Manchester United chief executive who is due to take over as Britain's FIFA vice-president today, expressed amazement at one of the charges listed in the US justice department indictments, which said that World Cup bribes were channelled via a FIFA bank account.
The 164-page indictment states disgraced former FIFA vice-president Jack Warner agreed a bribe of $10m US dollars with South African bid officials to vote for the 2010 World Cup with the cash transferred via a FIFA bank account in Switzerland, on the authority of an unnamed "high-ranking FIFA official" to an American bank account controlled by Mr Warner.
It added that the money was FIFA "funds that would otherwise have gone from FIFA to South Africa to support the World Cup".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:54:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Irish in decline in Gaeltacht areas - report</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/ireland/2015/0529/704583-irish-in-decline-in-gaeltacht-areas-report/</Link>
        <Description>A report published today concludes that Irish will no longer be the primary language in any Gaeltacht community in ten years.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Friday 29 May 2015 10.54
Irish is spoken on a daily basis by 67% or more of people in only 21 of 155 electoral divisions in Gaeltacht areas
A report published today concludes that Irish will no longer be the primary language in any Gaeltacht community in ten years.
The research, commissioned by State agency dars na Gaeltachta , is based on census figures for 2006 and 2011.
The authors conclude that the social use of Irish in the Gaeltacht is declining at an even more rapid rate than predicted in their last report in 2007.
They also conclude that spoken Irish in the Gaeltacht is becoming more confined to the academic setting of the classroom while declining in the community setting.
A dispute between dars na Gaeltachta and the authors has delayed publication of the report by over a year. The dars objected to the inclusion in the report of recommendations for preserving the language.
Some elements of the recommendations are highly critical of the State's approach to Irish in the Gaeltacht.
The research shows that of the 155 electoral divisions in the Gaeltacht, only 21 are communities where Irish is spoken on a daily basis by 67% or more of the population. 67% is regarded as a tipping point for language survival.
The report is being published by dars na Gaeltachta - minus the recommendations.
A compromise was reached several weeks ago and the authors agreed to publish the recommendations separately.
One of the authors, Professor Conchr  Giollagin, has told Nuacht RT he was not informed by the dars that the report was being published today.
He also said he has not been invited by the dars to the launch in Donegal.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:37:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>LÉ Eithne rescues 300 migrants off Libyan coast</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704624-le-eithne-migrants-rescue/</Link>
        <Description>The LÉ Eithne has carried out another rescue of 300 migrants off the coast of Libya in the early hours of this morning, bringing to 501 the number of people the crew has rescued since yesterday.</Description>
        <MainBody>0 0
Friday 29 May 2015 11.37
300 migrants, including a number of children, were found on the barge (All pics courtesy of the Defence Forces)
The L Eithne has carried out another rescue of migrants off the coast of Libya in the early hours of this morning.
The 300 migrants  men, women and children - were on board a barge trying to cross the Mediterranean.
The Irish Navy vessel was sent to the rescue at 12.10am (local time) by the Italian Rescue Co-Ordination Centre and located the barge around 45km north of Libya.
All those on board were transferred to the L Eithne by 4am and were given food, water and medical attention. Sea conditions at the time were calm.
The Navy said 217 men, 35 women and 48 children were rescued.
At around 9am the L Eithne came across 100 migrants on board a rubber dinghy and a rescue operation is under way.
These operations follow the successful rescue of 201 migrants who were found in five makeshift boats yesterday.
The L Eithne left Cork on 16 May to assist Italian authorities in the humanitarian search and rescue operations in the Mediterranean.
The European Union announced last month that is was to triple the funding for its mission in the Mediterranean to try to cope with the upsurge in migrants trying to reach Europe.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:49:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Agreement on pay talks expected today</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704559-progress-reported-in-public-sector-pay-talks/</Link>
        <Description>The head of the IMPACT has said he believed "it's quite likely we're in the concluding phase" of the public sector pay talks, which have resumed in Dublin.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 10.49
1 of 2
Talks broke up at 2am and resumed at 10am
Public sector workers could receive additional earnings of 1,000 next year if a deal is brokered
The head of the IMPACT trade union Niall Shanahan has said he believed "it's quite likely we're in the concluding phase" of thepublic sector pay talks, which have resumed in Dublin.
Mr Shanahan said significant progress was made during the week and in particular "lots of progress was made yesterday".
It is understood the various parties involved are waiting to hear back from the Government side as to whether the proposals on public sector pay rises coming from the talks are acceptable.
AS he entered the resumed negotiations, which adjourned at 2am today, John Redmond of the AGSI said "some i's have to be dotted and t's crossed, but I expect an early offer from Government this morning".
Liam Doran of the Irish Nurses and MidwivesOrganisation, responding to reports of 1,000increases next year and in 2017, said no concrete offer was available as of yetand when it was it would be up to his members to see if it was agreeable to them.
The talks in relation to restoring some pay levels lost by civil servants during the economic crisis began on 12 Mayand were due to conclude by the end of the month.
It appears at this stage most union leaders are agreeable to plans to restore pay using a combination of tax, pension and monetary increase methods.
However, the timescale and level of pay restoration has not been finalised.
It is understood the final outcome of these talks will be decided at Government level and put to the unions involved to consult their members.
The unions say no final figures have been put to them as of yet.
Elsewhere, an industrial relations expert and employment specialist has said the problem of low pay and high taxes needs to be addressed.
Gerry Flynn said thatnext month alone30 doctors are due to leave St Jamess Hospital in Dublin to work at a new hospital in Perth, Australia, because they will earn more money there.
Speaking on RTs Morning Ireland in relation to the talks on a new pay deal for public sector workers, he said a shortage ofteachers is also an issue that needs to be addressed.
In relation to the deal being discussed by unions and Government representatives, he said the fundamental of what is being proposed is a "claw back" on the pension levy, which will be worth about a 1,000 a year to workers.
Mr Flynn said technically it is not an increase in salary and that a pay rise looks more likely in 2017.
He said the new deal will give the Government an extension of the flexibilities under the Haddington Road Agreement until 2018.
Govt expected to seek specific reforms
Meanwhile, alaw professor and industrial relations experthas said it is likely the Government will seek specific and continuing reforms in return for a deal on public sector pay.
Also speaking on Morning Ireland, Professor Michael Doherty, who is head of the law department at the National University of Ireland, said he believes the Government will link any movement on pay to specific reforms in specific sectors.
Mr Doherty said both sides in the pay talks have something to gain.
He said workers will be in line for a pay rise, while the Government will have, what has been described, as an extension of the Haddington Road Agreement.
Mr Doherty said he believes a key element for the Government is dispute resolution, in that if there is a dispute that it must go to arbitration at the Labour Court in order to resolve matters in a more structured fashion.
He said an important element of this deal will be that lower-paid workers will benefit, which, he said, will make it easier for unions to bring the deal across the line with their members.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:50:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Irishwoman to become first female Oxford head</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/education/2015/0529/704562-louise-richardson/</Link>
        <Description>An Irishwoman has been nominated as Oxford University's first female vice-chancellor.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 10.50
Prof Louise Richardson with Hillary Clinton in St Andrews in 2013
An Irishwoman has been nominated as Oxford Universitys first female vice-chancellor.
Professor Louise Richardson, who is currently principal at St Andrews University, is set to take up the role at the start of next year, subject to the approval of the institution's legislative body, known as Congregation.
She has been put forward by a nominating committee led by Oxford's chancellor, Lord Patton of Barnes, who said the panel had been "deeply impressed" by Prof Richardson's commitment to the values that the university holds dear.
Lord Patton's role is ceremonial, so Prof Richardson is set to be theday-to-day leader of the university.
Her appointment will make her Oxford's first female holder of the post since the first leader was appointed nearly eight centuries ago in 1230.
Before joining St Andrews, where she is also vice-chancellor, Prof Richardson was executive dean of the Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study at Harvard University.
She said: "Oxford is one of the world's great universities. I feel enormously privileged to be given the opportunity to lead this remarkable institution during an exciting time for higher education.
"I am very much looking forward to working with talented, experienced, and dedicated colleagues to advance Oxford's pre-eminent global position in research, scholarship, and teaching."
Lord Patten said: "The panel was deeply impressed by Professor Richardson's strong commitment to the educational and scholarly values which Oxford holds dear.
"Her distinguished record both as an educational leader and as an outstanding scholar provides an excellent basis for her to lead Oxford in the coming years."
Prof Richardson, who is known for her work on terrorism and security studies and has advised policy makers, is due to take over from Oxford's current vice-chancellor Professor Andrew Hamilton, who is leaving to take over as president of New York University.
Born in Waterford, Prof Richardsonhas a BA in history from Trinity College Dublin, and MA in Political Science from the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) and an MA and PhD in Government from Harvard University.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:59:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Aviva to increase health premiums by 5.5%</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704646-health-insurance/</Link>
        <Description>Health insurer Aviva is increasing its premiums by an average of 5.5% with some plans rising by 10%.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 11.59
The insurer blames the rise on its increased cost of claims
Health insurer Aviva is increasing its premiums by an average of 5.5% with some plans risingby 10%.
The insurer blames the rise on its increased cost of claims. The increases will comeinto effect from 1 July.
The movecome despite expectations that the enormous rise in customers in the past month would put pressure on insurers to avoid inflating premiums.
In April74,000 people took out health insurancein order to avoid penalties on over-34s.
The surge in customers has reversed the decline of recent years. 2.1 million people now have health insurance cover.
VHI says it has no plans to introduce price hikes.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:48:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Funeral of Bill O'Herlihy taking place in Dublin</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704630-bill-oherlihy-to-be-laid-to-rest/</Link>
        <Description>Mourners have begun to arrive for the funeral mass of former RTÉ broadcaster Bill O'Herlihy.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 11.48
The funeral mass for Bill O'Herlihy is taking place in Foxrock
Mourners have begun to arrive for the funeral mass of former RT broadcaster Bill O'Herlihy.
The service is being held at the Church of Our Lady of Perpetual Succour in Foxrock.
It will be followed by burial at Shanganagh Cemetery.
President Michael D Higgins is among the mourners.
Minister for Arts Heather Humphreys as well RT broadcasters Miriam O'Callaghan, Des Cahilland Darragh Maloney are also in attendance.
Other mourners incudeformer minister for justice Nora Owen, soccer pundits Eamon Dunphy, John Giles, and Liam Brady, RT Head of Sport Ryle Nugent, and rugby analysts Tom McGurk and Brent Pope.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:56:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US demands rescue of Asian migrants adrift at sea</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/world/2015/0529/704573-us-demands-rescue-of-asian-migrants-adrift-at-sea/</Link>
        <Description>The United States has said thousands of vulnerable migrants adrift in Southeast Asian seas needed urgent rescue, as Burma told a regional meeting on the crisis that it was not to blame.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 10.56
Around 2,600 migrants from Burma and Bangladesh are still stranded in the Andaman sea
The United States has said thousands of vulnerable migrants adrift in Southeast Asian seas needed urgent rescue, as Burma told a regional meeting on the crisis that it was not to blame.
More than 3,000 migrants from Bangladesh and Burma, also known as Myanmar, have landed in Indonesia and Malaysia since Thailand began a crackdown on human-trafficking gangs this month.
About 2,600 are believed to be still adrift in boats, relief agencies have said. 
"We have to save lives urgently," US Assistant Secretary of State Anne Richard told reporters on her way into the meeting at a Bangkok hotel.
The gathering brings together 17 countries from across the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and elsewhere in Asia, along with the US, Switzerland and international bodies such as the UNHCR, the UN's refugee agency.
"More than ever, we need a concerted effort by all countries concerned," Thailand's Foreign Minister General Tanasak Patimapragorn told the meeting, in an opening address.
"It needs both Thai and international cooperation to solve the problem comprehensively."
He summarised the gathering's three objectives as being: first, to provide humanitarian assistance; then to combat the long-term problems of people smuggling; and finally to address the root causes of the problem.
      
Some participants have cautioned that the meeting was unlikely to produce a binding agreement or plan of action.
      
Many attendees are not ministerial-level and may not have the influence that organisers in Bangkok hoped for.
According to the Thai Foreign Ministry, at least three of the countries central to the crisis were not sending ministers - Burma, Indonesia and Malaysia.
      
An official at Burma's Ministry of Foreign Affairs said the region was suffering from a human trafficking problemand his countrywould cooperate with regional and international efforts to find "practical mechanisms" to deal with human trafficking.    
Officially called the Special Meeting on Irregular Migration in the Indian Ocean, the gathering takes place against the grim backdrop of Malaysia's discovery of nearly 140 graves at 28 suspected people smuggling camps strung along its northern border.
Thai authorities earlier found 36 bodies in abandoned camps on their side of the border, which led to the crackdown.      
A Malaysian officialsaid Malaysia had invited leaders of Indonesia, Thailand and Burma for an emergency summit on the crisis.
The crisis erupted at the beginning of the month, when a Thai crackdown on people-smuggling camps along its border with Malaysia made it too risky for traffickers to land migrants, prompting them to abandon thousands in crowded boats at sea.
      
Regional governments have struggled to respond, although images of desperate people crammed aboard overloaded boats with little food or water prompted Indonesia and Malaysia to soften their initial reluctance to allow the migrants to come ashore.
      
Malaysia, which says it has already taken 120,000 illegal immigrants from Burma, and Indonesia said last week itwould give temporary shelter to those migrants already at sea, but that the international community must shoulder the burden of resettling them.
      
Thailand has refused to allow the boats to land, saying it is already sheltering 100,000 migrants from Burma, but has deployed a naval task force to offer medical aid at sea.
      
Thailand on Friday said it had given the USpermission to fly surveillance flights over Thai airspace to identify boats carrying migrants.
While some of the migrants are Bangladeshis escaping poverty at home, many are members of Burma's 1.1 million Rohingya Muslim minority who live in apartheid-like conditions in the country's Rakhine state.
      
The USand the UNhave said the deadly pattern of migration across the Bay of Bengal would continue unless Myanmar ends discrimination against theRohingya.
      
Burma does not consider the Rohingya citizens, rendering them effectively stateless, while denying it discriminates against them or that they are fleeing persecution.
It does not call them Rohingya but refers to them as Bengalis, indicating they are from Bangladesh.
Source: Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:32:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jack and Emily still the most popular baby names</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704625-baby-names/</Link>
        <Description>Jack and Emily were again the most popular babies' names registered in 2014, according to figures just released by the Central Statistics Office.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 11.32
Girls are given a wider variety of names than boys
Jack and Emily were again the most popular babies' names registered in 2014, according to figures just released by the Central Statistics Office.
Jack has had the top position every year since 2007 and Emily has been at number one since 2011.
Jack, James, Daniel, Conor and Sen have been the top five boys' names since 2007, with four of those names in the top five since 1998.
It is the fourth year in a row that Emily has been the most popular name for girls.
Sophie, Emma, Grace and Ava were the next most popular names in 2014.
Henry, Hugo, Ollie and Luca were four first-time entries to the top 100 for boys.
Annie and Isla were two first-time entrants to the top 100 for girls.
Girls are given a wider variety of names than boys, with 4,586 girls' names registered compared to 3,486 boys' names.
There were 67,462 births registered in 2014, with 34,785 males and 32,677 females, a fall of 1,468 births on 2013.
The 2014 total is 8.6% higher than in 2004, when 61,684 births were registered.
The average age of mothers for births registered in 2014 was 32.3 years.
Over a third of births in 2014 were outside marriage, with 57.7% of the births outside marriage to cohabiting parents.
Births to mothers of Irish nationality accounted for 77.7% of the births in 2014.
There were 29,095 deaths registered in 2014, a fall of 3.1% from 2013. This equates to a death rate of 6.3 per 1,000 population.
There were 249 infant deaths registered, giving an infant mortality rate of 3.7 per 1,000 live births.
More marriages took place in 2014 than the year before, with 22,045 marriages registered last year. This was 1,365 more than in 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:58:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Australia says it is protecting Great Barrier Reef</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704563-great-barrier-reef/</Link>
        <Description>Australia has said it was confident it had done enough to prevent the United Nations from listing the Great Barrier Reef, the world's biggest coral reef ecosystem, as being "in danger".</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 10.58
Greenpeace says the reef is in danger
Australia has said it was confident it had done enough to prevent the United Nations from listing the Great Barrier Reef, the world's biggest coral reef ecosystem, as being "in danger".
Amid concerns about planned coastal developments, including ports, the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) is set to announce overnight a draft decision on the site, which teems with marine life.
"They can see we are doing real work to improve the reef," Environment Minister Greg Hunt told the Australian Broadcasting Corporation.
"We have carried this case to UNESCO and what they have said to us is that it's extraordinary the job Australia has done in the last 18 months.
"I believe that we're making once in a century changes to ensure that a century from now, the reef won't just be as it is, but will be better and stronger than it has been since European settlement."
Australia has recently ordered a ban on the century-old practice of dumping dredge waste, which conservationists says smothers corals and seagrasses, across most of the reef, and funded efforts to improve water quality.
Queensland, the gateway to the reef, has also promised to introduce laws to limit port development as it balances environmental concerns with the needs of the resources industry.
Earlier this week, Mr Hunt told The Australian Financial Review he was "increasingly confident the draft decision will recognise what we've done".
"The feedback from other countries has been increasingly supportive and there is no indication they are looking to delist it," he said.
The Great Barrier Reef, which covers an area of 348,000 square kilometres off Australia's east coast and contains 2,500 individual reefs, was listed as a World Heritage Site in 1981.
Paris-based UNESCO says it provides some of the world's most spectacular maritime scenery and one of the richest ecosystems for fish, birds, crustaceans and other marine life.
But in 2011 it declared "extreme concern" at the approval of liquefied natural gas processing and port facilities within the site and subsequently warned the reef could be deemed "in danger".
Queensland Environment Minister Steven Miles said UNESCO had indicated to the state government that it had taken significant steps to protect the site which faces threats from farming run-off, coral-eating crown-of-thorns starfish and climate change.
"I am hopeful, confident, that UNESCO will see we have done a lot since their last meeting, to do more to turn the reef around," Miles told ABC.
Greenpeace said successive governments' emphasis on expanding Queensland's resources industry had put the reef at risk.
"It's essential to have this international spotlight on the reef. The reef is in danger," Greenpeace's Jess Panegyres said.
UNESCO is due to deliver its final ruling next month.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:17:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Disadvantaged women more likely to smoke</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704606-smoking/</Link>
        <Description>Women living in poorer communities are more than four-and-a-half times as likely to smoke than those in more affluent communities, according to the latest figures from the HSE.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 11.17
The Irish Cancer Society has launched a new smoking cessation project
Women living in poorer communities are more than four-and-a-half times as likely to smoke than those in more affluent communities, according to the latest figures from the HSE.
The Irish Cancer Society revealed the figures as it launched the 'We Can Quit' project.
The ICS saidthe project is a community-based approach to support women from socially and economically disadvantaged communities to give up smoking.
It provides smokers with group and one-to-one support from trained community facilitators as well as access to free nicotine replacement therapies.
Minister for Health Leo Varadkar is launching the findings of a 'We Can Quit' pilot project this morning.
It recommends removing VAT on patches, gums and other products; and making nicotine replacement therapies available for free to those who sign up for cessation programmes.
The pilot project found that after four weeks, the validated quit rate was 41% and after 12 weeks, the validated quit rate was 46%.
The ICS saidthis compares favourably with other models of cessation programmes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:23:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News in Brief</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704602-news-in-brief/</Link>
        <Description>A round-up of national and international news stories</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 11.23
Peter Robinson was admitted to hospital on Monday morning
Peter Robinson due to be released from hospital
Northern IrelandFirst MinisterPeter Robinsonis being discharged from Belfast's Royal Victoria Hospital this morning following successful treatment for a heart condition.
The DUP leader was admitted to hospital on Monday morning.
He underwent treatment to alleviate a condition that was affecting his heart function.
The DUP did not appoint a temporary replacement for Mr Robinson during the week and senior party members anticipate he will return to work after a rest period.
Five more victims at Nepal helicopter crash site
Authorities have found DNA evidence that five more people may have been on board a US military helicopter that crashed during a humanitarian relief mission after the Nepal earthquake.
Investigators were exploring the possibility that the five new suspected victims of the crash were villagers picked up by the helicopter during its relief mission, a Nepali army spokesman said.
The helicopter and its crew were part of the large international aid effort after a massive earthquake and major aftershock struck Nepal on 25 April and 12 May, killing more than 8,600 people and making hundreds of thousands homeless.
Six US Marines and two Nepali soldiers are known to have died in the crash, the cause of which has yet to be determined.
6.8 magnitude earthquake strikes off Alaska
An earthquake with a magnitude of 6.8 struck off the southwest coast of Alaska last night, the US Geological Survey reported.
The USGS said the quake's epicenter was 104km south-southeast of Ugashik and 61.7km deep.
The USGS said the quake was unlikely to cause casualties and notable damage, and there were no immediate reports of such.
The area near the quake, centered 643km southwest of Anchorage, is lightly populated, according to the USGS.
Radioactive leak in Delhi was sodium iodide
The leak of radioactive material at Delhi's international airport was of sodium iodide 131, an official at India's Atomic Energy Regulatory Board (AERB) said.
Sodium iodide 131 is used in so-called nuclear medicine, and is used for treatment of hyperthyroidism and thyroid cancers.
It emits radiation and must be handled with care to minimize inadvertent exposure to health workers and patients.
The AERB official said one of four consignments of sodium iodide had leaked. It had been "separated" and the area cordoned off, he added.
Nine killed in Baghdad hotel bombings
At least nine people were killed after car bombs were detonated at two Baghdad hotels.
The blast at the Ishtar Hotel - formerly a Sheraton -shattered windows of the recently renovated building, turning rows of expensive cars and SUVs into charred, twisted metal.
The Ishtar is a popular site for wedding celebrations, and the area - which also includes a club and the Palestine hotel - is crowded with people on Thursday nights.
A second bombing struck the car park at the Babylon, another upmarket and recently refurbished hotel that overlooks the Tigris river in the Jadriya neighbourhood.
Police said security forces found another car bomb in the Babylon's car park and defused it.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:29:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Washington blocks Muhammad cartoon from transport</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704566-muhammad-cartoon/</Link>
        <Description>The winning entry from a Prophet Muhammad cartoon contest will not be allowed to be advertised on Washington's public transportation system, officials said last night.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 11.29
The Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority has suspended 'all issue-oriented' ads until the end of the year
The winning entry from a Prophet Muhammad cartoon contest will not be allowed to be advertised on Washington's public transportation system, officials said.
The cartoon was part of a contest that came under attack in Texas last month, when two suspected Islamist gunmen opened fire on event participants with assault rifles, before a traffic policeman shot them dead.
The competition was staged an anti-Muslim group, founded by Pamela Geller, who criticisedthe decision to ban the ads in the US capital, calling it an attack on freespeech.
"This is an end run around the First Amendment," Ms Gellar said on her website.
Shehad submitted an advert featuring the winning entry to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) for review, but on the agency yesterday suspended "all issue-oriented" ads until the end of the year, The Washington Post reported.
The WMATA did not respond to a request for comment.
With a banner reading "Support free speech," the ad would have featured the winning cartoon, which showed a sword-wielding Prophet Muhammad saying: "You can't draw me."
The cartoonist replies in a voice bubble: "That's why I draw you."
Ms Geller said on her website that "rewarding terror with submission is defeat. Absolute and complete defeat."
"These cowards may claim that they are making people safer, but I submit to you the opposite. They are making it far more dangerous for Americans everywhere," she said.
Ms Geller is the president of the American Freedom Defense Initiative, which has been listed as an anti-Muslim hate group by US civil rights watchdog the Southern Poverty Law Center.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:30:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China crushes 600kg of ivory in symbolic display</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/world/2015/0529/704565-china-crushes-ivory-in-symbolic-display/</Link>
        <Description>China destroyed more than 600kg of ivory in front of media and diplomats today, as it seeks to shed its image as a global trading hub for illegal elephant tusks.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 11.30
China is estimated to account for up to 70% of global ivory demand
China destroyed more than 600kg of ivory in front of media and diplomats today, as it seeks to shed its image as a global trading hub for illegal elephant tusks.
Engraved tusks and carved ivory chopsticks were fed into a crushing machine, which spewed powder and clouds of dust into the air on the outskirts of Beijing.
Surging demand for ivory in Asia is behind an increasing death toll of African elephants, conservationists say, as authorities fail to control international smuggling networks.
Experts believe that most illegal ivory is sold in China - where products made from the material are seen as status symbols - with some estimating the country accounts for as much as 70% of global demand.
Beijing has made efforts to curb the trade, stepping up prosecutions of smugglers and seizures of ivory at border posts, but campaigners say the measures have not gone far enough.
Diplomats from the United States, Britain and several African nations watched the destruction of the ivory, along with foreign media.
The event followed China's first public destruction of ivory, reportedly weighing six tonnes, in the southern city of Dongguan last year.
A joint report in December from Save the Elephants and The Aspinall Foundation campaign groups found that more than 100,000 wild elephants were killed from 2010 to 2012, with the slaughter largely fuelled by the "out of control" illegal ivory trade in China.
Beijing is a signatory to the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species, which in 2013 identified China as one of eight nations failing to do enough to tackle the illegal ivory trade.
China in February announced a one-year ban on imports of ivory carvings, but activists described the move as symbolic as legal imports are minor and most seizures of illegal items are of raw ivory.
Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 29 14:00:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>93-year-old Nazi suspect dies in Canada</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704580-vladimir-katriuk/</Link>
        <Description>One of the top suspects of Nazi war crimes has died aged 93, Canadian newspaper The Globe and Mail has reported.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 12.00
A Canadian court found no evidence Vladimir Katriuk had committed atrocities
One of the top suspects of Nazi war crimes has died aged 93, Canadian newspaper The Globe and Mail has reported.
A Canadian of Ukrainian descent, Vladimir Katriuk, was listed as the second most wanted Nazi this year by the US-based Simon Wiesenthal Center, which pursues war criminals.
Mr Katriuk died last week, his lawyer Orest Rudzik told the newspaper.
"Mr Katriuk has passed away, after years of unwarranted harassment, media not excepted," Mr Rudzik said.
"I'm glad he's at peace. He'd been ailing for a long time."
In 1999, the Federal Court of Canada ruled that Mr Katriuk lied to obtain Canadian citizenship by concealing his past collaboration with the Nazi regime.
But the court found no evidence he had committed atrocities.
Mr Katriuk argued that he was forced to enlist in a Ukrainian battalion responsible for crimes against Jews and other civilians from Belarus and Ukraine between 1942 and 1944.
He said his role was limited to protecting villagers and livestock against attacks.
Mr Katriuk said he deserted his battalion during its deployment in France in 1944, where he stayed after the war before emigrating to Canada in 1951.
The court found he had falsified his immigration papers, using the name of his brother.
In 2007, Canadian Prime Minister Stephen Harper decided not to revoke his citizenship.
Mr Katriuk had been living in the Canadian town of Ormstown near Montreal, where he devoted himself to beekeeping.
Prior to his death, an organisation for Jewish issues had asked the government to reopen the case against Mr Katriuk.
Most remaining Nazi war criminal suspects are now in their 90s.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:56:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Byrne takes up AIB chief executive job</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/business/2015/0529/704568-aib/</Link>
        <Description>AIB has announced the appointment of Bernard Byrne as its chief executive with immediate effect.</Description>
        <MainBody>Friday 29 May 2015 10.56
1 of 2
Mr Byrne will take up David Duffy's CEO role with immediate effect
Bernard Byrne joined AIB in 2010 as Group Chief Financial Officer
AIB has announced the appointment of Bernard Byrne as its chief executive with immediate effect.
Mr Byrne succeeds David Duffy who will step down as CEO and executive director from the bank with immediate effect. Mr Duffy's decision to leave was previously announced in January.
Mr Byrne will take up the CEO position with immediate effect.

Bernard Byrne, 47, joined AIB in May 2010 as Group Chief Financial Officer and as a member of the Leadership Team.
A chartered accountant, he worked at the ESB and PricewaterhouseCoopers before joining AIB.
Since 2011, he has held a number of roles at the bank andtook up his current role as Director of Retail &amp; Business Banking earlier this year.
"Bernard is the ideal candidate to succeed David Duffy and to lead the organisation forward", commented AIB Chairman Richard Pym.
"Having been one of the leading architects of AIB's customer-led strategy over the last number of years, Bernard is very well positioned to ensure that the momentum created by David Duffy and the senior management team is maintained," Mr Pym said.
"He is ideally suited to the task of continuing AIB's delivery of its strategic objectives for customers and stakeholders," the bank chairman added.
David Duffy is stepping down to take over National Australia Bank's troubled UK business, which he will try to revive ahead of a planned sale or stock market listing.
"He is ideally suited to the task of continuing AIB's delivery of its strategic objectives for customers and stakeholders," the bank chairman added.
David Duffy is stepping down to take over National Australia Bank's troubled UK business, which he will try to revive ahead of a planned sale or stock market listing.
In a statement, the bank said that Mr Byrne's remuneration package "will be fully in line with Government requirements". Bank executives here are subject to a government-imposed salary cap of 500,000.
Finance Minister Michael Noonan said last month that he would wait until the bank's half-year results before deciding on the timing of selling a minority stake and that November was the earliest date for a possible initial public offering (IPO). 
The Government sold a 25% stake in the smaller Permanent TSB in April in a share offer priced at the top of the range, a key test of appetite for 99% state owned AIB. 
Mr Byrne takes over after AIB, like most Irish banks, returned to profit for the first time since the 2008 financial crisis last year as Ireland's economy grew faster than any other in the euro zone. 
AIB said earlier this month that it remained profitable in the first quarter of this year after clawing back more money put aside for bad loans. 
But Irish banks have struggled to grow their loan books with repayments and redemptions among heavily indebted lenders exceeding new lending.
Central Bank Governor Patrick Honohan warned yesterday that the banks' return to profitability was modest and dependent on provision write backs, and that the crisis continued to have serious legacy issues.
Mr Byrne will also have to navigate the political and public pressure the banks have come under to cut mortgage rates deemed too high by the Government, which last week threatened to penalise lenders if no action is taken.
AIB is so far the only bank to announce a rate cut.
The bank nominated Mr Byrne to take over as chief executive a number of weeks ago, but had to wait for approval from the European Central Bank's new Single Supervisory Mechanism for the appointment.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:38:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Volcano erupts on Japanese island</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0529/704621-volcano-erupts-japan/</Link>
        <Description>A volcano on the remote southern Japanese island of Kuchinoerabujima erupted without warning this morning.</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
A 72-year-old man suffered burns to his face after being caught in the pyroclastic flow, but there were no reports of other injuries among the island's 137 residents, whose only access to the outside world is by boat.
Smoke rose 9,000m into the sky and officials warned that large-scale eruptions could continue. Theycalled for "extreme caution".
Japan's All Nippon Airways is diverting some flights to Okinawa Island and Southeast Asia as a precaution, but has not yet cancelled any flights.
Japan Airlines said it did not have any plans to change any of its flights.
A ferry from Yakushima, the closest neighbouring island, arrived and evacuated residents early this morning said Tatsuya Terada, a government official on Yakushima.
A Coast Guard ship is also standing by off the island.
Kuchinoerabujima Island is about 130km south of Japan's southernmost main island Kyushu, and roughly 1,000km southwest of Tokyo.
It is not yet clear if the eruption will affect the restart of Kyushu Electric Power's Sendai nuclear plant, which cleared the last step of the nuclear regulator's stringent safety hurdles introduced after the Fukushima Daiichi disaster in 2011 on Wednesday.
The company said an internal analysis showed the erupting volcano posed no risk to the Sendai plant.
The island has been the site of several previous eruptions, including one in 1933 that killed several people.
Mount Shindake erupted last summer and the area where that pyroclastic flow occurred has been off limits since then.
Japan is one of the world's most seismically active nations and there has been an upsurge in volcanic activity in recent weeks, which volcanologists said may have been ushered in by the massive earthquake in 2011.
In September 2014, 63 people were killed when Mount Ontake in central Japan erupted without warning while packed with hikers.
Source: Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:59:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter refuses to take responsibility for scandal</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704292-uefa/</Link>
        <Description>FIFA President Sepp Blatter has said he cannot be held responsible for the corruption scandal at the organisation and it must earn lost trust back.</Description>
        <MainBody>Visa threatened to break off its contract while other global brands such as Nike, adidas and Budweiser issued strongly-worded statements putting pressure on FIFA to take immediate action to restore its reputation.
Visa said its "disappointment and concern" was "profound" as it warned FIFA to begin changes immediately.
It said: "Our sponsorship has always focused on supporting the teams, enabling a great fan experience, and inspiring communities to come together and celebrate the spirit of competition and personal achievement - and it is important that FIFA makes changes now, so that the focus remain on these going forward.
"Should FIFA fail to do so, we have informed them that we will reassess our sponsorship."
Mr Blatter is under increasingpressure to resign before tomorrow's leadership election.
FAI Chief Executive John Delaney has said David Gill will reject a place onFIFA's Executive Committee if Mr Blatter is re-elected.
The vice-chairman of the English FA told a meeting of UEFA members he will not take up his place ifPrince Ali loses the election.
Mr Delaney also said the meeting agreed to throw its full weight behind Prince Ali.
British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said a UK politician in the same position as Mr Blatter "would be struggling to cling on".
"There's nodoubt, and there's been no doubt for many years, that FIFA needs to clean up its act," he told Sky News.
British Prime Minister David Cameron has also backed Prince Ali.
Britain has long been a critic of FIFA and unsuccessfully bid for the 2018 World Cup which was awarded to Russia.   
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said it "would make sense" to delay tomorrow's vote in light of the latest corruption investigation.
Mr Fabius said time was needed to establish exactly what was going on at FIFA.
"It's been several years that there have been accusations of corruption. It would make sense to take a bit of time, see what is true and not and then the authorities can adjudicate, but for now, it's giving a disastrous image," Mr Fabius told France Inter radio.
"I'm saying this on a personal level, but it would seem to make sense [to delay the election]," he said.
South Africa denies bribes paid to host tournament
South African sports minister Fikile Mbalula hasdenied allegations that huge bribes were paid to win the right to host the 2010 World Cup, sayingpublic money had not been given to "criminals".
The US attorney general allegesFIFA officials took cash in return for awarding the tournament to South Africa.
The US indictment alleged that bundles of cash in a briefcase were handed over at a Paris hotel as a bribe by a "high-ranking South African bid committee official".
It also alleged the South Africa government agreed that $10 million that was due to be paid to South Africa to run the World Cup was instead transferred from FIFA's funds to pay bribes to former FIFA vice president Jack Warner.
Mr Mbalula criticised how the US had made its allegations without consulting South Africa.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:44:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>TD outlines details of IBRC-O'Brien relationship</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0528/704498-dail-leaders/</Link>
        <Description>Independent TD Catherine Murphy has spoken in the Dáil about the business relationship between Denis O'Brien and the Irish Bank Resolution Corporation (IBRC) - the former Anglo Irish Bank - including alleged details of his loans.</Description>
        <MainBody>On Thursday 21 May the High Court granted Mr O'Brien an injunction against RT, which prevented the broadcaster from broadcasting any confidential information giving details of the businessman's personal banking arrangements with IBRC.
The injunction did not cover a statement Ms Murphy previously made in the Dil on 6 May.
In this statement she said Mr O'Brien's loans had expired and he had written to Kieran Wallace, the special liquidator of IBRC, seeking the same terms as the previous management of IBRC had allowed him to pay off his loans in his own time at low interest rates.
This afternoon under Dil privilege, Ms Murphy gave further details of Mr OBriens relationship with IBRC. However, RT is legally restricted from reporting what she said, because to do so would breach the injunction already granted against it.
Mr O'Brien today accused Ms Murphy of making false statements about him. He said it was a deliberate abuse of Dil privilege.
He claimed her ultimate objective was electoral advancement with a disregard for the truth.
Ms Murphy has reacted strongly, saying she got information from a number of reliable sources and that it was without doubt in the public interest.
She said she had a duty to put that information into the public domain and she added she fully intended to fulfil her democratic mandate.
She said she would not be intimidated by statements accusing her of wrongdoing.
Former CEO of IBRC Mike Aynsley issued a lengthy statement responding to Ms Murphy's comments in the Dil. RT cannot report all of his statement. He said he totally rejected her objectionable and untrue statements.
Mr Aynsley said he was concerned Ms Murphy had used Dil privilege to make defamatory comments.
He said he was also concerned about remarks she had made on social media and he said the matter was now in the hands of his solicitors.
He said after he was appointed following the nationalisation of Anglo in August 2009, he overhauled how the bank operated to ensure it did not repeat the mistakes of the past.
Mr Aynsley said clients and credit management activities were subject to ongoing oversight and scrutiny by people who were independent of the day-to-day management of the client relationships and governed by a credit control and committee approval process also independent of the day-to-day management structure.
He said he welcomed any review of the Siteserv transaction or any other transaction completed during the wind-down process, provided such a review was conducted fully and fairly.
TOP STORIES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
