<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Sky-News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:51:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter Appeals For Unity Ahead Of FIFA Election</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492650</Link>
        <Description>There are calls for a European boycott of the World Cup, as Sepp Blatter insists: "You cannot ask everyone to behave ethically."</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Blatter Appeals For Unity Ahead Of FIFA Election
There are calls for a European boycott of the World Cup, as Sepp Blatter insists: "You cannot ask everyone to behave ethically."
11:51, UK, Friday 29 May 2015
Play video "Blatter Appeals for Unity"
Video: Blatter Appeals for Unity
Share by email
FIFA president Sepp Blatter has appealed for "unity" as he fights for re-election amid corruption allegations engulfing the governing body.
Mr Blatter opened the 65th FIFAcongress before presidential elections this afternoon, as Europeconsidered boycotting the World Cup in 2018.
He insisted that it was "individuals" within FIFA who stood accused of corruption - not the whole of the organisation.
"I am willing to accept the president of FIFA is responsible for everything but I would at least like to share that responsibility with everyone," MrBlatter said.
"We cannot constantly supervise everyone in football ... you cannot ask everyone to behave ethically."
Play video "Big Players Arrive At FIFA Congress"
Video: Big Players Arrive At FIFA Congress
Mr Blatter has rejected calls to quit after allegations of "rampant, systemic and deep-rooted corruption" engulfed the organisation.
Instead he is pressing on with his attempt to win a fifth term by defeating Prince Ali bin al Hussein of Jordan .
He told delegates that the arrest of seven top officials in Zurich on Wednesday had unleashed a "storm".
But he added: "Today I appeal for a team spirit, unity, so we can advance together. It may not be easy but that is why we are here today.
"Join us in putting FIFA back on the right track where the boats will stop rocking and go calmly into port."
Questioning the timing of the arrests, he continued:"It's not good for all this to emerge just two days before FIFA presidential elections.
"I'm not going to use the word coincidence, but I do have a small question mark."
1/8
Gallery: Protests And Drama At FIFA Congress
A Palestinian protester is escorted from the FIFA Congress in Zurich, Switzerland, by security guards
His defiance comes as UEFA chief Michel Platini and FA chair Greg Dyke said they were now open to a European boycott of the World Cup.
"What there is no point in is one or two countries saying 'We're not going to take part' because they will carry on with the tournament without them and that is pretty unfair on the fans," Mr Dyke told the BBC Radio 4 Today programme.
"But if Uefa as a group said 'Look, unless you get this sorted we are not going to be in the World Cup' then I think that we would join them."
Whether or not Mr Blatter gets the opportunity to lead the organisation once more will be up to FIFA's 209 associations.
They will vote later today after both candidates have had the chance to address delegates at the congress.
If either candidate gets two-thirds of the votes in the first round (139 votes) then they will win outright.
That result is expected between 3 and4pm.
Play video "How FIFA Will Pick A New President"
Video: How FIFA Will Pick A New President
If this does not happen, the winner will be whoever gains more votes in the second round.
MrPlatini has estimated at least 45 UEFA members might vote for Prince Ali, and the US, Canada and Australia are likely to follow suit.
However, Sky's Enda Brady, reporting from Zurich, said it was highly unlikely that Mr Blatter would be ousted.
"All of Africa is behind Blatter, every single man, all of Asia ... despite everything he will come out of this as president of FIFA, unless there is a seismic shift," Brady said.
"He is deflecting any responsibility whatsoever."
On Wednesday, the US Department of Justice charged a total of 14 people over alleged bribes totalling more than $150m (98m).
The alleged bribes paid for television rights, sponsorship deals and World Cup votes.
Play video "Saha: FIFA Voting System 'Horrific'"
Video: Saha: FIFA Voting System 'Horrific'
The UK Serious Fraud Office today said it was also actively assessing "material in its possession" relating to Fifa corruption allegations.
Among the 14 arrested are seven FIFA officials including Jeffrey Webb, a FIFA vice-president from the Cayman Islands, with a British passport.
Fellow vice-president, Eugenio Figueredo, from Uruguay, was also arrested.
Meanwhile, former FIFA vice president Jack Warner left a Trinidad jail by ambulance, a day after he was charged in the case.
Warner, 72, complained of exhaustion and was not able to face questions from reporters gathered for several hours outside the jail.
But a short while later, Warner donned a cap and a garland of flowers to give a lengthy, defiant speech before a crowd of raucous supporters.
"If I have been thiefing FIFA money for 30 years, who give me the money?," Mr Warner said.
Play video "FIFA President Facing Vote"
Video: FIFA President Facing Vote
"How come he is not charged? Why only persons from Third World countries have been charged?"
He faces eight counts in the US, including conspiracy to defraud and to engage in racketeering.
Swiss authorities are also investigating the decision to award the 2018 World Cup to Russia and the 2022 tournament to Qatar.
They will question 10 current FIFA executive committee members who took part in the 2010 vote.
Prime Minister David Cameron and Culture Secretary John Whittingdalehave joined calls for Mr Blatter to step down.
During Mr Blatter's presidential address two pro-Palestinian demonstrators were taken out of the hall by security.
Palestine wants to hold a vote to expel Israel because of its treatment of Palestinian footballers.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:30:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Car Bombs Kill 10 At Top Baghdad Hotels</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492476</Link>
        <Description>The blasts, which appear to have been coordinated, went off in the car parks of the hotels a few minutes apart.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Car Bombs Kill 10 At Top Baghdad Hotels
The blasts, which appear to have been coordinated, went off in the car parks of the hotels a few minutes apart.
00:30, UK, Friday 29 May 2015
Smoke rises above one of the hotels where a car bomb exploded
Share by email
At least 10 people have been killed after car bombs exploded at two luxury hotels popular with Westerners in Baghdad, police say.
A further 30 people have been wounded by the blasts, which involved at least one suicide bomber, according to the Associated Press.
Photos on Twitter taken by witnesses show large explosions and palls of smoke rising above the scene.
The two hotels targeted were the Cristal Grand Ishtar and the Babylon Warwick.
The two blasts appear to have been coordinated
Both blasts went off in the car parks.
Several media outlets are thought to be based at the Cristal.
The blasts appear to have been coordinated and went off at around midnight local time (10pm UK time), a few minutes apart.
The first bomb hit the Babylon hotel, where government officials often hold meetings and news conferences, killing six people and wounding 14 others.
The second was outside the Cristal, which is adjacent to the Palestine Hotel, where four people died and 13 were injured.
The bombings come after Iraqi authorities lifted a decade-old night curfew in Baghdad earlier this year, as they sought to restore a sense of normality to the capital.
Nobody has claimed responsibility, but a growing number of attacks are being claimed by Islamic State since the group seized large areas of the country last year.
On 17 May, insurgents seized the city of Ramadi, about 70 miles (100km) west of Baghdad, in the most significant military setback to the government since a US-led coalition launched a campaign of airstrikes against IS last August.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:13:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Volcano Erupts On Japan Island Kuchinoerabujima</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492587</Link>
        <Description>A coastguard vessel has been sent to rescue the 140 residents of the southern island of Kuchinoerabujima.</Description>
        <MainBody>Volcano Erupts On Japan Island Kuchinoerabujima
A coastguard vessel has been sent to rescue the 140 residents of the southern island of Kuchinoerabujima.
09:13, UK, Friday 29 May 2015
Play video "Smoke Billows After Japan Eruption"
Video: Smoke Billows After Japan Eruption
Share by email
A volcano has erupted on the remote island of Kuchinoerabujima in southern Japan.
Plumes of black smoke were seen rising high into the sky as lava flowed down the side of Mount Sindake to reach the ocean.
A coastguard vessel has been sent to evacuate the 140 residents - whose only access to the outside world is by boat - and some flights have been diverted from the island which is around 1,000km (621 miles) southwest of Tokyo.
The volcano also erupted last summer, Japanese broadcaster NHK reported, adding that the area where lava was found has been out of bounds since.
Lava barrels into the ocean below Mount Shindake
Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe said officials would do everything to look after the islanders.
"We will expend all our efforts to ensure the safety of all the residents of the island," Mr Abe said.
Play video "Sept 2014: Ontake Eruption"
Video: Sept 2014: Ontake Eruption
The island is about 160 km (100 miles) south of Kyushu Electric Power's Sendai nuclear plant on Japan's southernmost main island of Kyushu.
The power company was given the final go-ahead on Wednesday to restart its plant following the 2011 Fukushima disaster, but it is not clear if the volcanic eruption will affect its plans.
Japan is one of the world's most seismically active nations and there has been a rise in volcanic activity in recent weeks.
More than 60 people were killed in September last year when Mount Ontake in central Japan erupted without warning while packed with hikers.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:05:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British Girls In Syria 'No Longer Together'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492358</Link>
        <Description>The teenagers are said to be "safe and in good health" but "unlikely to be returning to the UK in the immediate future".</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
British Girls In Syria 'No Longer Together'
The teenagers are said to be "safe and in good health" but "unlikely to be returning to the UK in the immediate future".
20:05, UK, Thursday 28 May 2015
Kadiza Sultana, Shamima Begum and Adiza Abase
Share by email
Three schoolgirls from London who crossed into Syria in February are no longer together, their families' solicitors have revealed.
Shamima Begum, Amira Abase and Kadiza Sultanaleft their east London homes for Syria, two months after a fellow pupil is thought to have left to join IS there.
And Waterford Solicitors said "some of the girls" had made contact with their families in the UK.
"They have made it known that they are safe and in good health but are no longer in the company of one another," the firm said on Twitter.
The three girls were captured by CCTV at Gatwick, on their way to Syria
"Furthermore, they have intimated that they are unlikely to be returning to the UK in the immediate future.
"The families are grateful to know that their daughters are alive and in good health."
Play video "'Special Mission' For IS Brit Girls"
Video: 'Special Mission' For IS Brit Girls
It comes after a senior female commander from Islamic State told Sky News she has no doubt the trio were groomed by a team of social media experts in Raqqa.
The woman, who calls herself Um Asmah and who defected from IS just days ago, was the first person to contact foreign girls crossing the border.
The 22-year-old said they will "never" go home and are more likely to "die in Iraq or Syria".
"IS is not stupid, they have educated people who know how to deal with (the) psychology of others, how to deal with the human being. All these are in IS," she said.
Play video "Inside The IS Social Media Centre"
Video: Inside The IS Social Media Centre
"They have ways to attract people - especially foreigners. Otherwise young British people wouldn't come and say they will change the flag on Buckingham Palace.
"IS have the ability to manipulate the minds of young people. If they can convince foreigners, it is even easier to convince Arabs and Syrians.
"They have freedom and everything is available - they have no need to come to Syria but they do."
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 12:33:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First Footage Of Islamic State Grooming HQ</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492005</Link>
        <Description>The internet cafe is where fighters target young foreigners, preying on their vulnerability, to entice them to join Islamic State.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
First Footage Of Islamic State Grooming HQ
The internet cafe is where fighters target young foreigners, preying on their vulnerability, to entice them to join Islamic State.
10:33, UK, Thursday 28 May 2015
Play video "Inside The IS Social Media Centre"
Video: Inside The IS Social Media Centre
Share by email
Sky News has obtained exclusive pictures of the online grooming centre used by terror group Islamic State.
The internet cafe in the Syrian city of Raqqa is the heart of the IS online operation, where fighters try to persuade young and vulnerable foreigners to leave their homes and travel to the war-torn country.
Sky News Chief Correspondent Stuart Ramsaysaid the cameraman had risked his life to get the footage.
It shows fighters and children milling around, chatting and laughing in the cafe, where they work in shifts according to their nationality and the time zones of the people they are targeting.
Ramsayalso spoke with Um Asmah, one of the most senior defectors from IS, who shared information on the sophisticated grooming plans to bring young foreigners to Syria to train and then return home to carry out attacks.
Play video "'Special Mission' For IS Brit Girls"
Video: 'Special Mission' For IS Brit Girls
She said: "IS is not stupid, they have educated people who know how to deal with (the) psychology of others, how to deal with the human being. All these are in IS.
"IS have the ability to manipulate the minds of young people. If they can convince foreigners, it is even easier to convince Arabs and Syrians."
The interview came as a study warned against thinking that women travel to Syria solely to become "jihadibrides".
It described the theory as "simplistic" and "hinder(ing) efforts to prevent other girls from being radicalised".
Other motivations include anger over the perceived persecution of Muslims and the wish to belong to a sisterhood of shared beliefs, according to the Institute for Strategic Dialogue and the International Centre for the Study of Radicalisation at King's College London.
The report's authors, Erin Saltman and Melanie Smith, say that describing the women as "brainwashed, groomed, innocent girls hinders understanding of the threat they pose".
Ms Smith said: "They're not being taken seriously. It's inherently dangerous to label people with the same brush."
Play video "Where Are Islamic State Strongholds"
Video: Where Are Islamic State Strongholds
Around 550 young women, some as young as 13, are estimated to have already travelled to Islamic State-controlled territory.
The authors looked at the social media accounts of more than 100 females on Twitter, Facebook and Tumblr, using photos, online chats and other accounts to place them in Syria or Iraq.
The women came from 15 countries and were largely operating in English.
They often talked about the camaraderie they experienced after moving to IS-controlled territory, regularlyposting images of veiled "sisters" posing together.
This was in contrast to the "false feeling or surface-level relationships" they talked of having held in the West, the report says.
The report says some women go in search of romance and marriage.
Play video "Missing Amira's Dad: 'Come Home'"
Video: Missing Amira's Dad: 'Come Home'
Images shared online of a lion and lioness are used to symbolise a union with a "brave, strong husband".
The idea promoted by the group's social media "messengers" is that "supporting a jihadist husband and taking on the ISIS ideology is an empowering role for females".
But the reality is quite different.
Any woman posting messages critical of life under IS is quickly reprimanded, say the report's authors, with the Twitter hashtag #nobodycaresaboutthewidow having only a very short cyberlife, for example.
But some women living under IS warn those following them that they should be ready to "be tested" by intermittent electricity, water shortages, bitter winters and the challenges of life in a warzone.
Healthcare is particularly difficult, with one western woman describing her experience of having a miscarriage in an IS hospital because she could not communicate with the doctor.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:33:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PM Fails To Win Polish Support On Benefits</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492416</Link>
        <Description>The PM is in Berlin for talks with Angela Merkel after failing to win the support of the Polish leader over his benefit plans.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
PM Fails To Win Polish Support On Benefits
The PM is in Berlin for talks with Angela Merkel after failing to win the support of the Polish leader over his benefit plans.
11:33, UK, Friday 29 May 2015
Play video "Cameron And Hollande Speak On EU"
Video: Cameron And Hollande Speak On EU
Share by email
David Cameron has failed to gain backing from Poland's leader for his planned crackdown on benefits for EU migrants on the second day of his two-day European diplomatic tour.
Number 10 said the Prime Minister had failed to agree with Ewa Kopacz on the issue as they discussed European reform ahead of Mr Cameron's meeting with German Chancellor Angela Merkel.
Poland has sharply criticised the plans to refuse benefits to EU migrants unless they have worked in the UK for four years saying they are "discriminatory".
EU freedom of movement rules means EU citizens should have the same entitlement to work and claim benefits as everyone in the member country.
The Prime Minister's spokesman said while Mr Kopacz and Mr Cameron found "much they could agree on", benefit restrictions had not been on of those things.
Play video "Cameron's Grand European Tour"
Video: Cameron's Grand European Tour
They spokesman said: "On immigration and welfare, Prime Minister Kopacz welcomed the PM's commitment to respect the principle of free movement. They agreed that there were issues concerning the interaction between free movement and national welfare systems that should be discussed further.
"Prime Minister Kopacz emphasised that Poland valued the UK's membership of the EU and said that she hoped they could work together in a positive spirit to keep Britain in."
The Prime Minister is now in talks with Mrs MerkelBerlin. The two are likely to hold more similar views than Mr Cameron and the Polish leader.
It comes after Mr Cameron called for "flexible and imaginative" reforms in the European Union after talks with French President Francois Hollande on Thursday.
:: Long Road Ahead For Cameron's EU Mission
Speaking after the talks in Paris, Mr Cameron said: "The status quo is not good enough and I think there are changes that can be made that can benefit not just Britain but the rest of Europe too".
The Prime Minister said solutions could be found to make Europe more competitive and "address the concerns of the British people" ahead of his in-out referendum on EU membership.
Play video "'A Flawed Union, But UK Better In'"
Video: 'A Flawed Union, But UK Better In'
Mr Hollande called Mr Cameron's plan for a referendum by the end of 2017 "very risky" - but made clear that France wants Britain to remain in the bloc.
"We think it's in the interest of Europe and in the interest of the United Kingdom to be together but the people must always be respected," he said at a joint news conference.
Mr Cameron added: "We have different priorities but we share a common objective, which is to find solutions to these problems.
"And what matters is that the European Union and its 28 members are flexible and imaginative enough to respond to these issues and to work together to find answers that will make the European Union more successful."
The PM is trying to charm EU leaders into backing his reform drive, something he has promised to complete before giving Britons a vote on staying in the EU.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 10:43:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA 16 Maker Hits Out At 'Misogynistic Vitriol'</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492615</Link>
        <Description>The game series started in 1993 and has never included women's teams in the game until now, but some have criticised the move.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sponsored By
FIFA 16 Maker Hits Out At 'Misogynistic Vitriol'
The game series started in 1993 and has never included women's teams in the game until now, but some have criticised the move.
08:43, UK, Friday 29 May 2015
Play video "FIFA 16 To Include Women's Football"
Video: FIFA 16 To Include Women's Football
The boss of EA Sports has criticised the "misogynistic vitriol" that followed the firm's announcement that women would feature in their upcoming FIFA 16 game.
The game series started in 1993 and has never included women's teams - until now.
But the announcement on Thursday led to a barrage of sexist responses on social media, something chief operating officer Peter Moore challenged on Twitter.
He wrote: "So sad to see the misogynistic vitriol following the FIFA 16 announcement regarding women in the game. We are better than this."
Other users joined him in criticising those who were against the move.
1/5
Gallery: New Feature Added To Popular Sports Console Game
FIFA 16 will include 12 international all-female teams including England, Brazil, Spain, Germany and Canada
One wrote: "Don't be hard on men complaining about women in FIFA 16. They are just scared because theyve never scored with a woman."
Another said: "There are men complaining about women's teams finally being included in FIFA 16 and not complaining about the actual FIFA corruption scandal."
The game will include 12 international all-female teams including England, Brazil, Spain, Germany and Canada.
Male teams will not be able to play female teams, and there will be no female equivalent of the Ultimate Team feature.
The game is set for release in late summer.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:51:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ex-Lehman Boss Has 'No Regrets' Over Collapse</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492684</Link>
        <Description>Dick Fuld, who was head of Lehman Brothers when it went bankrupt in 2008, says a "perfect storm" caused the financial crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Ex-Lehman Boss Has 'No Regrets' Over Collapse
Dick Fuld, who was head of Lehman Brothers when it went bankrupt in 2008, says a "perfect storm" caused the financial crisis.
10:51, UK, Friday 29 May 2015
Dick Fuld hadn't made a speech in public since the global crash in 2008
Share by email
The former head of Lehman Brothers has insisted it was "not a bankrupt company" at the time of its collapse in 2008.
In one of his first public appearances since the firm's demise - where it filed for the largest bankruptcy in US history - DickFuld claimed that the US Federal Reserve could have saved Lehman Brothers.
The 69-year-old said the bank was "mandated into bankruptcy", and went on to blame the 2008 global financial crisis on a "perfect storm" of factors - including rising unemployment and higher interest rates, which made mortgages unaffordable for many homeowners.
Mr Fuld also defended his decision-making in the run up to the financial crisis, adding: "Hindsight is 20-20. There is no 'if this' or 'woulda, coulda, shoulda'. You make a decision with the best information you think you have."
However, the financier admitted that "not a day goes by when I don't think about Lehman Brothers," adding: "I'd love to tell you I'm over it, it's behind me - it doesn't happen."
Mr Fuld, who now runs a small merchant banking firm, also claimed that rising levels of income inequality were harming "the belly of America".
At an investment conference, he said his other economic concerns included the rise of Islamic State, slowing growth in China, and the aggressive leadership style of Vladimir Putin.
He added that "taken together, they're fraying the fabric of our system".
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:55:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Apple Solution To Arabic iMessage Crash Glitch</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492701</Link>
        <Description>A bug is causing iPhone devices to crash if a certain string of Arabic characters is received in a text message.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sponsored By
Apple Solution To Arabic iMessage Crash Glitch
A bug is causing iPhone devices to crash if a certain string of Arabic characters is received in a text message.
10:55, UK, Friday 29 May 2015
Apple says it is working on a solution for the Messages glitch. (File pic)
Share by email
Apple has been forced to publish a temporary workaround for a bug which lets people crash iPhones using a text message.
A bug in Apple's operating system causes the device to crash if a certain string of Arabic characters is received in a message.
The problem arises due to a glitch in the way Arabic text is rendered in banner notifications.
Apple's software attempts to abbreviate the text with an ellipsis, which causes the system to crash and the phone to reboot.
Users then find they can no longer open the Messages app.
On Friday, Apple published a new page on its support website offering a way to deal with the glitch while it tries to update its software to fix it.
The glitch was first reported on Reddit, causing some to start sending the message to contacts as a prank.
An Apple spokesman said: "We are aware of an iMessage issue caused by a specific series of unicode characters and we will make a fix available in a software update."
Apple's solution
:: Ask Siri to "read unread messages"
:: Use Siri to reply to the malicious message. After you reply, you'll be able to open Messages again
:: In Messages, swipe left to delete the entire thread. Or tap and hold the malicious message, tap More, and delete the message from the thread
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:41:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mystery Of Holes In Swiss Cheese Solved</title>
        <Link>http://news.sky.com/story/1492423</Link>
        <Description>Researchers say the holes are caused by tiny particles of hay - contradicting the old wives' tale that mice are responsible.</Description>
        <MainBody>Switch to US Edition
Mystery Of Holes In Swiss Cheese Solved
Researchers say the holes are caused by tiny particles of hay - contradicting the old wives' tale that mice are responsible.
23:41, UK, Thursday 28 May 2015
Hay is responsible for the holes in cheeses like Emmentaler
Scientists have finally solved a mystery that has baffled them for a century - why does Swiss cheese have holes?
The old wives' tale claimed mice were responsible - but it turns out the culprit is hay.
These "microscopically small hay particles" get into the milk and create holes as the liquid matures into cheese.
The discovery also solves another riddle - why the famous holes in cheeses like Emmentaler or Appenzeller have been getting smaller or disappearing completely over the last 15 years.
It is because the milk has been getting cleaner.
The Agroscope institute claims the transition to fully-automated, industrial milking systems had caused holes to decline.
"It's the disappearance of the traditional bucket," said spokesman Regis Nyffeler.
Researchers at the government-funded body carried out tests in which they added different amounts of hay dust to milk.
Agroscope said the subject had been under study since at least 1917.
Promoted Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
