<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Telegraph">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:47:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fifa corruption scandal live: Sepp Blatter says ahead of election 'you can't ask everyone to behave ethically just like that'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bf73d5/sc/12/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Csport0Cfootball0Cfifa0C116375170CFifa0Ecorruption0Elive0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Fifa crisis: Blatter refuses to admit wrongdoing as Friday's election nears</Description>
        <MainBody>This page will automatically update every 30 secondsOn Off
Latest
12.03
Right, that's my lot. Thanks for joining this morning, I'm leaving you in the capable hands of Adam Hurrey. If you fancy a spot of tennis, join me for Roger Federer v Damir Dzumhur in the French Open here .
11.58
You may feel you know enough about Blatter, but here are 10 things you really should know about the Fifa despot . Here's one for free...
Blatter is fond of reminding journalists that he was once a sports writer and time member of the International Association of Sports Journalists. He had graduated from the University of Lausanne with a business degree and previously worked in PR. So legend has it, he also worked as a wedding singer to supplement his income.
11.54
Steve Searle has shared his thoughts about the England boycott. One thing I would say is that to be fair to Greg Dyke, he keeps saying that England pulling out on its own would be pointless, and that it needs a united front from Uefa to have any impact.
Having just read the piece online from Luke Edwards re England boycotting any future World Cups, I thought I'd throw these thiughts out there.
I can totally understand England trying to take a stand against the stench emanating from within FIFA. However, boycotting one or several World Cups on our own is pointless. If we think for one second that we are that important to World football, just because we're England, we are massively mistaken.
There is no doubt in my mind that any future World Cups would go ahead without us. Just look at past Olympics when the USA &amp; Russia didn't attend - they still went ahead and this would be similar.
Plus, don't forget that the real ones we punish are not those sat in board rooms at the FA but the players, and to a certain degree the fans. We would be taking away the players' opportunity to perform on the biggest stage &amp; for the fans to travel &amp; experience all that a major tournament has to offer.
I agree wholeheartedly that a stance has to be made but UEFA collectively has to do so &amp; take the lead. I sincerely hope they do as Blatter will win later today; of that we can be certain.
11.47
A lot of anti-Blatter sentiment as you'd expect - don't forget to vote in our poll as to whether England should boycott the World Cup.
Alastair C. Donald: This is like a very bad Dan Brown nove. Its awfully predictable.
Stephen Thomas: Should, as we all know is going to happen, Blatter is re-elected, Greg Dyke and the FA show some moral backbone and lead the way and pull out of the next World Cup. You will have the support of the majority English football fans. Something has to be done to get rid of this despot.
11.43
Dan Hickman has written in and asked: Charlie- the used to be a big fan of your work seemed a little pointed- did he hurt you in some way?
Good question, I thought it might sound like that after I wrote it. I should clarify: Mark did not hurt me, it's just I haven't seen him in years so can't really claim to still be a big fan. Anyway, good to clear that one up.
11.38
Bangladeshi's representative says he is going to vote for Blatter - 'he has done so much more than the other guy'.
11.36
In other news, Mark Watson confirms that he's not that Mark Watson.
11.35
Our reporter Luke Edwards has written an impassioned blog on why England should boycott the World Cup .
If we say enough is enough and withdraw from the Fifa umbrella, others could follow. A World Cup without England is still a World Cup, but should even half a dozen other nations also refuse to take part, it will not be a tournament worthy of the name.
Should any of the large football nations such as Brazil, Italy, Spain, Argentina, Germany, France or the USA stand with us, Fifas Empire will crumble. To survive, it must compromise.
Imagine the winter of 2022, when the major European leagues stop for the Qatar World Cup, some of the biggest names are elsewhere, playing in an invitational tournament, free from Fifas control. Even Blatter will fear that.
Wayne Rooney in action in the Brazil World Cup in 2014
11.28
A further update on the lunch situation...
Fifa redeems itself by allowing media to mix with delegates before shooting itself in the foot again by booting everyone out of the hall.
 Ben Rumsby (@ben_rumsby) May 29, 2015
11.26
More e mails coming in - keep sending your thoughts to charlie.eccleshare@telegraph.co.uk .
Mark Watson: Not sure what they'll have for lunch but has anyone noticed how Sepp Blatter and Silvio Berlusconi look the same? They could be twins!
Stephen Wagstaff: It would be best for the game if Sepp is re-elected, then it would force England to withdraw and maybe others to follow. But please FA, have some backbone and do it!
Is that the Welsh comedian Mark Watson? I used to be a big fan of your work if so.
11.22
Interesting story developing that the Serious Fraud Office failed in its duty by leaving it to the FBI to act on Fifa's corruption when the crimes came under the scope of the UK Bribery Act.
Jane Hickman, a partner at London law firm Hickman Rose said: The reach of the Bribery Act includes persons with a 'close connection' with the United Kingdom for the purposes of the act.
British citizens, citizens of British overseas territories and bodies incorporated under the law of any part of the UK, among others, are deemed to have a close connection with the UK and may be prosecuted where the entire offence takes place abroad.
FIFA has members from British overseas territories who compete in FIFA World Cup qualification tournaments despite not being sovereign states, including Anguilla, Bermuda, British Virgin Islands, Cayman Islands, Montserrat and Turks and Caicos Islands.
Two of the individuals arrested yesterday (Jeffrey Webb and Costas Takkas) are Cayman Islanders.
When allegations of corruption began to swirl around the successful Russian and Qatar bids, you might have expected English law enforcement to take a look. But nothing happened. We should have taken the lead.
Lets hope the public now start to realise that massive cuts to our law enforcement budgets over the last five years may actually harm the national interest.
11.15
A few more suggestions on Fifa's lunch menu, some seemingly serious, some less so, with the absence of humble pie on most of your lips:
Peter Ireland: Whatever FIFA have for lunch, Blatter wont be eating humble pie, perhaps they should have shipped in some US prison food to give some of them a taste, hopefully, of whats to come!
Simon Osborne: Humble Pie followed by Porridge
Trevor Anderson: McDonald's burger washed down with Coca-Cola
Ralph Hoarau: They are probably dining on rhino, armadillo and crocodile because Blatters own thick skin has been reenforced with a layer of each of those animals skins.
Tony Arrowsmith: Hopefully Sepps lunch will begin with a nice warm glass of shut the hell up, swiftly followed by simple Gelsemium salad.
Alan Morson: Two choices; Leatherback turtle en croute Or Black rhino tartare
Dan Davies: Brie Berry Flan - Sounds delicious.
Geoffrey Harrison: Plenty of Swiss cheese. Like the Financial Report, full of holes.
Marc Swallow: Rob Harris is having none of the porky pies
11.04
According to AP, media have been denied access to FIFA at congress lunch. Rob Harris asked security if media are not part of "football family" (as Blatter says): "probably not" was the response.
11.02
Rafik Attou has an interesting suggestion on what Fifa will be enjoying for lunch: A warm bowl of my favourite : Super Mario gold coins... For the love of the game.
10.56
Fifa is about to break for lunch. Send your suggestions of what they'll be munching to charlie.eccleshare@telegraph.co.uk
10.52
It would be great if Prince Ali was the knight in shining armour we all want him to be. It feels a little though that our view of him is based more on hope than expectation, and by dint of the fact he is not Sepp Blatter.
10.48
We've heard a lot about Blatter, but what about his opponent in today's election, Prince Ali of Jordan? Wonder no more, here's all you need to know...
10.44
Tom Embury-Dennis at the Mail has found the following:
The only comment allowed through FIFA moderation on their main news story pic.twitter.com/ZaacuBUkWO
 Tom Embury-Dennis (@TomEmburyD) May 29, 2015
10.34
Blatter really pushing this line that the current FIFA corruption crisis stems from decision to award Russia and Qatar the next World Cups. And good luck with the below Ben!
Have been assured the media will be allowed to mingle with congress attendees during formal breaks. Fingers crossed.
 Ben Rumsby (@ben_rumsby) May 29, 2015
10.28
Here's what will happen later today, with the Presidential election. Looks like it'll be another four years of Blatter.
10.26
Just heard someone mention the FA Cup final. I completely forgot it was happening.
10.22
It has emerged that Brazil's FIFA executive committee Marco Polo Del Nero left Switzerland ahead of the congress.
Del Nero's return to Brazil followed the arrest of Jose Maria Marin, his predecessor as Brazilian FA president.
Marin is one of seven FIFA officials who are facing extradition to the USA on corruption charges. A FIFA spokesperson confirmed it had been notified of Del Nero's departure.
It means four of the 25 FIFA ExCo members may be absent from Saturday's meeting; Jeffrey Webb from Cayman Island and Eduardo Li from Costa Rica are under arrest, while England's David Gill has announced he will refuse to attend if Blatter is re-elected for a fifth term.
10.11
Fifa have also confirmed this morning that the 2022 World Cup will be played over 28 days, meaning it will start on Monday November 21.
10.02
Blatter also said on the award of the 2018 and 2022 World Cups: If two other countries had emerged from the envelope, I think we do not have these problems today. Ben Rumsby reckons that's either a dig at the FBI for launching their investigation when USA failed to win the 2022 competition, or the British media for being sore after losing 2018 (or both).
09.58
Our chief football correspondent Henry Winter was not impressed by Blatter's address.
Shameless Congress: choreographed messages and pictures about how wonderful #fifa is. Up to Prince Ali at Congress to expose the rotten core
 Henry Winter (@henrywinter) May 29, 2015
09.56
And here are a couple of handy summaries of everyone's favourite football administrator.
09.54
To lighten the gloom, here are a couple of amusing things to have come out of the morning. Firstly, some wag has made a judicious edit to Sepp Blatter's Wikipedia page.
Elsewhere, let me introduce Blattr - a feed Blatter money game, whilst he laughes in a Brian Blessed style voice.
09.50
Wonderful pay-off line from Blatter: Join us to put Fifa back on the right track and where the boats will stop rocking and go placidly into port.
09.46
Blatter has effectively just said he's not to blame, and that there's no way he keep an eye on everyone in Fifa. He seemed to be channeling his inner Homer Simpson, who once said - "I can't be expected to keep track of all my wheelings and dealings!"
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:41:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US surveillance shows China positioning weapons on contested island</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c1387b/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cchina0C116380A440CUS0Esurveillance0Eshows0EChina0Epositioning0Eweapons0Eon0Econtested0Eisland0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>America concerned Chinese building up Spratly island in South China Sea for military purposes</Description>
        <MainBody>US surveillance shows China positioning weapons on contested island
America concerned Chinese building up Spratly island in South China Sea for    military purposes
China's frigate 'Yulin' in action in the South China SeaPhoto: GETTY
By Charlotte Middlehurst, Shanghai
11:41AM BST 29 May 2015
China sent a pointed signal this week by parading its military might through the capital of Hainan Island, the Chinese province located closest to the disputed waters of the South China Sea.
The demonstration followed an incident last week when a Chinese warship delivered a verbal warning to an American reconnaissance aircraft carrying a CNN crew who were filming Chinas construction of artificial islands in the contested Spratly chain.
The Patriotism National Defence Weapons Exhibition took place on Wednesday in Haikou, the capital of Hainan. The weapons on display - supposedly developed by China within the last 20 years - included a J-10 jet fighter, a WZ-10 helicopter gunship and an amphibious light tank.
Hainans position off Chinas southern coast means the island would be the primary base for military operations in the event of war in the South China Sea.
Chinese dredging vessels in the waters around Mischief Reef
Pheonix News, a Chinese state website, said that the show was well attended and displayed the nations prestige.
China has laid claim to 90 per cent of the South China Sea, which is believed to be rich in oil and gas. The countrys claims overlap with those of Brunei, Malaysia, the Philippines, Vietnam and Taiwan.
China has begun constructing artificial islands on the Spratly chain, located over 600 miles from its coastline. Neighbouring states fear these projects could be the basis for naval or other military facilities.
But the Communist Party has shrugged off the possible military significance of its island-building programmes, comparing them to road-building schemes in China and implying that the US is deliberately playing up the issue in order to raise tensions.
But American surveillance has detected two Chinese motorised artillery pieces positioned on one artificial island, built in the Spratly chain by China about one month ago. While the weapons would likely not pose a threat to US planes or ships, they could reach neighbouring islands.
We watch every outpost in the South China Sea carefully and monitor the actions of the countries concerned, said John Kirby, a State Department spokesman, in a statement to the Wall Street Journal.
CNES 2015, Distribution Airbus DS/Spot Images/IHS 1535921, first published by IHS Janes Defence Weekly
John Kerry, the US secretary of state, has repeatedly warned of the dangers of any country  including China carrying out building projects that change the status quo in disputed waters.
I wont speak to intelligence issues, but I can assure you that Secretary Kerry is in touch with the claimants, including China, and has been very clear in warning against actions that escalate tensions, added Mr Kirby.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:40:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hospitals overwhelmed as India heatwave kills nearly 1,700 people</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46b8e756/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cindia0C1163580A90CHospitals0Eoverwhelmed0Eas0EIndia0Eheatwave0Ekills0Enearly0E140A0A0Epeople0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Watch as an extreme heatwave causes roads to melt as soaring temperatures in India have claimed the lives of nearly 1,700 people</Description>
        <MainBody>India
Hospitals overwhelmed as India heatwave kills nearly 1,700 people
Watch as an extreme heatwave causes roads to melt as soaring temperatures in    India have claimed the lives of nearly 1,700 people
By Reuters, video source ITN
11:40AM BST 29 May 2015
A heatwave in India has killed nearly 1,700 people this week as temperatures soared above 47 Celsius (116.6 Fahrenheit), and doctors' leave has been cancelled to help cope with the sick.
Sunil, 30, gets medical treatment in Jai Prakash Narayan hospital after suffering sunstroke and severe dehydration (EPA)
May and June are India's hottest months, with temperatures regularly pushing above 40 Celsius. But meteorologists say the number of days when temperatures approach 45 Celsius has increased in the past 15 years.
An Indian worker uses a ricksahw to transport ice blocks in Amritsar (AFP)
The death toll in the worst affected states of Andhra Pradesh in the southeast and nearby Telangana is more than double the toll from a shorter hot spell there last year, officials said, with most of those killed elderly or labourers suffering sunstroke or dehydration.
A man sleeps in the shade in Delhi (EPA)
The toll in Andhra Pradesh alone has reached 1,020, officials said, and deaths have been reported in at least four Indian states.
Authorities have cancelled doctors' leave and advised people not to head outside in the middle of the day to avoid the worst of the heat. However for many Indians, staying indoors is not an option.
"I get headaches, fever sometimes. But (if I stay indoors) how will I make money?" scrap collector Akhlaq, 28, said in the capital Delhi, where temperatures touched 45 Celsius on Tuesday.
Animals seek refuge from the sun near Ajmer, India (REUTERS)
The heatwave entered its sixth day in parts of the south on Wednesday, double the time they generally last, according to Y.K. Reddy, a government meteorologist in Hyderabad in one of the worst affected regions.
Blamed on dry continental air blowing in from Iran and Afghanistan, the heatwave is forecast to subside later this week before monsoon rains bring relief to parched areas of the east and south.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:21:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The tension is palpable: Spelling Bee competition, in pictures</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c1387f/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Cworldnews0C116378510CThe0Etension0Eis0Epalpable0ESpelling0EBee0Ecompetition0Ein0Epictures0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In pics: National Spelling Bee competition</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE...
&lt; &gt;
Competitors    in the 88th annual Spelling Bee , held in Oxon Hill, Maryland, range in    age from nine to 15 and are the cream of more than 11 million hopefuls who    took part in local contests. They come from eight countries and all 50 US    states, the District of Columbia, US territories and Defense Department    schools.
Above: Eesha Sohail, left, of Bakersfield, California, and Marcus Behling    of Scottsdale, Arizona, wait for their turn
Picture: Joshua Roberts/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:57:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US charges 15 Chinese in university cheating scam</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c13882/sc/33/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cchina0C116379150CUS0Echarges0E150EChinese0Ein0Euniversity0Echeating0Escam0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Prospective students paid impostors to take entrance exams on their behalf using fake passports mailed from China</Description>
        <MainBody>US charges 15 Chinese in university cheating scam
Prospective students paid impostors to take entrance exams on their behalf    using fake passports mailed from China
The defendants paid impostors to take the Test of English as a Foreign Language (POSED BY MODELS)Photo: ALAMY
By Agencies
10:57AM BST 29 May 2015
The United States has charged 15 people from China with fraud and conspiracy over a four-year scam to fake entry tests for elite American universities.
The indictment exposed an elaborate cheating scam that saw prospective students pay impostors to take a test on their behalf using a fake passport mailed from China.
These students were not only cheating their way into the university, they were also cheating their way through our nations immigration system, said John Kelleghan for Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) of Philadelphia.
Between 2011 and 2015, mainly in western Pennsylvania, the defendants paid impostors to take the SAT  previously known as the Scholastic Aptitude Test  the Test of English as a Foreign Language (TOEFL) and the Graduate Record Examinations (GRE), under false names, according to the Justice Department statement.
Both the test takers and the people they claimed to be are being charged.
David Hickton, US Attorney for the Western District of Pennsylvania, said the beneficiaries secured admission to undergraduate and graduate schools that are among our finest educational institutions.
Mr Hickton declined to name the specific schools, but said that they are located all over the United States. The students also cheated student visa requirements by using counterfeit Chinese passports, he said.
 India arrests 300 over blatant cheating in school exams
One expert voiced fears that there were more students  foreign and domestic  who may be cheating their way into college.
All we have seen is the tip of the iceberg, said Robert Schaeffer, public education director at Fair Test, a national centre for fair and open testing based in Boston.
He told AFP news agency there had been many reports of cheating on the SAT test in Asia, particularly in China, Hong Kong and Korea.
The pressure, particularly in Asia, to get high scores so that you can be admitted to a US university apparently is so great that some students and their families resort to cheating, he said.
The defendants are men and women between the ages of 19 and 26 currently living in several cities where universities are located, including Blacksburg, Virginia, home of Virginia Tech and Boston, Massachusetts, home to dozens of colleges and several elite schools.
If convicted, the defendants face a maximum sentence of 20 years in prison, a fine of $250,000 or both for each count of wire and mail fraud. Conspiracy charges carry an additional five-year maximum sentence.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:50:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Marine le Pen told by grand imam of Al-Azhar her opinions about Islam 'need correcting'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c13885/sc/11/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Cfrance0C116378860CMarine0Ele0EPen0Etold0Eby0Egrand0Eimam0Eof0EAl0EAzhar0Eher0Eopinions0Eabout0EIslam0Eneed0Ecorrecting0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The French Front National leader met Ahmed al-Tayeb, grand imam of Al-Azhar, in Cairo to discuss the need to fight extremism</Description>
        <MainBody>France
Marine le Pen told by grand imam of Al-Azhar her opinions about Islam 'need correcting'
The French Front National leader met Ahmed al-Tayeb, grand imam of Al-Azhar,    in Cairo to discuss the need to fight extremism
Grand Imam of al-Azhar Sheikh Ahmed el-Tayeb met with Marine Le Pen in CairoPhoto: AFP
By AFP
10:50AM BST 29 May 2015
French far-right leader Marine Le Pen has held talks in Egypt with the grand imam of Al-Azhar that addressed the Sunni Muslim body's "serious concerns" over her party's stance on Islam, it said.
National Front president Le Pen met Ahmed al-Tayeb, grand imam of Al-Azhar , at its Cairo headquarters during which he questioned her organisation's "hostile opinions towards Islam and Muslims", an Al-Azhar statement said.
Mr Tayeb added that the National Front's "opinions must be reviewed and corrected".
The National Front, which had a strong showing in local elections in March, has campaigned on politically explosive issues of immigration and the integration of Islam into French society after the Paris Islamist attacks .
Le Pen, who did not wear a veil during the meeting, "recognised the need to not confuse Islam with the violent acts committed" in its name, Al-Azhar said.
The National Front leader tweeted: "Meeting in Cairo with the highest Sunni authority: strong agreement on the fight against extremism."
Rencontre au Caire avec la plus haute autorit sunnite, le grand imam d'Al-Azhar : forte convergence dans la lutte contre l'extrmisme. MLP
 Marine Le Pen (@MLP_officiel) May 28, 2015
Rencontre mouvante avec le patriarche copte d'gypte  qui nous avons exprim notre solidarit avec les chrtiens d'gypte et d'Orient. MLP
 Marine Le Pen (@MLP_officiel) May 28, 2015
Thursday's talks were conducted at Le Pen's request, Al-Azhar said, "to discuss matters related to erroneous ideas and concepts about Islam and extremist ideologies and racism that some Muslims in Europe are suffering from".
The millennium-old institution has emerged as a leading theological centre of Sunni Islam, the main branch of the religion, and shows a will to promote moderate Islam and dialogue with Christians.
Al-Azhar supervises several universities across the country offering courses to thousands of Muslim students from around the world.
It was founded in 970 by the Shiite Fatimid dynasty that ruled Egypt between 969 and 1171, but was converted to Sunni Islam after a Sunni dynasty took over the country.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:42:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Second 'Draw Mohammed' competition to be held outside mosque where Texas gunmen prayed</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c13886/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C116377350CSecond0EDraw0EMohammed0Ecompetition0Eto0Ebe0Eheld0Eoutside0Emosque0Ewhere0ETexas0Egunmen0Eprayed0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Arizona is to host a second "Draw Mohammed" competition - organised by a former Marine who urges everyone to bring guns and American flags</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
Second 'Draw Mohammed' competition to be held outside mosque where Texas gunmen prayed
Arizona is to host a second "Draw Mohammed" competition  organised    by a former Marine who urges everyone to bring guns and American flags
Jon Ritzheimer, right, a former Marine, has urged people to attend the mosque and bring their American flags and gunsPhoto: FACEBOOK
Follow
An American man is organising a second "Draw Mohammed" cartoon competition on Friday, outside a mosque in Arizona where Texas gunmen Elton Simpson and Nadir Soofi once prayed.
Jon Ritzheimer, a former Marine, has urged people to attend the mosque and bring their American flags and guns. He said that biker gangs will be there for protection.
"I admit that what I am doing is stupid," he said, in a Facebook post which showed him posing in a bullet-proof vest in his kitchen , holding an automatic rifle. "But so is stomping on the American flag and I support their rights and freedom to do so."
On May 3 a similar "Draw Mohammed" competition, held in the town of Garland in Texas, was attacked by two gunmen who claimed to be acting for Islamic State. The pair  Elton Simpson and Nadir Soofi  were shot dead as they drew their weapons. Pamela Geller, the anti-Islam activist , said that she had organised the event as a celebration of freedom of speech, despite depicting the Prophet being deeply offensive to the world's Muslims.
Mr Ritzheimer said that he was organising his event in Phoenix to show that the Garland shooting would not leave America cowed. To prove his point, he was also selling T-shirts bearing the slogan "---- Islam".
"Im a Marine, and I am far from politically correct," he told local television station KPNX-TV . "Im outspoken, and Ive just had it."
On Friday morning over 600 people said they were planning to attend the event.
"This is not an anti Islam rally," he said. "This is a pro freedom of speech rally, so don't let the media twist it."
He said that he and his family had received threats over the event, but vowed to press on regardless. On Facebook, he stated that an attack on the event was "much anticipated."
"We've received a bunch of credible threats," he told CNN. "I've already had the police come to my house. My family is currently packing up and they are going into hiding.
"True Islam is terrorism. The ones that are out committing these atrocities, they are following the book as it's written."
Usama Shami, the president of the Islamic Community Center of Phoenix, said he has been aware of the event and been contacted by both local police and the FBI.
"Everybody has a right to be a bigot. Everybody has a right to be a racist. Everybody has a right to be an idiot," he said.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:34:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Celebrity Sightings: Cressida Bonas, Megan Fox and Alessandra Ambrosio</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c02f80/sc/14/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Ccelebritynews0C116377610CCelebrity0ESightings0ECressida0EBonas0EMegan0EFox0Eand0EAlessandra0EAmbrosio0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Featuring: Cressida Bonas, Megan Fox and Alessandra Ambrosio</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE...
&lt; &gt;
Cressida Bonas signing autographs for fans at 'An Evening with Lucien Freud' at the Leicester Square theatre in LondonPicture: Rex

Comments are closed on this picture gallery.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:26:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Rihanna has become the latest US musician to enjoy Havana</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c02f88/sc/10/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ccentralamericaandthecaribbean0Ccuba0C116377570CHow0ERihanna0Ehas0Ebecome0Ethe0Elatest0EUS0Emusician0Eto0Eenjoy0EHavana0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Umbrella pop star was seen dancing and eating Cuban food for an impromptu visit</Description>
        <MainBody>How Rihanna has become the latest US musician to enjoy Havana
The Umbrella pop star was seen dancing and eating Cuban food for an impromptu    visit
Singer Rihanna on a photoshoot in Havana Photo: REUTERS
By AFP
Comments
Pop star Rihanna danced to Cuban music and sampled local cuisine on an impromptu visit to Havana, the latest big name from the US music scene to visit the island.
Rihanna, who hails from Barbados, arrived "on the fly, as we Cubans say," for an unscheduled visit, said Ernesto Blanco, the owner of the Restaurante-Paladar La Fontana, where she dined and danced on Wednesday night shortly after flying to the island.
"She specifically asked to eat Cuban food," he told AFP.
The Umbrella singer ate black beans, grilled chorizos, pork chops and a local dish called "grandma's steak", online magazine OnCuba said on its Facebook page.
 Watch: Rihanna slinks through the Palace of Versailles for Dior
She then jigged to "classic Cuban music" by the restaurant's in-house band, it said.
Rumours had been circulating in Cuba that Rihanna was on her way to the island to film her next music video.
Mr Blanco said Rihanna, 27, was travelling with four people, plus her bodyguards.
Fans wait to see Rihanna
As a Barbadian national, Rihanna is not subject to US restrictions on travel to Cuba.
But she faces the same obstacles as other US residents to travel to the communist island, which commercial airlines cannot service directly from the United States under the 1962 embargo.
President Barack Obama has eased restrictions on travel to Cuba as part of the landmark rapprochement that he and his counterpart Ral Castro announced last December.
But currently only approved charter flights can connect the two countries.
Rihanna's visit comes after pop diva Beyonce and her rapper husband Jay Z travelled to Cuba in April 2013 to celebrate their fifth wedding anniversary.
The US treasury department approved the couple's trip as a cultural exchange, though it drew criticism from Republican politicians who accused them of violating the ban on tourism.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:15:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Radioactive leak at India's Delhi airport</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c02f89/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cindia0C116377830CRadioactive0Eleak0Eat0EIndias0EDelhi0Eairport0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Radioactive liquid used in so-called nuclear medicine - leaked in cargo hold on board an inbound Turkish Airlines passenger flight</Description>
        <MainBody>India
Radioactive leak at India's Delhi airport
Radioactive liquid used in so-called nuclear medicine - leaked in cargo hold    on board an inbound Turkish Airlines passenger flight
The leak was found at the airport's cargo-handling complex at Indira Gandhi International AirportPhoto: ALAMY
By Reuters
10:15AM BST 29 May 2015
Radioactive material leaked from a medical shipment on Friday at Delhi's Indira Gandhi International Airport, Indian government and airport officials said, adding that the incident had been contained and there was no risk to passengers.
The leak was found at the airport's cargo-handling complex in a consignment of sodium iodide 131 - a radioactive liquid used in so-called nuclear medicine - that had been on board an inbound Turkish Airlines passenger flight.
"This area is far away from any of the passenger terminals and there is absolutely no risk of exposure to any passengers," Delhi International Airport Ltd, the airport's operator, said in a statement.
"The said area has been cordoned off and as per the preliminary assessment ... the material has been termed as that of low radio activity."
 India's tallest man struggling to find love: 'I have never found anyone to look up to'
Sodium iodide 131 is used to treat hyperthyroidism and thyroid cancers. It emits radiation and must be handled with care to minimise inadvertent exposure to health workers and patients.
The site was cordoned off by an emergency response team that included representatives of India's National Disaster Response Force and atomic regulators.
"It's a localised leak," R. Bhattacharya, vice-chairman of the Atomic Energy Regulatory Board, told Reuters by telephone.
Home Minister Rajnath Singh, who was holding a news conference when news of the leak broke, said atomic experts had been immediately dispatched to the scene.
"We have been getting regular updates on the situation at the airport," he told reporters. "The leak is under control but we are leaving no stone unturned to check all possibilities of the leakage."
Turkish Airlines had no immediate comment.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:11:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Swedish fathers to get third month of paternity leave</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c02f8a/sc/13/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Ceurope0Csweden0C11637780A0CSwedish0Efathers0Eto0Eget0Ethird0Emonth0Eof0Epaternity0Eleave0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Sweden offers generous 16-month parental leave, with three months of that set aside for fathers from next year</Description>
        <MainBody>Sweden
Swedish fathers to get third month of paternity leave
Sweden offers generous 16-month parental leave, with three months of that set    aside for fathers from next year
Sweden offers a generous 16-month parental leave which can be taken by either mothers or fathersPhoto: ALAMY
10:11AM BST 29 May 2015
The Swedish government plans to introduce a third month of paid parental leave reserved for fathers as of next year in a bid to further increase gender equality, it said on Thursday.
Sweden offers a generous 16-month parental leave which can be taken by either mothers or fathers, with two months of that set aside for dads.
A third month is something weve really looked forward to. We know that this is a key issue towards attaining greater (gender) equality, Social Security Minister Annika Strandhall told Swedish Radio.
The country introduced a first month reserved specifically for fathers under a use it or lose it system in 1995, and a second month in 2002.
 Baby Bjrns: are you as hands-on as a Swedish father?
Under the government proposal, both mothers and fathers would be required to take three months each, or lose them. The remaining 10 months would be divided however the parents wish.
But the reserved months have over the years become known as daddy months because they are aimed at encouraging fathers to share more of the parental leave.
Parents receive 80 per cent of their salary while on leave, capped at a salary ceiling of around 4,000 euros ($4,360) per month.
Despite great strides in gender equality, Swedish men still earn more than women in general, and as a result men take more of an economic hit by staying home with their children.
Forcing parents to use it or lose it, which means mothers cannot get the months reserved for fathers, the policy therefore encourages dads to stay home.
Women currently claim around some 75 per cent of parental leave, compared to 99.5 per cent when it was introduced in 1974.
Parental leave can be used anytime up until the child turns eight years old.
Some 80 per cent of children in Sweden have two working parents, but only around 40 per cent of women work full-time compared to some 75 per cent of men, according to 2013 statistics.
Official figures from Eurostat show that 77 per cent of women in Sweden held down a job in 2014, the highest level in the European Union.
Children are guaranteed a spot in day care as of the age of 12 months for a very modest sum, making it possible for women to return to work.
The minority Social Democratic-led government plans to present its bill to parliament in the autumn, and it is expected to pass with the support of the Left and Liberal parties.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:10:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al-Qaeda-led rebels take Idlib's last Syria regime bastion</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c02f8b/sc/11/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cmiddleeast0Csyria0C1163770A30CAl0EQaeda0Eled0Erebels0Etake0EIdlibs0Elast0ESyria0Eregime0Ebastion0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>After violent clashes,al-Nusra Front and its allies in the Army of Conquest - Jaish al-Fatah in Arabic - capture Ariha</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria
Al-Qaeda-led rebels take Idlib's last Syria regime bastion
After violent clashes,al-Nusra Front and its allies in the Army of Conquest  Jaish al-Fatah in Arabic  capture Ariha
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front ride on a pick-up truck as they head towards their positions during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of ArihaPhoto: REUTERS
By AFP
Comments
A rebel coalition led by the Syrian affiliate of al-Qaeda stormed and seized the last regime-held city in Idlib province on Thursday, as Iraq exhumed the remains of 470 jihadist victims.
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front fire their weapon during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha (REUTERS)
The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said al-Nusra Front and its allies in the Army of Conquest  Jaish al-Fatah in Arabic  captured Ariha after fierce clashes with regime forces including their Hizbollah allies, who were seen withdrawing.
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front gather before moving on Ariha (REUTERS)
The rebel sweep saw their fighters quickly enter outer districts of Ariha, Rami Abdel Rahman, the Observatory head, told AFP.
"Jaish al-Fatah has taken full control of the city of Ariha after a lightning offensive that ended with a heavy pullout of regime forces and their allies Hizbollah from the western side of the city," he said.
al Qaeda's Nusra Front head towards their positions (BLOOMBERG)
The coalition confirmed the takeover of Ariha on Twitter, saying it seized the city in just six hours.
Earlier, Mr Abdel Rahman said: "There was heavy shelling and rocket fire, then they stormed the city. They have entered the city and are engaged in fierce clashes on its peripheries."
al Qaeda's Nusra Front have taken control of Ariha (BLOOMBERG)
Ariha, which was home to 40,000 people before the conflict began, was the last remaining government-held city in Idlib province bordering Turkey .
"The march of lions has begun ... LET Allah liberate Ariha," the Army of Conquest's official Twitter account posted as the attack began.
The Britain-based Observatory said late Thursday that dozens of military vehicles were seen withdrawing from Ariha.
The Army of Conquest coalition has won a string of victories in Idlib, including taking the provincial capital on March 28 and the key town of Jisr al-Shughur on April 25.
Most recently, the rebels seized the massive al-Mastumah military base and overran a hospital complex where regime soldiers were trapped.
Many government forces retreated from these areas to Ariha, which Abdel Rahman said was heavily defended by fighters from Iran and Lebanese Shia movement Hizbollah.
The Army of Conquest vowed to consolidate its control of Idlib province, where before the latest attack the regime still held Ariha, the Abu Duhur military airport and a sprinkling of villages and military posts.
In the fight against the separate Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (Isil), the Pentagon said on Thursday US-led coalition had hit targets in both Syria and Iraq .
Aircraft targeted Isil with six strikes in Hasakeh and Deir Ezzor provinces, while in neighbouring Iraq warplanes launched a total of 20 strikes against the jihadists.
Iraq's health minister said on Thursday authorities there have exhumed the remains of 470 people believed to have been executed by Isil near Tikrit last year in what became known as the Speicher massacre.
"We have exhumed the bodies of 470 Speicher martyrs from burial sites in Tikrit," Adila Hammoud told reporters in Baghdad.
In June 2014, armed men belonging or allied to Isil abducted hundreds of young, mostly Shia recruits from Speicher military base, just outside the city of Tikrit.
They were then lined up in several locations and executed one by one, as shown in pictures and footage later released by Isil on the internet.
 Baghdad bombs kill at least 10
Some were pushed into the Tigris river, others hastily buried in locations that were discovered when government and allied forces retook Tikrit from the jihadists about two months ago.
The highest estimate for the number of people killed in one of the worst Isil atrocities stands at 1,700.
The exhumed remains came from four burial sites, including one which contained 400 bodies, said Ziad Ali Abbas, the chief doctor at Baghdad's main morgue.
"There were several layers of bodies all piled on top of each other," he said, adding that 50 bodies were found in a second site and nine more in the two remaining graves.
The health minister said the figure of 470 was not final.
"The work to exhume Speicher victims continues," Ms Hammoud said.
"The morgue also continues its work to identify the bodies ... It's complicated work. It's a huge case. It takes a lot of work to identify the victims," she said.
Officials had said in mid-April that up to 10 different suspected burial sites were identified in the Tikrit area after government forces recaptured it in late March and early April.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:50:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Catcalling happens to most women between the ages of 11 and 17</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c02f8c/sc/19/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cwomen0Cwomens0Elife0C116376970CCatcalling0EWomen0Esexually0Eharassed0Eon0Ethe0Estreet0Efrom0Epuberty0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The largest study of its kind has shown that 84 per cent of women, across 22 countries, are experiencing street harassment before the age of 17 - and that figure is even higher in Britain</Description>
        <MainBody>Women's Life
Catcalling happens to most women between the ages of 11 and 17
The largest study of its kind has shown that 84 per cent of women, across 22    countries, are experiencing street harassment before the age of 17 - and    that figure is even higher in Britain
Shoshana Roberts was catcalled 108 times as she walked around New YorkPhoto: YouTube / Street HarassmentVideo
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:49:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>One World Observatory: With a view from the skies, New York heals</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c02f8d/sc/38/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C116374950COne0EWorld0EObservatory0EWith0Ea0Eview0Efrom0Ethe0Eskies0ENew0EYork0Eheals0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Panorama of New York skyline once again centre-stage as observatory opens atop new World Trade Centre 14 years after 9/11 attacks</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
One World Observatory: With a view from the skies, New York heals
Panorama of New York skyline once again centre-stage as observatory opens atop    new World Trade Centre 14 years after 9/11 attacks
By Philip Sherwell , New York
9:49AM BST 29 May 2015
Comments
For New Yorkers, the void in the downtown skyline that was for so long dominated by the Twin Towers was as much of a scar on the city as the gaping holes at Ground Zero.
The lower Manhattan skyline is seen from One World Observatory at One World Trade Center in New York (BLOOMBERG)
Those clear skies were a constant reminder of the terrible day in September 2001 when al-Qaeda terrorists flew hijacked passenger planes into the World Trade Centre, the two structures that were once the tallest buildings on the planet.
Boats moving past the Statue of Liberty are seen from One World Observatory (BLOOMBERG)
Within hours of the attacks, Rudy Giuliani, the citys mayor, famously proclaimed: "We will rebuild. The skyline will be made whole again."
His pledge reflected the defiance of most residents of America s largest city. But it has taken nearly 14 years to be fulfilled.
The Manhattan skyline (BLOOMBERG)
On Friday morning, the One World Observatory at the top of the new World Trade Centre will open to the public for the first time. It will offer visitors not just a much-missed panorama of the city, but also signal a symbolic end to the healing process for the city.
At ground level, parts of the 16-acre plot are still a building site. But the landmark building here  the tallest in the Western Hemisphere  is finally whole again, to echo Mr Giulianis words.
And in another sign of changing times, the observatory is almost devoid of references to the horrors of 9/11, its operators preferring to focus on the future via new digital technology rather than dwell on the recent past.
That tragic history is marked in near-fetishistic detail at the neighbouring 9/11 Museum and Memorial . And it is impossible not to be moved by the solemn majesty of the reflective pools that occupy the footprints of the destroyed towers, the names of the dead etched around the edge.
But the observatory, with its stunning views, is focussed resolutely on the future in a tribute to New Yorks resilience rather than a mourning of its loss.
The recovery of Lower Manhattan has been slow and painful, mired by bickering over architectural style and political posturing, not to mention real estate deal-making at a site that is both the most symbolic and most lucrative in America.
Some had contended that it was inappropriate ever to build back on what was now hallowed ground; others argued about what could and should replace the iconic towers. There were also problems finding potential tenants.
The main tower went through three different designs and two names as the colloquial moniker of the Freedom Tower was eventually replaced less emotively by 1 World Trade Centre.
Illuminated One World Trade Center towers over the lower Manhattan skyline in New York
Construction finally began on the foundations in 2006. Even then progress was slow, but eventually the scaffolding-clad structure started to emerge into the landscape.
In April 2012, it surpassed the height of the Empire State Building, And in 2013 the structure was topped off with a beacon that gave it a final height of 1,776 ft  a historically laden number reflect the year of the signing of the Declaration of Independence. The building finally opened for business in November 2014.
The over-runs in time and cost continue elsewhere  for example, the new transit hub, a 10-year project designed by Spanish architect Santiago Calatrava will cost almost $4 billion, two times more than the initial estimate, The New York Times reported.
Even completing the memorial to the 9/11 victims in time for the 10th anniversary in 2011 required an intervention by Michael Bloomberg, the then mayor.
But from 1,250 feet above ground level, New York and its visitors can now revel in a view they have not seen since September 2001. For many, the citys comeback is complete.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:43:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>United Airlines cabin crew 'kick pregnant singer off plane because of her crying toddler'</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c02f8e/sc/3/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C116376320Cpregnant0Esinger0Esarah0Eblackwood0Eunited0Eairlines0Ecrying0Ebaby0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Seven-month pregnant Sarah Blackwood claims she was unfairly thrown off flight because her two-year-old son was crying</Description>
        <MainBody>United Airlines cabin crew 'kick pregnant singer off plane because of her crying toddler'
Seven-month pregnant Sarah Blackwood claims she was unfairly thrown off flight    because her two-year-old son was crying
Sarah Blackwood was kicked off the plane because her baby was crying
By Helena Horton
9:43AM BST 29 May 2015
If you take a young child on a plane, there will amost certainly be tears at some point. And understandably so.
While this may be frustrating for other passengers, most would argue that it's not worth being thrown off a plane for.
However, a seven-month pregnant woman claims she in this very situation when she took her son, two, on a United Airlines flight.
Cabin crew were apparently so enraged by Sarah Blackwood's crying toddler they turned around the plane and asked the pair to leave.
The Canadian singer, from the band Walk Off The Earth, was so furious she took to social media to complain about her treatment.
The angry mother said she was "disgusted and exhausted" in a post on her Facebook page.
She also tweeted about how she was treated, gained support from others who called for a boycott of the airline.
Rachel Ann posted on the singer's Facebook and said: "Today Sarah Blackwood was kicked off a UNITED AIRLINES flight because her 22-month-old toddler was crying. This is discriminatory, intolerant and uncharitable.
"The airline staff who told her to 'control' her crying baby should be reprimanded for unnecessarily kicking a seven-month pregnant mother off her flight, especially considering that by the time the plane was filled with gas, her son was sound asleep. Please boycott #unitedairlines for being #ignorant, #discriminatory, and #intolerant. #motherhaters #worstcustomerservice #unitedairlinesucks"
Just got kicked off a @united flight because my son was crying really loud. Stayed calm but overall #Discrimination #motherhaters @united
 Sarah Blackwood (@SarahBlackwood1) May 27, 2015
Paul William Moore was on the flight, and wrote to United: "I was on UA Flight 6223 from San Francisco to Vancouver today at 1:34 PM. Two rows in front of me sat an eight-month pregnant single mom with her 2 year old toddler. Evidently the child was upset about being on the flight and even though the mother was trying her best to stop her from crying, she would not."
 'Healthy' children's fruit snacks contain more sugar than Haribo sweet s
"The only person that was not empathetic to the clearly stressful situation was the flight attendant, who warned the mother 3 times to keep her kid quiet. Sure enough the flight attendant followed through on her warning and had the plane return from taxiing to position on the runway back to the airport.
"By this time the chid is now fast asleep. We then spent the next 75 minutes while the flight crew escorted the mother and child off the plane and the cargo crew removed all the luggage off the plane in order to find her bags. Everyone on that flight was shocked at how unprofessional, unreasonable and insensitive a certain member of your staff acted!"
Sarah Blackwood is a singer-songwriter in a Canadian rock and ska band (Picture: Instagram)
Skywest Airlines, which operates United, defended cabin crew's actions.
A spokesman said in a statement: "Despite numerous requests, the child was not seated, as required by federal regulation to ensure passenger safety, and was repeatedly in the aisle of the aircraft before departure and during taxi.
"While our crews work to make travelling safe and comfortable for all travellers, particularly families, the crew made the appropriate decision to return to the gate in the interest of safety."
 As "hashtag" is crowned children's word of the year, we list the top entries - ranked by you
Blackwood argued that her son had never been in the aisle. She told CBS news : "I had a window seat, there was a gentleman beside me, there's no way he could have been running around in an aisle, because it was impossible,"
"I don't want to cause a scene, ever, it just makes my life harder."
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:37:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pictures of the day: 29 May 2015</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bf7b89/sc/35/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cpicturegalleries0Cpicturesoftheday0C116375370CPictures0Eof0Ethe0Eday0E280EMay0E20A150Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In pics: Tiger cubs take first steps, Scripps National Spelling Bee and lots of lego</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE...
&lt; &gt;
An aerial photograph shows a view of a creation by German street artist 10.10 on the peripherique (circular road) in ParisPicture: JOEL SAGET/AFP/Getty Images

Comments are closed on this picture gallery.
Related Articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:26:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China detains artist for mocking leader Xi Jinping</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bf833c/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cchina0C116376510CChina0Edetains0Eartist0Efor0Emocking0Eleader0EXi0EJinping0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dai Jianyong has been detained for creating an image of the Chinese president with a crinkled face and a moustache, a human rights group says</Description>
        <MainBody>China
China detains artist for mocking leader Xi Jinping
Dai Jianyong has been detained for creating an image of the Chinese president    with a crinkled face and a moustache, a human rights group says
Di Jiayong, left, and his image of Communist leader Xi Jinping with a crinkled face and a moustache
By AFP
Comments
Chinese police have detained an artist for creating an image of Communist leader Xi Jinping with a crinkled face and a moustache, according to a human rights group.
Shanghai police held artist and photographer Dai Jianyong, who posted the image online, on Wednesday for picking quarrels and provoking trouble, said Chinese Human Rights Defenders, a coalition of Chinese and international rights groups.
The photo of Mr Xi, which was re-posted on the organisations website, showed the Chinese president and Communist Party chief with a moustache that some have compared to that of the leader of Nazi Germany, Adolf Hitler .
Shanghai artist Dai Jianyong demonstrates the 'Chrysanthemum Face' in an undated photo
The crinkled facial expression, which Mr Dai himself uses in photographs, has been likened to an anus.
Mr Dai also posted online the image of Mr Xi on a T-shirt, but it was unclear if Mr Dai ever sold or distributed products with the photo.
Shanghai police could not be reached for comment on Friday. Mr Dai is being held under administrative detention by the authorities in Shanghais Changning district, the rights group said. His fate remains unclear and he could be formally arrested.
Radio Free Asia, which is backed by the US government, quoted his friend and fellow artist Wu Tun as saying: He did a satirical portrait of Xi Jinping, merging his own face with Xis in Photoshop.
He added: Hes a photographer and he usually shoots a lot of different things.
China imposes tight controls over art and culture, though it has relaxed some cultural controls from the 1970s, when popular art consisted of little more than propaganda in accordance with the doctrines of then leader Mao Tse-tung.
Last year, Mr Xi told artists not to chase popularity with vulgar works but to promote socialism instead.
His comments drew comparisons to a well-known speech by Mao in the 1940s which outlined his view that the arts should serve politics.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:08:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US National Spelling Bee ends in tie for second year running</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bf8342/sc/13/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Cnorthamerica0Cusa0C116376470CUS0ENational0ESpelling0EBee0Eends0Ein0Etie0Efor0Esecond0Eyear0Erunning0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>National Spelling Bee ends in tie for the second year running, with one victor, Vanya, 13, the sibling of a past champion</Description>
        <MainBody>USA
US National Spelling Bee ends in tie for second year running
National Spelling Bee ends in tie for the second year running, with one    victor, Vanya, 13, the sibling of a past champion
By AP, video source ESPN
9:08AM BST 29 May 2015
US teenagers Gokul Venkatachalam and Vanya Shivashankar had worked too hard and come close too many times not to win the Scripps National Spelling Bee.
Winners Vanya Shivashankar and Gokul Venkatachalam (GETTY)
So they shared the title on Thursday, making history in two different ways.
The bee hadn't ended in a tie for 52 years  until last year . Now it's happened for an unprecedented two years running. Vanya, 13, of Kansas, is the first sibling of a past champion to win. Her sister, Kavya, won in 2009.
Vanya's final word was "scherenschnitte," which means the art of cutting paper into decorative designs.
Ankita Vadiala of Manassas, Virginia, reacts after correctly spelling her word (GETTY)
After being informed he'd be the co-champion if he got the next word right, Gokul didn't even bother to ask the definition before spelling "nunatak." For the record, it means a hill or mountain completely surrounded by glacial ice.
Cole Shafer-Ray (L) of Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, and Siddharth Krishnakumar of Houston, Texas, wait their turn (GETTY)
Asked what he thought when he got the word, Gokul said, "Me and Vanya were going to be the champions."
Gokul, 14, of Missouri, finished third last year, behind the two co-champions. He had a gruff onstage demeanour, asking about the word's roots and definition before chugging through the letters as if he had dinner plans.
Zander Reed, 12, a home-schooled seventh grader from Iowa, cringes after incorrectly spelling ''alleviate'' in round two (GETTY)
"I wasn't nervous," said Gokul, a LeBron James fan who said his priority for after the bee was watching the NBA finals.
Both are eighth-graders, so it was their last chance. Vanya was competing in the bee for the fifth and final time. Her sister, Kavya  now a sophomore at Columbia University  competed four times, which means the Shivashankar family has made the trip nine of the past 10 years.
Melina Gabele of Willoughby, Ohio, spells her word correctly (GETTY)
Vanya, who also acts and plays the tuba and piano, dedicated her victory to her grandmother.
"Everything takes hard work and passion," Vanya said. "That's definitely what I put in and I know Gokul put that into this endeavour as well."
Lora Kuhaneck, 13, is comforted after incorrectly spelling "kitsch" in round two (PHOTOSHOT)
Vanya and Gokul went head-to-head for 10 rounds before the list of 25 championship words was exhausted.
The words included: bouquetire, caudillismo, thamakau, scytale, Bruxellois and pyrrhuloxia. Vanya appeared to struggle only with the Fijian-derived thamakau, which is a type of outrigger canoe.
Vanya and Gokul each will receive more than $37,000 (24,000) in cash and prizes, and while they held up the trophy together as they were being showered with confetti, each will get one to take home. Fourteen-year-old Cole Shafer-Ray of Norman, Oklahoma, making his first appearance in the finals, finished third.
Fourteen of the past 18 winners have been Indian-Americans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:06:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Watch live: 65th Fifa congress</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46c13887/sc/6/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Csport0Cfootball0C116376560CWatch0Elive0E65th0EFIFA0Econgress0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Watch live from the 65th Fifa congress as members decide whether Sepp Blatter should stay on as Fifa president</Description>
        <MainBody>Football
Watch live: 65th Fifa congress
Watch live from the 65th Fifa congress as members decide whether Sepp Blatter    should stay on as Fifa president
By Telegraph Video, and agencies, video source FIFA TV
9:06AM BST 29 May 2015
Fifa members will decide today if Sepp Blatter should stay as president just days after the FBI revealed a major investigation into decades of corruption at the heart of international football.
Sepp Blatter address the 65th Fifa congress in Zurich (Michael Buholzer / Getty)
Football leaders and politicians from across Europe have called for Mr Blatter to either resign or be voted out after Swiss police carried out a dawn raid on Wednesday and arrested seven officials.
In an opening speech at the Fifa Congress in Zurich today, Mr Blatter said: "The events of this week unleashed a storm.
"It was even questioned whether this Congress would go ahead but I am appealing for unity and team spirit to tackle the problems that have been created and to solve them.
"It will not be done in a single day, it will take some time.
"The important point today is to move ahead - and the important point is transparency. We have a problem to solve."
How does the voting process work?
Each of Fifa's 209 associations should have a vote, in secret, although a few can face disqualification for reasons such as not playing in competitions.
If either candidate achieves two-thirds of the eligible vote in the first round then he wins outright - if there are 209 votes that means 139 to win outright.
Prince Ali bin al-Hussein and Michel Platini listen to President Joseph Blatter (Paul Grover)
If there is no outright victory, the winner will simply be whoever gains more votes in the second round.
Top Football Galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:03:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China executes teacher for rape and abuse of 26 children</title>
        <Link>http://telegraph.feedsportal.com/c/32726/f/568301/s/46bf8347/sc/7/l/0L0Stelegraph0O0Cnews0Cworldnews0Casia0Cchina0C116375870CChina0Eexecutes0Eteacher0Efor0Erape0Eand0Eabuse0Eof0E260Echildren0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Li Jishun raped or sexually abused 26 children aged between 4 to 11, the state news agency says</Description>
        <MainBody>China
China executes teacher for rape and abuse of 26 children
Li Jishun raped or sexually abused 26 children aged between 4 to 11, the state    news agency says
Li Jishun was convicted of having raped or sexually abused 26 girls aged from 4 to 11 (MODEL RELEASED)Photo: ALAMY
By AFP
9:03AM BST 29 May 2015
China has executed a former teacher for raping and sexually abusing 26 children at his school, state media reported.
Li Jishun was convicted of having raped or sexually abused 26 girls aged from 4 to 11, the official Xinhua news agency said.
The abuse took place in 2011 and 2012, when he was a teacher at a primary school, it added.
Li was put to death on Thursday by a court in Tianshui, in the north-western province of Gansu, Xinhua said, adding that he was handed the heaviest punishment possible because of the harm caused to the children and the extremely negative social impact of the case.
He took advantage of those who were both childish and timid and committed his acts in dormitories or classrooms, Xinhua added.
It cited Chinas Supreme Peoples Court as saying child sexual abuse cases have risen in recent years, with 7,145 across the country in the 2012-2014 period.
Top news galleries
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
