<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="thestar">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>U.S. says China agrees &amp;#39;pressure&amp;#39; key on North Korea</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/US-says-China-agrees-pressure-key-on-North-Korea</Link>
        <Description>BEIJING (Reuters) - China has agreed that &amp;#34;pressure&amp;#34; on North Korea is an important element in a push to rid the country of its nuclear weapons, a U.S. official overseeing policy on North Korea said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 7:00:07 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 7:00:07 PM
U.S. says China agrees 'pressure' key on North Korea
BEIJING (Reuters) - China has agreed that "pressure" on North Korea is an important element in a push to rid the country of its nuclear weapons, a U.S. official overseeing policy on North Korea said on Friday.
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry said last week the United States and China were discussing imposing further sanctions on North Korea, which he said was "not even close" to taking necessary steps to end its nuclear programme.
China is North Korea's most important trading partner and only major ally, though the North's nuclear and missile tests over recent years have strained their ties.
"The Chinese agree that pressure has to be an important part of our approach on North Korea," Sung Kim, the U.S. special representative for North Korea policy, told a media briefing in Beijing.
Chinese Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying said that the issue of the Korean peninsula was "the common responsibility of all parties concerned".
"The North Korean nuclear issue is very complex and requires dialogue and consultation to resolve the concerns of all parties," Hua said at a regular news briefing.
China has always called for "denuclearisation" of the whole peninsula, including any weapons held by U.S. forces in South Korea, being careful not to point the finger of blame solely at the North.
Kim represented the United States in talks this week with its two important Asian allies, South Korea and Japan, on how to step up pressure on North Korea to give up its nuclear ambitions. Those talks were in the South Korean capital, Seoul.
Kim also told the briefing in Beijing that the United States believed China was fully implementing sanctions on North Korea brought by the U.N. Security Council.
Kim's visit to the region follows a test of what the North said was a submarine-launched ballistic missile this month, which if true, could mean progress in the reclusive state's military capabilities.
North Korea's first nuclear test was in 2006. It tested again in 2009, and more recently in 2013, drawing criticism from many countries including China.
It has defied pressure to abandon its missile and nuclear programmes.
(Reporting by Megha Rajagopalan, Additional reporting by Sui-Lee Wee; Editing by Robert Birsel and Nick Macfie)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Iran provides some information in U.N. nuclear inquiry - IAEA</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Iran-provides-some-information-in-UN-nuclear-inquiry--IAEA</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - Iran has provided some information about one of two open items in a U.N. nuclear watchdog investigation into whether it may have researched an atomic bomb, the International Atomic Energy Agency reported on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:35:06 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:35:06 PM
Iran provides some information in U.N. nuclear inquiry - IAEA
by michael shields
VIENNA (Reuters) - Iran has provided some information about one of two open items in a U.N. nuclear watchdog investigation into whether it may have researched an atomic bomb, the International Atomic Energy Agency reported on Friday.
The confidential IAEA report, obtained by Reuters, said Tehran had "shared some information in relation to one of these measures. The Agency and Iran agreed to continue the dialogue on these practical measures and to meet again in the near future."
The latest quarterly IAEA report on Iran was issued to the U.N. agency's member states with Iran seeking to nail down final terms of an accord with six world powers on curbing its disputed nuclear programme in exchange for relief from sanctions.
The seven countries have set themselves a deadline of June 30 but that is showing signs of slipping.
The Vienna-based IAEA also said it remained vital that Iran provide answers to the agency's questions on and access to the Parchin military base, where Western officials suspect Tehran conducted explosives tests relevant to nuclear bombs.
The Islamic Republic denies this and has long maintained that it is enriching uranium only for electricity and medical isotopes rather than to develop a nuclear bomb capability in secret as the West has suspected.
"The (IAEA) remains ready to accelerate the resolution of all outstanding issues under the Framework for Cooperation. This can be realised by increased cooperation by Iran and by the timely provision of access to all relevant information, documentation, sites, material and personnel in Iran as requested by the agency," the report said.
Western diplomats have viewed Irans stonewalling of the IAEA inquiry as an indicator of the its unwillingness to cooperate fully until punitive sanctions are lifted in talks with the six powers that resumed in Vienna this week.
The United States said it is not considering negotiating beyond the end-June deadline despite comments from France and Iran indicating there was some room to do so.
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry is to reconvene with Iranian counterpart Mohammed Javad Zarif in Geneva on Saturday. The lead U.S. negotiator, Wendy Sherman, flew to Vienna on Wednesday for talks among Iran and the powers and will join Kerry in Geneva before resuming talks in the Austrian capital.
The deal sought by the powers would have Iran accept limits to its uranium enrichment capacity and open up to unfettered IAEA inspections to help ensure it could not put its nuclear programme to developing bombs. They also want Iran to resolve all IAEA questions to build trust in its nuclear aspirations.
In return, OPEC member Iran would see a lifting of international sanctions that hobbled its oil-based economy.
A tentative agreement was reached between Iran, the United States, France, Britain, Germany, Russia and China on April 2.
But pivotal issues remain unresolved, including the pace of easing Western sanctions and the extent of monitoring and verification measures to ensure Iran honours any agreement.
(Editing by Mark Heinrich)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Suicide bomber, two people killed outside a Shi&amp;#39;ite Mosque in Saudi - witnesses</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Car-explodes-near-mosque-in-Saudi-Arabias-Dammam--witness</Link>
        <Description>ABU DHABI (Reuters) - Three people were killed on Friday when a suicide bomber tried to enter a Shi&amp;#39;ite Muslim mosque in eastern Saudi Arabia, witnesses said, the second attack of its kind in a week.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:35:05 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:35:05 PM
Suicide bomber, two people killed outside a Shi'ite Mosque in Saudi - witnesses
ABU DHABI (Reuters) - Three people were killed on Friday when a suicide bomber tried to enter a Shi'ite Muslim mosque in eastern Saudi Arabia, witnesses said, the second attack of its kind in a week.
A witness identified only as Ahmed said he was with his family near the al-Anoud Mosque when "a quick explosion" happened. He did not know the cause of the blast.
He said acquaintances at the mosque told him a man was killed along with a bomber when the man tried to prevent him from reaching the building.
Another witness said a passer-by was also killed in the blast.
A suicide bombing on May 22 killed 21 worshippers at a Shi'ite mosque in al-Qadeeh village in an attack claimed by Islamic State.
Residents circulated pictures of the body of a man believed to be the suicide bomber as well as pictures of large black clouds of smoke billowing over a parking lot outside the mosque.
Social media accounts showed video purporting to show the congregation inside the mosque reacting with shock and alarm to the sound of the explosion outside the building.
Saudi security forces surrounded the area and began investigating the incident.
(Reporting By Sami Aboudi; Writing By Maha El Dahan and William Maclean; Editing by Angus MacSwan)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>South Africa frees anti-apartheid hero murder mastermind</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Killer-of-South-African-politician-Hani-granted-parole</Link>
        <Description>PRETORIA (Reuters) - The right wing politician who masterminded the killing of a South African anti-apartheid hero was granted medical parole on Friday, setting aside an earlier decision by the justice minister to block his release.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:30:10 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:30:10 PM
South Africa frees anti-apartheid hero murder mastermind
PRETORIA (Reuters) - The right wing politician who masterminded the killing of a South African anti-apartheid hero was granted medical parole on Friday, setting aside an earlier decision by the justice minister to block his release.
Clive Derby-Lewis, an ultra-right wing politician who masterminded the 1993 assassination of Communist Party leader Chris Hani in an attempt to trigger a race war, had been serving a life sentence for the murder.
Derby-Lewis was diagnosed with cancer and had asked to be paroled. But Justice Minister Michael Masutha denied his request in January on grounds that his cancer was Stage 3 and not Stage 4, a prerequisite for medical parole to be considered.
He then asked the court to review the minister's decision.
"The applicant has made out a case for placement on medical parole. The applicant is placed on medical parole with immediate effect," said High Court Judge Selby Baqwa, adding that the parole board would determine his release conditions.
Derby-Lewis, who escaped the death penalty when capital punishment was abolished, has served over 20 years in prison.
Hani's murder threatened to derail South Africa's transition from white minority rule to multi-racial democracy, leading to riots across the country and triggering fears of a civil war.
The justice minister had granted parole in January to apartheid death-squad leader Eugene de Kock, dubbed 'Prime Evil' after more than 20 years in prison.
De Kock was jailed for his role in the torture and murder of scores of black South African activists in the 1980s and early 1990s and was released by the minister "in the interests of nation-building and reconciliation".
(Writing by Olivia Kumwenda-Mtambo; Editing by James Macharia)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>Thailand says 300 &amp;#39;boat people&amp;#39; landed in recent weeks</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Thailand-says-300-boat-people-landed-in-recent-weeks</Link>
        <Description>BANGKOK (Reuters) - Around 300 &amp;#34;boat people&amp;#34; have landed on Thailand&amp;#39;s shores in recent weeks, Sek Wannamethee, director-general of the information department at Thailand&amp;#39;s Foreign Ministry, said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:20:08 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:20:08 PM
Thailand says 300 'boat people' landed in recent weeks
BANGKOK (Reuters) - Around 300 "boat people" have landed on Thailand's shores in recent weeks, Sek Wannamethee, director-general of the information department at Thailand's Foreign Ministry, said on Friday.
That was in addition to around a further 300 people who were already being held in temporary holding areas in the country, Sek said.
More than 3,000 migrants have landed in Indonesia and Malaysia since Thailand launched a crackdown on human trafficking gangs this month. About 2,600 are believed to be still adrift in boats, relief agencies have said.
The Thai crackdown made it too risky for traffickers to land migrants, prompting them to abandon thousands at sea with scant supplies of food and water.
The foreign ministry gave the numbers to clarify remarks made earlier on Friday by the country's Deputy Prime Minister General Tanasak Patimapragorn, who had said there were 600 new "boat people" in Thailand.
The Southeast Asian nation also shelters around 130,000 asylum seekers and refugees, Tanasak said earlier, many of whom have been in Thailand for years.
(Reporting by Amy Sawitta Lefevre; Editing by Alex Richardson)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>U.S. says China has placed mobile artillery on reclaimed island</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/US-says-China-has-placed-mobile-artillery-on-reclaimed-island</Link>
        <Description>SINGAPORE (Reuters) - The United States said on Friday that China had placed mobile artillery weapons systems on a reclaimed island in the disputed South China Sea, a development that Republican Sen. John McCain called &amp;#34;disturbing and escalatory.&amp;#34;</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:20:06 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:20:06 PM
U.S. says China has placed mobile artillery on reclaimed island
SINGAPORE (Reuters) - The United States said on Friday that China had placed mobile artillery weapons systems on a reclaimed island in the disputed South China Sea, a development that Republican Sen. John McCain called "disturbing and escalatory."
Brent Colburn, a Pentagon spokesman travelling with Defense Secretary Ash Carter, said the United States was aware of the weapons.
McCain, chairman of the Senate's Armed Services Committee, said the move would escalate tensions but not lead to conflict.
"It is a disturbing development and escalatory development, one which heightens our need to make the Chinese understand that their actions are in violation of international law and their actions are going to be condemned by everyone in the world," he said at a news conference in Ho Chi Minh City.
"We are not going to have a conflict with China but we can take certain measures which will be a disincentive to China to continue these kinds of activities," he said.
In Beijing, China's foreign ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying said she had no information on the weapons.
U.S. officials say Chinese dredging work has added some 2,000 acres to five outposts in the resource-rich Spratly islands in the South China Sea, including 1,500 acres this year.
It has released surveillance plane footage showing dredgers and other ships busily turning remote outcrops into islands with runways and harbours.
Carter called on Wednesday for an immediate halt to land reclamation in the South China Sea and was expected to touch on the issue of maritime security and freedom of navigation again on Saturday in a speech at the Shangri-La Dialogue security conference in Singapore.
China says the islands are in sovereign Chinese territory.
 Pentagon officials said efforts by China and other claimant countries to turn reefs into islands in the Spratlys undermines international law and raises questions about their future plans and intentions.
"It creates an air of uncertainty in a system that has been based on certainty and agreed-upon norms," said Colburn, the Pentagon spokesman. "So anything that steps outside of the bounds of international law we see as a concern because we don't know what the ... motivations are behind that. We think it should concern everyone in the region."
Asian military attaches and analysts said the placement of mobile artillery pieces appeared to be a symbol of intent, rather than any major development that could tilt any balance of power.
"It is interesting and a point to watch. But it should be remembered theyve already got potentially a lot more firepower on the naval ships that they routinely move through the South China Sea," one military attache said.
China claims most of the South China Sea. The Philippines, Vietnam, Malaysia, Brunei and Taiwan also claim parts of the vital trade route. All claimants except Brunei have military fortifications in the Spratlys.
(Reporting by David Alexander in Singapore, Mai Nguyen in Hanoi, Sui-Lee Wee in Beijing and Greg Torode in Hong Kong; Writing by Raju Gopalakrishnan; Editing by Nick Macfie)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Special Report - Russian fighters, caught in Ukraine, cast adrift by Moscow</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Special-Report--Russian-fighters-caught-in-Ukraine-cast-adrift-by-Moscow</Link>
        <Description>KIEV (Reuters) - From his hospital bed in the Ukrainian capital, Russian fighter Alexander Alexandrov feels abandoned by his country, its leaders and even the local Russian consul.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:15:06 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:15:13 PM
Special Report - Russian fighters, caught in Ukraine, cast adrift by Moscow
by maria tsvetkova
KIEV (Reuters) - From his hospital bed in the Ukrainian capital, Russian fighter Alexander Alexandrov feels abandoned by his country, its leaders and even the local Russian consul.
Alexandrov, 28, says he's a Russian soldier who was captured in east Ukraine after being sent there on active duty with Russian special forces to help separatists fighting Kiev. He said he was serving on a three-year contract. "I never tore it up, I wrote no resignation request," he said. "I was carrying out my orders."
Yet Russian President Vladimir Putin, in the face of widespread evidence to the contrary, has repeatedly said there are no Russian soldiers in Ukraine  only volunteers who have gone to help the separatists of their own accord.
So Alexandrov and Yevgeny Yerofeyev, another Russian who was captured with him, find themselves pawns in the deepest confrontation between Moscow and the West since the Cold War.
They believe they should be treated as captured servicemen. But Moscow will not admit they are any such thing, or that it has sent any soldiers into Ukraine to help wrest swathes of east away from Kiev's control. To do so would undermine Moscow's claims that the separatist uprising there is a spontaneous reaction by Russian-speaking communities against Kiev.
The Kremlin has described the two men as Russian citizens, and Russia's defence ministry has said they are former soldiers who left the military before they were captured.
Disowned at home, the two men stand accused by Ukrainian authorities of being terrorists.
In an interview from his bed, Alexandrov, wearing a hospital-issue green T-shirt and with several days stubble on his face, told Reuters he felt alone and trapped between these vast forces. He said the Russian consul in Kiev had visited him and Yerofeyev, but had been a let-down. The two captives had hoped Moscow would get them home in a prisoner exchange, but they said the consul had been non-committal.
"I asked him a few questions. There was no answer to them. He said that when he has the answers, he will come again and let us know what they are, said Alexandrov, whose leg was shattered in a gun battle.
The Russian embassy in Kiev had no comment on Friday. In an earlier statement it had described Alexandrov and Yerofeyev as Russian citizens detained in the Luhansk region and said they were receiving proper medical treatment. Embassy officials plan to visit the compatriots regularly, the statement said.
Ukrainian armed servicemen and officials in civilian clothes were present during the interviews Alexandrov and Yerofeyev gave to Reuters. Both Russian men made it clear they were active service members of the Russian military on the day they were captured. Alexandrov said he knew his military identification number off by heart: E131660.
He also said he fears for his relatives back in Russia. A few days ago, his wife, Yekaterina, appeared on Russian state television. Looking nervous, and talking in stilted phrases, she said her husband had quit the Russian military in December last year. That account was helpful to Putin's claims that only volunteer Russians have gone to Ukraine.
"They said I was no longer a serviceman," Alexandrov said. "It's a bit hurtful, especially when they do it through your family, through your wife. That crosses a line."
Alexandrov, who was captured on May 16, said he had been unable to get hold of his wife by telephone for nearly two weeks. She has not replied to his messages posted on social media accounts. A photograph of him with his wife stood on the table next to his bedside.
He said Yekaterina always used to pick up his calls, even before they were married, when sometimes he would call in the middle of the night. He asked to borrow a Reuters correspondent's mobile telephone so he could try calling her. Yerofeyev, also in a green T-shirt, his right arm in a bandage binding it to his torso, came into the room and watched.
Alexandrov dictated the number to the correspondent, and checked it was correct. With the phone in speaker mode, the call connected, and the ringing tone could be heard. But no one picked up.
"I'm really worried about my wife," he said. "Right now all this has fallen on her small, fragile shoulders."
Reuters was unable to contact his wife independently for comment.
CRIMINAL CHARGES
Ukrainian prosecutors say the two men will be charged with acts of terrorism, alleging they killed Ukrainians in combat. The soldiers have denied that, saying they did not fire their weapons.
If they had the status of soldiers fighting a war, international law would give them some protection from those charges; but they do not have that status since Moscow has said they were not acting on its orders.
"I can understand, of course, why they have turned their back on me as a serviceman, but I'm still a citizen of my country, said Yerofeyev, 30. At least don't turn your back on me as a citizen.
Asked about the two servicemen on Thursday, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said he had nothing to add to previous comments, when he had said they were ordinary Russian citizens who were being held prisoner.
"Everything that concerns servicemen, you should address your questions to the defence ministry," said Peskov.
An official answering the telephone in the defence ministry press service on Thursday evening said no one was available to comment. There was no immediate response to written questions sent to the ministry. Previously, a defence ministry spokesman had told Russian state media that Alexandrov and Yerofeyev had served in the military in the past, but were no longer serving when they were captured.
MURKY WAR
The accounts given by the two Russians of how they came to be in Ukraine paint a different picture, shedding light on the realities of a shadowy war that has killed thousands of people.
They said they serve in a unit of the main intelligence directorate of the Russian general staff, based in the city of Togliatti on the Volga River. The directorate, known by its Russian initials G.R.U., is one of the military's elite forces, usually used for highly sensitive operations.
According to Alexandrov, their unit of 200 men was sent into Ukraine on March 26. Before crossing the border, he said, they were instructed to surrender their dog tags and military identification. They were also told to swap their uniforms for mismatched camouflage fatigues to blend in with the separatist irregulars.
Once inside Ukraine's separatist-held Luhansk region, his unit provided reconnaissance support to the separatists, he said. Separatist irregulars did most of the fighting, he said, and on occasion came close to shooting the Russian forces by mistake.
"I think that probably they need to drink less. Half of them are ex-convicts."
He said the May 16 firefight in which he and Yerofeyev were injured was the first time they had been involved in combat during their mission in Ukraine. Alexandrov described how he was hit in the leg, and tried to crawl to safety. When Ukrainian soldiers approached him, he thought they would kill him, but instead they picked him up, carried him to a vehicle and took him to hospital.
A DILEMMA
In past cases when Russian citizens have been captured or killed in Ukraine, officials in Moscow have said they were on leave from the military and fighting as volunteers - or in one case that a group of soldiers had got lost and entered Ukrainian territory by accident.
The case of Alexandrov and Yerofeyev is not so easy to brush aside. On Thursday Ukrainian President Petro Poroshenko said bluntly: "These are special forces soldiers who killed Ukrainians, who were sent here. They are part of the regular Russian Federation military."
One Ukrainian soldier was killed in the firefight in which the two Russians were captured, Ukrainian soldiers who witnessed the incident told Reuters. However, a Ukrainian army colonel, whose unit was involved, said that none of his men had seen Alexandrov or Yerofeyev shooting anyone.
The case against the two men is being handled by the Ukrainian Security Service (SBU). It had no immediate comment on the case.
The SBU previously posted a statement on its website saying the two Russians were suspected of involvement in terrorist activity, but did not mention any specific evidence that either of them had been directly involved in killing Ukrainians.
Now, both Alexandrov and Yerofeyev are torn. They say they yearn to get home to their families  but they worry about how they can live in a country which, in their view, has disowned them, even though they were prepared to give their lives for it.
"It's scary. There, no one is going to be saying thank you to me, I don't suppose," said Yerofeyev when asked about going back to Russia. "I think that my biggest adventures will start when I get home."
(Additional reporting by Gabriela Baczynska, Tatiana Ustinova and Vladimir Soldatkin in Moscow, and Pavel Polityuk and Richard Balmforth in Kiev; Editing By Christian Lowe and Richard Woods)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Michael Jackson’s Neverland to go on sale for $100 million</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Michael-Jacksons-Neverland-to-go-on-sale-for-100-million-report</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON, May 29, 2015 (AFP) - The sprawling California property that was once the location of the‘king of pop’ Michael Jackson’s mind-boggling amusement park is going on sale for $100 million, the Wall Street Journal reported on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:13:00 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:22:53 PM
Michael Jacksons Neverland to go on sale for $100 million
A file photo shows an aerial view of the Neverland Ranch of late US pop star Michael Jackson in Santa Ynez near Santa Barbara, California, USA, 20 November 2003. - EPA
WASHINGTON, May 29, 2015 (AFP) - The sprawling California property that was once the location of the king of pop Michael Jacksons mind-boggling amusement park is going on sale for $100 million, the Wall Street Journal reported on Friday.
The late star built up his Neverland Ranch on 2,700 acres outside Santa Barbra to include zoo animals, numerous amusement rides and lavish gardens. It has 22 buildings on it, the paper said.
The zoo animals have been removed, save for a single llama, and the property has changed hands. Now called the Sycamore Valley Ranch, the Wall Street Journal reports that an investment firm renovated the property and several real estate agents are looking for a buyer at the cool-listing price of $100 million.
The property includes a massive six-bedroom main house, a movie theatre and stage.
Michael Jackson, considered by some to be the greatest pop artist of all time, wrote some of his top hits on the ranch.
The ranch was also the infamous location where Jackson invited children to visit and sleep over and where he was accused of molesting young boys.
He was never found guilty in court, but the charges engulfed Jackson in the mid-2000s before the singer songwriter died in 2009.
The Wall Street Journal reported that in order to avoid Jacksons passionate fan base, tours will not be given of the property.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>One Ukrainian servicemen killed in east Ukraine</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/One-Ukrainian-servicemen-killed-in-east-Ukraine</Link>
        <Description>KIEV (Reuters) - One Ukrainian serviceman has been killed and six other have been wounded in attacks by Russian-backed separatists in eastern Ukraine, a Kiev military spokesman said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:10:14 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:10:14 PM
One Ukrainian servicemen killed in east Ukraine
KIEV (Reuters) - One Ukrainian serviceman has been killed and six other have been wounded in attacks by Russian-backed separatists in eastern Ukraine, a Kiev military spokesman said on Friday.
Violence has fallen off significantly in Ukraine's east since a ceasefire was brokered in the Belarussian capital of Minsk in mid-February but government forces and separatists accuse one another of violations, with almost daily casualties.
Military spokesman Andriy Lysenko said at a briefing that separatists were keeping up regular attacks on government forces outside the rebel-controlled cities of Donetsk and Luhansk as well as near the port city of Mariupol.
(Reporting by Pavel Polityuk; Editing by Angus MacSwan)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Fighters battle Houthis in Yemen&amp;#39;s southern city of Aden</title>
        <Link>http://www.thestar.com.my/News/World/2015/05/29/Fighters-battle-Houthis-in-Yemens-southern-city-of-Aden</Link>
        <Description>ADEN (Reuters) - Heavy fighting erupted in southern Yemen near Aden airport on Friday when a Sunni Muslim militia attacked Shi&amp;#39;ite Houthi rebels in a push to drive Houthis from the district, residents and fighters said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Published:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:10:05 PM
Updated:                 Friday May 29, 2015 MYT 6:10:10 PM
Fighters battle Houthis in Yemen's southern city of Aden
ADEN (Reuters) - Heavy fighting erupted in southern Yemen near Aden airport on Friday when a Sunni Muslim militia attacked Shi'ite Houthi rebels in a push to drive Houthis from the district, residents and fighters said.
Saudi-led forces also made four air strikes on a military base near the airport, a source in the southern militia told Reuters.
A Saudi-led coalition began air strikes in Yemen on March 26 in a campaign to restore Yemeni President Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi to power. He fled in March, after Iranian-backed Houthi rebels seized the capital Sanaa in September and then thrust into central and south Yemen.
Aden is Yemen's commercial hub. Its airport has been closed since fighting began but its port provides sporadic access for desperately needed humanitarian aid to enter the country.
Houthis and forces loyal to former president Ali Abdullah Saleh are concentrated around Aden's districts of Khor Maksar, Crater and Moalla.
The fighting in Khor Maksar has killed four southern militia fighters and 15 Houthis so far, the militia source said.
Intense air raids by the Arab alliance were also reported overnight by residents of Saada province, which borders Saudi Arabia in northwestern Yemen. Raids also targeted a weapons storage site in Sanaa, said residents.
On Monday, Houthi fighters suffered their first significant setback in the south in two months of civil war when local Sunni militia ejected them from much of the southern city of Dalea, about 170 km (105 miles) north of Aden.
The Sunni militias, who call themselves the Southern Resistance, are a loosely allied group of fighters who took up arms against the Houthis.
U.N.-sponsored peace talks set to be held in Geneva this week have been postponed because of the heavy fighting.
(Reporting By Mohammed Mukhashaf; additional reporting by Mohammed Ghobari in Cairo; Writing By Maha El Dahan; Editing By Katharine Houreld and Angus MacSwan)
You May Be Interested
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
