<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Yahoo">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:49:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former House Speaker Dennis Hastert indicted on federal charges</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/former-u-house-speaker-hastert-indicted-federal-charges-212302057.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Former U.S. House Speaker Hastert indicted on federal charges
12 hours ago
View gallery
Former U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Dennis Hastert (R-IL) speaks during a news conference in
(Reuters) - Former U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Dennis Hastert was indicted on Thursday on federal charges, including for lying to the FBI, relating to an alleged effort to hide $3.5 million in payments to a person to conceal past misconduct.
The Illinois Republican, who left office in 2007, was charged with structuring the withdrawal of $952,000 in cash in order to evade the requirement that banks report cash transactions over $10,000, and lying to the FBI about his withdrawals, the U.S. Attorney's Office in Chicago said.
Each count of the two-count indictment carries a maximum penalty of five years in prison and a $250,000 fine.
Hastert, 73, was not available for comment, according to his office at the Dickstein Shapiro law firm in Washington where he is listed as a senior adviser.
According to the indictment, the unspecified misconduct involved payments to an unnamed individual who had been a Yorkville, Illinois, resident and had known Hastert for most of the person's life.
Before his terms in Congress, Hastert served three terms as an Illinois state representative and was a teacher at Yorkville High School in suburban Chicago for 16 years, according to a biography from Wheaton College where he graduated in 1964.
View gallery
Former U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Dennis Hastert (R-IL) announces that he will not seek a
According to the indictment, Hastert met with the person several times around 2010 and discussed past misconduct by the former lawmaker. Eventually, Hastert agreed to pay the person $3.5 million in compensation to conceal the misconduct, the indictment said.
Shortly afterward, Hastert began making cash payments to the individual, according to the indictment.
Hastert served as a congressman from suburban Chicago for more than 20 years before resigning from the House in November 2007, having lost the speaker's job when Democrats gained control of the House in the 2006 elections.
Hastert joined Dickstein Shapiro in 2008 as a senior adviser. Hastert resigned from the board of the exchange operator CME Group Inc on Thursday, the company said.
(Reporting by Eric Beech in Washington, Tom Polansek in Chicago and David Bailey in Minneapolis; Editing by Peter Cooney and Eric Beech)
Dennis Hastert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Bill Clinton as first gent? He'd break new ground — and maybe a little White House china</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/bill-clinton-as-first-gent-hed-break-new-ground-120118281561.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 13:16:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter expected to win re-election despite soccer corruption scandal</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/blatter-seeks-election-scandal-engulfs-fifa-065948369--sector.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>.
View gallery
FIFA President Sepp Blatter arrives for the opening ceremony of the 65th FIFA Congress in Zurich, Switzerland,
By Mike Collett and Brian Homewood
ZURICH (Reuters) - World soccer boss Sepp Blatter was expected to be re-elected on Friday, defying growing calls for him to step down in the face of corruption scandals engulfing the sport's governing body.
Addressing FIFA delegates at the body's annual Congress in Switzerland, where members will later vote to decide the organization's presidency, Blatter promised more transparency and urged members to remain unified.
He also said that FIFA would probably not be facing its present problems if Russia and Qatar had not been awarded the 2018 and 2022 World Cups, respectively.
"Today, I am appealing to unity and team spirit so we can move forward together," he said, in a low key-address that contrasted with his more defiant reaction on Thursday.
Blatter also sought to distance himself from the scandal, the biggest crisis FIFA has faced in its 111-year history.
View gallery
FIFA President Sepp Blatter makes a speech during the opening ceremony of the 65th FIFA Congress in 
U.S. authorities have accused top FIFA figures and sports executives of corruption, while Switzerland is separately investigating the award of the next World Cup finals to Russia and Qatar.
"We cannot watch everyone all the time. We have 1.6 billion people directly or indirectly touched by our game," Blatter said.
He recalled that the Russian and Qatar awards were announced together in 2010 and "if two other countries had emerged from the envelope I don't think we would have these problems today".
His opening address was briefly interrupted by a female protester waving a Palestinian flag and shouting at Blatter before being removed. The Palestinians are seeking to have Israel suspended from FIFA at the Congress.
Blatter, who has been heavily criticized for not doing enough to combat corruption in FIFA, is being challenged by Jordanian Prince Ali bin Al Hussein for the most powerful job in soccer.
View gallery
FIFA President Sepp Blatter leaves the stage after making a speech during the opening ceremony of th
Anger within Europe's powerful regional soccer body UEFA and other members over the damage allegations of bribery and corruption are doing to FIFA is unlikely to be enough to topple the 79-year-old Swiss, who is backed by the Asian and African confederations and many Latin American states.
English Football Association chairman Greg Dyke said England would support a possible boycott of the 2018 World Cup if Blatter was re-elected president of FIFA.
But the numbers appear to be in Blatter's favor, despite some countries saying they were switching allegiance and predicting that the scandal would finish Blatter as FIFA chief.
Most of the developing world in Africa, Asia and parts of Central America and the Caribbean are reluctant to vote for change in FIFA leadership given that the organization guarantees them annual grants and bonus payments in World Cup years.
Kuwait's Sheikh Ahmad Al-Fahad Al-Sabah, one of the most powerful men in world sport, said Blatter is the right man for the job and should be re-elected.
View gallery
FIFA President Sepp Blatter arrives for the opening ceremony of the 65th FIFA Congress in Zurich, Sw
"FIFA should have a leader with a lot of experience," the FIFA executive committee member told Reuters at Zurich's Baur au Lac hotel, where seven FIFA executives were arrested on Wednesday.
On Friday, New Zealand Football said it would vote for 39-year-old Prince Ali despite a previous unanimous commitment from countries in the Oceania Football Confederation in January to back Blatter. Canada also said it would not support Blatter.
INVESTIGATIONS WIDEN
Nine soccer officials and five sports media and promotions executives have been charged by U.S. prosecutors with corruption the authorities said involved more than $150 million in bribes.
Swiss authorities also announced a criminal investigation into the awarding of the next two World Cup tournaments, which are being hosted in Russia in 2018 and Qatar in 2022.
View gallery
FBI agents bring out boxes after an operation inside the CONCACAF (Confederation of North, Central A
Both countries deny any suggestion of wrongdoing over their bids to host one of the world's top sporting events, and Russian President Vladimir Putin has accused the United States of meddling in an effort to prevent the re-election of Blatter.
Adding to the pressure on FIFA and Blatter, there are growing concerns from major sponsors, many of whom have solidly backed the organization despite nearly 20 years of bribery and corruption allegations.
German sportswear company Adidas said FIFA should do more to establish transparent compliance standards. Anheuser-Busch InBev, whose Budweiser brand is a sponsor of the 2018 World Cup, said it was closely monitoring developments.
Credit card company Visa Inc urged immediate reforms.
"It is important that FIFA makes changes now so that the focus remain on these going forward. Should FIFA fail to do so, we have informed them that we will reassess our sponsorship," it said in a strongly worded statement.
View gallery
A combination photo shows eight of the nine football officials indicted for corruption charges in th
Coca-Cola Co, another sponsor, said the charges had "tarnished the mission and ideals of the FIFA World Cup and we have repeatedly expressed our concerns about these serious allegations".
The corruption scandal is unlikely to go away soon, as investigations into wrongdoing widen.
A judge in Argentina ordered the arrest of three businessmen accused of conspiring to obtain lucrative media rights contracts from regional soccer federations through the payment of up to $110 million in bribes.
In Brazil, the Senate, led by former national soccer star Romario, now a legislator, moved to open a formal inquiry into bribes that authorities said were paid to obtain contracts with the Brazilian Soccer Federation.
The Miami-based Confederation of North, Central American and Caribbean Association Football (CONCACAF) president Jeffrey Webb, who was among those arrested, has been provisionally dismissed from his role, the confederation said on Thursday.
(Story corrects reference to Qatar, not Kuwait, as Cup hosts in second bullet point before headline)
(Writing by Mike Collett-White and Giles Elgood; Editing by Peter Graff)
Sepp Blatter
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 12:28:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds seek safety from Texas floods, severe weather kills 17</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/hundreds-seek-safety-texas-floods-severe-weather-kills-023616710.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Hundreds seek safety from Texas floods, severe weather kills 17
By Jon Herskovitz 1 hour ago

.
View gallery
Amy Gilmour, a volunteer from San Antonio, Texas, walks past a pile of debris, which included parts of
By Jon Herskovitz
AUSTIN, Texas (Reuters) - Hundreds of people fled areas near Texas rivers that overflowed their banks on Thursday as the state reeled from severe storms this week that killed at least 17 people, flooded cities and set a record for the wettest month.
The National Weather Service issued a flash flood watch stretching from south of San Antonio to Dallas, through Oklahoma, where severe weather this week killed an additional six people, and into Kansas. Thunderstorms pelted large parts of the affected region.
Teams worked overnight to rescue people affected by the flood waters. Officials said Travis County firefighters saved 21 people from a drifting houseboat while Johnson County emergency workers rescued 14 drivers and residents. No injuries were reported among them.
The city of Wharton, about 60 miles (100 km) southwest of Houston, issued a voluntary evacuation notice for about 300 homes along the Colorado River, where water was expected to rise through Friday.
The Brazos River flooded about 30 miles (50 km) west of Fort Worth and was expected to crest on Thursday evening. Hundreds left their homes on Wednesday as the waterway began breaching its banks, Parker County officials said.
View gallery
Amy Gilmour describes how the Blanco River crested at a record 43 feet during the Memorial Day weeke
State climatologist John Nielsen-Gammon said the average rainfall across the state was 7.54 inches (19 cm) in May, breaking the record of 6.66 inches (17 cm) set in June 2004, according to records that date to 1895.
"It has been ridiculous," Nielsen-Gammon said.
The body of a man was found on the banks of the Blanco River in San Marcos, authorities said on Thursday, bringing the number of fatalities to at least 17.
The man, who was discovered among flood debris, was not yet identified, according to Hays County officials.
The body of a boy was recovered on Wednesday near San Marcos, Hays County officials said. The boy was thought to have been swept away in Blanco River floods that ripped houses off their foundations.
Volunteers gather in a shopping center parking lot before dispersing to help with flood relief effor
The new storms could hinder rescue workers searching for those washed away along the river.
"We are not expecting another surge of the river, but it is going to shift debris piles," Kharley Smith, the county's emergency management coordinator, told a news conference.
President Barack Obama has pledged federal support and said the government had been working with local officials.
"They appear to have the assets they need at this stage to respond, but there's going to be a lot of rebuilding," Obama said in Miami on Thursday during a tour of the National Hurricane Center.
There was no damage estimate available for Texas, which has a $1.4 trillion-a-year economy and is the country's leading domestic source of energy.
(Additional reporting by Jim Forsyth in San Antonio and Roberta Rampton in Miami, Editing by Angus MacSwan)
National Weather Service
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 11:11:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>7.0 magnitude quake strikes offshore Alaska: USGS</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/6-9-magnitude-quake-strikes-offshore-alaska-usgs-071917408.html</Link>
        <Description>(Reuters) - An earthquake with a magnitude of 7.0 struck off the southwest coast of Alaska late on Thursday, the U.S. Geological Survey reported. The USGS said the quake's epicenter was 104 km (64 miles) south-southeast of Ugashik and 61.7 km deep. The Pacific Tsunami Warning Center said that based on its available data, no tsunami was expected.</Description>
        <MainBody>Content preferences
Done
(Reuters) - An earthquake with a magnitude of 7.0 struck off the southwest coast of Alaska late on Thursday, the U.S. Geological Survey reported.
The USGS said the quake's epicenter was 104 km (64 miles) south-southeast of Ugashik and 61.7 km deep. The agency upgraded the temblor to a 7.0 after initially stating it was slightly weaker.
The Pacific Tsunami Warning Center said that based on its available data, no tsunami was expected.
The USGS said the quake was unlikely to cause casualties and notable damage, and there were no immediate reports of such.
The area near the quake, centered some 400 miles (643 km) southwest of Anchorage, is lightly populated, according to the USGS.
(Reporting by John Stonestreet in London and Curtis Skinner in San Francisco; Editing by Mark Heinrich)
U.S. Geological Survey
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:44:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FBI launches probe into theft of U.S. taxpayer information</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/fbi-launches-probe-theft-u-taxpayer-information-174426501.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FBI launches probe into theft of U.S. taxpayer information
17 hours ago
.
View gallery
A general view of the U.S. Internal Revenue Service (IRS) building in Washington May 27, 2015. REUTERS/Jonathan
View gallery
United States Internal Revenue Service Commissioner John Koskinen appears before a House Oversight a
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The FBI said on Thursday it had begun looking into the illegal access of the tax-return information of about 100,000 people disclosed by the Internal Revenue Service earlier this week.
"The FBI has opened an investigation into the recently reported incident at the Internal Revenue Service and is working with our interagency partners to determine the nature and scope of this matter," a spokesman said.
IRS Commissioner John Koskinen said Tuesday cyber criminals had sought to gain access to personal tax information 200,000 times from February to May, and were successful in about half of those attempts.
The FBI spokesman said individuals alerted to the illegal access of information should report "any suspected instances of identify theft" to the FBI's Crime Complaint Center at the website www.ic3.gov.
On Tuesday, the Senate Finance Committee is scheduled to hear testimony about the incident from Koskinen and J. Russell George, the Treasury Department's inspector general for tax administration.
(Reporting by Lindsay Dunsmuir; Editing by Richard Cowan and Bernadette Baum)
Internal Revenue Service
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 06:51:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>National Spelling Bee ends in tie for 2nd year in a row</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/familiar-faces-among-top-49-national-spelling-bee-140725494.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>National Spelling Bee ends in tie for 2nd year in a row
By BEN NUCKOLS 7 hours ago

National spelling bee ends in tie for 2nd year in row

National spelling bee ends in tie for 2nd year in row
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
National spelling bee ends in tie for 2nd year in row
 Replay video
Nebraska Death Penalty Repeal Faces Challenge

Android&amp;#39;s next version to offer new ways to fetch information, pay merchants, protect privacy. (May 28)
Load More
OXON HILL, Md. (AP)  They couldn't be rattled. They couldn't be denied. Gokul Venkatachalam and Vanya Shivashankar had worked too hard and come close too many times not to win the Scripps National Spelling Bee.
So they shared the title on Thursday, making history in two different ways.
The bee hadn't ended in a tie for 52 years  until last year. Now it's happened for an unprecedented two years running.
Vanya, 13, of Olathe, Kansas, is the first sibling of a past champion to win. Her sister, Kavya, won in 2009.
Vanya's final word was "scherenschnitte," which means the art of cutting paper into decorative designs. After being informed he'd be the co-champion if he got the next word right, Gokul didn't even bother to ask the definition before spelling "nunatak." For the record, it means a hill or mountain completely surrounded by glacial ice.
"I knew it right away," he said. "I didn't want to keep everyone waiting."
View gallery
Vanya Shivashankar (L) of Olathe, Kansas, and Gokul Venkatachalam, St. Louis Missouri lift the troph
Gokul, 14, of Chesterfield, Missouri, finished third last year, behind the two co-champions. He had a gruff onstage demeanor, confirming a word's roots and definition before chugging through the letters as if he had dinner plans.
Underneath his blue-and-white button-down shirt, Gokul wore the jersey of his idol, LeBron James.
"I wasn't nervous," he said.
Gokul hopes to attend Stanford and become an entrepreneur or stockbroker. But his immediate priority is to watch the NBA Finals.
While Gokul wowed the crowd with his machinelike efficiency, Vanya has been the darling of the bee since she made her debut as a vivacious 9-year-old in 2010. Also an actress, she was poised and graceful, smiling and nodding when she got a word she knew instantly  which was nearly every time.
View gallery
Dev Jaiswal, 13, of Jackson, Miss. reacts as he correctly spelled "boucl" during the semi
Both are eighth-graders, so it was their last chance. Vanya was competing in the bee for the fifth and final time. Her sister, Kavya  now a sophomore at Columbia University  competed four times, which means the Shivashankar family has made the trip nine of the past 10 years.
"I'm so, so proud and in awe of my sister," Kavya said.
Vanya, who also acts and plays the tuba and piano, dedicated her victory to her late grandmother, who died in 2013.
"Everything takes hard work and passion," Vanya said. "That's definitely what I put in and I know Gokul put that into this endeavor as well."
Vanya aspires to be a cardiac surgeon. In the meantime, she hopes to devote more time to acting and persuade her family to take a Caribbean cruise this summer.
Ten spellers advancing to the finals of the 2015 Scripps National Spelling Bee, stand on stage toget
"It's definitely going to be weird not doing spelling in high school," she said.
Proving their superiority over even their toughest competitors, Vanya and Gokul went head-to-head for 10 rounds before the list of 25 championship words was exhausted.
The words included: bouquetire, caudillismo, thamakau, scytale, Bruxellois and pyrrhuloxia. Vanya appeared to struggle only with the Fijian-derived thamaku, which is a type of outrigger canoe.
"It was on our list," said Mirle Shivashankar, Vanya's father and spelling coach. "But I couldn't remember it."
Before the bee began, executive director Paige Kimble predicted it would be another 50 years before it ended in a tie. Now she's thinking differently.
View gallery
Ankita Vadiala, 13, of Manassas, Va. reacts as she correctly spells "improvisatrice" durin
"I think it's time to consider that the bee may be entering a new era where the level of competition is so intense that we need to entertain this as a possibility every year," she said.
The last 10 winners of the bee, and 14 of the past 18, have been of Indian descent, a run of dominance that began in 1999 with Nupur Lala's victory, which was later featured in the documentary "Spellbound."
Vanya and Gokul each will receive more than $37,000 in cash and prizes, and while they held up the trophy together as they were being showered with confetti, each will get one to take home. Fourteen-year-old Cole Shafer-Ray of Norman, Oklahoma, making his first appearance in the finals, finished third.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 06:28:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Psychiatrist: Colorado shooter knew what he was doing</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/theater-shooting-prosecutors-build-case-holmes-sane-063454947.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Japan Meteorological Agency warns more eruptions are expected from southern Japanese volcano, as population evacuates. Rough Cut (no reporter narration).
Load More
CENTENNIAL, Colo. (AP)  The man who killed 12 moviegoers and wounded scores of others in a suburban Denver theater was mentally ill but legally sane, a court-appointed psychiatrist testified Thursday.
Prosecutors called Dr. William Reid to testify as they meticulously painted a portrait of James Holmes as a calculating if unstable killer  an image that defense attorneys will then try to destroy with their own complex narrative.
Holmes pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity. Jurors have the final decision, and Judge Carlos A. Samour Jr. has repeatedly told them they may ignore all the expert testimony if they wish. The case turns on legal subtleties, presenting a challenge for laypeople that was clear as soon as Reid gave his central opinion from the witness stand Thursday.
Reid, who interviewed a medicated Holmes two years after the shooting, declared that whatever mental illness Holmes had, "it did not prevent him from forming intent and knowing the consequences of what he was doing."
The defense quickly asked to speak to the judge and requested a mistrial, but their arguments weren't audible. Samour denied the request.
Reid acknowledged that much had changed between the attack and his interview. He said Holmes suffered a "physical and mental breakdown" in November 2012, five months after his arrest, when he was treated at a Denver hospital and began taking anti-psychotic and other medications.
Holmes Trial Sparks Survivor Nightmares Play video
Reid said that in order to get a picture of Holmes at the time of the shooting, he spent 300 hours reading reports from other mental health experts who had examined Holmes, talking to the defendant's friends and parents and watching videotapes of him in jail in the days immediately after the attack.
Jurors saw and heard some of Reid's videotaped interviews with Holmes on Thursday. In one segment, Holmes tells Reid he sometimes cries before he goes to bed because he regrets the shooting.
Holmes had just dropped out of a graduate neuroscience program before the attack. Because he pleaded insanity, prosecutors have to prove he was sane, and therefore guilty, at the time of the attack. Prosecutors want him executed, not sent to a mental hospital.
Officials at the state mental health hospital asked Reid to evaluate Holmes after Samour ruled an earlier state-ordered review of his sanity was flawed. On the opening day of the trial, District Attorney George Brauchler said both Reid and Dr. Jeffrey Metzner, who conducted the first evaluation in December 2013, had determined Holmes was legally sane.
While denying the defense request for a mistrial Thursday, Samour acknowledged Reid came close to offering an opinion not simply on whether Holmes was capable of understanding right from wrong, as he is legally allowed to do, but strayed into an area that is up to the jury  deciding the defendant's exact state of mind on the night of the massacre.
View gallery
FILE - In this June 4, 2013, file photo Aurora theater shooting suspect James Holmes appears in cour
After a break to discuss defense objections to Reid's testimony and how best to explain Colorado law on insanity, jurors were brought back in and the judge repeated instructions he has given them previously. He said the statute defines a defendant as insane if he or she was so mentally diseased or deficient at the time of committing a crime as to be incapable of telling right from wrong, or of forming a culpable state of mind. Samour also told jurors that the measure of right and wrong is determined by society, not individuals.
Brauchler then asked Reid "to be precise" about his findings. The psychiatrist gave the briefest possible responses, but his conclusion was the same.
Did Holmes have a serious mental illness? "Yes."
Despite that illness, did Holmes have "the capacity to know right from wrong" on July 19 and 20, 2012, the night of the attack? "Yes."
Did Holmes have the capacity to form the intent to act after deliberation, and to act knowingly? "Yes."
And did Holmes meet the legal definition of sanity? "Yes."
Earlier this week, prosecutors showed jurors a notebook in which Holmes, before the attack, described his mind as "broken" and sketched out his choices as he saw them: mass murder or serial murder; attack a theater or an airport; use guns, bombs or biological warfare.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Google wants to store all your photos for free, forever</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/tech/google-wants-to-store-all-your-photos-for-free-120120559004.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:00:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chicago’s heart of mercy for the disabled</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/chicago-s-heart-of-mercy-for-the-disabled-170042234.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Done

Nestled away in a northern Chicago suburb, among tree-lined streets, white picket fences and perfectly manicured lawns, is a 31-acre complex known as Misericordia . Misericordia, whose name means heart of mercy in Latin , is home to more than 600 children and adults with a wide range of physical and mental disabilities.

Sister Rosemary, a Catholic nun and devout caregiver, runs Misericordia. She has ushered in a change in care for the disabled thats being noticed around the country as religious and mental health leaders are visiting Misericordia to see what Sister Rosemary has accomplished.

When I came to Misericordia in 1969, we had 132 children under the age of 6, said Sister Rosemary. Sixty-nine of them were babies with Down syndrome. It was a time when professionals were telling parents, Get on with your life, theyre not going to amount to much anyway, you have other children to worry about. When I came, I came as a social worker and a teacher with that kind of background. I had no experience in special education, but the day I walked into Misericordia I thought, This is right  thank you God, this is right.

Sister Rosemary was one of the first caregivers who believed that caring for the disabled was about more than just providing the basics for these children  it was about making sure they enjoyed every minute of life.

Since taking over Misericordia in the late 60s, Sister Rosemary has expanded the campus into a sprawling home where those with disabilities have jobs, responsibilities and constant activities, from painting pictures to baking sweet goods. Every year, residents artworks are auctioned off at the Art Institute of Chicago, raising thousands of dollars.

Residents who need constant care are helped at a special facility that provides daily medically advanced therapy, ranging from sensory to aquatic, performed by a team of experts.

Sister Rosemary said that all of these programs are helping residents to live longer.

We developed really wonderful programs, and I see the children who are now adults today living at Misericordia, enjoying good lives, living very independent as they can, she said.

All these programs come at a cost. Misericordia is partly funded by the state of Illinois, but Sister Rosemary said that if Gov. Bruce Rauners new budget passes, the institution will be forced to increase its fundraising. Right now, Misericordia must raise $15 million in private funds annually to keep its doors open; if the governors budget passes, Sister Rosemary said that it would have to raise $21 million annually.

Despite the financial concerns, Misericordia continues to serve and grow as new homes are currently being built for the communitys aging population. Thats a group of residents who just a generation ago would not have grown to old age.

Years ago, a person with Down syndrome generally died when they were 12 or 15 years old, said Sister Rosemary. Today, doctors and teachers and therapists are all involved in their lives, so theyre living longer. Our oldest resident (with Down syndrome) is 68 years old.

Even though she doesnt have any children of her own, she feels as if all the residents at Misericordia are her children.

Its been a joy, said Sister Rosemary, as a religious sister to have this opportunity of being a mother to so many of them.
Health
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:54:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CDC investigating error that caused live anthrax shipments</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/army-chief-human-error-likely-not-cause-anthrax-142140710--politics.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>CDC investigating error that caused live anthrax shipments
By ROBERT BURNS and BRADY McCOMBS 11 hours ago

.
.
WASHINGTON (AP)  The U.S. Army's top general said Thursday that human error probably was not a factor in the Army's mistaken shipment of live anthrax samples from a chemical weapons testing site that was opened more than 70 years ago in a desolate stretch of desert in Utah.
Samples from the anthrax lot ended up at 18 labs in nine states and an Army lab in South Korea, leading more than two dozen people to get treatment for possible exposure.
Gen. Ray Odierno, the Army chief of staff, told reporters the problem may have been a failure in the technical process of killing, or inactivating, anthrax samples.
Odierno said the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention is investigating what went wrong at Dugway Proving Ground, the Army installation in Utah where the anthrax originated.
Officials said the government labs that received the suspect anthrax were at the Army's Edgewood Chemical Biological Center in Maryland and the Naval Surface Warfare Center in Virginia. The rest were commercial labs, which the Pentagon has declined to identify, citing legal constraints.
Some of the samples sent from Utah were also transferred to other labs in the U.S. by the Edgewood center, a research and development resource for nonmedical chemical and biological defense.
CDC spokesman Jason McDonald said four people at labs in Delaware, Texas and Wisconsin were recommended to get antibiotics as a precaution, although they are not sick. U.S. officials at Osan Air Base in South Korea said 22 people were being treated for possible exposure.
View gallery
FILE - This Jan. 27, 2010, file photo, shows the main gate at Dugway Proving Ground military base, a
Odierno said normal procedures had been followed, and that he was not aware that such a problem had surfaced previously at Dugway.
But there have been at least two other questionable incidents at the military post 85 miles west of Salt Lake City that has been testing chemical and biological warfare weapons since it was opened in 1942.
In 2011, Dugway was locked down for 12 hours because less than one-fourth of a teaspoon of VX nerve agent was unaccounted for.
Military officials launched an internal investigation, but the results were not released. Questions about the incident were not answered Thursday by military officials. Utah Gov. Gary Herbert said in 2011 that he met with the base commander and that the issue had been resolved to his satisfaction.
In 1968, Dugway came under scrutiny when 6,000 sheep died nearby. An Army report acknowledged that the nerve agent was found in snow and grass samples, The Salt Lake Tribune reported based on a report that was declassified in 1978. An Army spokesman said in the late 1990s that state agriculture scientists never identified the cause of death of the sheep.
Herbert said in a statement he's concerned about the incident and is working with the CDC to monitor the investigation.
View gallery
FILE - In this Sept. 18, 2013 file photo, Army Chief of Staff Gen. Ray Odierno testifies on Capitol 
Test facilities like Dugway are intended to develop ways to defend against biochemical warfare, which some fear could be used by terrorists, said Barry M. Blechman, co-founder of the Stimson Center, a nonpartisan global security group in Washington.
He doesn't know why it was sending anthrax and is perplexed at how the mistake was made.
"This is an accident that should never happen," Blechman said. "You should have double-triple-positive controls over any live, lethal agent."
Steve Erickson, of the volunteer military watchdog group Citizens Education Project, said the incident isn't cause for panic but suggests more oversight is needed.
"Ever since 9/11, there's been a propensity to throw money at biodefense," Erickson said. "When you allow these activities to blossom and burgeon over a period of years without any effective oversight, you are asking for trouble."
The Dugway Proving Ground was created by President Franklin D. Roosevelt. The site has gone through name changes and been closed and reopened several times.
It sits on 180,000 acres of flat, desert terrain. It's miles from any population base, but it has a village with an elementary and high school, medical clinic, a few restaurants, a theater, pool, gym, and homes and temporary lodging.
About 1,700 people work at Dugway, including a mix of military and nonmilitary scientists, chemists, microbiologists and engineers.
It is one of six Army equipment-testing facilities that also include sites in Maryland, Arizona, Alabama and New Mexico.
In one of the chemical testing buildings at Dugway, chambers are used to test chemical warfare agents, the Army says in online materials. An outdoor range tests smokes, obscurants and explosives.
___
Associated Press writer Brady McCombs reported from Salt Lake City.
anthrax
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Matt Bai: Hillary Clinton's not like the rest of us? Good!</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/democratic-presidential-candidate-hillary-clinton-120050918741.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:43:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pataki record: A Roosevelt Republican from N.Y.’s crime-crackdown years</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/the-george-pataki-record-a-roosevelt-republican-120112481156.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:34:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin accuses US of meddling into FIFA affairs</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/putin-accuses-us-meddling-fifa-affairs-093647908--spt.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Putin accuses US of meddling into FIFA affairs
By NATALIYA VASILYEVA 20 hours ago

Putin says FIFA arrests show US meddling abroad

Putin says FIFA arrests show US meddling abroad
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Putin says FIFA arrests show US meddling abroad
 Replay video
Barbra Scrivner: 21 Years From Home

View gallery
Vitaly Mutko, Russia's minister for sports arrives for a meeting of the European Soccer federati
MOSCOW (AP)  Russian President Vladimir Putin accused the United States of meddling in the affairs of soccer's governing body and hinted that its corruption investigation is part of an attempt to take the 2018 World Cup away from his country.
Putin said in televised comments Thursday that he found it "odd" that the FIFA probe was launched at the request of U.S. officials for crimes which do not involve its citizens and did not happen in the United States.
Corruption charges in the U.S. were announced Wednesday against 14 people, at least two of whom have American citizenship. Seven of the 14 were arrested Wednesday morning in Zurich ahead of a FIFA meeting and Friday's presidential election in which Sepp Blatter is expected to win a fifth term. Much of the money that allegedly changed hands went through U.S. banks, which is why U.S. officials were able to bring charges.
In a separate probe, Swiss prosecutors opened criminal proceedings into FIFA's awarding of the 2018 World Cup to Russia and the 2022 tournament to Qatar.
Putin said even if "someone has done something wrong," Russia "has nothing to do with it." He then tried to portray the probe as a U.S. attempt to go after dissenters, likening the case to the persecution of whistleblowers Julian Assange and Edward Snowden.
"Our American counterparts, unfortunately, are using the same methods to reach their goals and illegally persecute people. I don't rule out that this is the case in relation to FIFA," Putin said. "I have no doubt that this is yet another evident attempt to derail Mr. Blatter's re-election as FIFA president. We are aware of the pressure that he was subjected to in relation to Russia holding the 2018 World Cup."
Russian Sports Minister Vitaly Mutko, who is also a FIFA executive committee member and is in Zurich for the governing body's congress and presidential election, said Wednesday that his country welcomes the investigation.
Vladimir Putin
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>George Pataki announces 2016 presidential bid</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/pataki-announces-presidential-bid-120100166576.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:29:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. military mistakenly ships live anthrax to labs in nine states</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/u-military-mistakenly-ships-live-anthrax-labs-9-000151602.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>U.S. Army chief says no human error seen in anthrax mishap
By Phil Stewart 19 hours ago

.
View gallery
Spores from the Sterne strain of anthrax bacteria (Bacillus anthracis) are pictured in this handout scanning
By Phil Stewart
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. personnel working at an Army facility in Utah appeared to follow correctly all the outlined procedures to inactivate anthrax before they mistakenly shipped off live samples of the deadly bacteria, the Army's top general said on Thursday.
Army Chief of Staff General Raymond Odierno said investigators were now reviewing the procedures themselves to determine why the bacteria was not rendered inactive.
"The best I can tell there was not human error," Odierno told reporters, cautioning that his information was based solely on preliminary reports.
U.S. officials disclosed on Wednesday that U.S. Army facilities mistakenly shipped live anthrax bacteria to laboratories in nine states and an air base in South Korea.
The Pentagon has said there was no known suspected infection or risk to the public.
View gallery
Spores from the Sterne strain of anthrax bacteria (Bacillus anthracis) are pictured in this handout 
But four U.S. civilians have started taking preventive measures called post-exposure prophylaxis, which usually includes the anthrax vaccine, antibiotics or both.
Twenty-two personnel at the base in South Korea were also given precautionary medical measures although none have shown sign of exposure.
The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)  has begun an investigation of the incident. Odierno said the CDC was reviewing whether "we have to change the procedures that are in place."
Odierno did not offer specifics and said he did not know how long the procedures had been in place.
"But we definitely believe no one is in danger. We believe we followed all the proper procedures," Odierno said.
The mishap comes 11 months after the CDC, one of the government's top civilian labs, similarly mishandled anthrax.
Researchers at a lab designed to handle extremely dangerous pathogens sent what they believed were killed samples of anthrax to another CDC lab, one with fewer safeguards and therefore not authorized to work with live anthrax.
Scores of CDC employees could have been exposed to the live anthrax, but none became ill.
That incident and a similar one last spring, in which CDC scientists shipped what they thought was a benign form of bird flu but which was actually a highly virulent strain, led U.S. lawmakers to fault a "dangerous pattern" of safety lapses at government labs.
In the latest case, the Army's Dugway Proving Ground in Utah reported in March 2014 that gamma irradiation had inactivated the anthrax stock in question, and along with another Army facility, began shipments that continued through April 2015, a U.S. official said.
(Additional reporting by Sharon Begley in New York and James Pearson in Seoul; Editing by Frances Kerry)
Raymond Odierno
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jan 01 02:00:00 EET 1970</date>
        <title>Russia ‘reset’ architect to next president: Don’t try that again</title>
        <Link>http://www.yahoo.com/politics/russia-reset-architect-to-next-president-dont-120051660936.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Thank you for your patience.
Our engineers are working quickly to resolve the issue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 01:43:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Santorum faces daunting task in White House bid</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/rick-santorum-faces-steep-climb-second-white-house-072018684--election.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Rick Santorum announces second White House run
By STEVE PEOPLES and JOE MANDAK May 27, 2015 6:43 PM

Santorum Making Another Run For President

Santorum Making Another Run For President
Now watching
Next video starts in : 7 Play
Santorum Making Another Run For President
 Replay video
Pataki Announces 2016 Bid, Clinton Trust Falls

May 22 -- In this Bloomberg Politics/Purple Strategies Iowa focus group video, Democratic caucus participants discuss whether the Clintons are secretive and if Bernie Sanders can pull Hillary to the left.
Load More
CABOT, Pa. (AP)  Conservative culture warrior Rick Santorum launched a 2016 White House bid on Wednesday, vowing to fight for working-class Americans in a new election season that will test his influence  and focus on social issues  in a changing Republican Party.
The former Pennsylvania senator may have exceeded his own expectations by scoring a second-place finish in the race for the Republican presidential nomination four years ago. Yet as he enters a more powerful and diverse 2016 field, he may struggle even to qualify for the debate stage in his second run.
"I am proud to stand here, among you and for you, the American workers who have sacrificed so much, to announce that I am running for president of the United States," the 57-year-old senator said, flanked by factory workers and six of his seven children in a cinderblock warehouse near his western Pennsylvania hometown.
"The last race, we changed the debate. This race, with your help and God's grace, we can change this nation."
Santorum opens this political season as a heavy underdog in a race expected to feature more than a dozen high-profile Republicans  most of them newcomers to presidential politics. He is among the nation's most prominent social conservatives, having dedicated much of his political career to opposing same-sex marriage and abortion rights, while advocating for conservative Christian family values.
He mentioned cultural issues briefly Wednesday in remarks designed to broaden his appeal to working-class Americans. "As president, I will stand for the principle that every life matters  the poor, the disabled and the unborn," said Santorum, a Catholic.
View gallery
Republican presidential candidate and former U.S. Senator Rick Santorum is flanked by his daughter E
He ultimately won 11 states in the GOP's 2012 primary election after an unexpected and narrow victory in the opening contest in Iowa, where he emerged as a conservative favorite after touring the state's 99 counties in a pickup truck.
His road to relevancy this time won't be easy.
"It's going to be much more competitive," said Foster Friess, a prominent donor who was standing near the podium during Wednesday's announcement.
Santorum has acknowledged his challenges in 2016, but says his experience could pay dividends the second time around. Most of the GOP's recent presidential nominees, Mitt Romney and President Ronald Reagan among them, needed more than one campaign to win the nomination.
He faces considerable competition for his party's social conservatives in particular. The list of Republicans already courting religious voters includes former Arkansas Gov. Mike Huckabee, a Baptist pastor who won the Iowa caucuses in 2008, former Texas Gov. Rick Perry, Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal and Texas Sen. Ted Cruz. And like Santorum, former Florida Gov. Jeb Bush is a Catholic.
View gallery
Former U.S. Sen. Rick Santorum, left, stands with his wife Karen Santorum as he announces his candid
Polling suggests a shift in voter attitudes about the importance of social issues, particularly gay marriage, which has long been a defining issue for Santorum. Like others in his party, he has appealed to religious voters recently by criticizing what he calls President Barack Obama's "war on religious freedom," which includes the broader debate over whether private businesses can deny services to same-sex couples.
Santorum promised Wednesday to "fight for the freedom for you to believe what you are called to believe, not just in your places of worship, but outside your places of worship, too."
His longshot status may keep him out of presidential debates altogether.
Only those who place in the top 10 of national polls will be allowed to participate in the first Republican presidential debate in August, according to guidelines released by network host Fox News. Santorum is on the bubble.
While advisers suggest he will benefit from a donor network that has grown in recent years, questions remain about Santorum's ability to raise money as well.
View gallery
Former U.S. Sen. Rick Santorum announces his candidacy for the Republican nomination for President o
Friess, who previously gave more than $2 million to a pro-Santorum super PAC in 2012, said he would continue to support Santorum's White House ambitions, although he plans to avoid donating large amounts directly to the campaign or a supportive super PAC, both of which would disclose their donors.
"Any giving I'm doing is going to be lower-profile and less noticed," Friess told The Associated Press.
Santorum immediately launches a rollout tour that begins in Iowa on Thursday and Friday and moves to South Carolina on Saturday and Sunday. He is not scheduled to appear in New Hampshire, where voters typically don't favor candidates who focus on social issues.
A crowd of hundreds watched Santorum's announcement at Penn United Technologies, an employee-owned manufacturing company based in the western Pennsylvania county where Santorum grew up.
Wallace Cypher, 54, who lives a half mile away, said he's backing Santorum because he wants a true conservative to win the GOP presidential nomination.
"I think he'd be a whole lot better than what we've got in there right now," Cypher said.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
