<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="zeenews-india">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title> Hong Kong pro-democracy lawmaker barred from Malaysia</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/hong-kong-pro-democracy-lawmaker-barred-from-malaysia_1603904.html </Link>
        <Description>  Malaysia barred a veteran Hong Kong pro-democracy lawmaker from entering the country Friday branding him a &amp;#34;troublemaker&amp;#34;, days after student leader Joshua Wong was denied entry over fears he would threaten ties with China.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Hong Kong pro-democracy lawmaker barred from Malaysia
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 16:00
0
Comment
Hong Kong: Malaysia barred a veteran Hong Kong pro-democracy lawmaker from entering the country Friday branding him a "troublemaker", days after student leader Joshua Wong was denied entry over fears he would threaten ties with China.
Leung Kwok-hung -- known as "Long Hair" -- of the League of Social Democrats was turned away from Kuala Lumpur airport and sent back to Hong Kong.
Leung, 59, had been due to speak about Tiananmen Square and Hong Kong`s electoral reforms to local activists on Friday night with an open discussion on human rights scheduled for Saturday.
"We do not welcome troublemakers into Malaysia and that is why we deported him (Leung) back to Hong Kong. We only welcome peace-loving people," Inspector-General of Police Khalid Abu Bakar told AFP.
Khalid would not say whether Leung`s deportation was tied to Malaysia`s close ties with Beijing.
"The fiasco is unfounded and unnecessary," said Avery Ng, the vice chairman of the League of Social Democrats, who works closely with Leung.
"This act shows that the Malaysian government does not respect freedom of speech."
Hong Kong`s security minister Lai Tung-kwok said the city`s authorities would not intervene.
"We respect and we do not intervene in decisions made by immigration authorities in accordance with their law," he told reporters.
The Malaysia-based group that had arranged Leung`s visit said he had told them by phone that his passport had been seized by immigration officials at Kuala Lumpur airport and he had been detained for 90 minutes, before being sent back to Hong Kong on a Cathay Pacific flight.
"Leung said that the officials declined to explain why he was not being allowed into the country despite repeated demands," said Ng Yap Wah, a local committee member of the "June 4 Tiananmen Square Incident" group, which organised both Leung and Wong`s visits.
"I suspect... similar to the recent deportation of Joshua Wong, China could have put pressure on Malaysia to ban Leung from entering.
"We demand Beijing and Kuala Lumpur explain why the pair are not allowed into Malaysia," he said.
Wong had also been due to talk about the Tiananmen Square crackdown and the democracy movement but was denied entry at Penang airport Tuesday and sent back to Hong Kong.
The teenage face of Hong Kong`s pro-democracy "Umbrella Movement", Wong, 18, helped galvanise mass rallies which brought parts of the city to a standstill for more than two months late last year, calling for fully free leadership elections.
Malaysian police chief Khalid said Tuesday Wong had been blocked for his "anti-China" views.
Wong was also on a watchlist held by Malaysian authorities, reports said.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 16:00
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title> Court acquits femme fatale who toppled Czech PM</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/court-acquits-femme-fatale-who-toppled-czech-pm_1603902.html </Link>
        <Description>  A Prague court on Friday dropped abuse of power charges against a top aide to former Czech prime minister Petr Necas, whose centre-right government collapsed over a bribery and spy scandal in 2013.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Court acquits femme fatale who toppled Czech PM
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:58
0
Comment
Prague: A Prague court on Friday dropped abuse of power charges against a top aide to former Czech prime minister Petr Necas, whose centre-right government collapsed over a bribery and spy scandal in 2013.
Jana Necasova, formerly Nagyova, was charged with abusing military intelligence in 2012 to spy on Necas`s then wife Radka.
At the time, it emerged that Nagyova and Necas were having an affair. The scandal that ensued toppled Necas`s government and sparked a drawn-out political crisis.
The court, which ruled that Necasova`s actions did not constitute a crime, also acquitted three military intelligence officers charged with having ordered the spying.
Necas divorced Radka, his wife of more than 25 years with whom he has four children, in August 2013 to marry Nagyova just a month later.
The scandal triggered a political firestorm in the EU country of 10.5 million people and led to a snap election in October 2013.
The leftwing Social Democrats won the vote and formed a three-party coalition government with the centrist ANO movement of billionaire Andrej Babis and the smaller Christian Democrats party.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:58
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title> Army in retreat as rebels tighten grip on Syria`s Idlib</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/army-in-retreat-as-rebels-tighten-grip-on-syrias-idlib_1603899.html </Link>
        <Description>  Syrian troops retreated as regime warplanes bombarded Al-Qaeda-led rebel fighters on Friday, a day after the insurgents overran the last government-held city in the key northwestern province of Idlib.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Army in retreat as rebels tighten grip on Syria`s Idlib
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:56
0
Comment
Beirut: Syrian troops retreated as regime warplanes bombarded Al-Qaeda-led rebel fighters on Friday, a day after the insurgents overran the last government-held city in the key northwestern province of Idlib.
Opposition forces now control the vast majority of Idlib after Al-Nusra Front and its allies in the Army of Conquest captured Ariha and surrounding villages on Thursday in a swift assault.
It was the latest blow to loyalist forces who have been battling myriad groups of rebels for four years, after the fall of the ancient city of Palmyra to the Islamic State (IS) extremist group last week.
"The lightning offensive ended with a heavy pullout of regime forces and their allies Hezbollah from the western side of the city," said Rami Abdel Rahman, head of the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights.
"We can`t even say there were real clashes with the government in Ariha."
The Army of Conquest -- Jaish al-Fatah in Arabic -- had also seized villages around Ariha as regime warplanes bombarded the city.
The rebel alliance has won a string of victories in Idlib, including the provincial capital, the key town of Jisr al-Shughur, and a massive military base.
Government forces had retreated from these areas to Ariha, which Abdel Rahman said was heavily defended by fighters from Iran and the Lebanese Shiite movement Hezbollah.
But the city fell to the Al-Nusra-led alliance "in a few hours," he said. "The territories that are vital to protect for the regime are Damascus, Homs, Hama, and the coast," a Syrian security source said.
"Idlib is no longer part of these calculations, which explains the army`s rapid retreat," he told AFP.
President Bashar al-Assad`s regime still holds the Abu Duhur military airport and a sprinkling of villages and military posts in Idlib.
The province borders Turkey to the north, coastal regime bastions to the west, and the flashpoint province of Aleppo to the east.
Abdel Rahman said the regime was suffering from a serious lack of fighting forces and "could no longer afford any more human losses".
"Even with the support of Iran and Hezbollah, it cannot make up the soldiers," he said.
"If this continues, the regime might lose Aleppo."
Meanwhile in neighbouring Iraq, government and allied paramilitary forces pressed an operation aimed at severing supply lines of the Islamic State group in the western province of Anbar.
Clashes with IS in nearby Salaheddin left nine dead among the security forces and Hashed al-Shaabi, an umbrella for mostly Shiite militia and volunteers, an army lieutenant colonel and a source at Dujail hospital said on Thursday.
Anti-IS forces continued to close in on Ramadi, the capital of Anbar which jihadists captured on May 17, but no offensive to wrest back the city itself had begun.
Prime Minister Haider al-Abadi said in a recent BBC interview that IS had been using fleets of huge truck bombs packed with several tonnes of explosives, making it difficult for his troops to enter the city. Also on Friday, Iraqi officials said at least nine people were killed and dozens wounded when bombs ripped through two upscale Baghdad hotels.
The explosions, which struck the Ishtar and Babylon hotels, were heard across the city centre just before midnight (2100 GMT) on Thursday.
Iraq`s health minister said the country`s authorities have exhumed the remains of 470 people believed to have been executed by IS near Tikrit last year in what became known as the Speicher massacre.
"We have exhumed the bodies of 470 Speicher martyrs from burial sites in Tikrit," Adila Hammoud told reporters in Baghdad.
In June 2014, armed men belonging or allied to IS abducted hundreds of young, mostly Shiite recruits from Speicher military base, just outside the city of Tikrit.
They were lined up in several locations and executed one by one, as shown in pictures and footage later released by IS on the Internet.
The highest estimate for the number of people killed in one of the worst IS atrocities stands at 1,700.
The exhumed remains came from four burial sites, including one which contained 400 bodies, said Ziad Ali Abbas, the chief doctor at Baghdad`s main morgue.
"There were several layers of bodies all piled on top of each other," he said.
The Speicher massacre played a key role in the mass recruitment of Shiite volunteers to fight the Sunni Muslim jihadists.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:56
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title> 4 mild tremors rock Nepal</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/4-mild-tremors-rock-nepal_1603898.html </Link>
        <Description>  Tremors continued to rock Nepal following last month&amp;#039;s devastating earthquake as four aftershocks of over 4 magnitude were felt today in central and northern parts of the country.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>4 mild tremors rock Nepal
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:53
0
Comment
Kathmandu:Tremors continued to rock Nepal following last month's devastating earthquake as four aftershocks of over 4 magnitude were felt today in central and northern parts of the country.
A 4 magnitude tremor was recorded at 8.30 am with its epicentre located in Gorkha district, according to the National Seismological Centre in Kathmandu.
Two other 4.2 magnitude tremors were recorded at 12.37 am and 5.20 am with epicentres at Dolakha and Dhading districts.
A 4.8 magnitude earthquake was recorded at 12.30 pm with epicentre at Gorkha-Dhading, the NSC said.
So far, 289 aftershocks of 4 or above magnitude have been recorded since the April 25 earthquake.
The 7.9-magnitude quake which struck Nepal on April 25 and another having a magnitude of 7.3 on May 12 have left nearly 9,000 people dead and over 21,000 injured.
The two massive quakes have destroyed or damaged tens of thousands of buildings in Nepal.
PTI
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:53
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title> Man executed in China for rape of 26 minors</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/man-executed-in-china-for-rape-of-26-minors_1603891.html </Link>
        <Description>  A man in northeast China`s Gansu Province was executed for the rape and sexual abuse of 26 children, the Supreme People`s Court (SPC) said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Man executed in China for rape of 26 minors
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:46
0
Comment
Beijing: A man in northeast China`s Gansu Province was executed for the rape and sexual abuse of 26 children, the Supreme People`s Court (SPC) said.
Li Jishun, a former primary school teacher, was put to death by the Intermediate People`s Court of Tianshui City on Thursday night after the SPC approved the death penalty, state-run Xinhua news agency reported.
Li was found by the court to have raped or sexually abused 26 girls aged from four to 11 when he was a teacher from 2011 to 2012. He took advantage of those who were both childish and timid and committed his acts in dormitories or classrooms.
Considering the harm Li caused to the girls concerned and the extremely negative social impact, Li was given the most stringent punishment, said a judge from the SPC.
The SPC also published the details of four other cases involving sexual abuse of minors. In one case, a man raped five girls in a school dormitory. He was given a death sentence reprieved for two years.
The SPC said child sexual abuse cases are on the rise in recent years, with 7,145 such cases being handled by courts across the country from 2012 to 2014.

First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:46
0
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title> Thailand says 300 &amp;#38;quot;boat people&amp;#38;quot; landed in recent weeks</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/thailand-says-300-boat-people-landed-in-recent-weeks_1603888.html </Link>
        <Description>  Around 300 &amp;#34;boat people&amp;#34; have landed on Thailand`s shores in recent weeks, Sek Wannamethee, director-general of the information department at Thailand`s Foreign Ministry, said on Friday.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Thailand says 300 "boat people" landed in recent weeks
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:45
0
Comment
Bangkok: Around 300 "boat people" have landed on Thailand`s shores in recent weeks, Sek Wannamethee, director-general of the information department at Thailand`s Foreign Ministry, said on Friday.
That was in addition to around a further 300 people who were already being held in temporary holding areas in the country, Sek said.
More than 3,000 migrants have landed in Indonesia and Malaysia since Thailand launched a crackdown on human trafficking gangs this month. About 2,600 are believed to be still adrift in boats, relief agencies have said.
The Thai crackdown made it too risky for traffickers to land migrants, prompting them to abandon thousands at sea with scant supplies of food and water.
The foreign ministry gave the numbers to clarify remarks made earlier on Friday by the country`s Deputy Prime Minister General Tanasak Patimapragorn, who had said there were 600 new "boat people" in Thailand.
The Southeast Asian nation also shelters around 130,000 asylum seekers and refugees, Tanasak said earlier, many of whom have been in Thailand for years.

First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:45
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title> Pilot orders pizzas for grumpy passengers on delayed flight</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/pilot-orders-pizzas-for-grumpy-passengers-on-delayed-flight_1603885.html </Link>
        <Description>  Flight delays can make passengers grumpy but not when the pilot orders pizzas for them as a treat and that too on the runway.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Pilot orders pizzas for grumpy passengers on delayed flight
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:43
0
Comment
Washington: Flight delays can make passengers grumpy but not when the pilot orders pizzas for them as a treat and that too on the runway.
That is exactly what a Delta Airlines pilot did to calm angry passengers, when the airline's plane bound for Atlanta from Philadelphia was diverted to Knoxville, Tennessee, because of storms.
As torrential rains swept through Atlanta on Tuesday afternoon, some flights were delayed arriving at one of the world's busiest airport and Delta's home base.
Pizza delivered to the aircraft via baggage cart seemed to cheer everyone up, according to their social media posts.
"We are sitting on a runway stuck on a @Delta flight because of weather," tweeted @RileyVasquez. "So they're throwing us a pizza party!"
"Delta continues with class," tweeted @BillyTheKidWitt. "Stuck due to weather and the crew ordered everyone pizza. #deltaairlines."
The Philadelphia to Atlanta flight, which usually takes about two hours, landed three hours late in the evening, CNN reported.
Passengers on other delayed Delta flights reported similar feasts and it turned out that the pizza was the result of a broader edict.
"It's part of an effort company-wide when weather disrupts our operation to get food and beverages to delayed customers," Delta spokesman Morgan Durrant said.
It was a bad weather day for both Delta and Atlanta's busy airport.
Delta had 106 cancellations and 653 flight delays on Tuesday, according to Daniel Baker, head of Flightaware.Com.
Baker applauded the use of food to handle the potentially difficult situation. "A meal can go a long way to calming nerves and it raises the observation that there were far fewer incidents of air rage when airlines gave out food and cocktails for free!" he said.
Such gestures have been reported in the US earlier as well.
Last year in July, Gerhard Bradner, a Frontier Airlines pilot and captain of an Airbus A320, ordered 50 pizzas -- enough for the whole plane -- when severe thunderstorms forced the plane to divert to southern Wyoming. He had paid out of his own pocket for the pizzas then.
Brandner had said he was hungry when the plane touched down so he decided to call a pizza outlet. And instead of eating the pie himself, he ordered 50 pizzas.
PTI
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:43
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title> Volcano erupts on remote Japanese island, residents flee by boat</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/volcano-erupts-on-remote-japanese-island-residents-flee-by-boat_1603872.html </Link>
        <Description>  A volcano erupted on a remote Japanese island on Friday, blasting black smoke thousands of metres into the sky and forcing residents to flee by boat and an airline to re-route flights.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Volcano erupts on remote Japanese island, residents flee by boat
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:33
0
Comment
Tokyo: A volcano erupted on a remote Japanese island on Friday, blasting black smoke thousands of metres into the sky and forcing residents to flee by boat and an airline to re-route flights.
A pyroclastic flow of super-heated gas and rock rolled down the side of Mount Shindake, on the southern island of Kuchinoerabujima, and into the ocean.
A 72-year-old man suffered minor burns to his face but there were no reports of other injuries among the island`s 137 residents.
"It sounded like dynamite had exploded, and the house shook," one resident told TV Asahi.
Others described a smell of sulphur and clouds of smoke that blacked out the sky. Ash blanketed lower slopes and fell like snow on Yakushima, 12 km (7 miles) to the east.
Residents, many elderly and carrying boxes and bags,
fled by boat to the closest neighbouring island of Yakushima, an hour away, where they disembarked shortly before sunset. Several struggled to control excited dogs on leads.
"All I could bring were a few emergency goods. It was utter chaos," one man told Fuji TV. "I`m really worried about things back home."
Smoke shot more than 9,000 metres (29,000 feet) into the sky and officials warned of more big eruptions and urged "extreme caution".
All Nippon Airways said it would divert some flights as a precaution but it did not cancel any. Japan Airlines said it did not have any plans to change flights.
Kuchinoerabujima is about 130 km (70 miles) south of Japan`s southernmost main island of Kyushu, and 1,000 km (620 miles) southwest of Tokyo.
It was not clear if the eruption would affect the restart of Kyushu Electric Power`s Sendai nuclear plant, which on Wednesday cleared the last of the nuclear regulator`s safety hurdles, introduced after the Fukushima Daiichi nuclear plant disaster triggered by a March 11, 2011, earthquake and tsunami.
The company said the volcano posed no risk to the Sendai plant on Kyushu, and volcanologists agreed.
The island has seen several eruptions, including one in 1933 that killed eight people, but Mount Shindake was dormant for 34 years until last year.
Japan is one of the world`s most seismically active countries and there has been an upsurge in volcanic activity in recent weeks, which volcanologists said may be linked to the big 2011 earthquake that set off a tsunami that killed nearly 20,000 people.
In 2014, 63 people were killed when Mount Ontake in central Japan erupted while packed with hikers.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:33
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title> Muhammadu Buhari sworn in as president of Nigeria</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/muhammadu-buhari-sworn-in-as-president-of-nigeria_1603870.html </Link>
        <Description>  Muhammadu Buhari was sworn in as the new president of Nigeria on Friday in a historic ceremony after he won the country`s first ever opposition victory over a sitting president.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Muhammadu Buhari sworn in as president of Nigeria
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:31
0
Comment
Abuja:Muhammadu Buhari was sworn in as the new president of Nigeria on Friday in a historic ceremony after he won the country`s first ever opposition victory over a sitting president.
Buhari took the oath of office in the capital Abuja standing next to the man he defeated, former president Goodluck Jonathan.

First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:31
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title> Soldier surrenders after taking bus passengers hostage in Philippines</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/soldier-surrenders-after-taking-bus-passengers-hostage-in-philippines_1603867.html </Link>
        <Description>  A Filipino soldier who took more than 30 bus passengers hostage on Friday in north Philippines has surrendered, media reported.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Soldier surrenders after taking bus passengers hostage in Philippines
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:29
0
Manila: A Filipino soldier who took more than 30 bus passengers hostage on Friday in north Philippines has surrendered, media reported.
All passengers were safe, according to ABS-CBN, a major commercial television network in the Philippines.
The soldier, identified as 36-year-old Corporal Rene Prajele by the military, held the passengers on a tour bus hostage on Maharlika Highway in Del Gallego town in Camarines Sur. He was reported to have carried an M16 rifle.
The bus left Naga City on Friday morning and was bound for Metro Manila, the country`s capital, Xinhua news agency reported.
IANS
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:29
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title> Hong Kong pro-democracy lawmaker barred from Malaysia</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/hong-kong-pro-democracy-lawmaker-barred-from-malaysia_1603904.html </Link>
        <Description>  Malaysia barred a veteran Hong Kong pro-democracy lawmaker from entering the country Friday branding him a &amp;#34;troublemaker&amp;#34;, days after student leader Joshua Wong was denied entry over fears he would threaten ties with China.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Hong Kong pro-democracy lawmaker barred from Malaysia
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 16:00
0
Comment
Hong Kong: Malaysia barred a veteran Hong Kong pro-democracy lawmaker from entering the country Friday branding him a "troublemaker", days after student leader Joshua Wong was denied entry over fears he would threaten ties with China.
Leung Kwok-hung -- known as "Long Hair" -- of the League of Social Democrats was turned away from Kuala Lumpur airport and sent back to Hong Kong.
Leung, 59, had been due to speak about Tiananmen Square and Hong Kong`s electoral reforms to local activists on Friday night with an open discussion on human rights scheduled for Saturday.
"We do not welcome troublemakers into Malaysia and that is why we deported him (Leung) back to Hong Kong. We only welcome peace-loving people," Inspector-General of Police Khalid Abu Bakar told AFP.
Khalid would not say whether Leung`s deportation was tied to Malaysia`s close ties with Beijing.
"The fiasco is unfounded and unnecessary," said Avery Ng, the vice chairman of the League of Social Democrats, who works closely with Leung.
"This act shows that the Malaysian government does not respect freedom of speech."
Hong Kong`s security minister Lai Tung-kwok said the city`s authorities would not intervene.
"We respect and we do not intervene in decisions made by immigration authorities in accordance with their law," he told reporters.
The Malaysia-based group that had arranged Leung`s visit said he had told them by phone that his passport had been seized by immigration officials at Kuala Lumpur airport and he had been detained for 90 minutes, before being sent back to Hong Kong on a Cathay Pacific flight.
"Leung said that the officials declined to explain why he was not being allowed into the country despite repeated demands," said Ng Yap Wah, a local committee member of the "June 4 Tiananmen Square Incident" group, which organised both Leung and Wong`s visits.
"I suspect... similar to the recent deportation of Joshua Wong, China could have put pressure on Malaysia to ban Leung from entering.
"We demand Beijing and Kuala Lumpur explain why the pair are not allowed into Malaysia," he said.
Wong had also been due to talk about the Tiananmen Square crackdown and the democracy movement but was denied entry at Penang airport Tuesday and sent back to Hong Kong.
The teenage face of Hong Kong`s pro-democracy "Umbrella Movement", Wong, 18, helped galvanise mass rallies which brought parts of the city to a standstill for more than two months late last year, calling for fully free leadership elections.
Malaysian police chief Khalid said Tuesday Wong had been blocked for his "anti-China" views.
Wong was also on a watchlist held by Malaysian authorities, reports said.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 16:00
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title> Court acquits femme fatale who toppled Czech PM</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/court-acquits-femme-fatale-who-toppled-czech-pm_1603902.html </Link>
        <Description>  A Prague court on Friday dropped abuse of power charges against a top aide to former Czech prime minister Petr Necas, whose centre-right government collapsed over a bribery and spy scandal in 2013.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Court acquits femme fatale who toppled Czech PM
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:58
0
Comment
Prague: A Prague court on Friday dropped abuse of power charges against a top aide to former Czech prime minister Petr Necas, whose centre-right government collapsed over a bribery and spy scandal in 2013.
Jana Necasova, formerly Nagyova, was charged with abusing military intelligence in 2012 to spy on Necas`s then wife Radka.
At the time, it emerged that Nagyova and Necas were having an affair. The scandal that ensued toppled Necas`s government and sparked a drawn-out political crisis.
The court, which ruled that Necasova`s actions did not constitute a crime, also acquitted three military intelligence officers charged with having ordered the spying.
Necas divorced Radka, his wife of more than 25 years with whom he has four children, in August 2013 to marry Nagyova just a month later.
The scandal triggered a political firestorm in the EU country of 10.5 million people and led to a snap election in October 2013.
The leftwing Social Democrats won the vote and formed a three-party coalition government with the centrist ANO movement of billionaire Andrej Babis and the smaller Christian Democrats party.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:58
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title> Army in retreat as rebels tighten grip on Syria`s Idlib</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/army-in-retreat-as-rebels-tighten-grip-on-syrias-idlib_1603899.html </Link>
        <Description>  Syrian troops retreated as regime warplanes bombarded Al-Qaeda-led rebel fighters on Friday, a day after the insurgents overran the last government-held city in the key northwestern province of Idlib.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Army in retreat as rebels tighten grip on Syria`s Idlib
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:56
0
Comment
Beirut: Syrian troops retreated as regime warplanes bombarded Al-Qaeda-led rebel fighters on Friday, a day after the insurgents overran the last government-held city in the key northwestern province of Idlib.
Opposition forces now control the vast majority of Idlib after Al-Nusra Front and its allies in the Army of Conquest captured Ariha and surrounding villages on Thursday in a swift assault.
It was the latest blow to loyalist forces who have been battling myriad groups of rebels for four years, after the fall of the ancient city of Palmyra to the Islamic State (IS) extremist group last week.
"The lightning offensive ended with a heavy pullout of regime forces and their allies Hezbollah from the western side of the city," said Rami Abdel Rahman, head of the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights.
"We can`t even say there were real clashes with the government in Ariha."
The Army of Conquest -- Jaish al-Fatah in Arabic -- had also seized villages around Ariha as regime warplanes bombarded the city.
The rebel alliance has won a string of victories in Idlib, including the provincial capital, the key town of Jisr al-Shughur, and a massive military base.
Government forces had retreated from these areas to Ariha, which Abdel Rahman said was heavily defended by fighters from Iran and the Lebanese Shiite movement Hezbollah.
But the city fell to the Al-Nusra-led alliance "in a few hours," he said. "The territories that are vital to protect for the regime are Damascus, Homs, Hama, and the coast," a Syrian security source said.
"Idlib is no longer part of these calculations, which explains the army`s rapid retreat," he told AFP.
President Bashar al-Assad`s regime still holds the Abu Duhur military airport and a sprinkling of villages and military posts in Idlib.
The province borders Turkey to the north, coastal regime bastions to the west, and the flashpoint province of Aleppo to the east.
Abdel Rahman said the regime was suffering from a serious lack of fighting forces and "could no longer afford any more human losses".
"Even with the support of Iran and Hezbollah, it cannot make up the soldiers," he said.
"If this continues, the regime might lose Aleppo."
Meanwhile in neighbouring Iraq, government and allied paramilitary forces pressed an operation aimed at severing supply lines of the Islamic State group in the western province of Anbar.
Clashes with IS in nearby Salaheddin left nine dead among the security forces and Hashed al-Shaabi, an umbrella for mostly Shiite militia and volunteers, an army lieutenant colonel and a source at Dujail hospital said on Thursday.
Anti-IS forces continued to close in on Ramadi, the capital of Anbar which jihadists captured on May 17, but no offensive to wrest back the city itself had begun.
Prime Minister Haider al-Abadi said in a recent BBC interview that IS had been using fleets of huge truck bombs packed with several tonnes of explosives, making it difficult for his troops to enter the city. Also on Friday, Iraqi officials said at least nine people were killed and dozens wounded when bombs ripped through two upscale Baghdad hotels.
The explosions, which struck the Ishtar and Babylon hotels, were heard across the city centre just before midnight (2100 GMT) on Thursday.
Iraq`s health minister said the country`s authorities have exhumed the remains of 470 people believed to have been executed by IS near Tikrit last year in what became known as the Speicher massacre.
"We have exhumed the bodies of 470 Speicher martyrs from burial sites in Tikrit," Adila Hammoud told reporters in Baghdad.
In June 2014, armed men belonging or allied to IS abducted hundreds of young, mostly Shiite recruits from Speicher military base, just outside the city of Tikrit.
They were lined up in several locations and executed one by one, as shown in pictures and footage later released by IS on the Internet.
The highest estimate for the number of people killed in one of the worst IS atrocities stands at 1,700.
The exhumed remains came from four burial sites, including one which contained 400 bodies, said Ziad Ali Abbas, the chief doctor at Baghdad`s main morgue.
"There were several layers of bodies all piled on top of each other," he said.
The Speicher massacre played a key role in the mass recruitment of Shiite volunteers to fight the Sunni Muslim jihadists.
AFP
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:56
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title> 4 mild tremors rock Nepal</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/4-mild-tremors-rock-nepal_1603898.html </Link>
        <Description>  Tremors continued to rock Nepal following last month&amp;#039;s devastating earthquake as four aftershocks of over 4 magnitude were felt today in central and northern parts of the country.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>4 mild tremors rock Nepal
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:53
0
Comment
Kathmandu:Tremors continued to rock Nepal following last month's devastating earthquake as four aftershocks of over 4 magnitude were felt today in central and northern parts of the country.
A 4 magnitude tremor was recorded at 8.30 am with its epicentre located in Gorkha district, according to the National Seismological Centre in Kathmandu.
Two other 4.2 magnitude tremors were recorded at 12.37 am and 5.20 am with epicentres at Dolakha and Dhading districts.
A 4.8 magnitude earthquake was recorded at 12.30 pm with epicentre at Gorkha-Dhading, the NSC said.
So far, 289 aftershocks of 4 or above magnitude have been recorded since the April 25 earthquake.
The 7.9-magnitude quake which struck Nepal on April 25 and another having a magnitude of 7.3 on May 12 have left nearly 9,000 people dead and over 21,000 injured.
The two massive quakes have destroyed or damaged tens of thousands of buildings in Nepal.
PTI
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:53
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title> Man executed in China for rape of 26 minors</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/man-executed-in-china-for-rape-of-26-minors_1603891.html </Link>
        <Description>  A man in northeast China`s Gansu Province was executed for the rape and sexual abuse of 26 children, the Supreme People`s Court (SPC) said.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Man executed in China for rape of 26 minors
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:46
0
Comment
Beijing: A man in northeast China`s Gansu Province was executed for the rape and sexual abuse of 26 children, the Supreme People`s Court (SPC) said.
Li Jishun, a former primary school teacher, was put to death by the Intermediate People`s Court of Tianshui City on Thursday night after the SPC approved the death penalty, state-run Xinhua news agency reported.
Li was found by the court to have raped or sexually abused 26 girls aged from four to 11 when he was a teacher from 2011 to 2012. He took advantage of those who were both childish and timid and committed his acts in dormitories or classrooms.
Considering the harm Li caused to the girls concerned and the extremely negative social impact, Li was given the most stringent punishment, said a judge from the SPC.
The SPC also published the details of four other cases involving sexual abuse of minors. In one case, a man raped five girls in a school dormitory. He was given a death sentence reprieved for two years.
The SPC said child sexual abuse cases are on the rise in recent years, with 7,145 such cases being handled by courts across the country from 2012 to 2014.

First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:46
0
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title> Thailand says 300 &amp;#38;quot;boat people&amp;#38;quot; landed in recent weeks</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/thailand-says-300-boat-people-landed-in-recent-weeks_1603888.html </Link>
        <Description>  Around 300 &amp;#34;boat people&amp;#34; have landed on Thailand`s shores in recent weeks, Sek Wannamethee, director-general of the information department at Thailand`s Foreign Ministry, said on Friday.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Thailand says 300 "boat people" landed in recent weeks
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:45
0
Comment
Bangkok: Around 300 "boat people" have landed on Thailand`s shores in recent weeks, Sek Wannamethee, director-general of the information department at Thailand`s Foreign Ministry, said on Friday.
That was in addition to around a further 300 people who were already being held in temporary holding areas in the country, Sek said.
More than 3,000 migrants have landed in Indonesia and Malaysia since Thailand launched a crackdown on human trafficking gangs this month. About 2,600 are believed to be still adrift in boats, relief agencies have said.
The Thai crackdown made it too risky for traffickers to land migrants, prompting them to abandon thousands at sea with scant supplies of food and water.
The foreign ministry gave the numbers to clarify remarks made earlier on Friday by the country`s Deputy Prime Minister General Tanasak Patimapragorn, who had said there were 600 new "boat people" in Thailand.
The Southeast Asian nation also shelters around 130,000 asylum seekers and refugees, Tanasak said earlier, many of whom have been in Thailand for years.

First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:45
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title> Pilot orders pizzas for grumpy passengers on delayed flight</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/pilot-orders-pizzas-for-grumpy-passengers-on-delayed-flight_1603885.html </Link>
        <Description>  Flight delays can make passengers grumpy but not when the pilot orders pizzas for them as a treat and that too on the runway.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Pilot orders pizzas for grumpy passengers on delayed flight
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:43
0
Comment
Washington: Flight delays can make passengers grumpy but not when the pilot orders pizzas for them as a treat and that too on the runway.
That is exactly what a Delta Airlines pilot did to calm angry passengers, when the airline's plane bound for Atlanta from Philadelphia was diverted to Knoxville, Tennessee, because of storms.
As torrential rains swept through Atlanta on Tuesday afternoon, some flights were delayed arriving at one of the world's busiest airport and Delta's home base.
Pizza delivered to the aircraft via baggage cart seemed to cheer everyone up, according to their social media posts.
"We are sitting on a runway stuck on a @Delta flight because of weather," tweeted @RileyVasquez. "So they're throwing us a pizza party!"
"Delta continues with class," tweeted @BillyTheKidWitt. "Stuck due to weather and the crew ordered everyone pizza. #deltaairlines."
The Philadelphia to Atlanta flight, which usually takes about two hours, landed three hours late in the evening, CNN reported.
Passengers on other delayed Delta flights reported similar feasts and it turned out that the pizza was the result of a broader edict.
"It's part of an effort company-wide when weather disrupts our operation to get food and beverages to delayed customers," Delta spokesman Morgan Durrant said.
It was a bad weather day for both Delta and Atlanta's busy airport.
Delta had 106 cancellations and 653 flight delays on Tuesday, according to Daniel Baker, head of Flightaware.Com.
Baker applauded the use of food to handle the potentially difficult situation. "A meal can go a long way to calming nerves and it raises the observation that there were far fewer incidents of air rage when airlines gave out food and cocktails for free!" he said.
Such gestures have been reported in the US earlier as well.
Last year in July, Gerhard Bradner, a Frontier Airlines pilot and captain of an Airbus A320, ordered 50 pizzas -- enough for the whole plane -- when severe thunderstorms forced the plane to divert to southern Wyoming. He had paid out of his own pocket for the pizzas then.
Brandner had said he was hungry when the plane touched down so he decided to call a pizza outlet. And instead of eating the pie himself, he ordered 50 pizzas.
PTI
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:43
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title> Volcano erupts on remote Japanese island, residents flee by boat</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/volcano-erupts-on-remote-japanese-island-residents-flee-by-boat_1603872.html </Link>
        <Description>  A volcano erupted on a remote Japanese island on Friday, blasting black smoke thousands of metres into the sky and forcing residents to flee by boat and an airline to re-route flights.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Volcano erupts on remote Japanese island, residents flee by boat
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:33
0
Comment
Tokyo: A volcano erupted on a remote Japanese island on Friday, blasting black smoke thousands of metres into the sky and forcing residents to flee by boat and an airline to re-route flights.
A pyroclastic flow of super-heated gas and rock rolled down the side of Mount Shindake, on the southern island of Kuchinoerabujima, and into the ocean.
A 72-year-old man suffered minor burns to his face but there were no reports of other injuries among the island`s 137 residents.
"It sounded like dynamite had exploded, and the house shook," one resident told TV Asahi.
Others described a smell of sulphur and clouds of smoke that blacked out the sky. Ash blanketed lower slopes and fell like snow on Yakushima, 12 km (7 miles) to the east.
Residents, many elderly and carrying boxes and bags,
fled by boat to the closest neighbouring island of Yakushima, an hour away, where they disembarked shortly before sunset. Several struggled to control excited dogs on leads.
"All I could bring were a few emergency goods. It was utter chaos," one man told Fuji TV. "I`m really worried about things back home."
Smoke shot more than 9,000 metres (29,000 feet) into the sky and officials warned of more big eruptions and urged "extreme caution".
All Nippon Airways said it would divert some flights as a precaution but it did not cancel any. Japan Airlines said it did not have any plans to change flights.
Kuchinoerabujima is about 130 km (70 miles) south of Japan`s southernmost main island of Kyushu, and 1,000 km (620 miles) southwest of Tokyo.
It was not clear if the eruption would affect the restart of Kyushu Electric Power`s Sendai nuclear plant, which on Wednesday cleared the last of the nuclear regulator`s safety hurdles, introduced after the Fukushima Daiichi nuclear plant disaster triggered by a March 11, 2011, earthquake and tsunami.
The company said the volcano posed no risk to the Sendai plant on Kyushu, and volcanologists agreed.
The island has seen several eruptions, including one in 1933 that killed eight people, but Mount Shindake was dormant for 34 years until last year.
Japan is one of the world`s most seismically active countries and there has been an upsurge in volcanic activity in recent weeks, which volcanologists said may be linked to the big 2011 earthquake that set off a tsunami that killed nearly 20,000 people.
In 2014, 63 people were killed when Mount Ontake in central Japan erupted while packed with hikers.
Reuters
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:33
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title> Muhammadu Buhari sworn in as president of Nigeria</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/muhammadu-buhari-sworn-in-as-president-of-nigeria_1603870.html </Link>
        <Description>  Muhammadu Buhari was sworn in as the new president of Nigeria on Friday in a historic ceremony after he won the country`s first ever opposition victory over a sitting president.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Muhammadu Buhari sworn in as president of Nigeria
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:31
0
Comment
Abuja:Muhammadu Buhari was sworn in as the new president of Nigeria on Friday in a historic ceremony after he won the country`s first ever opposition victory over a sitting president.
Buhari took the oath of office in the capital Abuja standing next to the man he defeated, former president Goodluck Jonathan.

First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:31
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title> Soldier surrenders after taking bus passengers hostage in Philippines</title>
        <Link> http://zeenews.india.com/news/world/soldier-surrenders-after-taking-bus-passengers-hostage-in-philippines_1603867.html </Link>
        <Description>  A Filipino soldier who took more than 30 bus passengers hostage on Friday in north Philippines has surrendered, media reported.
 </Description>
        <MainBody>Soldier surrenders after taking bus passengers hostage in Philippines
Last Updated: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:29
0
Manila: A Filipino soldier who took more than 30 bus passengers hostage on Friday in north Philippines has surrendered, media reported.
All passengers were safe, according to ABS-CBN, a major commercial television network in the Philippines.
The soldier, identified as 36-year-old Corporal Rene Prajele by the military, held the passengers on a tour bus hostage on Maharlika Highway in Del Gallego town in Camarines Sur. He was reported to have carried an M16 rifle.
The bus left Naga City on Friday morning and was bound for Metro Manila, the country`s capital, Xinhua news agency reported.
IANS
First Published: Friday, May 29, 2015 - 15:29
TAGS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
