<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbsnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 20:03:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World's oldest man dies in Japan</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/worlds-oldest-man-guinness-world-record-holder-sakari-momoi-dies-japan/</Link>
        <Description>Retired educator and Guinness World Record holder succumbs to kidney disease in nation which boasts around 54,000 centenarians</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
TOKYO -- The world's oldest man, a retired educator from Japan, has died at the age of 112, an official said Tuesday.
Sakari Momoi died from kidney failure Sunday at a nursing home in Tokyo, said Saitama city official Aya Kato.
Momoi was born Feb. 5, 1903, in northern Japan's Fukushima prefecture, where he became a teacher. He later moved to Saitama, north of Tokyo, and served as a high school principal until retirement.
Momoi, who enjoyed Chinese poetry and drawing, was certified by Guinness World Records as the world's oldest man in August 2014, when he was 111.
Another Japanese man, 112-year-old Yasutaro Koide of Nagoya, succeeds Momoi as the world's oldest man, according to the Los Angeles-based Gerontology Research Group. Koide was born March 13, 1903.
One of the world's fastest-aging countries, Japan has about 54,000 centenarians.
The world's oldest person is Susannah Mushatt Jones of Brooklyn, New York, who celebrated her 116th birthday on Monday.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 20:16:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Prosecutors announce prison wishes for ex-Nazi guard</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/prosecutors-3-years-former-nazi-guard-oskar-groening/</Link>
        <Description>Oskar Groening, 94, should be convicted of 300,000 counts of accessory to murder for his Auschwitz role, prosecutors say; verdict expected this month</Description>
        <MainBody>BERLIN - German prosecutors are asking for 3.5 years in prison for a 94-year-old former SS sergeant who served at the Auschwitz death camp in Nazi-occupied Poland.
Oskar Groening has admitted guarding prisoners' baggage after they were unloaded from cattle cars onto the camp's ramps, and collecting and counting money stolen from the new arrivals and sending it to Berlin.
The dpa news agency reported prosecutors said in closing arguments Tuesday that his role helped the camp function, and he should be convicted of 300,000 counts of accessory to murder for those killed while he was there.
When his trial began in April, Groening said he felt moral guilt but it was up to the court to decide if he was legally guilty of a crime.
A verdict is expected this month.
Groening has told the Lueneburg state court in a statement read by his attorney that it was hard today to understand the blind obedience he had to the Nazi system even when witnessing the terrible atrocities perpetrated at the death camp in German-occupied Poland.
"There was a self-denial in me that today I find impossible to explain," Groening said, the dpa news agency reported. "Perhaps it was also the convenience of obedience with which we were brought up, which allowed no contradiction. This indoctrinated obedience prevented registering the daily atrocities as such and rebelling against them."
Left: Oskar Groening as a young man in an SS uniform in an undated photo; right: Groening in the dock of the court in Lueneburg, northern Germany, Tuesday, April 21, 2015.
AP
In his statement, Groening said even though he had known what was going on at Auschwitz, the personal stories of the co-plaintiffs during the trial had brought home the enormity of the atrocities.
"I can only ask my God for forgiveness," he said.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 18:17:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosives, detonators stolen from French military</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/explosives-grenades-and-detonators-stolen-from-military-site-in-france/</Link>
        <Description>"Professional" theft comes as France remains on high alert due to recent terrorist attacks</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
PARIS -- French authorities are investigating the theft of roughly 200 detonators plus grenades and plastic explosives from a munitions depot in southeastern France.
The thefts at the Miramas site, which is operated by a combination of military services west of Marseille, appeared to have occurred overnight from Sunday to Monday. The break-in comes as France has strengthened its security measures after two deadly attacks by extremists this year.
Top French security and defense officials were meeting Tuesday about the theft. A gendarmerie official said the thief or thieves appeared to have cut through a fence to enter the high-security depot. He was not authorized to speak publicly because the operation is ongoing.
Marseille prosecutor Brice Robin said in a statement that an investigation has started on charges of "theft with break-in carried out by a criminal group" and "fraudulent entry into a military compound."
Mayor Frederic Vigouroux of Miramas told the BFM television network the theft appeared to be "very professional."
Vigouroux told the AP he did not know precisely what was stolen, but said it was the first theft at the site. He said the outer fences were broken into, and that nine storehouses were affected.
"It wasn't cotton candy that was stolen," he said. "These are dangerous munitions. Everything is inherently dangerous."
CBS Radio News correspondent Elaine Cobbe reports that French Defense Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian has ordered a security review on military weapons depots following the heist at the site, which doesn't utilize any security cameras.
Cobbe reports that no one has suggested the heist is terror related, and nearby Marseille is a hotbed of violent gang crime.
However, the theft comes at a time when France is on a high level of alert for terrorism in the wake of recent attacks .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 19:07:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Shrinking pockets of normality in war-torn Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/shrinking-pockets-of-normality-in-war-torn-syria/</Link>
        <Description>The stepped-up U.S. airstrikes in Syria are meant to stop ISIS from taking new territory</Description>
        <MainBody>Shrinking pockets of normality in war-torn Syria
July 7, 2015, 7:16 AM
|The stepped-up U.S. airstrikes in Syria are meant to stop ISIS from taking new territory. The extremist group and other rebel fighters are battling for a bigger share of the country from Syrian government forces. Elizabeth Palmer reports from Latakia, one of the last areas under full government control.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 18:35:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>10 years after London bombings, threat still "real"</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/london-7-7-suicide-bombings-anniversary-al-qaeda-attack-terror-threat/</Link>
        <Description>As nation reflects on suicide blasts that killed 52 on trains and a bus, spy chief warns threat still posed by "tiny fraction of the population"</Description>
        <MainBody>Coordinated bombings by Islamic extremists on Britain's biggest transport network leave 52 people dead
Four British men inspired by al Qaeda blew themselves up on three London subway trains and a bus during the morning rush hour on July 7, 2005, killing 52 commuters. Last month's gun rampage in the Tunisian resort of Sousse was the deadliest attack on Britons since then.
The head of Britain's MI5 domestic intelligence agency said the country faced a "serious societal and security challenge" from "a tiny fraction of the population" willing to use violence against their fellow citizens.
MI5 chief Andrew Parker said the 2005 bombings "and other appalling acts are attempted by individuals who have grown up here but decided for whatever twisted reasons to identify their own country as the enemy."
"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly," Cameron said in a statement.
He said Britain would continue to fight extremism, protect the public and promote "the shared values of tolerance, love and respect that make Britain so great."
Cameron will lay a wreath at a monument to 7/7 victims Tuesday before attending a memorial service at St. Paul's Cathedral in London.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 17:00:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taliban bomber hits NATO convoy in Kabul</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/afghanistan-taliban-bomber-attack-nato-convoy-kabul/</Link>
        <Description>At least 2 people injured in attack as reports emerge of a 2nd blast followed by gunfire elsewhere in Afghan capital</Description>
        <MainBody>Some coalition troops will remain as advisors, but many are heading home as the year comes to a close
The Taliban claimed responsibility for the initial attack on the convoy. A NATO spokesman in Kabul, Col. Brian Tribus, confirmed the attack shortly before noon and said the coalition was gathering more information on the incident.
One of the wounded was an Afghan civilian while the second person was from the convoy, said Gen. Abdul Rahman Rahimi, the city's police chief who was at the scene of the blast. He did not elaborate.
In a text message to media, Taliban spokesman Zabihullah Mujahid said the attack targeted a "foreign car."
U.S. and NATO combat troops pulled out of the country at the end of last year, leaving full security responsibility in the hands of Afghan forces. The coalition has remained in Afghanistan in a training and support role.
Since then, the Taliban have stepped up attacks targeting Afghan officials, soldiers and local security forces.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:39:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek leader heads to Brussels looking for a new deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/greece-prime-minister-alexis-tsipras-brussels-bailout-deal-referendum-vote/</Link>
        <Description>Following referendum vote against deeper austerity cuts, no guarantees that Greece can secure infusion of cash to shore up flailing banks</Description>
        <MainBody>With the nation on the brink of default on its international loans, Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras called for a referendum and the governmen...
In a sign of compromise, Tsipras appointed a new finance minister to lead talks with creditors and replace Yanis Varoufakis, who clashed with his European counterparts.
Euclid Tsakalotos, a 55-year-old economist, has appeared more willing to engage with creditors. He will be tested as soon as Tuesday, in Brussels.
"I won't hide from you that I am very nervous and very anxious. I am not taking over at the easiest moment in Greek history," Tsakalotos said after being sworn in.
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras (L), Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos (C) and the new Greek Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos pose for the photographers at the presidential palace during the swearing in ceremony of the new finance minister Euclid Tsakalotos in Athens, Greece on July 6, 2015.
Getty
Greek banks are running out of cash even after the government placed  limits on how much depositors can withdraw. The ECB has been providing  emergency credit to the banks, but on Monday said it could not increase  the amount offered because the banks' collateral was weaker now, after  the "no" vote.
Normal commerce is now impossible in Greece. Small businesses, lacking use of credit cards or money from bank accounts, were left to rely on cash coming from diminishing purchases from customers. But Greeks are holding tightly onto what cash they have. And suppliers are demanding that businesses pay cash up front.
In Paris, Merkel and Hollande both expressed respect for Greek voters, but urged swift action from Athens.
"I stress that there is not lots of time left. There is urgency for Greece. There is urgency for Europe," Hollande said.
Spanish Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy said that if Greece is to remain part of the eurozone, it needs to enact reforms that will spur economic growth and pay off its debt.
"We're inclined to help Greece but Greece must follow Europe's rules," he said in an interview on Spain's Telecinco evening news program.
The ongoing Greek drama hurt stocks around the world, particularly in Europe. The losses were not as great as some had feared, however, suggesting investors think that a possible Greek exit from the euro would be manageable for the global economy, though devastating for Greece and destabilizing in Europe.
"The 'no' vote in Greece's referendum on Sunday dramatically increases the risk of a slide toward a disorderly Greek exit from the eurozone," ratings agency Fitch said. "An agreement between Greece and its official creditors remains possible, but time is short and the risk of policy missteps, or that the two sides simply cannot agree on a deal, is high."
Tsipras has agreed to imposing more harsh austerity measures, but he wants eurozone lenders to grant the country better terms for bailout debt repayments.
"The prime minister is ... committed to starting a fundamental debate on dealing with the problem of sustainability of the Greek national debt," a statement signed by the government and three pro-European opposition parties said in a rare sign of solidarity.
Greece, after years of crippling recession and spiraling unemployment, has already been granted 240 billion euros in loans from other eurozone countries. But the spending restraint demanded as a condition for the loans hurt economic growth, and reforms to make Greece more business-friendly have been slower than hoped.
European officials remain split on Greece's demand for easier debt repayment - with lead eurozone lender Germany still reluctant.
James Nixon, chief European economist at Oxford Economics, said there's "a narrow trajectory from here that sees an emboldened Greek parliament accepting the need for reform in return for a debt write-down."
"The next 48 hours will be crucial."
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:24:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuke talks to drag on through 2nd deadline</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/iran-nuclear-talks-deadline-iaea-access-military-sites-arms-embargo-kerry/</Link>
        <Description>Hours before diplomats hoped to have final agreement in place to reign in Tehran's atomic program, officials say it's going to take longer to clear hurdles</Description>
        <MainBody>Pamela Falk, CBS News Foreign Affairs Analyst, discusses the ongoing negotiations to reach a nuclear deal with Iran.
With time running out, Kerry brought the world powers together for the first time in three months. Their central goal remains elusive: convincing Iran to give international inspectors broad access to suspect nuclear sites, including those on military installations.
A top European official said Tuesday that the talks would continue after Tuesday night, but insisted that would not mean the deadline had been missed.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days.This does not mean we are extending our deadline," European Union foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said.
"We are interpreting in a flexible way our deadline, which means that we are taking the time, the days we still need to finalize the agreement, which is something that is still possible even if now we are getting into the difficult time," Mogherini added.
Brennan reports Kerry is to remain in Vienna until Friday, but that he and his team were still very much hoping to get a deal signed for Congress to review in Washington by Thursday.
In exchange for oversight and parred-back enrichment activities, Iran  wants a battery of punishing economic sanctions levied during the last  decade by the international community lifted.
"Access is really important," explains Laura Rockwood, who wrote the access rules for inspectors during her time at the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA), the United Nations' nuclear watchdog.
"The IAEA should have access to military bases. They have access in other countries, at least 10 other countries... there's no exemption, no automatic exemption for access to a military location," Rockwood told Brennan.
Iran wants arms embargo dropped in nuke talks
If access to those key sites is limited, it would make it difficult to prove whether Iran is complying with any final deal the diplomats do reach.
Inside the IAEA in Vienna, new technology is being designed to make cheating on an inspection regime harder than ever: encrypted, real-time cameras are immune to hacking, 3-D laser sensors that register movement of equipment, and highly sensitive radiation detectors are all in the works.
U.S. officials also want to monitor what isn't visible, by questioning Iran's nuclear scientists about how much they know. But Iran is reluctant to make those individuals available because at least five top scientists have been mysteriously killed after their identities were revealed.
Former arms control negotiator Tarik Raouf said just because the U.S. demands it, doesn't mean Iran will comply.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:54:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greeks say "we have a strong voice" despite financial uncertainty</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/greeks-say-we-have-a-strong-voice-despite-financial-anxiety/</Link>
        <Description>Voters rejected the demands of international creditors in a referendum, but potential turmoil awaits</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
ATHENS -- On Sunday, Greek voters said "no" to foreign creditors who demanded strict belt tightening in return for more loans. It was a win for national pride but, in victory, Greeks now confront banks critically short of money and a government can't pay its debts.
Roula Antonopoulou, a Greek pensioner, supported the "no" vote in Sunday's referendum.
CBS News
Greece is on the edge of a financial abyss , but last night there were celebrations after Greek voters rejected the demands of international creditors.
One of them was Roula Antonopoulou, a pensioner.
"At last we can stand up and say here we are, we have a strong voice, and you're going to listen to what we have to say too," she said.
In exchange for an extended $8 billion bailout, Greece's foreign creditors wanted the country to live within its means by increasing taxes and cutting pensions and public spending.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:40:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>​War encircles popular summer vacation spot in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/war-nears-popular-summer-vacation-spot-in-syria/</Link>
        <Description>Latakia is one of the last cities under full government control; but its residents are growing increasingly nervous its stability will soon end</Description>
        <MainBody>ByElizabeth PalmerCBS NewsJuly 6, 2015, 7:21 PM
War encircles popular summer vacation spot in Syria
Shares
More +
CBS News correspondent Elizabeth Palmer traveled to Syria for a rare look at how the country's civil war is impacting its people and cities. Palmer filed this report from Latakia - one of the last remaining areas under full government control.
LATAKIA, Syria -- There are few places left in Syria where a "good shot" has nothing to do with guns, but instead, a score on a volleyball court.
Latakia, on the Mediterranean Sea, is one of the last cities in the country under full government control. If you're Syrian and you can afford it, this is where you come for your summer vacation -- and to block out Syria's vicious war , which is creeping ever closer.
Less than 50 miles away, extremist fighters took the city of Jisr al Shugour in May. Rebel groups now control large areas of countryside.
Men play volleyball in the resort area of Latakia, Syria
CBS News
Only half an hour's drive out of Latakia we found one of the Syrian army posts holding the line. We weren't allowed to film their fighting positions, just the soldiers checking traffic for rebel sympathizers and weapons.
Beyond the Syrian government checkpoint is contested territory.  The Syrian military -- tired and overstretched -- doesn't like to admit it, but things are not going well. Over the past year they've lost ground to ISIS and a whole patchwork of extremist groups.
CBS News correspondent Elizabeth Palmer stands in front of a Syrian army checkpoint in Latakia
CBS News
One man we met, Haeyk, has a family home in government territory. But he tells me his son's school -- just a mile away -- has fallen to the opposition.
"What would happen if you went there?" I asked him.
"Not a chance," he answered. "The snipers would get us."
Latakia's city center is still bustling with life, but everyone here, just like the people on the beach, is afraid that the little pockets of stability remaining are on borrowed time.
Latakia has an extra measure of protection because a majority of the people who live here are big supporters of President Bashar al-Assad and his government, so any rebel attack is bound to meet with ferocious resistance from the population.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:19:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What it's like inside Latakia, Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/what-its-like-inside-latakia-syria/</Link>
        <Description>Latakia is one of the last cities in Syria under full government control</Description>
        <MainBody>What it's like inside Latakia, Syria
July 6, 2015, 6:42 PM
|Latakia is one of the last cities in Syria under full government control. As CBS News correspondent Elizabeth Palmer reports, there are concerns the city's stability could be at risk as fighting nears.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:11:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Will unrest in Greece impact U.S. markets?</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/will-unrest-in-greece-impact-u-s-markets/</Link>
        <Description>As Greece faces a risk of dropping out of the eurozone, there are questions as to what their financial situation will mean for U.S. markets</Description>
        <MainBody>Will unrest in Greece impact U.S. markets?
July 6, 2015, 6:38 PM
|As Greece faces a risk of dropping out of the eurozone, there are questions as to what their financial situation will mean for U.S. markets. CBS News correspondent Anthony Mason takes a look.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:03:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama: Fight against ISIS a long, slow battle</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/obama-fight-against-isis-a-long-slow-battle/</Link>
        <Description>After being briefed at the Pentagon about the latest Islamic State counterstrategies, President Obama declared it will be a long, drawn-out campaign against a "nimble" opponent</Description>
        <MainBody>Obama: Fight against ISIS a long, slow battle
July 6, 2015, 5:47 PM
|After being briefed at the Pentagon about the latest Islamic State counterstrategies, President Obama declared it will be a long, drawn-out campaign against a "nimble" opponent. CBS News White House correspondent Major Garrett disccuses the President's remarks.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:19:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis draws hundreds of thousands in Ecuador</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/pope-francis-draws-hundreds-of-thousands-in-ecuador/</Link>
        <Description>On three-nation South American tour, Latin America's first pope returns to his home soil for a Mass dedicated to the family</Description>
        <MainBody>By Anna MatrangaCBS NewsJuly 6, 2015, 3:19 PM
Pope Francis draws hundreds of thousands in Ecuador
Shares
More +
GUAYAQUIL, Ecuador -- Pope Francis has concluded the first mass of his Latin America trip in Quayaquil, Ecuador, where hundreds of thousands of faithful braved high temperatures and humidity in order to catch a glimpse of him. Guayaquil, Ecuador's major port city, is the nation's financial capital and its biggest city.
Pope Francis waves at the crowd of faithful gathering for an open-air mass at Samanes Park in Guayaquil, Ecuador, on July 6, 2015.
RODRIGO BUENDIA/AFP/Getty Images
The area around the mass, held in a park outside Guayaquil, had a very festive atmosphere, with people selling hats, food and drinks, souvenirs and all kinds of head coverings.  Almost everyone wore a hat or carried an umbrella, due to the intense heat.  Entire families huddled under sheets or blankets to shield themselves.  People of all ages attended.  One father carried his one-month-old daughter in his arms, while his wife held their two small boys by hand; they said this event was too important for them to miss.
Pope Francis is known for doing things no other pope has done before; he's cracked down on abuse in the church; he's washed the feet of female pr...
The service was colorful, incorporating local music and traditions.  In his homily, the pope spoke about the value of the family, saying the family is the foundation of society, "the nearest hospital, the first school for the young, the best home for the elderly." He said the family is where we learn to forgive, even after fighting.
After the mass, Pope Francis heads to a Jesuit school nearby, where he'll spend time with Father Paquito, a 90-year-old Jesuit priest who is an old friend.  Then, he flies back to Quito for a courtesy visit with the President of Ecuador, and a prayer at the Quito Cathedral.
This is the Francis' second trip to Latin America as Pope.  He'll also visit Bolivia and Paraguay, and the entire trip will last 9 days.
Pope Francis greets the crowd of faithful from a popemobile in Quito, Ecuador, July 5, 2015.
REUTERS
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:03:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cyclists injured in Tour De France crashes</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/cyclists-injured-in-tour-de-france-crashes/</Link>
        <Description>The Tour De France was briefly put on hold and several cyclists dropped out of the race entirely after two crashes along the course</Description>
        <MainBody>Cyclists injured in Tour De France crashes
July 6, 2015, 2:50 PM
|The Tour De France was briefly put on hold and several cyclists dropped out of the race entirely after two crashes along the course. CBSN's Anne-Marie Green describes the accidents.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:03:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>President Obama to discusses ISIS at the Pentagon</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/president-obama-to-discusses-isis-at-the-pentagon/</Link>
        <Description>The President is headed to the Pentagon to discuss counterstategies to combat the Islamic State.</Description>
        <MainBody>President Obama to discusses ISIS at the Pentagon
July 6, 2015, 2:51 PM
|The President is headed to the Pentagon to discuss counterstategies to combat the Islamic State. CBS News White House correspondent Major Garrett has the latest from the capitol.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:00:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Massive crash at Tour de France leaves 20 riders on ground</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/tour-de-france-crash-20-riders-fall-several-quit-chris-froome-takes-yellow-jersey/</Link>
        <Description>Some riders lay on their backs in the grass and others were curled up in agony on the hot tarmac</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS/APJuly 6, 2015, 3:01 PM
Massive crash at Tour de France leaves 20 riders on ground
Shares
More +
HUY, Belgium -- British rider Chris Froome took the Tour de France leader's yellow jersey after finishing second behind Spanish veteran Joacquim Rodriguez in Monday's crash-marred third stage, as a second straight day of chaos caused around 20 riders to fall and several to quit.
Filippo Pozzato of Italy and Lampre-Merida adjusts his clothing following a crash near Brabant Wallon during stage three of the 2015 Tour de France, a 159.5 km stage between Anvers and Huy, on July 6, 2015 in Huy, Belgium.
Doug Pensinger, Getty Images
The 2013 Tour winner Froome almost caught Rodriguez near the top of the day's final climb, but the Spaniard held on for his second career Tour stage win five years after his first.
"I didn't expect to be in yellow this early on. Couldn't be a better feeling," said Froome, whose title defense ended when he crashed early in last year's race. "I may look calm on the outside but I assure you I'm not. A huge thank you to my teammates, they turned themselves inside out to keep me at the front."
(L-R) William Bonnet of France riding for FDJ, Simon Gerrans of Australia riding for Orica-GreenEdge, Jose Mendes of Portugal riding for Bora-Argon 18, Greg Henderson of New Zealand riding for Lotto Soudal and Ramon Sinkeldam of the Netherlands riding for Giant-Alpecin lay on the ground after being involved in a crash with 65km remaining in stage three of the 2015 Tour de France from Anvers to Huy on July 6, 2015 in Huy, Belgium.
Doug Pensinger, Getty Images
He now leads German rider Tony Martin - who is not a threat for overall victory  - by just one second and is 13 seconds ahead of American rider Tejay Van Garderen, who is shaping up as a dangerous outsider.
More importantly, Froome's touted main rivals are lagging.
Froome is now 36 seconds clear of two-time champion Alberto Contador of Spain, 1:38 ahead of defending champion Vincenzo Nibali of Italy and 1:56 ahead of Nairo Quintana of Colombia, the Tour runner-up two years ago.
"I'd rather be in this position that I'm in now rather than having to make up time," said Froome, who took the race leader's jersey from Swiss veteran Fabian Cancellara. "I just hope to get through these next few days without any major issues."
Froome's relief was understandable, given how heavy the crash behind him was. It happened with a little under 37 miles remaining, forcing the stage to be neutralized and then stopped altogether shortly after - for nearly 20 minutes.
With the race moving from neighboring Netherlands into Belgium, stage three was 99 miles from Antwerp to Huy. It featured four short and sharp climbs but the crash took place shortly before climb No. 1 when Frenchman William Bonnet's wobbling bike slid forward and down.
Racing at tremendous speed, it was impossible for those behind to either slow down or get out of the way, and one after the other they went up, down, or sideways in a bewildering flash of colors, bobbing helmets and spinning wheels.
The end result was a tangled mess of bikes, spewed in all directions. Some riders lay on their backs in the grass and others were curled up in agony on the hot tarmac.
Cancellara was one of the last to go down, leaping into the air with his bike attached to him, then landing with a thud: the grass landing saving him from being more seriously hurt.
Huge crash. Cancellara down but back up riding. Lots others involved. Follow live: http://t.co/TpLnnXG6Gl #TDF2015 pic.twitter.com/fyoHmenjOb
 Sky Sports Cycling (@SkyCycling) July 6, 2015
Bonnet was taken off on a stretcher with a brace around his neck. Dutch rider Tom Dumoulin - competing for the best young rider's white jersey - Australian veteran Simon Gerrans, and Russian Dmitry Kozontchuk also withdrew from the stage and race.
As the pack up ahead waited, riders started coming back: cuts and bruises decorating their backs and legs. According to CBSSports.com, Cancellara  was able to continue despite feeling "groggy," said  Alain Gallopin,  who is a sports director for Cancellara's Trek Factory  Racing team.
Cancellara grimaced in pain, Australian Michael Matthews looked to be in tears, and it was hard to see which team Johan Van Summeren was riding for given how shredded his shirt was.
The stage re-started for good with about 31 miles remaining. But it almost seemed like a training ride as no rider wanted to speed up.
Finally, about a dozen riders surged ahead.
Exhausted, the others let them go.
After taking chunks of time out of Nibali and Quintana on Sunday's rain-soaked and wind-battered second stage, Froome did it again as he accelerated in the last climb.
"It's never too early to take the yellow jersey," Froome said. "Really happy to come second and put more time on my GC (general classification) contenders."
Rodriguez and Froome clocked the same time of 3 hours, 26 minutes, 54 seconds. Frenchman Alexis Vuillermoz was third, four seconds behind them.
The day's final two climbs - 0.8 miles - up Cote de Cherave and the Mur du Huy featured on this year's Fleche Wallonne (Walloon Arrow) classic - which Rodriguez has previously won and where Froome crashed in this year's race.
Froome had better luck this time, gaining 11 seconds on Nibali and Quintana and 18 seconds on Contador.
"Froome is very strong and he's come here in good form," Contador said.
Tuesday's fourth stage stays in Belgium's Walloon region, starting out from Seraing, and ending in the northern French town of Cambrai 138.6 miles later. With 8 miles of cobblestone sections dotted around the route, it could also prove treacherous.
"There have been nerves and stress every day," Contador said. "Tomorrow will be the same."
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:33:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In nuclear talks, Iran renews call to end arms embargo</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/nuclear-talks-iran-renews-call-to-end-arms-embargo/</Link>
        <Description>With the deadline fast approaching, the Islamic Republic revisits old grievance</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS/APJuly 6, 2015, 11:37 AM
In nuclear talks, Iran renews call to end arms embargo
Ministers sit around the table at the Palais Coburg Hotel where the Iran nuclear talks meetings are being held in Vienna, Austria, on July 6, 2015.
JOE KLAMAR/AFP/Getty Images
More +
VIENNA - A day before the new deadline for a nuclear accord , Iran pushed Monday to lift the U.N. arms embargo on the country as a parallel deal - a demand that the United States opposes as it seeks to limit Tehran's Mideast clout.
Speaking on the eve of a belated target date for a complete agreement , a senior Iranian official said his country and the six world powers it is negotiating with are also working on a U.N. resolution that endorses any future nuclear deal.
The nuclear negotiations with Iran could go either way if Iran does not bend on critical remaining issues. The latest adjusted deadline is just t...
CBS News correspondent Margaret Brennan reports that the pace of talks has been slowing as the July 7 deadline near. There has, however, been significant headway made on the topics of sanctions, as well as the possibility of an investigation into whether Iran has already tried to make a nuclear weapon.
Lifting the arms embargo would be separate from a long-term accord that foresees limits on Iran's nuclear programs in exchange for relief from crippling sanctions on the Islamic Republic. But Iran also sees existing U.N. resolutions imposed on Iran's nuclear program and the accompanying sanctions as unjust and illegal. It has insisted that those resolutions be lifted since the start of international negotiations nearly a decade ago to limit its nuclear-arms making capability.
After world powers and Iran reached a framework pact in April, the U.S. said "important restrictions on conventional arms and ballistic missiles" would be incorporated in any new U.N. guidelines for Iran.
Negotiators and some foreign ministers of the six world powers plus Iran gathered in Vienna to complete a comprehensive nuclear deal by June 30. When they couldn't reach agreement by then, they agreed to extend the deadline to July 7. But many core issues remain, and an announcement on Tuesday is unlikely.
While the discussions have been focused on uranium stockpiles and the timing for lifting economic sanctions, Iran's long-standing desire to have the arms embargo lifted at the signing of a deal is another wrinkle thrown into the mix.
Russia and China have expressed support for lifting the embargo, which was imposed in 2007 as part of a series of penalties over its nuclear program.
But the U.S. doesn't want the arms ban ended because it could allow Tehran to expand its military assistance to Syrian President Bashar Assad's embattled government , for the Houthi rebels in Yemen and Hezbollah in Lebanon. It also would increase already stalwart opposition to the deal in Congress and in Israel.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:29:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>"Sea of blood": Airstrike hits Yemen market, killing dozens of civilians</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/airstrike-hits-yemen-market-killing-dozens-of-civilians/</Link>
        <Description>Officials say Saudi-led airstrikes against the rebels continued across the country, with nine provinces and the capital hit</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS News correspondent Clarissa Ward was among the first set of journalists to enter Yemen -- a country in the midst of a civil war. Ward spoke t...
Last month, CBS News' Clarissa Ward had a rare look at the destruction wrought inside the country by weeks of fighting and relentless Saudi airstrikes. Upon landing at Sanaa's airport, the first thing Ward and her team saw was an airplane sitting on the tarmac, nearly cut in half by a missile.
The Old City, in the heart of the capital, dates back more than 2,500 years. The area has now been hit by the airstrike . Resident Abdullah Kakalla showed Ward his family home, which was destroyed by a strike just days earlier.
"They destroy our people for not any reason," said Kakalla, asking sardonically, "Is this a military site?"
The conflict has left 20 million Yemenis without access to safe drinking water and uprooted over one million people from their homes, the United Nations said. Last Wednesday, it declared its highest-level humanitarian emergency in the country, where over 80 percent of the population needs assistance.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:03:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British Princess Charlotte Elizabeth Diana of Cambridge christened</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/british-princess-charlotte-elizabeth-diana-of-cambridge-christened/</Link>
        <Description>The newest British royal was christened in a ceremony steeped in British tradition</Description>
        <MainBody>British Princess Charlotte Elizabeth Diana of Cambridge christened
July 6, 2015, 9:46 AM
|The newest British royal was christened in a ceremony steeped in British tradition. CBS News' royal contributor Victoria Arbiter talks to CBSN about the little princess.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
